Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hey, this is Season 1, Episode 1 of the Virtual Coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah and this a podcast that features members of the community.
Bekah: Virtual Coffee is an intimate group of developers at all stages of their coding journey,
Bekah: And we're here to share that with you.
Here with me today is my co host, Dan, how's it going Dan?
Dan Ott: It's going pretty good. Thanks, Becca.
Today, we have a great episode. We're going to hear from Nick Taylor.
Dan: Nick is a Software Engineer at Forum, the company behind Dev.
He's a big fan of TypeScript, JavaScript, React,  Preact, and Node.
Dan: Once upon a time, he was into C# and ASP.net.
Aside from programming, he enjoys hitting the gym, snowboarding, and a long, long time ago, Rugby.
Dan: Nick is also one of our first members.
He's been in Virtual Coffee since nearly the beginning.
Dan: He's [Nick] helped us out in many ways.
He's been a note taker, and a room leader, a mentor, and open source maintainer and an all around awesome human being.
Dan: So Nick is going to talk about live streaming and open source
And he will share with us his approach to life which he calls structured YOLO.
Bekah: We start every episode like we start every virtual coffee
We introduce ourselves with our name, where we're from what we do and a random check in question.
Bekah: Today's question is
What is one thing that are you afraid of?
Dan: We hope you enjoy this episode of Virtual Coffee podcast
Bekah: Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end developer from a small town in Ohio.
And one of my biggest fears is waffle bridges.
Dan: Hi I am Dan. I am a front end developer from Clevland, Ohio.
And one of my biggest fears is hornets.
Nick Taylor: Hornets[silence]
Dan: Don't like them [silence] yeah
Nick: My name is Nick Taylor. I'm a senior software engineer at Forem
And I say one of my biggest fears is heights.
Nick: I am not a fan of heights.
I remember in grade six,
I cried at the bottom of the CN Tower because I had a hard time going up.
Nick: And it was traumatic
Bekah: [giggles] Oh no
Nick: So you wanna know how I ended up?
Bekah: Yeah, yeah. Let's start with your origin story.
Bekah: How'd you get into programming?
Nick: Uhh [pauses] I don't know.
Nick: I feel like it's a [pauses] classic story
Of uhh [pauses] somebody who has no idea what they wanna do.
**Do tomorrow**
software development. Because
think of a recipe is kind of
like building a website, like,
"Oh, I know I need this piece.
But what if I don't know how to
do this piece? I'll go look it
up, go watch a YouTube video."
And then eventually, you get to
a place where you're like,
comfortable. "Oh, I can make
cookies now without looking at
the recipe. I can make this, I
can
do -- I can create a modal, I
can do the CSS Grid without
really
having to go to the
documentation every single
time."
Bekah: And Tori Crawford about
the problems of
interviewing in the industry.
Tori Crawford: Interviewing was
crazy for me. I think I went
through 53 interviews. Yeah, it
was, like, quite a struggle at
times.
Dan: You also get a special
bonus episode that we recorded
live after Hacktoberfest.
Kirk Shillingford: Hacktoberfest
happened because we were like,
"Hey, we wanna do something
good," you know? And then people
were like, "I don't wanna do
this with strangers, but I
wouldn't mind doing it with-
with everybody here." And I
think
that's like very important.
Like, I wouldn't have done this
with
people who I didn't consider,
like, friends, and good people.
Bekah: Best of all, you'll get
to hear so much
of the heart that goes into the
community. And we're very
excited to share that with you.
Dan: If you'd like to learn more
about Virtual Coffee,
please check out our website at
virtualcoffee.io or say hi to us
on Twitter @VirtualCoffeeIO and
we will talk to you soon!