Bekah: Hey, this is season one
episode, one of the
Virtual Coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah and this is a podcast
that features
members of the community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
to share their stories and talk
about what they've learned.
And we're here to share that
with you here with
me today as my co-host Dan,
how's it going, Dan?
It's going
Dan: pretty good.
Thanks.
Bekah.
Um, today we have a really great
episode.
We're gonna hear from Nick
Taylor.
Uh, Nick is a senior software
engineer at forum.
Uh, the company behind dev.
He's a big fan of type script,
JavaScript, uh,
react and pre-ACT and node.
Um, once upon a time he was into
C sharp and esp.net.
Aside from programming, he
enjoys hitting the
gym snowboarding and a long,
long time ago.
Rugby Nick is also one of our
first members.
He is.
Been in Virtual Coffee since
nearly the beginning, he has
helped us out in, uh, many ways.
He's been a note taker and a
room leader, a mentor, an open
source maintainer, and an all
around awesome human being.
So Nick is gonna talk about live
streaming and open
source, and he will share with
us his approach to life,
which he calls structured.
Yo.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast.
Like we start every Virtual
Coffee.
We introduce ourselves with our
name where we're
from, what we do and a random
check-in question.
Today's question is what is one
thing you are afraid
Dan: of?
We hope you'll enjoy this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
Nick: podcast.
Bekah: Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a
front end developer
from a small town in Ohio.
And one of my biggest fears is
waffle bridges.
Dan: Hi, I am Dan.
I am a front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio, and one of
my biggest fears is Hornets.
Don't
Nick: like 'em.
Ah, yeah.
My name is Nick Taylor.
I'm a senior software engineer
at forum and.
I'd say my, one of my biggest
fears is Heights.
I am not a big fan of Heights.
Uh, I remember in grade six, I
cried at the bottom of the scene
tower because I had a hard time
going up and it was traumatic.
Oh no.
So you wanna know how I ended up
Bekah: yeah.
Yeah.
Let's start with your origin
story.
How'd you get into programming.
Nick: Uh, it's I don't know.
I feel like it's a classic story
of, uh, somebody who has
no idea what they wanna do.
Um, I, I had a computer.
Like we had computers when I was
younger, like, uh, had
a V 20 I'm a little older.
So that's like bef I think that
was before the Commodor
64 or after I can't remember the
order, but, you know,
so it was, that was fun as a
kid, just doing stuff like
printing your name multiple
times over the screen.
And, uh, we eventually got like
a, a clone PC, which was,
seemed to be the, the big thing
in the day in the eighties.
Uh, The actual, like, I guess, I
guess it would've been
IBM machines were a lot more
expensive and, uh, Didn't
really do too much on there.
Like my, my dad's an accountant
and financial planner, so he
he's always like working in
spreadsheets and stuff and we
didn't really have any games.
So like I was making pie charts
in Lotus 1, 2, 3, and
I just thought that was cool on
a monochrome, uh, monitor.
But, uh, and then eventually got
a, a couple, couple
games there and like a clone
pack, man, a lot of stuff.
But that was, that was kind of
like my early
introduction to computers.
Uh, but I honestly was never
like a diehard programmer.
Um, it was only a really, once I
got to C J, C E is like, it's
like the last two years of high
school in the states, I guess.
It's we don't have like a grade
12 grade 13.
So you, you go to grade 11.
And you can either go straight
to university.
Like if you go out of province
or out of country,
but if you're in Quebec, you,
you typically need to
do these, um, which is where I'm
from, I'm from Montreal.
Um, but I.
Basically, I ended up bombing my
first semester cuz uh,
I was dating somebody and I was
just doing that and
playing rugby pretty much.
Um, and then after failing my
first semester, I just kinda got
back on track a bit and I was in
creative arts, which at the
time there was like, literally
take any courses you want.
And I was always.
Pretty pretty good at math.
So I ended up taking, uh, Cal
one and Cal two courses and
I took a C plus plus course.
And, uh, literally the only
reason why I ended
up going into computer science,
the only reason why
I did was like I did okay.
In that C plus plus course.
And.
but it wasn't anything special.
It's like, I think I remember
one of the final exercises was
like making a Christmas tree
outta stars, you know, and
it's, you're just basically
repeating it, but, uh, yeah,
that's, that's really kind of
how I got into programming,
I guess, which I know that
doesn't sound that exciting.
Um, I.
but the exciting part for me was
there was the, there was
no web courses at the time.
Like I was in university when it
was always just
like, learn about databases,
data structures, uh,
operating systems and.
There was everything web.
I literally learnt on my own.
I remember opening no joke,
notepad dot exc in a, in
a cracked version of, uh,
windows, uh, server 2000
I think, or something.
And I just started learning
HTML, JavaScript,
and CSS through there.
And you know, the computer.
Background helped, but, uh, I
probably could have done
a lot better in school, but I, I
was doing a lot
of sports and stuff too.
I, I was pretty active playing
rugby, so, um, but
yeah, that's, that's, that's my
boring origin story for
getting into programming.
It's not like, yeah.
I was like hacking the matrix
when I was two or something.
but, uh, but the funny thing is
once I finished school,
I felt like I was learning more
outside of school.
Like I was actually motivated to
learn outta
school when I was in school.
I wasn't as motivated.
So it's, uh, it's kind of funny,
uh, in that respect.
And then it's pretty much just
gone from there.
Uh, I've been mostly, I'd say
about two thirds of my career
has been in the.net ecosystem.
So, uh, well, even before.net,
before.net, there was
something called ASSP.
So active server pages and you.
They even had JS script, which
was like Microsoft's
version of JavaScript and there
was VB script.
So you could program pages.
It's, it's kind of like PHP kind
of, and then.net came
out and then you ended up with
asp.net, which, uh, and then, so
that's the whole.net ecosystem.
And I basically was in the area
up until about 2016.
But I was, was a big fan of
JavaScript and I like the
web stuff and I just happened to
be in the.net ecosystem
cuz that's just where jobs ended
up coming from.
Like somebody I knew and say,
oh, why don't
you come work here now?
And um, but yeah, when I, when I
hit 2016, I had this
opportunity to I'd already.
Been doing, uh, kind of more
full stack at that point, uh,
and, uh, had an opportunity to
take a, a role as a front
end dev doing react and type
script for this FinTech startup.
And I haven't looked back since
then.
Like, I mean, uh, everything
pretty much is front end for me.
Now I can, I mean, I have no
problem working in back end if I
need to, but for now, at least.
Super stoked about working in
the front end and like,
like anything, always lots to
learn there still, even if
I've been around for a while.
So
Bekah: yeah.
I love that.
I think that's really great.
And I like that, you know,
you've been here for a while,
but you've done a lot of
different things and you have
a good understanding of, um, you
know, where you're going
and what you're interested in.
And I think that, you know,
that's really, um, a fun and
interesting thing to talk about.
Nick: Yeah, I, I find, uh, I
find I've been able slowly
over time to figure out what I
don't wanna do, which is good.
So
Dan: that's that's that sounds
familiar.
yeah, that, that's sort of how
I've I, that sounds familiar to
me, you know, I've, I've done
end up doing the same thing.
I make more decisions based on,
yeah, I don't wanna do that
then, then practical, like,
okay, this is the thing that
I'm going to do, you know?
Yeah.
Served me, served me pretty well
too.
Nick: Yeah, for sure.
And, and the front end right
now, I feel like, I mean, uh, I
mean the tech space in general
is, well, I guess, I guess
it's a little different cuz of
the pandemic, but I at least
what I've seen, like excluding
the pandemic for now, uh, like
just front end jobs typically.
Just like everywhere.
Everybody's O I mean, a lot of
'em are always asking for
react because that's like pretty
much the dominant front end
framework right now, I would
say, but, uh, but still like
just lots of opportunities.
So I don't know.
I feel like I transitioned to
doing that.
At, uh, at the right time.
So,
Bekah: yeah, and I love that
idea.
I know when I was learning, so,
you know, I'm a
newer programmer, but
everybody's like, well,
what do you want to do?
Like, what do you really like?
But nobody says like, what don't
you like?
Right.
Um, and I think that could be a
really great way to
kind of narrow it down.
It's a different approach to
things, but, um, you know,
ideally you find a job that you
enjoy doing and that's what
kind of creates longevity and
helps you to avoid burnout.
And that type of.
Nick: Yeah, for sure.
And it's yeah.
It's but I feel like it, it it's
honestly, only something you
can really get with experience.
I think, because like, cuz I've
been working
in at like my first real
programming job was in 2002.
So I've been in the space for
like about 18 years now.
So.
You know, if you asked me as a
junior, I wouldn't
say, uh, you know, this is not
what I wanna do.
My first job.
I just took it without asking
any questions because I was
just happy to get a job.
So.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's
great.
I know that I really hated react
when I was doing it.
And that's pretty much all I've
done.
So I guess that there are times
that you find things
that you, you enjoy, even if you
initially don't like them.
Um, I would love to know how you
found out about Virtual Coffee,
because I, I, this is how I met
you and I just wanna know,
like, how did you end up here?
Nick: Yeah, well, uh, you know,
I think, uh, as we all know,
2020 is a dumpster fire, uh,
for, for many, many reasons,
but predominantly the pandemic.
Um, and I actually remember, I
didn't know you at the
time, but, uh, I'm generally
pretty active on Twitter.
And because I work at forum,
which was previously dev
I'm, I'm usually interacting a
lot with, I, I tend to
interact with the community a
lot and I remember.
I only saw this in hindsight,
but I, I, I realized that,
uh, I was actually responding to
some of your questions
on code newbie at one point.
Uh, and then I, I forget when
you posted it, but
you had your initial.
Uh, tweet that was like, Hey,
Virtual Coffee,
come check it out.
And I said yes to the first one,
but then something came
up, I think, at a, something for
work or something had
a appointment or something.
And so I couldn't make it.
And then I, I think the next one
you had, I said,
Hey, I'm free again.
And I, I just basically
contacted you out of the blue.
I, I think I sent you a DM or I
responded directly
in the tweak cause.
Because we weren't following
each other at the time,
but, um, it was pretty much
that, you know, uh, I.
I'm a, I'm a pretty sociable
person.
And like outside of, I mean, I'm
working full remote now,
even pre pandemic, but you know,
I'll go out for drinks,
grab coffee with friends, or,
you know, do stuff.
Um, and.
Obviously cuz of the pandemic,
not a lot of that is happening
or none of it is happening.
So I was just like, I dunno, I
was just like, Yolo,
you know, Hey, whatever, let's
go check it out.
And, uh, it was one of the best
things that happened
to me in 2020, honestly, uh, met
a lot of great.
Folks like your both view and
just, I really enjoy the
community and it's, it's kind of
really cool to see how
it's grown and because we know
each other a lot better now,
too, you know, it's because
those initial conversations
in a, in the Virtual Coffee, or
like the slack chat, you
know, people don't really know
how people are, so
it's, uh, but you can tell.
People people know who's who
now.
So it's.
Yeah, no, I just love it.
Bekah: Yeah.
I, I love it too.
And who knew, who knew that, you
know, in, in April I
would, um, lose my job because
Dan would fire me and then
Nick: I didn't fire you.
Bekah: I mean, it's, it's
semantics, right?
Like I work for Dan's important
semantics.
Dan was like, Hey, we don't have
work anymore.
So call it what you want.
Um, Uh, but yeah, like it
started there and it
was like, okay, well I need to
be around people.
And now we're recording a
podcast.
Right?
Like nowhere in my mind.
Did I ever think that this was
gonna be where we would be,
you know, eight months later?
Yeah,
Nick: yeah.
No, a lot of stuff.
I mean, the podcast is amazing.
Uh, we we've been doing brown
bags.
Uh, we just did, the lightning
talks was last Thursday, right?
Yeah.
Friday.
I think yeah.
Yeah.
Um, yeah, so just lots of stuff
going on and it's, uh, you know,
people are always like, Hey,
let's try this or let's do this.
Or, you know, or if somebody
brings up something like, oh,
that'd be a good brown bag.
You know?
So, uh, I think it's, it's just
been a, just a
really cool experience for
everybody, you know, like,
because it's kind of like a.
Almost like a mini Twitter or
it's, it's a, it's a
mini commun basically.
So, uh, it's kind of nice.
Yeah.
You know?
Dan: Yeah.
That like size of it is, is one
of my, I don't know one
of the things I like too, that
sort of what everybody
kind of knows each other, like
you were saying.
Yeah, it's been cool.
It's been cool.
Kind of being around, you know,
since, since it, like, since it
started, you know, seeing kind
of everybody become close, but
you know, grow a little bit too.
Nick: Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Bekah: Yeah.
And I think, you know, being
able to meet developers, you
know, I'm a new developer and
I'm a mom of four kids, so it
is not like I get out that much.
Right.
Like my kids are young, so
people are like go to meetups
and meet people or conferences.
And, you know, it's only doable
for, um, so many people.
Right.
And that was not something that
was doable for me.
And so I missed that community,
a.
I learned online in a like
self-paced program and
there wasn't that community.
And so like finding people here
at all stages has been such a
great way to learn and grow.
Dan: Yeah.
Yeah.
The other thing about going to,
uh, like events and
stuff is they're, they're just
like they come and go,
you know, and then it's.
I don't know.
Yeah.
But sometimes you make friends,
you know, but
most of the time not
Right.
Uh, so they, even if it's a
great event and then
when you go home, it's, I don't
know, then you're
back to your job and stuff.
Um, that's one of the like, nice
things about this, this
sort of ongoing community.
Yeah.
Nick: Yeah, I find it's
consistent, cuz like we meet,
I mean, for those who don't
know, we, we have two Virtual
Coffees, uh, one on Tuesdays and
Thursdays and I typically
try to go to both of them.
I usually I miss a Tuesday one
if I have an all hands
meeting for work, cuz I, I work
in a distributed company.
So like cuz the time zones we
alternate.
The time of the all hands on the
Tuesday and sometimes
it's on Wednesday, but, uh, so I
think like once every
three weeks I have to miss a
Virtual Coffee, but, uh, I look
forward to them and I, and I
feel kind of down when I miss
one  it sounds kind of funny.
It's like, uh, I dunno.
Like crack cocaine.
I don't know.
Bekah: um, there have been a
couple of times where I, I
thought I was gonna miss and it
was like, I'm, I'm gonna miss.
And then I would like log in
from my phone or
rush home or whatever.
Um, so I've been super excited
to make all of them except
this week is Thanksgiving.
So I think I will be missing my
first one,
American Thanksgiving.
Um, oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
But, but don't worry.
The show will go on and we will
have a, a host for everybody.
Um, Nick, I wanna dig into a
little bit of some of the cool
stuff that I think you're doing.
Um, you have been really great
with our community.
We did the hack Tober Fest
initiative where we.
Um, worked with community
members to, uh, work on HEC
Tober Fest, where they're trying
to get, uh, four pool requests
into open source projects.
And we set up mentorship and we
worked with maintainers
and, um, And the contributors as
well, and you pretty
much played a role in all three
of those things.
Um, you contributed to my open
source project.
And I wanna say like, I, that
was really great to
have somebody who has a good
idea and understanding of
what it's like to, um, be an
open source maintainer.
And so.
You contributed to my project
and at the same time,
mentored me as a maintainer.
um, and I just wanna say, first
of all, thank you.
And second of all, um, can you
talk a little bit about
your experience in open source
and the things that you've
learned and maybe some things
that, um, contributors and
maintainers can kind of learn.
Nick: Yeah, for sure.
Um, I got into open source in,
it was either 20.
I think it was 2015, maybe 2016,
but I, I think
it was like late 2015.
I, uh, It was, I'd never
contributed to
open source at all.
At that point, I didn't know,
get, because I was
working in the.net ecosystem
and@thetimelikemicrosoftisopensourcenowintermsofthe.net
framework and all that.
And, uh, they've.
They've they used it heavily
now, but prior to that, I was
in other, uh, source control,
um, systems like, uh, for
those who are really old, there
was one from Microsoft
called visual source safe, which
got corrupt all the time.
And so like, your, your code
base would sometimes just kind
of go in the dumpster, but, um,
worked in like SVN and then
TFS, which is team foundation
server from Microsoft.
So.
The first thing that was.
The way it happened was I was
like, this was kind
of my, I wanna really just focus
on front end.
And I had started messing around
with media.
Media is like a, it's a
universal JavaScript framework.
It's, it's changed a bit over
the years, uh, for those who
are in the react ecosystem,
Apollo like GraphQL that
actually came from media.
Um, um, and then some other
projects.
Uh, I was like, yeah, I'm gonna
mess around with this.
So it was like literally
JavaScript everywhere.
It was MongoDB for the database.
You'd write code on the front
end and JavaScript obviously,
and note in the back end.
And then you could also have
certain parts of the
code that you could share that
could be used server
side and client side.
So maybe something, for example,
like client side
validation, you could do it on.
Well, not just client side
validation, validation, you
could do it on both sides.
So I, I just started messing
around with that.
And then, but I really didn't
know anything about it.
And.
I forget where I saw this
posted.
It was on some message board.
I, I really can't remember where
I think it
actually might have been.
I think media at the time had
job boards or like some kind
of community board, maybe.
I, I think that's where it came
from.
Somebody from San Francisco who
I did not know, just said,
uh, I have a paying gig for.
Media and it's working in open
source.
And I just said yes, even though
I didn't  didn't know
it really, uh, this, this is
kind of where my journey
of structured Yolo begins.
Um, so yeah, I just said, yeah.
And then I met up with him, uh,
uh, we ended up being
a team of five people.
We were working on this really
cool application
that was called push pickup.
So it.
It was web tech, but the idea
was to make it a mobile app.
And it was like, if you wanna
play basketball, you can
just find friends around you
and, and organize a game.
Cuz there's, there's several
sports platforms.
Now I think to do this kind of
thing, but this was
like, it just seemed like a
better way of doing it.
And so that was the project.
And then.
I remember, like I got some code
working and I'm like,
okay, first poll request ever.
Uh, I I'm like, I gotta make it
perfect all this stuff.
And of course it wasn't perfect.
I messed something up.
And then this is pre like
prettier days and ES Lynn.
So then there was a lot of, can
you change this
formatting and stuff too?
So basically.
It wasn't a disaster, but it was
like not great.
Um, but you know, uh, continuing
on with the structured Yolo,
I just kept going and just kept
contributing and, and
then I react was out at the time
it came well, react came
out in 2013, I believe at.
The F eight conference or was it
2015?
I can't remember.
Um, anyways, uh, react was like
the hot new thing and I was
like, I need to learn react.
So, uh, like I've mentioned to
you before, I'm not really
good at starting projects.
I'm good at jumping onto
projects.
So I found this, uh, react
boiler.
Boiler plate project that used
Redux, uh, it was called react.
Slingshot still exists in a, uh,
is by Cory house.
Who's a react consultant.
He's I would say he's.
I mean, it depends whenever I
think people are well known.
Like a lot of people are like, I
have no idea who
you're talking about, but he
seems to be, he's pretty
active in the react ecosystem.
He used to do a lot of.net.
He's a plural site author, all
that stuff.
So I just started contribut.
and I think after my 13th poll
request, he's like, oh, Hey, uh,
do you wanna become a maintainer
and, and small world, this
is also how I met Kyle Welch.
He's actually a maintainer on
there as well.
So that's, that was my kind of
first kind of deep dive into.
I mean post post the media
project.
Um, and it was cool that I was
asked to be a maintainer and I
was just like, you know what,
I'm just gonna say yes, cuz I
just thought it was interesting.
And there was three of us on the
project.
So, so this is like kind of one
of the first points
of like, if you're working in
open source, uh, Ken
Dodds does this very well.
He will.
He'll create really great
projects, but Kent see,
DODs does not scale.
Nobody scales like at, at the
level of when
people are, are asking for
fixing things and stuff.
So typically at least from what
I've seen, Kent will make
like a great project, like his
most recent one, like the
whole testing library stuff.
Um, and then he'll, I.
Typically, what he'll do is kind
of what I mentioned is
people start contributing and he
probably, he just
asked him, Hey, do you wanna
become a maintainer?
And then all of a sudden you're
scaling because
you have all these other
maintainers and they're people
that are interested in the
project, cuz they were most
likely contributing to it.
So, um, So that's kind of like
story slash also first advice
about if, if you wanna create a
project, that's, you know,
I, if it's your own personal
project, you know, maybe that's
not something you need right
now, but as soon as your thing
potentially gets popular or
start, or you notice it's
starting to pick up steam it's I
would say it's definitely
a good idea to at least.
One of the folks that contribute
to your project
to become a maintainer.
Um, and yeah, that was, there
was that.
And then there was.
Little other bits, like, uh, I
wrote a post about
this, but like even
documentation's important.
And I remember in 2016, when I
was working at this
FinTech, uh, we were working in
electron and I was trying to do
something and it wasn't working.
And then I realized there was an
error in the
documentation and electron.
So mm-hmm,  just, I started
doing like little poll
requests, stuff like that.
I
Bekah: wanna like, just pause
for a second
because I think that.
Gave us so much great
information.
And I like wanna make sure that
that all of this
stuff gets highlighted.
One of the things that I find
like super inspirational, I
love your, um, Structured Yolo.
Nick: Yeah.
Structured.
Yeah.
I coined that last week.
I forget what way, but
Bekah: yeah.
And that's great.
Like, I, I think that's
wonderful because I think for
a lot of new developers or
probably like just lots of
developers in general, like
there's this fear of trying
something out and failing right.
Or of, you know, not doing it
right.
Or like, I remember when I.
Started working like my husband
is a developer too, and I would.
Type out a message.
And then I'd be like, can I read
this to you?
Does it make sense at all?
Like, am I saying the things in
the right ways?
Right.
You know, cause you're learning
an entirely new vocabulary,
but I think that getting over
that hump and that fear of not.
Saying it right or not doing the
poor request, right.
Is like half of the battle to
becoming more confident
as a developer and like that
attitude of structured Yolo, um,
I think really would benefit.
I like, I want your structured
Yolo course.
So when you drop that, can you
let us know?
And we'll put it out there for
everybody.
Nick: yeah, my, uh, masterclass
along with, uh,
Tom Morelo from rag gain some
machines, guitar class.
Yep, sure.
Bekah: No problem.
Yep.
Right there.
I want it.
Um, but I think that that's
great.
And I think that's really
helpful to hear your story about
that and to hear like, Hey, like
you might not have gotten it.
Perfect.
And, but also like you're
talking about.
You're you're using, um, this
open source project
and they didn't get it right in
the documentation
or something changed.
Right.
And I think that also as a new
developer, there's this tendency
to believe that everything that
you see on the screen is
the right way of doing things.
But sometimes things change.
Or sometimes it's, it's not
documented, right.
Or, you know, a better way of
doing things.
And so, you know, realizing that
you have value in
where you are at your stage is
really important too.
And I think that you captured
that a lot.
Nick: Oh, thanks.
Thanks.
Yeah.
That's the other thing, because
all these
things are open source.
It's like, it, it, the software
is not perfect.
Like there there's tons of great
projects.
I don't, I'm not, I I'm not, I
don't mean that in a
negative way, but like I've.
I've ran into issues like, uh,
with Webpack, for example,
it ended up being my fault, but
because the code was
open source, I, I was able to
literally debug in the
Webpack code because when you
install Webpack, it goes in
your node models and it's, it's
literally all the source code.
So you can actually.
Debugging in that cause like I
was, I had this
Webpac loader for anybody that's
familiar with Webpac.
Um, and it wasn't doing what it
was supposed to.
And then, because I was able to
go in the code and step through,
I, I actually figured out that
the, the configuration options
for that loader were wrong.
Like I had done something wrong
and I, I probably didn't read
the documentation probably.
So that's probably my bad too.
But, um, I, I think that's the
cool thing about open source,
uh, you know, uh, It just
helping, you know, there's,
there's another side to it.
There's the whole burnout thing,
which is a whole other topic.
Uh, I personally haven't
experienced it because.
One where I am now.
It's like, my job is to work in
opensource.
Like I'm paid to work in
So it's, it's not like, like,
you know, when like Sebastian
McKenzie who created babble, uh,
used to be, uh, six to five,
the project, but like, it was
literally just him initially.
And then he abandoned the
project because he, he
literally got so burnt out
because it's babble is like,
literally in probably any modern
front end project.
Like it, like it's everywhere,
you know?
And so, but that, that ties into
getting more maintainers into
your project as well, you know?
Um, but at the end of the day,
too, you know, and I talk about
this in my talk, getting the
most outta open source that
I did for Octoberfest is, you
know, a lot of people it's,
you know, Take take take, or
just like, you know, this
doesn't work, fix it, or why
isn't this merged yet, yet?
It's like people sometimes
forget that there's people
behind the projects, you know?
So you have to, like, one of the
things they talk about
is like, like, don't forget, you
know, like somebody might
be on vacation, they might be
sick, you know, like they're
doing it on their own time, you
know, unless it's a.
Project or like some kind of
Patreon or like it's
your actual job to be paid to
work in open source.
So, you know, it's just stuff.
I think that folks forget
sometimes, you know, and
like, and one of my favorite.
Things to do is if anybody's
ever snarky is you can
just say, oh, thanks.
You know, would you like to
create a poll request
or , you know, so you're not,
it, it's kind of like a, a
nice, a funny way to sh to kind
of shut down an asshole.
Yeah.
I look forward to your poll
request.
yeah, yeah, exactly.
So, uh, you know, But yeah, no,
Dan: it's, uh, I think that
what, what you're saying about
remembering people are behind,
you know, is, is important.
And I, I feel like, um, another
thing that I have like been,
I don't know, trying to figure
out how to sort of communicate
to people is remembering that
like, just because somebody
has been a developer for a long
time doesn't mean that they.
Know everything or are better
or, you know, like experts or
anything, you know what I mean?
And so, like, it's sort of what
Bekah was saying before.
Like, you know, just like
learning to trust yourself,
um, and your judgment, you know,
as you, as you and your
abilities as you, uh, become a
more experienced developer,
you know, I, I feel like is one
of those like big steps,
big, important steps, um, and
something that I've been
trying to figure out how to help
people with, you know, As
they start out, you know, as
they start out their career.
Nick: Um, for sure.
Cuz like a lot of it could just
be like from experience
you like you, you know, certain
things because they've
happened to you, but like you.
I'm, I'm not really good at
animations, but it's
because I haven't really had to
ever really do them.
It's not because I'm horrible at
them.
It's just, I haven't had enough
time to really
dedicate it to it.
But I think, I think what you
get better at too is Scott.
I'm dropping like names here,
but like Scott Hanson
gave a, a great talk.
Code land this year.
And he's just talking about cuz
he's, he's been in the space
for like a long, long time.
And he was just saying like, you
get better, you know, he
wasn't saying why I'm better
than you, but I, I can't
remember exactly how he said,
but he's, he's basically said
I'm older now I have experience,
but I know how to Google
better than you, you know?
So like, cuz it's true.
Like half the time, like you'll
get an error.
It's like you're gonna paste in
that error.
You're gonna go see almost
always.
Somebody's had that error.
You get the occasional, like,
you know, Russian site with
one hit where it's like that
error and you have no idea
but uh, nothing get Russia.
It's just it's happening yet.
So many times that it's like
one, one hit on a Russian site.
I don't know why, but, um, but
yeah, no,
that's, that's the thing.
And nobody's ever gonna know
everything.
Like, you know, it'd be kind of.
Well, you know, it'd be kind of
a little presumptuous that, you
know, everything too, you know,
like, like the whole know it all
thing it's like, I think your
brain would probably explode if
you did know everything anyway.
So
Bekah: I think that's why, you
know, it's so important
to have this community of people
that are at.
All stages of the journey,
right.
Um, because you learn a lot from
seeing other people talk about
how they don't know something
or, you know, Molly STR I
think tweeted once about, um,
bringing new people on board.
And one of the things she does
is talk about like, okay, this
is a thing that I messed up last
week or something like that.
And that just kind of, yeah.
Yeah.
You know, if you're allowed to
admit your failures, I think,
and well, okay, so maybe it's
not called failure, right?
Like  you're yeah.
If you're allowed to admit
things that didn't go right
the first time, then, then
you're better able to learn
and grow from that experience.
And I think also like your live
streaming goals
in line with that too.
Right.
Because there's kind of a lot at
stake, but I feel like you
make things very accessible and
you make it friendly to a
lot of different people because
you're willing to put yourself
out there and live stream.
So, um, can you talk about that
a little bit?
Nick: Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Uh, I started live streaming in
April this year.
Once again, pandemic 2020 is a
dumpster fire.
And I was like, uh, I don't
know.
It kind of ties into, uh, SWS.
Uh, Sean Wang's like learn in
public and,
um, It's kind of cool.
Actually, I got to interview him
a couple weeks ago,
which was kind of nice too, but,
um, but yeah, it just
started live streaming mainly.
And I was literally doing like
my real work.
It wasn't like, this is my side
project.
I was doing my actual work, live
streaming and
my own account on Twitch.
I don't have a lot of followers.
I've got like a hundred
something, but I was.
Talking to myself.
Like I, I found the live
streaming helped me articulate
either like rubber ducking, the,
the screen basically.
And so I'd be talking about my
whole thought process and stuff.
And, and then, then I got the
idea, which I don't
think is, uh, like a, a new idea
or anything, but
I was like, why don't I.
Tried pairing with folks in the
community to pair on
issues in the forum code base.
And so I just sent out a tweet
and then spoke to my work and
they said like, yeah, yeah.
That's yeah.
That's that's cool.
Go ahead.
Um, and this was initially all
on my Twitch account.
Um, I had done one with Sophia
Lee.
Uh, who's in the community.
I did one with Chuck Smith.
Who's in our Virtual Coffee, Nia
Jackson as well.
And, um, I think those were the
first three I did.
And that was still on my own
stream.
And then this was getting close
to Octoberfest.
And I was actually running, not
running.
I was like my, my main job for
the month of hack
Octoberfest was to work on hack
Octoberfest for dev slash forum.
So me and Christina Gordon, my
other coworker, who's
our community manager.
Um, I, I pitched the idea to
Jess.
One of the co-founders they
said, well, why
don't we do pairing for
Octoberfest fast and.
then we got some other ideas
too.
Like, uh, it was, I think, uh, I
just thought walk through
Wednesdays sounded cool.
So then I, I was like, we'll
just start interviewing people.
And so like, it started off with
some of our team members and
I'm still interviewing some of
our team members, but also just
people in the dev community.
Uh, and this kind of ties into
my structured Joel.
I'm just like, I have nothing to
lose.
I'm just gonna.
People who I would like to
interview if they wanna come on.
And they, they said yes.
So that's kind of cool.
So it's.
Had like Sean w like I said, uh,
recently, uh,
spoke with somebody from the MPM
GitHub team last week.
RUO Eve Portello of GraphQL fame
react.
She's coming on.
Uh, I don't know if I'm saying
her name correctly,
but Vinny Che, she runs
diversified tech she's
coming on and GA coming on.
Jerome Hardaway from, uh, SSU
code.
I dunno.
It's just kind of cool, like,
uh, and just to be
able to do that's kind of fun,
but, uh, yeah, we did
more live, live coding.
Uh, and like you said, it's,
it's not set up to succeed.
Like it's set up to succeed in
the sense, like, yes, we're
gonna have fun and stuff, but
like the whole, the whole goal
of the, the live pairings is.
It's not that I'm trying to make
it as realistic as
possible, but like in real life,
like you get an issue.
You're gonna start looking up
stuff.
You're gonna start trying to
figure things out and
you're not necessarily.
Gonna figure it out in like an
hour and a half,
which is typically what we do
for the stream.
So, you know, uh, I always tell
folks at the beginning,
you know, like, uh, they
introduce themselves and
stuff, but I, I stress that
we're here to have fun.
Just get you introduced to the
code base, uh, you know,
uh, Before or after help them,
if they're new to open
source to, you know, create a
branch, create a poll request,
follow up after as well.
You know, and, and there's some
prep too, like, uh, getting
them set up with the code base
and we have some talks as well.
Uh, um, so yeah, I've, I've just
really been enjoying
it for many reasons.
One it's I.
Engaging with the community.
And I also like the element of,
I don't know if this is gonna
work or not  and like I've been
even doing some Ruby live code
pairing, which I don't really
have a lot of experience in,
so that's kind of fun too.
So, uh, yeah, it's, uh, that's,
that's my structured
Yolo kind of in a nutshell.
So.
That's awesome.
Bekah: Yeah.
I love that.
And I think that that's great
for, for everybody to hear.
And I do love how you use, like
this person centered approach.
I think like when you're doing
this, right, like you're
meeting people as human beings
where they're at and it's
not this high pressure thing.
Right.
It gives everybody the ability
to learn and to grow.
And I think that's really.
Nick: Yeah.
And it's, it's interesting too,
because like on the
live stream, there's, uh,
there's chat in Twitch.
Like we put 'em on YouTube
after, but uh, so people
from the community will actually
interact too.
Oh, did you try this?
Like do this, you know, so
there's, it's, it's pair
programming, but kind of like
slightly mob programming, a
bit to the certain degree,
depending on the, the stream,
I guess, but, uh, yeah.
Yeah,
Bekah: that's great.
Um, we've got a couple of
questions from the Virtual
Coffee community that I wanna
make sure that I ask.
Uh, the first one is, can you
talk about your
funniest bug or your biggest
whoops moment, or maybe
that's a time you took down
Nick: prod?
Uh, yeah, I, I didn't.
Take down.
Well, I guess I somewhat took
down pride.
Um, I was doing my first
deployment at a smaller
company in like 2009.
And it was my, like I said, my
first deployment, this is like
pre, there was no real like CI
cd@thetimeiwasusingsomethingcalledcruisecontrol.net,
which is.
It's like a task runner, but
like a lot of the stuff
I'd done custom, like stuff,
but, um, I was getting ready.
I had my checklist.
I go, okay, let's upgrade the
database.
And like, I don't remember what
happened, but like I
literally locked the database.
Like the first thing I did.
So like basically the entire
deploy was
botched at that point.
And.
The DBA, the database
administrator that I
worked with, we'd worked in
other places before, too.
She just kinda laughed and kind
of did a disk, but she's
like, she's kind of like, yeah,
move out of the way.
Let me start this out for you.
So, uh, so that, there's that,
um, another place which was.
It, it wasn't my fault, but it
was still a very
interesting scenario.
Um, I was working at, uh, the
eCommerce company and we had a
client, a fairly large company.
So like, I think about 40,000,
maybe 60,000
folks with single sign on.
And I was working on the
project, which was the
single sign-on project.
And we had this custom single
sign-on, uh, Thing initially.
And then we migrated to a out of
the, off the
shelf, uh, solution, cuz it just
made sense.
Let people who know, you know,
authentication
authorizing, let you know, let,
let them handle that.
So we had our development
environment, our tests
and staging environment and then
production.
So got tested it through every
part of the process, get to
production and uh, I run.
And all of a sudden, the sign on
is in infinite loop.
Um, and this is like for, for,
it's not, it
wasn't OWA for anybody that's
familiar with SAML.
So it's like Ws Federation.
It's just a little more
complicated, but basically,
yeah, the thing was spinning
like crazy and
I'm like, We're deploying.
These are like, this was a large
SharePoint application
and this takes like the deploys
were like a long time.
Uh, we, we typically did it from
like 5:00 PM to like two in the
morning or three in the morning.
And.
It's like one in the morning,
this thing's happening.
I'm like, oh my God, you know,
checked everything.
And like I said, every stage of
the process was fine.
Dev tests, staging, no issues
whatsoever.
I get on the phone with their
technical support.
We're trying to figure it out,
you know?
And in the end it turned out
that the software had.
You can do in, in, in, in, uh, C
sharp, you can kind
of have conditional stuff.
Like if I'm in debug mode, do
something.
And, uh, there was something
that was in one of those, like,
If debug, uh, it was, it was, I
think it was logging something
and it was preventing this
infinite loop from happening.
So when we were in development
test and staging, no issues
at all, but production, it wa I,
I think it was
like a log or something.
And it's because it didn't do
that step.
Like maybe it was like, just to
prevent like a,
uh, you know, like a.
What's the, I'm drawing a blank
here, uh, like a race condition.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So I think it was preventing a
race condition, even
though they didn't realize.
So we figured that out.
So then we had to redeploy and
we redeployed it in debug mode
so that the deploy could finish.
And then after that, you know,
we've filed an issue with the
company and then they fixed it
and then everything was
fine on the next deploy, but it
was just like high stakes
at like, you know, and it's.
One or two in the morning, you
know, like you
just want to go to bed.
It was, it was, it was pretty
stressful.
Um, but that sorted out, so
yeah.
So those are kind of the two,
those are probably the two
notable ones I can think of.
Bekah: um, yeah, that sounds
rough.
Um, how about kind of the flip
side of this?
The other question we have is
what is the most excited
you've ever been about a piece
of code working.
Nick: Uh, I think it's working
well.
It was dev at the time, but
forum, uh, my first,
I don't know it was cool.
Cuz I contributed to the, I was
actually the first
external contributor to the dev
code base back in 2018.
Uh, so I've been contributing to
the project since 2018,
but uh, or was it 27?
No, it was 2018.
Um, but.
Uh, when I started working there
in January, the first
thing I did was we overhauled
the feed and the, if you're
logged in, uh, because you can
personalize it to some degree.
And it originally was all server
side rendered, cuz
for those who don't know the.
The form code base, it's a
primarily a Rubion rails app.
And then we sprinkle pre-ACT
wherever it makes sense to
have interactions typically in
the logged in experience.
So I got to do that and then it
just felt really cool knowing
that once I ship like a feature
that everybody sees, like every
day, uh, was in production and,
you know, like getting
millions of views every month.
So that, that just felt really
good.
You know, it's just been fun.
Like anything new I do in there.
It's it's just been a lot of
fun.
So
Dan: seems like a pretty great
organization,
uh, to, to work with.
Nick: I won't lie.
It's it's pretty awesome.
Bekah: that's great.
Well, thanks so much, Nick, for
being here with us.
Um, can you tell, uh, folks what
you're working
on or where they can find.
Nick: So, uh, I'm at Nicki T
online pretty much everywhere.
GitHub, Twitter, dev two and all
that.
Um, you can also check out my
website.
I am developer.com.
I have no idea how I was able to
snag that domain, but I did.
Um, and also, uh, live coding.
If you wanna check that out, you
can go to.
Live coding.ca I don't know how
I got that one either,
but, um, and Twitch TV slash the
practical dev,
um, for live coding as well.
Um, and projects right now.
Um, I guess I've been working on
a few, well, I, for
Octoberfest, like you said, I
had contributed to yours.
Uh, I've been working, uh, with
someone who I
contributed to last year.
Her her, I don't remember her
full name, but her first name's
Ray and she, uh, they have a
Gaby plugin for, uh, Owen beds.
So I I'm a maintainer on there
now.
So, uh, I've been working on
there too.
So that's fun.
And, you know, and then there's
my day to day, which is an open
source, uh, the form code base.
So, so lots of fun stuff going
on in there.
That is awesome.
Bekah: And we will link all of
those things in the show notes.
Um, is there any last advice you
have for our listeners?
Nick: Uh, spiders aren't bad.
It's just, I, I have.
Unnatural fear of them.
I don't know why.
Um, but they eat bugs.
So I, I have some in the corners
of my office and
I know they're there and they're
doing good work.
So thanks buddy.
Bekah: That is excellent.
Thank you so much, Nick, for
being here with us.
Thank you, Nick.
Uh,
Nick: thanks for having me.
Bekah: Thanks for hanging out
with us.
As we talked to Nick Taylor on
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee podcast, this episode was
edited and produced by Dan OT.
You can check out our show.
For links to things we talked
about in the episode.
And how to contact us or Nick.
I'd like to thank the Virtual
Coffee community
for being awesome.
As always, we really enjoyed
talking about Nick's journey
into software, how he found
Virtual Coffee and how open
source live streaming and Yolo
played an important role in his
life as an awesome human being.
If you have questions or
comments for the
podcast, you can email
us@podcastvirtualcoffee.io.
To find out more about Virtual
Coffee, you can
check out Virtual Coffee.io or
come hang out with us
on a Tuesday or Thursday.
Hope to see you there soon.