Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season one, episode two of
the virtual coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah.
And this is a podcast that
features members of the
virtual coffee community.
Virtual coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
They're here on this podcast,
sharing their stories
and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you here with me.
Today is my co-host Dan.
Dan: Hey everyone.
Um, we have another great
episode today.
Um, Kirk will be joining us to
interview Marie Antones
about how she went from being a
chef to a junior developer.
Marie is from Cedar rapids,
Iowa.
And she changed careers from the
culinary industry
to software development in 2020,
after living in
Bermuda for four years.
Um, she's currently a c.net
developer, uh, working
for a small startup.
Um, Marie shared with us, her
story, how she's used
her past experience as a chef to
help understand
coding in her own way.
She also talked about the
challenges of coming into her
first job from a bootcamp and
what she wishes she would've
known before starting that.
Marie is one of my favorite
people, uh, in virtual coffee.
And I was just very glad that
she agreed to come and talk with
us and, uh, share her story.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast.
Like we start every virtual
coffee.
We introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're
from, what we do and a random
check-in question.
Today's question is what are you
most looking forward to today?
We hope you enjoyed this
episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from a small
town in Southeastern Ohio.
And what I am most looking
forward to today because we are
recording on a Friday is the new
episode of the Mandalorian.
Dan: Hi, I am Dan.
I am front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio, and
the thing I'm most looking
forward to is the lunch I'm
going to have after this.
Kirk: Hi, I'm Kirk, I'm a.net
developer and the Caribbean.
The thing I'm most looking
forward to today is working on
a secret project after work.
Marie: Hi, I'm Marie Antones.
I am from Cedar rapids, Iowa.
I am a junior developer for a
small startup called
strata folio and the thing I'm
most looking forward to.
Today is going for a walk on the
beach.
Bekah: That sounds amazing.
We are super happy to have you
here with us today, Marie.
Thanks so much for agreeing to
be on the podcast.
Thanks for having me.
Yeah.
All right, Marie, I think what
we wanna start off with
is finding out a little bit
about your origin story.
So you come from a
non-traditional
path to programming.
Can you tell us a little bit
about how you got.
Marie: Yeah, well, I have had
many different paths in
my educational background.
I first started off with
nutrition.
I wanted to be a nutritionist,
but then I
moved around quite a bit.
And then I got into kinesiology
and then eventually I got
into the culinary industry,
which I stuck with.
Um, and then my husband and I
actually moved to Bermuda.
He, he got a different promotion
for his job.
He works for Transamerica.
And he was like, oh, Hey, this
position opened up in Bermuda.
We should go.
And I was like, sure, no way
we're ever gonna get
that, but might as well.
And then lo and behold, we were
here.
I thought there was gonna be
like forest, lots of
animals, lots of like fruit and
tropical stuff, but that
was not the case, which.
Leads me to kind of where I am
now.
Bermuda's quite hard for some
expats, depending on
your industry to have a job
without work, permits,
visas, all of that.
And so I really took a four year
vacation basically, where
I didn't really have a job.
I, I then spent my time
volunteering for a
international women's club.
, which does a lot of like
marketing and fundraising for
local charities on the island.
So I really spent all my time
doing that, which
that was, that was fun.
But then when he got a new
position back in
Iowa, I was like, perfect.
I can get a job thinking I was
gonna go back to
the culinary industry.
And then my main idea was to
build a pasta website so I
could sell homemade pastas at
the local farmer's markets.
So like no one sells fresh
pasta, homemade,
fresh pasta anywhere.
So I was like, this would be
perfect.
No one does it.
Like it would be great.
So then I was researching how to
build a website or to
find someone like you guys to
build a website for me.
And I was.
Wow.
That's a lot of money that I
don't have.
So I was like, I'm just gonna do
it myself,
basically with everything.
If I can do it myself, I'm gonna
do it myself.
Anything from like going to get
a manicure.
I just watch the lady take
notes, go home, buy
the stuff, do it myself.
save myself some money.
But that really led me to
finding Delta V code
school, which is the bootcamp I
attended.
And.
It was actually right across the
street from where I lived.
So I was like, this is so
perfect.
And so my husband told me that,
yeah, you could try the
first, first class because I'm
not a technical person.
My background's not technical.
I only use a computer when I was
on social media or looking
at the recipe, but that's about
the extent of my te knowledge.
So I took it.
The first class was just on
basic HTML, CSS.
They had you build like a 1, 1,
1 page website.
It was one, a one day course.
I fell in love with it.
I was like, wow, this is great.
I can make anything I want.
like anything.
And then I took one or two to
really like, make sure.
I wanted to do this career path,
which it was the same story.
Still loved it.
Still.
We had to do some pre-work on
Khan academy.
I don't know if you guys have
done any Khan
academy, but I built this.
I spent all week building this
little pixelated,
Mario with animations.
That's awesome.
And that's, that's all I could
spend my time on.
So I was like, if I, if I could
get lost spending
my time on something, it's
definitely worth my time.
So that's kind of how I got into
software development.
Bekah: I have to say, I love so
much, um, hearing your
story, but also the idea of not
having a technical
background at all, because I
would say like, my background
was not technical at all.
I taught college English for 10
years and I also was not.
building my space pages when I'm
working or whatever, you
know,  um, but I think that it's
really good to hear that
because I think sometimes people
get really nervous about
thinking that they can do it.
Like, well, I don't have
background.
Like, I don't know what HTML
means.
And I think that you don't have
to know that.
I mean, it's, it's about like,
exactly what you're saying.
It's about the learning process.
Marie: Mm-hmm . One thing that a
lot of times in bootcamp they
talked about is your previous
experience really helps you in
software development, because
think of a recipe as kind
of like building a website,
like, oh, I know I need this
piece, but what if I don't know
how to do this piece?
I'll go look it up, go watch a
YouTube video.
Do all the stuff to like, do a
little research
or fiddle with it, play around
with it experiment.
And then eventually you get to a
place where
you're like comfortable.
Oh, I can make cookies now
without looking at the
recipe, I can make this, I can,
I can create a modal.
I can do this CSS grid without
really having to go to the
documentation every single time.
Cuz it kind of just practice
and.
Enjoying the, the process.
Yeah, it's awesome.
Dan: I could see a lot of like a
lot of the thought processes
like that are the same.
And there's also like with
cooking there's language
stuff that you need to learn,
there's, you know,
terminology and everything.
Um, there's, there's a lot of
like a lot
of parallels for sure.
I, in the kitchen, when I'm
cooking, I'm totally lost all
the time and I'm looking up
every single word and, you
know, doing that same thing.
So it's, I can see a lot of, a
lot of parallels there.
That's.
Kirk: So king makes me angry
because I want the food to be
ready immediately and it is not.
And I suppose that is the way my
clients feel when they're
like, why isn't the code done?
Uh, well it takes time to get it
right, but I'm hungry now.
I will also say when you said
like, Knowing what HTL means.
I did have to do a quick self
check.
Like, do I know what HTML means?
I text.
Okay.
I'm cool.
but definitely echoing what
everyone else is saying.
Like at the beginning, there's
so much, you don't know.
And I feel like software is one
of those spaces.
Where's almost like immediately
obvious how much you don't
know, because you're seeing
everyone's conversations and
you can't follow any of them.
And like, I suppose the solution
is just like, kinda
like put your head down and like
focus on what's in front
of you, but it's definitely
daunting at the beginning.
Um, and kind of in the middle,
cuz like, I don't know,
like it just never stops.
Like you'll go online and used
to people talk about something,
you know, nothing about.
And you're like, I really don't
know anything.
Marie: Yeah.
Or that's like even being in the
industry for a
long time, you could hear
something completely new.
I think Kirk, when we were
pairing the other day for
the code challenge, you're like,
oh, dot net has
so many new cool things.
I was like, yeah, I'm guessing
most people in.net
when something new comes out,
they're just like, wow.
Or something they haven't worked
with before or a section
they haven't worked with.
It's really hard to know
everything.
So, yeah.
Which is kind of what makes it
fun.
There's a million new recipes.
There's a million.
Code things, new new
technologies.
Yeah.
Bekah: I think you need to start
a site.
That's called code recipes.
If there's not one, it would be
like, so
Marie: perfect.
That one would be perfect.
Dan: Yeah.
Sorry.
I was just gonna say no, go
ahead.
I was just gonna say recipes has
become like a language in
code documentation that has I
found actually to be really,
um, really helpful, like cuz cuz
people know what it means.
Like what a recipe means.
Like this is like a, a set of
steps and ingredients
that you need to.
Do this one thing, you know, and
it's, it's just like
that sort of thought process.
I've, I've found to be very
level as a, as a consumer of
documentation or whatever, you
know, it's like a, trying to
learn how to do a thing, you
know, like here's a recipe
for whatever, whatever.
Marie: Yeah.
Like, like wiring up a mole,
like first you do this and then.
What would be great.
And like a recipe book would be
like, oh, here are the
problems you could encounter.
Mm-hmm  and here's how you solve
them.
Have you checked this?
Bekah: That's so awesome.
I love that, Marie.
I know you have gone through
such a journey since I've
met you at virtual coffee.
You know, I think that you are
still in school and
then you got your first job.
Um, but one of the things I've
always been super impressed
with is I know that you say that
you're a junior developer,
but you've never felt like a
junior developer when
I'm talking to you, you are just
very knowledgeable and,
um, great at communicating what
you're talking about.
um, but so it's been great to
see that whole journey
through virtual coffee.
And just out of curiosity, how
did you find out
about virtual coffee?
Marie: I found virtual coffee
because.
In bootcamp, they were like, oh,
networking,
networking, networking, which
I'm pretty sure.
I was the only one who did
Twitter at that time.
Cuz I only got a Twitter to
follow tech people and your name
actually popped up as someone to
follow Bekah and I saw, oh,
she's from Ohio, I'm from Ohio.
We're gonna be like the same
person.
So I followed you and then you
kept tweeting about, and
I'm like, Hmm, virtual coffee.
That seems is weird.
And I'm like, I might as well
just go.
It's just like how I found the
women's club.
If I hear about it enough, I'll
be like,
might as well try it out.
And so there I was, I'm like,
oh, I'm nervous, new people.
I'm also not a great public
speaker.
So I was just nervous in
general, but.
It's nice seeing people's faces.
Everyone had their cameras on.
You're like, oh, these are real
people.
I'm not talking to a wall.
They have emotions.
And that just makes it more
comfortable.
And then also the icebreakers
that we do, the random questions
that also helps because it kind
of like lets you know
more about the person other than
just their tech side.
And there's not these barriers
of, oh, you
have to speak about tech.
When you come to virtual coffee.
We talk about so many things
that it just
makes it more personal.
And I get to know everyone who
comes and you get to
know like their story.
And it really feels like, oh,
we're actually friends.
This is like, I'm going to
coffee to meet a friend because
how many times do you go to a
meetup and everyone's silent.
No one knows what to talk about.
You don't really know how to
introduce yourself, even
if I've been to say a meetup
that I'm consistently at.
There's some weird barrier
communication barrier or
something where you're like, I
don't really know this person.
And in virtual coffee, that's
completely different.
Everyone knows everyone's story.
Everyone knows your background.
Everyone knows what you like,
what your strengths are.
Like every time I see F sharp,
I'm like, where is Kirk at?
Kirk: I like a
Marie: brain.
We all know.
Yeah.
We all know like about each
other.
What's which makes it like
really great
to just come back to.
And I think you really get a
sense of community with that.
I'm
Bekah: just gonna start crying
over here though.
so wonderful.
Marie: Thank you.
Yeah, but it is great because no
other meetup and I go
to a lot of meetups because
Delta V really like was like,
networking is probably the most
likely to get you a job.
So I'm like, well, looks like
I'm going to everything now.
So.
Out of all my meetups, nothing
has ever felt
like a solid community.
So it's just great.
Kirk: Yeah.
I really, as somebody who used
to go to a lot of meetups, I
definitely remember being that
guy by like the cheese plate.
The only I can think of saying
is like, oh,
a lot of cheese today.
So, you know, like, I don't know
what we're supposed to
do here until like the main
presenter starts stalking.
So I'll just try and look.
Mm-hmm,  intrigued at
everything.
Um, I do definitely also
appreciate that.
The conversation, isn't that
hard to start here.
Like, you know what to do, like
there's a nice lead in versus
just middle about make friends.
It seems like between the ages
of four and like 74,
we still have the same advice
for certain people.
Like you just sort of push them
in a room and
say, go, go be yourself, which
is not as helpful.
Terrifying.
Bekah: I am very much an
introvert.
So like going to a conference or
I've, I've never
actually been to a meetup.
Um, that's not online, but I, I
will just stand by the
wall and then like, Try and make
eye contact with somebody
and hope they're friendly.
Marie: I am the same way.
And then when they come up to
you and talk, you're just like,
Dan: I actually have been
running the, the
Cleveland react meetup.
We started like a, I don't know,
a year and a half
ago or something back when we
could see people.
Uh, but I was also the same way,
like in general,
you know, wanting to like, I
don't know, just kind
of hang back or whatever.
And.
It was a really hard problem to
solve for, you
know, as an organizer.
And I saw it happening and, you
know, didn't know
how to fix it, really.
Um, having this sort of
structure that we have is, I
don't know, has been really
awesome at virtual coffee.
Nice way to solve all
Bekah: that.
Yeah.
I, I was talking to a conference
organizer recently
about, you know, the, that idea,
that same idea, like
how do you bring people in?
How do you make people feel
welcome?
And one of the things that he
was talking about was when,
you know, the people who are
there, um, that's how you're
able to make the connections and
with virtual coffee
and having these, you know,
frequent coffees, we, we do
get to know each other and, um,
it makes it easier for all
of us to kind of talk to each
other about different things.
Um, and also I think it provides
a really great environment.
People at all levels, um, which
can be, I think really
challenging, but to, you know,
feel welcome as a
new developer and to feel like
you have a place here.
If you've been doing this for
your whole career is just
something that is, I don't know.
I really value it about this
community.
Um, Marie I, one of the
questions that I, I love
to hear people answer is, um,
Finding that transition
period from going to bootcamp
into your first job and
how, how does that play out?
So I know for everybody it's
different, but it
can be really challenging.
So can you talk a little bit
about that experience and
maybe some of the challenges you
didn't anticipate?
Marie: So I think the biggest
challenge with transitioning
from bootcamp to my job.
I assumed a lot of things would
be similar to how we
structured, like the code base
or laid things out
because we did C sharp the last
six weeks of bootcamp.
And the project I'm on now works
as C sharp, but things
are completely different how
they're laid out, which going
into a really huge code base.
I didn't really learn how to
navigate through.
Something with hundreds of
files.
So I'm also lucky that my
instructor, Keith,
which you guys have met, he also
consults for us.
So he is in with me most days,
teaching me how to navigate,
how to just like go from one
part of the project to the next
or little tips like, oh, this is
like, look, look for this.
Or you can tell why this.
Which is nice because I'm not
sure how other teams are, cuz
I only have this experience with
a very small team, but I'm
guessing on a bigger team you'll
you would have someone pairing
with you showing you kind of the
ropes of, oh, here's the project
you might run into this or like
here's how we, I personally
get from file to file.
Um, But I think that was the
hardest transition was, wow,
this there's a lot of files.
This isn't just like 10 files.
And then just all of the, the
new things of adapting to
people you don't know, like, of
course, like I've been
there since July, whenever you,
you start something new
or go to a new school or go.
Anywhere new you're very like
closed off.
You don't really wanna tell them
like, oh, I'm
not really sure about this.
You just wing it until you're
like, okay, I
actually need help now.
so it's just like, uh, and then
Keith is always like,
no, just ask right away.
It's just better.
Yeah, probably just adapt
adapting to new the new
code base and new structure.
That's not the same as.
The day to day bootcamp life.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure.
I'll echo that as a bootcamp,
grad myself.
I mean exactly what you're
saying.
Like you go from working with 10
files and then you're like, what
is this even, um, how do these
things connect and why and what?
Um, and then it is that, that.
Time period.
You have to figure out how to
communicate.
And this is why I har on
communication being like
one of the most important skills
all of the time.
Um, especially as a new
developer, because it's
hard, like one, you don't know
when to ask, right?
Because certainly you need to
dig in and you need
to learn things yourself.
Um, and there's not really a
hard and fast role.
I know some people say, well,
like look at it for 15 minutes
and if you don't know, then.
Ask, but when you have a huge
code base, I think
that maybe is not, at least for
me, it's not a, a good
tool for judging one to ask.
If you're going from piece to
piece, just trying to
track down where all of this
stuff is coming from,
it's gonna take you longer than
15 minutes and that's
still valuable time spent.
Um, but it is that like, okay, I
need to learn these new things
and I need to learn how to
communicate with these people.
And, and basically, you know,
how to trust the people
that you're working with.
That's super important to, I
think, growing as a develop.
Marie: Yeah.
And trying to, um, kind of make
the connection between,
oh, let me just look at this
file and piece things together
and see if I can figure that
much out by myself so I can
explain kind of where I'm going.
Um, I keep mentioning Keith, but
he's very big on, you
should probably draw it out.
Can you just draw it out or
explain.
Just earlier today, he was like,
explain to me what
you were trying to do.
Mm-hmm  because usually that
gives you a hint to where
you're going in the first place.
Yeah.
And if you're writing it wrong,
then you're like, oh, could
you read that code out to me?
What is that doing?
Oh, that's not even what I said
in the first place.
So just trying to figuring out
how to communicate that
way as well, I think is very.
Kirk: That, um, that I, I'm
starting to think
about that concept.
I feel like a lot of people,
almost everyone from boot
camps could probably echo the,
I, I had very small
projects in boot camp and then
IL, they are not so small.
Mm-hmm  and it sort of makes me
wonder if that's there's
is there a way to like, work
that into curriculums?
Like maybe like part of the
process, like.
This section, we're working on a
large established code base
where obviously as the bootcamp
student, like you're not
building it from scratch, but
it's like this already exists.
And some part of the learning is
like, okay, how do you
integrate into like an already
existing system that feels
like something that can be
really valuable for people?
Or maybe
Marie: even like, yeah, I think
even just, um,
maybe boot camps could.
I guess talking from my bootcamp
experience, maybe,
um, have you tried to work on an
open source project?
Because even just trying to work
through that, because usually
those projects are big anyways.
Um, like the forum project,
there's so many files in that,
that, so you could even pair up
with another boot grant boot.
Person in your class and just
try to pair on it, figure it out
and walk through it that way.
Dan: Yeah.
That's interesting.
There's a lot of different, like
ways to that, that sort of
how to make a small change in a
large code base, I feel like
is an important skill and seems
like a solvable one from like a
bootcamp's perspective, whether
it's open source thing or just
like, I dunno, just like they
just have a large app that they
use, you know, like the open
source stuff is, is important
and, but it has its own whole
set of, you know, Whatever.
And then also, if it's not your
open source project,
then you, you know, have to hope
that there's just issues
that are appropriate to work on,
you know, but yeah,
just having some huge app.
Yeah.
That, and you're like, okay,
your next assignment is fix
this bug, you know, whatever.
But in this huge app, you know,
that, that's
interesting to think.
Marie: I don't know if, uh,
bootcamps can
pair with like local.
I don't know if flat iron has
sponsors, but
Delta V has sponsors may.
Maybe they could for a week out
of the, out of the, uh,
curriculum pair with those
sponsors and have students work
on a small feature, like, oh,
get to know our, our product.
I know a lot of companies are
private.
but even just like looking,
looking at sign some consent
form or something, but looking
at a large company's
code base and being like, oh,
maybe partner or pair
with one of the employees,
because that even will give
them an insight to how like day
to day jobs are as well.
Bekah: Yeah.
I think, um,  there's a program
called collab lab.
Um, and they are doing something
similar because they're working
with a lot of people who, um,
Are from nontraditional
backgrounds, but they're finding
that the issue when they go
to interview is, well, you don't
have enough experience
or you, the way that you talk
about code, isn't clear.
I mean, a lot of us aren't used
to talking about it.
If we're coming from
nontraditional backgrounds, if
you're teaching yourself, who
are you talking to about code?
If you're in a bootcamp or
you're working self-paced,
um, remotely, then it's the,
it's the same issue.
So they pair up teams to work on
a project.
And I, I don't wanna say exactly
what it is cuz I can't remember,
but it's a larger project.
It helps 'em to develop skills,
um, team building communication.
They're using GitHub for the
project.
So really developing a lot of
the skills that I think
that boot camps miss out on.
So that's, you know, certainly
helpful.
And I think like for me, one of
my favorite things that we've
done at virtual coffee is the
hack Tober Fest initiative.
Mm-hmm  um, and that was just a
really great way to learn about.
um, working on different
people's projects, how different
people communicate, um, how to
work with contributors and then
just have a wide variety of
both, um, open source projects,
but support of the community.
So, you know, having that there
as well was, was really
fruitful, um, for me anyway.
And I think that, you know,
you're definitely on the right
track of terms of like, kind of
thinking through some of
the issues, um,  and I love too
how you were describing
like different how learning a
process almost for what you're
doing and how you're doing it,
um, is, is super valuable too.
Marie: Yeah.
One thing I liked about Heto
Fest is I worked with
a lot of people's projects who
weren't my language
that I was comfortable with.
So I'm most comfortable with C.
I worked with Kirk quite a bit
on his Elm project.
And we could talk about like
similarities between what I know
and what he knows through Elm.
I'm like, oh, I like, I can, I
can basically understand this
or get where this is going.
Even though I don't know the
language.
And this is the first time I've
ever worked in Elm before.
So it's kind of nice just
knowing that, oh, I know
the basic core concept of like
JavaScript C sharp.
HTML all that.
And then I could translate it
into how to help Kirk
with his Elm project, which is
nice to know like, oh,
or nice to gain experience,
knowing like, oh, even though
I don't know this language or
know this, this project
or no, like this library, I know
I can at least figure
out some pieces to make the
connection between what I know.
And the new project language or
anything new
that I might be working on.
Kirk: What also Marie did not
mention was that while
she was pairing with me, we
totally found a weird
thing that VSCO does.
And I had no idea what was going
on and I was panicking
and I'm like, I've ruined her
hack, Tober Fest experience.
Everything is terrible now, but
she was very, she was
very pleasant about it and she
told me it was fine.
And we eventually figured it.
, um, which is one of the fun
things about, about pairing,
but yeah, I, I do, cuz I
remember when we, we spoke about
Octoberfest and how we wanted to
do it, we spent a lot of
time thinking, well, do we wanna
reach out to different groups?
And should we source like good
projects?
And then we realized it was so
hard to sort of do quality
control on like the wider open
source universe that.
We just, oh, we should probably
just like do our own thing at
least make sure, like, we have
one established project that
like, we know will provide like
a good experience for people
because like we made it and
we're the ones maintaining it.
Um, and I think that actually
turned out pretty well.
And then, you know, everybody
who participated kind of
like fed off each other.
So someone had a good read me.
I'm like, oh, okay.
I'm gonna use a read me like
that.
Oh, you have good, um,
templates.
I'll borrow your templates.
So.
and the projects are still the
projects they're still, you
know, like unique in different
languages and wonderful, but
at least the approach and the
user friendliness for newer
developers was like something we
could try and standardize.
And I'm, I'm really happy with
how that turned out.
Um, you know, even, even for me,
like, I, I didn't have that much
experience contributing to other
people's projects before this.
Um, it was fun.
That was, that was really, that
was really cool.
And I, I, I also wish, like I'd
had more chances to do that way
earlier in my career than now.
I wish I had just been doing
that from the start, cuz that
is the majority of people.
When you work in software, like
you're not fielding
up something from scratch,
you're working on something
already established, right.
Marie: One of the aspects of
Octoberfest that I really
enjoyed was, um, Nick helped me
set up, um, forums, project,
which you get to learn about how
to be taught by someone
else, because how many times are
you on a new job?
And then you have to work with a
new developer or a
new senior developer, or just
someone new on your team.
And you have to like try to find
a way to.
Discuss your problems or like
collaborate with them and figure
out what they're trying to say.
Cuz everyone explains things
differently.
But I think having virtual
coffees hack Octoberfest,
we, most of you guys had smaller
projects.
And that even helps people with
an introductory
project because it's like, oh,
here's my project.
I have like five to 10 files,
maybe a few more.
And then you guys are like, oh
no, I'm trying to
build this feature in this
feature and this feature.
So we have quite a bit more code
and then you could go to even
bigger open source projects like
forum and then, and then work.
Like my work has.
A ton of files.
So it's just like more steps, I
guess.
Bekah: Dot net.
Yeah.
I wanna touch.
Something that you said, um, the
ability to be able
to dive into code bases with
different languages.
And one of the things that I
heard pretty
early on was, well, okay.
You learned Ruby in bootcamp and
you learned JavaScript, but that
doesn't mean that you should
limit yourself to applying for
jobs with just those languages.
And I had heard that, but I
didn't.
Quite understand it.
And I think that you did a
really good, I, uh, good job of
kind of talking through how that
works, because so much of it
is the thought process, right?
It's problem solving.
Yep.
Um, and it's just, you know, you
have, there are gonna be
different terms and there are
going to be different patterns
with different languages that
you have to learn.
But essentially, if you have
that problem solving down,
and if you could do a good
analysis of what you're looking
at, then, then that does open
doors for you to move
to projects with different
languages or to apply for a
much wider variety of positions.
Marie: One thing we did at
bootcamp at Delvy is we had
mock interviews on Fridays.
So.
um, one of our sponsors actually
came into interview us.
They, he got a huge like
question packet and one
of my questions was about a
Python dictionary.
I don't, I know a little Python,
but I don't know Python,
but I know C has dictionary.
So I explained it.
Oh, I'm, I'm not familiar with
Python as much as I am C sharp
and I know C has dictionaries,
then I want to explain how I
know dictionaries and I'm like,
I'm assuming it's like Python.
They might not be exactly the
same, but here's what I know
about dictionaries, which I
think that like, anytime you're
in an interview and you don't
exactly know, but you've heard
something that could tie in.
I think that that is just really
good.
Just to know, oh, you might not
know the answer, but if
you can make connection to
something that, you know,
that really will benefit you in
the long run and even make
you possibly stand out, cuz some
people will just say.
Sorry.
I don't know Python.
I can't answer the question, but
maybe elaborate a bit more and
be like, oh, well, I don't know.
However, I am familiar with C
sharp and they have have a
dictionary and here's how I
would use a C sharp dictionary.
Python might be similar, but I
know I have
enough information to.
Find out how a Python dictionary
works.
Dan: I think that's great
advice.
Just like the, I think the thing
that people are looking
for when they're hiring,
especially, um, you know,
earlier career developers is, is
not so much the knowledge
of everything, but just the
ability to maybe connect the
dots and willingness to learn.
And.
Maybe some evidence that they
have learned things , you know,
and it's like, cause you know,
if you're hiring somebody, uh,
you know, in a, I don't know,
junior or whatever, that sort
of role you're expecting them to
be learning, you know, I
mean expecting everybody to be
learning on the job, but
you know, I, I think that just
great advice is like connecting
mm-hmm  like going into an
interview knowing like, I know
I'm not gonna know everything in
the world cuz nobody can,
you know, but um, the, the like
practicing and connecting the.
There are questions to your
knowledge, you know, uh,
is, is like a great, I think
that's some great insight.
Marie: Yeah.
Bekah: Um, one of the things I
also wanted to ask, I know,
um, it, in tech, there's so much
to learn and so much to
be excited about, like all the
shiny things are out there
and like, how do you figure out
what you wanna learn next?
So I just am curious, you know,
what are things that you are
interested in learning about in
the future and kind of how, how.
Or why you decided on those
things
Marie: right now?
I am one of my, uh, tasks or
requirements in my contract.
When I, when I started work with
strata, folio is creating
a dashboard using D three JS.
So I actually started the
interview process
with strata folio before I
graduated bootcamp.
And they told me about this.
So I did a bit of research and
in our bootcamp we spend
a week doing self-learning so
teach yourself something new.
So I got to play around with it.
So I am really trying to learn
more D three ass and create
more graphs and charts and just
really cool things with it.
Um, even just trying to do that
in my free time,
or at least reading about.
I don't really have too much
free time, but when I do
finally get the free time,
that's what I would like to
work on just to play around with
it and see, see some
cool things I can do with it.
Cause you always on, I think D
three has a website called
observable, which you can like
look at all the different,
um, like implementations of, of
the library.
I think just playing around with
it and learning about
it is just gonna be fun.
That sounds awesome.
I was just thinking about like,
oh, maybe, maybe I
could use one of my cookbooks
and like, try to like chart
something from a cookbook.
Oh, wine regions verse like, oh,
this said it
could pair with this.
This like type of dish or some,
some sort of graphic
I could make just to be fun or
different, I guess.
And just to, just to keep
learning fun.
That's
Dan: awesome.
D three D three's really cool.
There's some really cool stuff.
I think you can do with it.
I've only like you just
scratched the surface of it,
but I always keep trying, I'm
like, oh wait, let's use that.
You know, everyone's like, no,
no, it's not.
It's not about yet, but.
Marie: I'm not, I'm not into
like physics or anything
like that, but they have that
like force mm-hmm
force, layout, or force.
And so like playing with the
bubbles and like pulling
the bubbles and yeah, it's
really interesting.
And I would definitely like
playing with that a bit
more just to tinker and.
Like have fun with it.
I guess I'm it's
Bekah: on my list too.
So we should like get something
going so we
can all do fun stuff.
I feel like there's gotta
Dan: be something, something we
can put on the website.
So on the VC website,
Marie: one of, one of my
thoughts for next year
is Octoberfest, which I know a
bunch of people.
I just know everyone's gonna
love it is creating
something for students, for data
structures.
Because D three uses can use a
lot of animations.
So like, as you scroll through
the page, like maybe like
building like link list or going
through different, um,
data structures and explaining
how they work and different
problems that go along with them
as using D three.
And just like, as you scroll
through the page, like, oh,
this is how you go through a
binary tree or reverse
a binary tree or anything.
It would just be really cool to
build something out like that.
As you scroll through the page,
you just see like the data
structures being like built or
like going through a array or
a multi-dimensional array or
something like that would be, I
think that would be really fun
to do as like a group project.
Cuz we do the exorcism or
different like advent of
code, just like then you would
have to like the, the.
Code recipes is kind of
explaining in more basic
terminology, how to work through
like data structures
or different challenges.
Dan: There is somebody's I'm
man, there's a woman who has
a blog that she does kind of
like what you're talking about.
And I cannot remember what her
name is, but I will,
I will send you the link.
I'll share the link.
As soon as I find it, cause she
has done, she's done
some they're mostly front end
tutorials, I think.
But, um, mm-hmm,  uses D three
and uses animation
as you scroll and like all this
really cool stuff.
I, I haven't, it's spoken me
that I can't remember her
name, but I will, I will, uh, I
will send it to you.
And I'll if I remember it, I'll,
I'll put in the show
notes as well, so yeah.
Marie: Yeah.
Cuz that, just doing that, like.
Is exciting because you get to
build something cool.
And then you're like learning in
the process like, oh, I'm
not like awesome at DSAs.
But if I get to like fiddle
around with something, pick
apart something, and then show
you this website I
built that shows you this cool
DSA  using D three.
It kinda like solidifies your
knowledge while keeping
totally like how kids play with
like fun, like little.
Little things and they still
learn from it.
So
Kirk: that's, um, there's
another project you might
be interested in Marie.
Uh, one of the folks in the Elm
community, he does touch
dreams and he was working on a
recipe site for himself in Elm.
Yeah.
And an interesting thing he was
doing was trying to make it so.
You could adjust, you could
scale recipes.
So like there's the way it's in
the book, like
a slider and like, okay.
But what if I actually need more
servings?
Marie: Um, yeah, like for 10
people or what if I wanna cut
it just for date night for 10,
instead of having to like
Kirk: buy hand, figure out, oh,
how do I trim
all these ingredients?
And he was working on that, and
that was really interesting.
Because of course, nothing in
software is ever easy.
Like some things don't scale
linearly.
So he would end up with weird
units, one third of an, a
yeah, like 0.01 grams of salt.
And it's like, that can't be
right.
So it was just, it was just like
a really interesting
problem space that I think he's
still working on it.
But I'm wondering, I don't know
when you mentioned, I
feel like we still haven't
established by the way, whether
you made the fresh plastic site.
Marie: Do I made just like the
basic like first page,
but then from then on, I've just
been making other things.
So it's kind of hard to get back
and careers have shifted now.
I'm like, oh, just focusing on
software.
So maybe in the future, people
will get fresh
pasta, people need fresh
Kirk: pasta.
Um, yeah.
But yeah, I just, I remember
like I would watch him.
that was one of the ways like I
wanted to learn, not just
Elm cuz at that point, like I
was pretty familiar with the
language, but all the stuff you
were talking about, like how
to actually set up a project,
you know, you know, what,
what is his build process?
Like?
What is his order of operations
when he is working on
something as somebody who's like
been in the industry
for a really long time.
Um, so that was really fun to
watch and even just like how
he did his tests and like how he
iterated through solutions.
Bekah: um, okay.
Marie, you talked a little bit
about you're working
on different things you started
with this pasta site.
What other fun stuff are you
working on?
Marie: Currently?
I'm working still trying to tidy
up some of my projects
from boot camp, but, uh, we made
this C sharp website called AYQ
in and it's just asynchronous.
Like adding hotels, deleting ho
hotels editing, but I am trying
to tidy that up and just like
really build it out into like a
whole hotel website, which has
the backend like administrative
section with like permissions
and then the actual like hotel
site where you can go look at
these fake hotel rooms that
I'm gonna put up fake hotels.
So like a multi-branch hotel.
Um, corporation and then every
time you click, like,
oh, I'm going to go to, well,
I'm in Bermuda now.
So I'm gonna look at hotels in
Bermuda.
It'll show these fake hotels I
populated or put in the database
and then the rooms and, um,
prices, amenities, all of that.
Just building out that kind of
stuff, because I.
Right now we do stuff with like
permission checks.
So just like practicing what I
know and I'm learning on
the job, but applying it to a
different project that I'm
working on to kind of like
solidify my knowledge, which
I'm gonna do it differently in
my personal project versus
work because my personal project
is set up completely
different than work.
And, um, Yeah, just, just using
what I'm learning, like kind of
fresh on the job and applying it
to my like fun side project
that I'm, I guess didn't start
as a fun side project, but it's
now a fun side project, but kind
of just solid solidifying,
like what I'm doing.
To Ayn, which is gonna be super
cool when it comes out.
Because I think I'm even gonna
add like, maybe not with D three
GS, but like putting in, um, on
the administrative side, like.
Expense reports and salary and
payroll and all of that
to like have some sort of
dashboard to show, oh, you've
paid employees this much, but
you only made this much or
here's where your money's going.
Or I, I haven't worked out
exactly what I wanna do with
it, but it's gonna turn into a
whole work in progress.
It's like huge, huge project
sounds.
Dan: Sounds awesome.
Kirk: Find someone ambitious,
but.
Like developers look at their
side projects.
Bekah: yeah.
I also love how you're talking
about taking what you are
learning at work and applying it
to a different project,
because that does really help to
solidify your knowledge.
Cuz sometimes I find that I can
do something in one project.
And then when I go to transfer
to the other project, I'm
like, wait, why, what, why isn't
this working?
Right.
And so to ha to be able to.
Skills from one and put them
into another really does, um,
you know, help you to get a well
rounded understanding
of what you're doing.
And I think that's really great
advice.
Marie: Yeah.
And trying to figure out, oh,
now these are the differences
between my work project and my
personal project, because we use
old.net and my project is new.
The new do net core, I think.
Um, so there's just little tiny
little differences that
you're just gonna do completely
differently because there's
now new built in features and
methods, but just, yeah.
Learning to translate something
that.
Maybe I watched this on a
YouTube video or Kirk walked
me through this, on his project
and he set his, his project up
one way because we paired the
other day and I was like, oh
Kirk, you you're, you're setting
your project up this way.
And then see him was also there.
And she's like, oh, that's not
how we set it up.
But you also did yours
completely
different, which worked.
And you.
There's a million different ways
to do the same thing.
And it's still right.
It still works, but it's just
figuring out, oh yeah, I
can think about it that way.
And it still works.
And Kirk explained, oh, I did it
because, because this
is how I know how to do it.
And I was like, oh, I did it
because this is
how I know how to do it.
Yeah.
Don't give
Kirk: me too much credit and
they're completely different.
I didn't, because that's, I only
know one away.
I'm like, well, this is gonna,
Marie: yeah, exactly, exactly
though.
But then you see like, You think
of it one way.
I think of it this way.
They're both right.
We both got solutions to work
and like, if you see
someone's stuff, their code and
it's not how you do it,
just have them walk you through
it and be like, oh yeah,
that is how it could work.
Bekah: Yeah, I love that so
much.
And I, uh, with my background
being in English, I always
like, think about it in terms of
literature and writing.
And so much of coding is, is
you're an author of something
that's being written, right.
There are different styles and
there are different
patterns and ways of doing
things, um, that give you.
Different feels, um, and can
provide different things,
but there are many valid ways of
doing it and also fun.
Like if you've ever written with
a person, um, if you've
collaborated on a project, like
there's a negotiation,
like it, it has to flow, right?
Like it all has to sound the
same.
And I think too, when you're
diving into a new code base,
you might have come with.
A certain style or even certain
bad habits.
Right.
And then you're working through
that like, okay, well, this
is, this is the style of this
project that I'm working on.
And now I need to figure out how
to kind of
translate that in my brain.
And when you're looking at
people doing the same thing in
multiple different approaches, I
think that can also really
help you to understand, um, how,
how many different methods
there are and inform your, your
own understanding and style.
Marie: Yeah.
I, I think like collaborating
with people, hearing how they
work, seeing how they work and
just having all of that
knowledge of different ways,
even not of the same thing,
but like Kirk working on his
project, you working on your
project and me pairing with Nick
on forum, seeing all the
different ways you could set
projects up, it just helps,
you know, that you can adapt.
And learn new styles, learn or
just read other people's
work and understand it can still
work, even if it's not
exactly how you would set it up.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely.
All right, Maria, I wanna thank
you so much
for being here with us.
Uh, this has been a great
interview before,
uh, we end the episode.
I just wanna make sure that I
haven't missed anything
that you wanna talk about or
anything that you'd like to.
Marie: No, I think, I think we
discussed it a lot.
Not really sure what else?
That's great.
Bekah: I think this has been
really fantastic.
So thank you so much for being
here with us
and sharing your story.
Um, So where can our listeners
find you?
Marie: You can find me on
Twitter as Marie.
Antones my, just my full name or
LinkedIn.
Bekah: Awesome.
Thank you so much.
And we'll link those all in the
show notes.
Um, so thanks again for being
here.
Thanks for having
Marie: me.
Thanks Marie.
Thanks everybody.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of
the virtual coffee podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
OT and Bekah OT,
Weigel, and edited by Dan OT.
If you have any questions or
comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at.
Virtual coffee IO, or you can
email
us@podcastvirtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show
notes@virtualcoffee.io.
Plus you can sign up for the
newsletter to find out what
virtual coffee's been up to.
Dan: Please remember to
subscribe and leave us a review
on apple podcasts or wherever
you're getting your podcast.
Next week, we have Tori Crawford
on the podcast, um, discussing
the problems of interviewing,
uh, in the tech industry.
Thanks so much for listening and
we will see you next week.