Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season one, episode three of
the virtual coffee podcast.
I am Bekah and this is a podcast
that features members of the
virtual coffee community.
Virtual coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their stories
and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you here with me.
Today is my co-host Dan.
Dan: In this episode, Tori
Crawford joins us to talk
about her journey through the
interview process that
included about 53 interviews,
430 applications in a pandemic
offer that ultimately led to her
being ghosted by the company.
She gives her tips and tricks,
including recognizing that
interviews are a two-way street
and her hope for industry.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast.
Like we start every virtual
coffee.
We introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're
from, what we do and a random
check-in question.
Today's question is what is one
interesting
thing about yourself?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah.
I am from a small town in Ohio.
I'm a front end developer.
And one interesting thing about
me is that my first pet was
a hamster and I named it star
scraper to the highest moon.
Dan: Star scraper.
Hi, I'm Dan.
I am a front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio, and
an interesting fact about me is
that I play disc golf.
Tori: Hi, I'm Tori I'm from San
Jose, California.
I am currently a back end
engineer specializing
in Ruby on rails and interesting
a fact about me.
Would have to be that I
hopefully plan to retire
in Ireland, someday.
So on site.
nice.
Very, very cool.
Bekah: Yeah.
Um, thanks for being here with
us, Tori.
We are very, very excited to be
talking to today.
A little background about Tori.
She is a software engineer, a
blogger, and
a mental health advocate.
She graduated from the flat iron
school software engineering
program in February of 2019.
After 14 months and over 15
interviews landed her first
role as a backend engineer in
June of 2020 since landing her
first role, she's gotten married
and is now an expecting mother
with the aspiration of becoming
a site reliability engineer.
Also like to, um, say that Tori
is a Steelers fan and she knows
the value of square pizza.
And that's very,
Tori: very important to me.
Very important.
Ohio valley pizza is the best
pizza  that's right.
I,
Bekah: um, very much had some
this weekend.
So if you have not had that,
Google it, you are missing out.
And I am sorry for everyone who
does not
live in the Ohio valley.
Tori: Um,
Bekah: all right, Dan, you're
missing out.
It's mm-hmm  it's.
Uh, so Tori, I just love to get
started with origin stories
and I know our paths have
overlapped in a lot of ways.
We both went to flat iron, Ohio
valley connections,
Steelers fans, um, software
engineers, moms.
Um, but I wanna get more details
about your story.
So can you tell us how you got
Tori: into software engineering?
Yeah.
So, um, We'll go back a little
bit further.
I guess I am a career changer.
Um, I did go to flat iron
school, um, as a bootcamp
and, uh, previously I was an
athletic trainer.
Um, I went to school for five
years.
I got two bachelor's degrees and
a master's degree.
Um, and.
Yeah, I worked for an east coast
hockey league team called the
Wichita thunder for a season.
And it was a lot of fun.
Um, but I was working like a
hundred hours a week and
it was an insane schedule to
keep traveling constantly.
I kind of learned that that
isn't really what I
wanted and, um, Yeah, it was
like a hard wake up call.
And I had to like reevaluate
things and discovered that I
didn't really have the same
passion for athletic training.
If it wasn't sitting on the
bench on beside ice, watching
hockey players dodging pucks
sticks, you know?
Um, so yeah, I.
Reevaluated, everything kind of
decided what I
wanted to move into next.
My now husband is a data
engineer and he suggested,
because he knew how creative I
liked being possibly looking
into front end engineering.
And I learned HTML and CSS
started to learn.
JavaScript felt like I couldn't
wrap my head around it at all.
So , I tried to look for some
structure, which landed
me at flat iron school.
And, um, it was there that I
fell in love with Ruby and.
Decided to completely pivot to
back end and yeah, it just  fell
right into that, that fun spiral
of then not really liking front
end and despising JavaScript.
Um, but you know, it's okay.
Got through it.
And I still, to this day, work
with our front front
end engineers at my company to
like, keep those skills.
Kind of like brushed up on
because I struggled
learning them so much.
I'm not gonna lose them.
So , yeah.
Bekah: I love that.
That's just a really great
attitude to have.
Um, I also love that you are a
collector of degrees.
Tori: yep.
Um, lots of school
Bekah: and also you've been
coming to virtual coffee since
almost the very beginning.
I think the first tweet that I
sent out in the beginning
of April, um, you responded to,
and I don't think maybe
you made that one, but you made
the second one and
you've been here for a while.
So I'd love to know a little bit
more about like how you
came to find virtual coffee.
Tori: Yeah.
Um, Obviously like through
bootcamp, you and I
had communicated a few times and
I was already
following you on Twitter.
And, um, I feel like with the
pandemic and everything,
obviously the need for community
was there.
And before the pandemic, I
really tried to go out
and do a lot of meetups.
And like I was driving an hour
up to San Francisco to do a
few different meetups up there,
like a month, like once a month.
And, um, when the pandemic hit,
I kind of lost that.
Um, And when you mentioned doing
the virtual coffee
stuff, I was like, oh my.
This sounds amazing.
Um, I was super excited and then
of course I, I was in California
and you're on the east coast and
you're like, yeah, it's gonna
be at 9 AM Eastern time.
And I was like, I am not waking
up at 6 AM.
so I was really happy that the
next time you move, like
the Thursday, I think it was a
Thursday meeting the next time.
Um, Was at noon.
And I was like, oh, that's
totally doable.
Um, so I started going to those,
but yeah, it was just
that need for community.
And also like, while I enjoyed
going to in person, um, events,
it did suck having to drive all
the way up to San Francisco.
Whenever I wanted to do one.
Um, while there were some in the
south bay, they just
were more along the lines of.
Super educational, like
technical interviewing, um,
prep, which like I went to
those, but the fun ones,  where
they would do like karaoke and
like really like have
like happy hour type things were
up in San Francisco.
And I enjoyed those felt a
little bit more lax for me.
Um, So definitely it was nice to
be like, okay,
well this, I won't have to drive
an hour to get to.
And then an hour back at like
nine o'clock at night
and  so yeah, it was, it was a
good, a good little
like, yeah, I wanna do this.
It's gonna be great doing
something virtual.
Um, and then, you know, pandemic
is still going
months later and we can't do
anything in person yet.
So this has become the new
normal and yeah.
It's great to have found my
community that I really like,
and I feel very accepted in, so,
and I can be myself.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah.
It's been great having you here
and, you know, I so much
admire your vulnerability and
how much you've been able
to share with the community,
because, you know, just to have
that, like closeness allows for
such a stronger, a stronger
community, when you can talk
about things like that, the
challenges that you're facing.
So it's been
Tori: great having you here.
Yeah.
It's been really nice.
Being able to be open and
vulnerable with a.
100%.
Like, I really feel like I can
come to the group with a lot of
different problems that I face
and someone's gonna be there to
tell me that it's gonna be okay
or like help give me advice.
Um, so it's, or just like say
that they relate and
like we can discuss our feelings
together and I.
So unique and I really love it.
Bekah: Yeah.
I, I also love that very much
about the community.
And I think that, you know,
being able to share these
things also, you know, you don't
feel alone in circumstances
where you might feel alone.
Um, mm-hmm
Tori: that's
so
Bekah: you.
Are maybe a prolific interviewer
Tori: um,
Bekah: I think probably not by
choice and I just am
was like, remember being so
surprised at all the stuff
that you had to go through as
you were interviewing.
So can you just talk through
that journey a little bit?
Tori: Yeah.
yeah.
Um,  interviewing was.
Crazy for me.
Um, when I first graduated from
flat iron school, I
took about a month and a half
off from when I graduated to
when I started my job search.
Um, so I started my job search.
Late March or early April of
2019.
Um, and it went until June of
2020.
And, uh, I think I went through,
I have a blog post
on all of my stats and I think I
went through 53 interviews.
Um, it was crazy.
I was talking to my husband last
night and he was like, you know,
like most people go through
like, 10 in their lifetime or
they like go through like a
handful in their lifetime and
you went through so many and I'm
like, yeah, it was like
quite a struggle at times.
Um, I was getting through a lot
of first round interviews
getting through a lot of them.
Um, I don't.
Think that I have a real issue.
Personality wise that like has
red flags that like
recruiters are like, Nope, we're
not letting them go past.
Um, so like that's nice.
Um, I got really good at doing
those interviews,
but technical interviews were
the tough part for me.
Um, definitely just like nerve
wracking at the beginning.
I.
At some points, like, honestly,
like I cried
before the interview, I was
like, so stressed out and
nervous and just like, felt so
down on myself, like, I'm
not gonna be good at this.
Like, this is like, it's so much
pressure to like
one have a time limit.
Two have like one to who knows
how many other people sitting
there, like watching you code?
Um, I was still.
Not confident in speaking out
loud while coding, like I
could do it, but I still like to
this day, I still feel like
I'm not the most technical
speaker when I'm talking, when
I'm going through my code.
Like, I feel like I don't say.
Technically right thing all the
time.
Um, and a few of my coworkers
always ensure me now.
They're like, no, this is gonna
come with months of experience.
Like, you're gonna get the hang
of it eventually.
Um, this isn't something that
you have to know right now, but
like, you feel that pressure
when you're in interview.
Um, so those, those were where I
was failing at first.
I like would not make it past
technical interviews.
Um, Eventually, I like really
worked on one.
I was getting so many technical
interviews that I was getting a
little less nervous about them.
I was feeling more comfortable
in myself.
speaking out loud.
I was just like getting used to
the process and, um, Things
got a little bit easier.
I felt more lax and you know, it
was, I was getting
past them a little bit more and
eventually I started
making it to final rounds and,
you know, got ghosted a
few times and , you know, it
happened way more often than
I would have expected it to.
I got ghosted by a company who
offered me a job.
Mm-hmm  so.
That was fun.
it was a crazy process going
through, um, it
was a rollercoaster ride.
Yeah.
And I'm I'm, it was all worth it
in the end.
I love where I work now.
I love the people I work with.
So, you know, everything I went
through was completely worth
what I'm getting to do now.
Dan: Did you find yourself like
having to, um, with
the technical interviews?
I mean, having all that practice
makes sense that you would be
more comfortable near the end of
the process, but, um, as
far as like, actually learn,
like trying to, I don't get
better at the technical part or
anything, like, did you
find yourself like trying to
study or, or do more things
or learn more things when you
were in that, you know, stage.
Tori: Yeah, I definitely did.
Um, I actually started taking, I
realized that the questions
that were really getting me
stumped and whatnot was like,
I would be able to write out the
solution, but it
wouldn't be super efficient.
And like, I would be asked the
question, like, how
would you make this better?
Like, how would you decrease
the, the time
that it takes to complete.
This algorithm or whatever.
And, um, I, I wasn't able to
answer it.
Like I like big O time
complexity.
Like I, I had no idea.
I wasn't taught that in
bootcamp.
Um, I didn't do a good job at
going out and
trying to teach myself it either
at the beginning.
Um, I realized that that, that
was kind of my weakness.
It was happening over and over
again.
And, you know, eventually you
have to look at yourself
and be like, okay, well, you
need to learn this.
You keep ask, getting asked
these types of questions.
Um, you're not going, gonna get
past these types of
interviews if you don't learn.
Um, so I.
Um, bought a U Demi course.
I don't know if that's how you
say it.
U Demi, you D me . I bought a
course on data
structures and algorithms.
Um, it was like mastering the
coding interview
and I went through.
The whole data structures,
section and big O section.
And I learned so much and I was
like, oh my gosh, this
all makes so much more sense.
Like, this is why I should be
writing my code this way.
It's so much more efficient.
And like, oh, if I like assign
in a ver a variable here,
like that takes up more space.
And I  like I had no.
Idea of any of those things.
When I first started
interviewing and I went
through this course and like, I
really felt like things
were starting to click for me.
And I started to get a lot
better at interviewing
being able to answer questions,
feeling a lot
more comfortable speaking.
And, um, it was just, I don't
know, it was like
a whole different like
confidence booster that I
was like, this is great.
Um, I just.
I don't know, I feel like I kind
of like blossomed and took off
at that point that I was able to
like, learn those small things.
And I was starting to get past
those interviews and
I was like, okay, this was
totally worth the money
that I paid for this course.
And I've like really starting to
see progress.
Um, and.
I finally got an offer and then
the pandemic hit.
And then I got ghosted by the
company that offered me
the job and , um, and like a
little bit of a confidence,
ER, at that point, cause it was
like interviews basically
stopped for a month or two.
And I was like, man, I just hit
my stride.
Yeah.
I, I had just hit my stride and
like really felt like
things were going well.
Um, And kind of got halted, but
then things started
picking back up again, started
interviewing what the company
that I'm working with now.
And it was . It was great.
And you know, the company that I
work for now, didn't give me
some crazy technical interview.
Like a lot of other companies
did.
Um, I got to walk through an old
project that I created
for a different company.
Uh  when I interviewed through
them, something that I was proud
of, but I didn't make it past.
That interview process.
Um, but I was proud of the
project that I built.
I got to walk through it with,
um, my director
of engineering now.
And, uh, , it was, it was a
great thing of like him
just like asking me a bunch of
questions, why I built
it the way that I did.
And, um, the thought process
that went into.
Like why I chose to use
technology XYZ and like all
of these, like more thoughtful
technical questions, um, that
weren't like solve this crazy
algorithm because you're
totally gonna use this and
Dan: work.
Right.
Was he, wasn't just trying to
stump you or whatever.
Tori: Yeah.
Bekah: I also think that's a
really good indication of
the type of workplace too.
Um, you just covered so much
stuff, uh, that I
wanna talk about, but I wanna
back up for a second.
Um, so I was talking to some
people this weekend and one
of the things I said is, um,
when you hear somebody
say no so many times.
There's I think so many times
you can hear it before you
start to believe it yourself.
Right.
And I think that we see that
happening with a lot of
people who are interviewing for
jobs and getting
those repeat rejections.
And I'm, I am curious like how
you dealt with
that because that's a lot.
And I think, you know, that just
says a lot about
you, that you were able to keep
working through
that, but how were you able
Tori: to keep working?
Yeah.
It's oh man, it's crazy.
Um, it it's tough.
I honestly, at the beginning I
had a really hard time with it.
Um, I think one lesson that I
had to learn through
the process of getting rejected
so many times was.
It's not personal.
Um, as much as it's like, yeah,
they're rejecting you.
They're denying you.
Um, you're not a good fit.
It's like, okay.
But you may not be the best fit
right now for that company
that doesn't always necessarily
mean that you won't always be
a good fit for that company.
Um, your skills may not be where
they need to
be at that point for the role
that you applied to.
That's that's okay.
It's it's not, it's not
personal.
It's, they're looking for
specific things.
You're not really meeting those
criteria and that's, it's okay.
You're not gonna meet the needs
of every company.
You're not gonna, I hate using
this cultural fit thing, but
like, you're not gonna fit the
culture of every company.
You're not it.
You just, you can't take it
personally.
Like you really have to detach
and it.
At first, like, I, I cried a lot
at the rejections.
Um,  I struggle.
I mean, I'm, I'm open about
this.
I, I struggle with depression.
I struggle with anxiety.
This is like, that was something
that like, I ended up going to
therapy, like at the beginning
of my job search because I was
having a hard time handling the
rejection thing and it was like
really making my depression bad.
And, you know, you just, you
have to learn to,
to kind of detach from it,
realize that it's.
Personal attack.
It's not anything really
against, against you and you
kind of just, you, you have to
like take a moment and reflect
and be like, okay, well, why
could they have rejected me?
And, and like, in a way of like
being detached, like
think, okay, was I missing some
certain skills that they
were definitely asking for?
Um,  and that kind of gives you
a moment to like, reflect and
be like, okay, well, I didn't
have skill X, Y, Z, or sometimes
like, I even had to like think
through the interview that I
had with the person and be like,
okay, was there something, was
there something that I wouldn't
have liked about the company?
Did they ask me weird questions
that like, I, that would like
raise a little flag in my head.
At that point too.
Like, I definitely had a lot of
those.
I pulled out of interview
processes with companies because
like I was feeling red flags.
Um, and you have to realize that
the interview
process goes both ways.
And in that it's like a company
might not be a good fit for you.
You might not be a good fit for
a company.
And like, it's okay.
It's nothing against that
company.
It's nothing against.
You just like, you kind of have
to see it from an outside
point of view and try not to get
down on yourself about it.
I think it was really tough for
me to get that into
my head for a long time.
But it made things a lot better
when I was able to detach
from it a little bit more
personally and not feel like it
was an attack against myself.
Um, yeah,
Bekah: I think again, like
you're just dropping
every gem out there.
Um, I love that you are talking
about.
Pulling out of interviews.
I think it can be so hard,
especially when you're
looking for a role and you're
looking for one so long.
And then to think like, man,
there are a lot
of red flags here.
What should I, that has to be a
difficult decision to make.
And then, you know, also this
idea, you are also
interviewing them as well.
I think that, you know, that is
something that needs
to be really emphasizes.
People are going into
interviews.
I know I've done a really bad
job of like using my gut to
check whether or not like, okay,
this feels really awful.
And she's making me feel really
bad right now, but I, I probably
should keep trying anyway.
Right.
You know?
And so, yeah, I think those are
skills that, that
those are skills, right?
Those are things that you
develop and that you
Tori: build.
And you definitely like build
them the more you go
through the interview process.
And that was something that
like, once I started
having interviews, that made me
feel really good.
I started to realize how many
interviews I had had
that made me feel really bad.
um, and like made those terrible
interviews and like a lot of
those red flags that like, I
hadn't really recognized
as red flags in the past.
As I started having like
interviews with companies who
like genuinely cared about who
they were, like the person
that they were interviewing for,
like interviewing, um,
it wasn't like there are some
companies that you are just on
a line and they're just like
bringing you through the process
and you're just a number.
Um, but then there are also
interviews who care.
The candidate and their time,
there are, there
are companies that will pay you
for trial periods.
When I had that happen, I got
paid for a week of
work because the company wanted
to trial me and, you
know, it was, it was great.
It was very like breathtaking.
It was like, oh my gosh, this
actually does happen.
Um, so, um, yeah, so there
there're obviously companies.
Care about their candidates, um,
and treat them correctly.
There are some companies that
treat you like you're
just another number.
And I think that one thing that
you really have to remember
when you're going through the
interview process is like
I said before, and like you just
said, Bekah is that.
The interview process is a two
way street.
Like you are also interviewing
the company as
they are interviewing you.
Um, that is one thing that I
like really, really like drove
myself home with all the time.
I like prepared questions before
every interview.
I was like, I am going to ask
them all of the questions
that I need to know to know if I
want to work at
this place because yeah.
I wanted a job really bad, but
like, I wasn't
gonna put myself in a bad.
Work environment just because I
wanted a job really bad.
Like, I, I know that like, it's,
it's such a, a hard
thing, but I, I put myself in.
A work environment where I was
sexually harassed in the past.
And that is something that like
I would ask about diversity.
I would ask about like questions
of how they go
about dealing with things like
that in the workspace.
And those are tough questions to
ask during interviews.
But like, if it's something
that's important to you,
like you need to ask them.
And if the company like towers
down, when you ask
them those questions, it's not
somewhere that you wanna work.
Um, so like it.
It's something that like, you
have to interview
the company too.
And, um, at my current job, like
I, I am interviewing
people  to work, to work with us
and, um, I am.
I I'm always thrown when
candidates don't prepare
questions  and they're like,
yeah, I don't have
any questions for you.
And I'm like, I literally left
like 15 minutes for you to
like, drill me with questions.
I'm ready for them.
Like give 'em to me.
Like you should also be
interviewing us.
Like, this is very important.
Like, you should know that you
wanna work here.
Um, and.
Yeah, I think, I think it's so
important that like, you know,
the questions that you wanna ask
a company, you, you have to
know yourself and know what you
want out of a work environment.
And I think that's really
important in
the job search process.
Dan: You, um, you mentioned how
this process kind of a
skill that you build up, right?
The, the, like the way to be an
interviewer interviewee.
Um, I was wondering if that sort
of skill changed the way that.
Search for jobs or like apply,
you know, like change, which,
which companies you would apply
or which positions you would
apply for things like that.
As you sort of went through the
process, um, you know,
if you could talk about like how
you try to find different
positions to apply for, um, or
if that changed, you know,
from the start to the end.
Tori: Yeah.
It definitely changed from the
start to the, to the end of it.
Um, at the beginning I was kind
of applying to like everything.
Everything that I could find.
Honestly, when I first started
looking for a job,
I wasn't, I wasn't being picky
about working backend.
I was like, I'm gonna apply to
front end positions.
I'm gonna apply to full stack.
I'm gonna apply to backend.
I'm apply to everything.
Um,  and.
Man.
That was, that was a mistake.
I think.
I mean, like you, you spend so
much time
putting in applications.
And I think even at the
beginning, I wasn't
tailoring my resume to meet the
job application.
Like if I would've done that, I
would've spent like so many more
hours because I, it was, it.
Ridiculous that I was applying
to as many companies
as I was at the beginning.
Um, and towards, I don't know, a
few months in, I started
to realize that I needed to do
quality of a quantity.
And I started tailoring my
resume and cover letter to the
applications I was sending in.
Um, I was really trying to make
contacts with people
who worked at the company.
Um, I, I really started to, to
try to like put my best foot
forward, rather than just like
sending in an application to
the unknown , um, where like
hundreds of other applications
also go, uh, I started to
realize when I was applying
everywhere that often more often
than not, I, I wasn't
really getting replies back at
all, rejections or.
Like interest for interviews.
Um, and I was applying to big
companies and small companies.
I, yeah, I, I was applying to
everything
under the, under the sun.
And then eventually I learned
that, um, I
learned what I wanted.
I like, I started to realize
through some of
the interview processes that I
was going through.
The bigger companies were the
companies that did those like
crazy technical interviews that
were like, here's this
crazy algorithm solve it.
And the startups were more the
ones of like giving take homes
or like walking, like pair
programming more like Laly I
guess, like it wasn't such a
high stress type of environment.
Um, so.
I think that like, eventually
through that, that interview
process of like going through
the interviews with
different types of companies, I
learned that I wanted to
stay more towards startup.
Um, it seemed like it was more
the environment of what I
would want to work in because I
mean, I think we all kind
of recognize that these crazy
algorithm interviews are just,
they're not applicable to.
The daily job that you do there.
It's not a, I don't know, it's
not an indicator.
I don't think it's an indicator
of like how good
you're gonna do at this job.
I, I really think that it's,
it's messy.
And, um, I think that there are
startups and smaller
companies that are kind of going
against the grain of what the
larger companies are doing.
And.
I think that I personally made
the decision that I would rather
work for a company like that.
So, you know, started tailoring
my, um, applications
towards startups and smaller
sized companies.
And then eventually I made the
decision.
Yeah.
I wanna work back end.
I don't wanna do full stack.
I don't wanna do front end,
started tailoring
them more that way.
Um, So I think through the
process, I started applying
to everything and then I like
funneled down  and
eventually like became a little
bit more specialized
in what I was applying to.
And I started, I realized that I
was getting more responses,
more interviews that way.
So that was.
That was great.
I think that's so
Bekah: great.
And I think that especially, uh,
when you're fresh out of
school or bootcamp or whatever,
when you're first applying,
there's this tendency for a lot
of people just to start learning
everything at like a very.
Shallow level, because I think
that's going to make them more,
um, relevant in job search.
But I think that you're right
specializing or really
understanding yourself and what
you are interested
in can, can be useful.
I mean, it also can help you to
be more excited about what
you're doing and more relaxed.
And when you're in an interview
and you can.
Act in that way, it definitely
makes you a, a candidate
that seems confident.
I think.
Tori: I think you definitely
come off better.
Um, so
Bekah: you have touched on this
a couple of times,
but like, obviously there's an
industry problem with
interviewing, right.
And we see more people talking
about it.
Um, and I wonder what you think
about, or if you have
ideas about how to improve the
interview process, but
like also keeping in mind.
Is it an industry problem?
Is it a, um, my bootcamp or my
university didn't train me
well enough before going into
the job market, a combination
or, you know, what are your
thoughts on, you know, this
process and making it better?
Tori: Yeah.
Um, I think, I think first to
touch on the whole like
bootcamp and, um, computer
science degree thing.
I think bootcamps do, um, some
bootcamps are great.
Some bootcamps are not just like
some computer
science degree programs are
great and some are not.
Um, I, I have a friend who got a
computer science degree.
Like he knew a lot of the, the
theory and principal stuff, but
didn't really know how to code.
Um, and he struggled to find a
software engineering job.
He ended up finding a support
job, um, and has
kind of been stuck in that.
But he's finally got outta
finally got out of it recently
and just moved to Columbus, Ohio
and is working for a startup
and I'm super happy for him.
Um, but it took some time for
him to like pull out of that.
And I think.
I also struggled with my
interview process because
I came from a bootcamp cuz I
didn't know the
computer science like stuff.
I think there's weaknesses in
both areas.
Some bootcamps, maybe great at
teaching that stuff.
And they like the students come
out well rounded.
Some computer science degrees
are that way.
Um, but there's weaknesses in
everything.
Um, and.
I think that not everybody comes
out well rounded and to, as an
industry to expect . Brand new,
like entry level engineers to
solve these crazy algorithms.
Like, I mean, even senior
engineers, I've like, I've
heard, I've spoken to a few of
them who are terrified
to go back into the job market
because they would
have to do these things.
They don't feel comfortable
doing it either.
Which like, I think just that
fact alone that like, it doesn't
matter what level you are.
Whether you're entry, you're
senior you're principal.
Like it doesn't matter.
Like you can be just as afraid
of these crazy algorithm
questions as anyone else.
And I think that that speaks to
the fact that like somebody
with 10 years industry
experience can't solve it.
I.
I, why are you giving them if
it's something that
somebody has been working, like
doing this job for 10
years, like you would expect
them to be able to answer it
Bekah: easily.
But they can't
Tori: and it like it's, I, I
definitely think it's broken.
I think that there's been this
idea that solving
these algorithms is a great way
to get to know
how the candidate thinks.
Like, if you wanna know how the
candidate thinks
or plans, then like speak to
them about planning.
Or like, like ask them those
types of driven questions.
Don't try to pull that out by
asking like some crazy,
like, weird question and like
try to get about it and get
to it in a roundabout way.
Like that's not, it doesn't seem
efficient.
It doesn't like, I, I don't know
it to me.
It just, everything seems kind
of broken and I feel like.
One day, one of these big tech
companies was like, we're gonna
ask this question and we have a
great interview process.
And like, it's really hard.
And then all of these other
companies were like, oh, we're
gonna implement that too.
And it's just been like a
copycat process.
And a lot of companies wanna be
like these big tech companies.
So they just, they just copied
the process and.
Whether it's good for their
company or company
or not, whether it's beneficial
for them or not.
And it's, I don't know.
I think, I think like a lot of
things, the head of industries
set a lot of standards that they
kind of like set those
standards and everybody follows
just, it's not necessarily,
uh, Not necessarily the best
thing  and it's tough and it's
tough to go against the grain.
But I think that there are a lot
of startups out there and
a lot of smaller companies and
even some like decently
large companies that are going
against the grain.
And I think that that's
wonderful that it's
being recognized that our
interview process is broken.
It's great that people are like
really standing up and being
like candidates are people too.
you need to respect their time.
You need to respect, like giving
somebody a take
home project or something.
That's gonna take four to six
hours.
That's a huge chunk of their
time.
I like, I just, if you're not
gonna pay them for
that work, it's crazy.
Like doing a two hour, one is
still a lot, but
I that's more reasonable.
It's I, it's just tough.
I think that there's a lot of, a
lot of things that are wrong in
the interview or yeah, like in
the interview process right now.
Um, and I'm not sure that there
is a blanket way to fix it.
Like it's really gonna be case
by case company by company.
And I think just recognizing
that there is an issue is the
first step to fixing the issue.
Um, and I think having more
people.
Being outspoken about it is like
really important because
it's gonna start pushing, um,
it's gonna start pushing
people that are the heads of
these companies and whatnot
to like, kind of look at their
processes and kind of.
Adjust and see what could be
going wrong and like
why people are unhappy and, you
know, we'll see.
Bekah: Yeah.
I, um, was talking to somebody
recently about the situation
in this, um, what you said it
not being a blanket.
Um, Like one, one answer for it.
Right.
And that we're looking at people
and people are complex.
I think really sticks out to me.
Um, in finding this idea of like
a, a person first
interview process is important.
And, um, one guy was saying,
well, well like, well, we
have to standardize it as best
as we possibly can.
And like, I, anytime that I hear
that, it just makes me cringe
a little bit because you can't
really standardize the process.
And I think if you're trying to
standardize.
Sanitizes things in some way,
and you don't see the complex
person and you're not allowing
for different perspectives.
And in that way, you are
probably cutting out some really
amazing candidates because maybe
they don't perform well
while you're staring at them or
with a timed test or something,
you know, there's all of these
problems and it's not just in
tech, but, um, not allowing for.
I think diversity of approach or
allowing a candidate to
fully explore what they would do
is really not good for
the company or the industry
Tori: either.
No, definitely not.
And it feels that would be
really hindering on some people
like you're not letting them.
Like show you their full
potential.
You're not letting them have a
creative mind or like
showing you something that you
wouldn't have thought of.
Like, if you're, if you're
setting a standard, it's you
also, you cut people out.
Of the process.
Like I, when you start setting
standards, I think that's
when you really start to get
into the issue of like really
messing with minority people and
you start messing with.
A lot of stuff.
Yeah, go ahead, Dan.
Dan: sorry to, I was just gonna
say, then you just
start hiring people that are
good at the stand getting
through the standard process.
It's like, this is the same
problem with the standardized
tests in public schools, you
know, um, all of the, like
then all of the learning will be
about trying to, you know,
Get through the standard test or
whatever it is.
I mean, this happens in schools,
but like, if that was the
process with interviews, you
know, and it already sort of
happens, there's so much effort
gone into, um, like that course
you bought was like, you know,
you used it to learn a specific
thing, but it was geared towards
passing technical interviews.
Right.
Like that was the whole thing.
Yeah.
And, uh, and like the there's a
lot of people, you know,
making money on that sort of
thing anyway, and so
much time and effort, and then
you get your job and.
You never use any of, any of
that stuff ever again.
Right?
Any of those skills?
I mean, obviously not totally
true, but there's just so
much, so much, uh, you know,
sweat that you put into
getting good at something.
And then like a lot of that
isn't transferable or doesn't
transfer, you know, to what
you're actually doing anyway.
Um, yeah.
Tori: And you hear all these
like crazy stories of
people who essentially train
themselves for the interview
process and then they get in and
they can't do the job.
Yeah.
Bekah: 100%.
Tori: No it's.
Yeah.
And like, how are these
companies filtering for that?
You can't, because like you're
not actually
testing for things that.
Job applicable , which is
Dan: crazy.
Yeah.
It's a hard problem.
And it's, and it's a hard
problem from the
employers side too.
You know, the smaller company is
the easier, I think it is.
So the company you started
working for, you know, you're
a man, I don't remember what
position, but whoever hired
you, you know, like sat and like
worked with you, like
talked with you for a while.
And that's really, I agree the
best way to find if a
person fits all of that stuff.
Um, but.
That's time consuming on their
end, you know, to, and you get
a large company where there's
literally millions of people
applying for a position  and
the, you know, they can kind
of see how this stuff happens.
Not, not that the solution is
good, but
like how they got there.
Right.
You know, just because just so
many people
applying and there are
programmers on the other end.
You know, like trying to
optimize it, like, you know,
like Bekah was saying, I'm sure
the person you were talking
to that said that we should
standardize the process was,
uh, in development somewhere.
I'm guessing, you know, cuz
that's the kind of, uh, like
that's the kind of answer that
you jump to first.
Right.
If I see a problem, I'm like,
okay, how can like, how can
we fix this with my hammer?
That is, you know, that is like
development,
you know what I mean?
but it's not a development
problem.
Right.
It's a people problem.
So mm-hmm  I.
I don't really have a point
there.
It's just a  it's a very complex
problem.
Tori: Um, yeah, it, it is a very
complex problem.
I absolutely love everything
that you said.
So it's yeah, it's, it's a tough
topic.
It's a really tough topic.
Bekah: Yeah.
Yeah.
I, and I think I step one is
talking about it, right?
yep.
Thinking about it.
Step one on a larger scale, if
you can, and just like
realizing and identifying.
The things that are wrong.
And sometimes it's hard to put
those things
into words, I think.
Or like, you're not exactly sure
why they're wrong, but
just acknowledging like,
something feels bad about this.
Right.
And then kind of building from
there and talking
to other people is.
Is moving in the right
direction.
Right.
You need to get some momentum,
so start there and
then keep moving forward.
And then, you know, definitely
have a support system as
you're going through the
interview process because it is
Tori: hard mm-hmm  yeah, it's
really hard.
And I think honestly, virtual
coffee kind of
came about right at the perfect
time for me because.
Interviewing did slow down a
ton.
And I really felt like I had
lost my momentum and was
feeling kind of down on myself.
And when interviews started
going well again, I was like
posting a bit and I was getting
cheered on and, you know, it was
just, it was great at the time.
And also when sad things happen,
like you don't get a job, like
you're told, like don't give up
and, you know, it's, it's a
great community to be a part of.
And I think.
I don't wanna say we're all
cheerleaders, but like , we're
all very positive and, um, very
much like pushing for one
another to do our best and to
keep our heads held high and
not get too down on ourselves.
So it's great.
Wanna, thank
Bekah: you so much for being
here.
Tori, you said so many awesome
things.
Um, what are some things that
you have coming up or
things that you're interested
Tori: in?
Yeah.
Um, well, one huge thing coming
up.
I'm expecting my baby in my .
Um, but yeah, besides that,
I am kind of just trying to get
used to, you know, working
I'm about to hit my six months
mark of officially working as a
software engineer and I'm really
excited to hit it and I'm.
I'm almost getting to like full
autonomy and working
on my own, which is great.
Um, my coworkers are great,
confident, confident boosters.
They are like, I'm like, uh, can
we pair on this ticket?
And they're like, you got this,
you got this, like, okay, that
happened this morning again.
it keeps happening.
Um  but yeah, it's, it's fun.
I'm.
I'm just excited to continue
working and building
my backend skills and.
I am hoping to move into site
reliability
engineering in the future.
And I'm like slowly reading
through the Google
site, reliability book.
And, uh, I'm working with our
site reliability engineer
and our head of engineering who
used to be an SRE, um,
going through some things, uh,
on our product and learning
a little bit about that stuff as
well as my backend.
So.
It's fun.
They're grooming me.
They're getting me ready and I'm
really liking it.
So it's great.
Bekah: that is very awesome.
Um, okay.
So if our listeners want to find
you, how can they do that?
Tori: Yeah, I am over on Twitter
and I need to look up.
I never remember my username,
your underscore T O
Bekah: O R R.
We'll include it in the show
notes.
Yeah.
And then you're also blogging
Tori: over at dev two, right?
Yes, I am.
I've it's, it's been a little
bit since I've posted on there.
Um, I've been writing on my
work, uh, on my company's
blog a bit more, um, because
when  I joined, I was like
super excited to start writing
for the blog and, um, Yeah.
Yeah.
It's I don't know.
I really enjoy it, but I've got
a little bit more
technical stuff over there.
Whereas my blog on dev two is
kind of a mix
of technical stuff.
And then also just like
interview woes and tips and,
you know,  so if you need any
help with interviewing,
um, or dealing with like the
mental aspects of interviewing,
I've got a lot of great blog
posts over there.
Bekah: Yeah, you definitely do.
And we'll post that too.
So thanks again for being here.
And we'll talk to you soon.
Tori: Yeah.
Thank you for having me.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of
the virtual coffee podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
OT and Bekah harra,
Weigel, and edited by Dan OT.
If you have any questions or
comments, you can hit
us up on Twitter at virtual
coffee IO, or you can email
us@podcastvirtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show
notes@virtualcoffee.io.
Plus you can sign up for a
newsletter to find
out what we've been up
Dan: to.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure
to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.