Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season 1 episode
4 of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here, on this podcast,
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. In this
episode, you'll hear from Vic
Vijayakumar. Vic is a principal
software engineer at Research
Square, a preprint platform.
When he's not at his day job, he
works on his bootstrap startup,
Everyoak school management
system. Vic is addicted to
building things. Vic sat down
with us to tell us about his
experiences with indie hacking,
and gave us his take on when to
ship, what to focus on, and the
value of diverse opinions in
your community among many other
things. It was a really great
conversation. And I personally
learned a lot. Just as a
production note, this is
actually the second time we've
recorded with Vic. We had a
technical mishap and lost the
first recording. But Vic was
gracious enough to sit down with
us for a second time. And so I
just wanted to say another thank
you to Vic for joining us again.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee. We introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random check-in
question. Today's question is,
if you could add any superpower
to your abilities, what would
you choose? We hope you enjoy
this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could add one
power, I would add telepathy.
Dan Ott: Telepathy is dangerous.
Hi, I'm Dan. I'm a front end
developer from Cleveland. And I
think if I could pick a
superpower, it might be
teleportation, that always
seemed like a good and handy one
to have.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Solid
choice.
Vic Vijayakumar: You would save
so much time.
Hi, I'm Vic. I am a full stack
principal engineer from Raleigh,
North Carolina. I'm also an
indie maker. My preferred
superpower of choice would
probably be to be right the
first time, every time.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Also would
save you time.
Vic Vijayakumar: So much time.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All of
these, this is, this is what it
essentially is all about. We
just want the superpower that
saves us the most time.
Dan Ott: It's really just
telling honestly (laugh). We're
just telling on ourselves.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: (laugh) Awesome.
Well, thank you, Vic, for being
here with us. We are very happy
to be recording with you. So we
always like to get a little bit
of background on our guests. And
so we'd love to hear about how
you got into tech.
Vic Vijayakumar: Sure. Okay. So
I actually have kind of a
traditional background, if you
will, in the sense that I have a
bachelor's degree in Computer
Engineering from Iowa State
University. But before that,
probably, so we, we used to own a
computer when, not like when I
was super young, but when I was
in high school. And then
probably the first like
programming thing I did was that
in high school one of my
parents friends actually, they
invited me to come do like a
month long internship with them.
So I wrote software for them the
very first time. Like I'd never
written code before. But they
helped me kind of write code for
the Kenya duty-free shopping
network. So I've worked in
Visual Basic and, Visual Basic
and like Access or something
like that. And for that, they
paid me with a US robotics
modem. So that was my very first
quote, unquote paid project for
writing code. And then let's see.
And then really I didn't do
anything else kind of like
programming related until I went
to college. Where I kind of did
a lot of different like tech
support kind of jobs. But my
very first kind of like breakout
into software development like
web development came when I got
let go from the support job and
then I was looking for something
else. And the Office of
Admissions at the university,
they were looking for an entry
level programmer and I was
completely unqualified for this
job, but I applied for it anyway
because someone said I should.
And I figured, okay, so I
applied for this job. And they
pretty much told me that they
said, you are not qualified for
this role at all. But you sound
confident, and you look like you
could learn. And so they gave me
this job, and which then became
a full time role after I
graduated college for a little
bit. And then, when my
girlfriend then wife now moved
to North Carolina, I got another
job. And I've been at that job
for 14 years, that actually is
the entirety of my journey to
tech.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I love
that. And there are so many hot
tips dropped there, apply for
jobs that you are not qualified
for. Sound confident. Who knows (laugh).
Alright, so that is how you got
into tech. Now. How did you come
to find Virtual Coffee?
Vic Vijayakumar: Oh, this is a
fun one, too. So I think I saw
one of your tweets, Bekah. It
was April last year, everything
was a dumpster fire. And I think
I hadn't like seen any adults in
a couple months. Because I, you
know, I haven't been going into
work anymore. Since about
February or so actually. And
then I saw your tweet, I think
it was in a CodeNewbie's thread
or something like that, where you
talked about Virtual Coffee. And
I figured, hey, I should go make
some new friends. So that was
probably, I, no, I remember
responding to your tweet and
that I missed the first one of
those. And then I came to the
second one. And I think I've
come to just about at least one
session every week or so.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, that
is awesome. You have been here
for almost the entirety of
Virtual Coffee. Because we did, I
think it was the first week of
April, we're coming up on our
one year birthday, or
anniversary, or whatever, very
soon.
Dan Ott: It's crazy.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Right?
Vic Vijayakumar: Virtual party.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: (laugh) It's like,
literally, I have an issue open
in a repo that's like birthday
party (laugh). Okay, so we are talking
to you today about indie
hacking. And so the first time I
heard the term indie hacking, I
thought it meant like somebody
that hacked independently. And
so let's start there with the
actual definition of what indie
hacking is.
Vic Vijayakumar: Sure, I mean,
so it is a portmanteau of
independent and hacking, but
hacking in this case actually
refers to I think indie making
is probably a better term than
indie hacking, but I think
right now, it's used kind of
synonymously with the indiehackers.com
community, which is
like one of the largest
community of indie makers. But
it, you know, oftentimes refers
to people that are just
independent, like solopreneur,
like bootstrap developers that
are kind of making and pushing
out various products, you know?
Sometimes you do it for money, a
lot of times you just do it
because making things makes you
happy. I fall into the latter
category.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Alright, so
let's talk about some of those
things, because you're making
lots of them, right? (laugh)
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, some
things end up, some things end
up going out publicly. And a lot
of things don't. And I'm trying
to do a much better thing about
this year. So I built a lot of
stuff. And then I used to kind
of have this outlook of, oh, I
didn't, this thing is not
perfect. And I'm just going to
kind of, you know, not let it go
out. And my, my thing now has
been to like push things out as
drafts and kind of talk about
them publicly. Because you never
know who is going to be
interested in the thing you're
building. Let's see. One of my
biggest projects, and it's
actually used, it's called Everyoak.
It's at everyoak.com. It's a
preschool management software.
And it's used by my kids' school
actually. I was really sick of
filling out all the various
forms that I had to fill out
when I dropped them off. So like
right now they do COVID
screening, they don't use paper,
because they use you know, Everyoak.
When you're applying, you
have to fill out all these
various forms, you have to fill
out all the allergy information.
And when it changes, you have to
go drop off new forms and all
kinds of things. And I didn't
really want to do that. So I
worked with them to basically
build this thing. And a lot of
different schools were
interested in it. I have two
schools that use it right now.
And you know, it's profitable.
But yeah, that's probably the
biggest one. I've dealt a few
other things that, so I run this,
ran, ran this beer festival for
the last 10 years in Raleigh.
It's not happening this year,
but it happened the last like
nine years or so. Let's see what
else.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Well, I
just want to pause for a second
and touch on Everyoak, because
I've got four kids. So filling
out those forms requires an
incredible amount of time and
ridiculous effort, because we're
doing it every single year, the
same forms, right? Like there,
why do we have to continually do
this. So anything that makes
that process easier is in my
book, like the best thing ever.
Vic Vijayakumar: And a lot of
parents think that too. Like this,
so usually what happens, right,
is the schools open up
enrollment, and then it like
goes on for like, a month or so.
And then the schools, the schools
take another like, I don't know,
month or so to do the
assignment. And at my, at my
three year old school, they
actually just finished doing
enrollment, and then did a class
assignment and like a few hours
and send all those out already.
And the parents all love their
choices. And meanwhile, you have
all these other schools that are
still having their parents drop
off forms. And, and I mean,
it's, you know, is a pandemic
out, even if you're not lazy, I
still don't want to come drop
off forms. And then their class
assignment takes so long. Anyway,
it's, the parents love it, the
schools love it. And it's, and
it's going decently. You know, I
don't expect to get rich off of
what the preschool
square me (??), but it makes me
really happy to be able to do
this. And it makes me especially
happy that I don't have to fill
out forms.
Dan Ott: So, so with, with
Everyoak in particular, I, I
imagine with the indie hacking
sort of like mantra is, you
know, if you, you have an idea
of something either in your life
or something that like you are
excited about, or would like
make your life easier, and just
kind of go for it, right? With
Everyoak, there's, like, the
motivation from your side as a
parent is clear, you know? The,
and it seems like a cool problem
to solve. And you said you, so
the next step, but, you know,
you can either do it in a
vacuum, or you said you actually
worked with your school to
figure it out. Especially with,
with daycares, and things like
that. That seems like a tricky
thing to step in, into unless
you have, you know, some
assurance that, you know, you're
doing it the right way, or the
way that a school would want.
So, so how, like, how did that
process work out? Like at the
beginning, at least?
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah. So you
said the right thing there,
which is that it, so it
definitely is easier to work on
things that scratch your own
itch. Because you just have to
talk to fewer people, right? But
in order for something to be, I
mean, it depends on how you
define success, right? If you
want to build something for the
sake of building something, and
just get those, you know, get
that muscle memory working, of
just building things and getting
them out, you know? Maybe you
want to only scratch your own
itch. But if you're trying to
monetize it, or if you're trying
to help people other than
yourself, you're gonna have to
go talk to people. It's
definitely easier when there's,
when you're working with just
one school, right? But then the
fun thing is, so I built
something very custom to that
school. But then I saw things in
their process that I could
improve. So I would work on like
those improvements, and then
show it to them. And they were
really happy with what I did.
And they just, they kind of just
once, once they realized that I
was making their process better
for them, they just let me just
do the things that I thought
were good ideas. And (laugh), and then
when the next school joined up,
I said, here's a system that
works really well for school
one. And they said, great, if it
works for them, it'll probably
work for us. So at this point,
I'm basically, you know,
becoming an expert in building
workflows for, for preschools.
And they trust that I know what
I'm doing because some other
school uses it. So it's kind of
like, I don't know what to call
it. It's kind of just like, I
don't know what you call it, cloud
by, by just faking it, I guess.
Dan Ott: Yeah. No, that's,
that's really interesting. And,
and, yeah, I don't know, I lost
my, I lost my train of thought there (laugh).
Vic Vijayakumar: I mean, I've
worked on a few other things
there too, that like, don't
necessarily kind of are not that
easy in terms of thinking about
how to make it work. So let's
see. So I have like, I mean, you
want me to tell you about things
that didn't work?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah!
Dan Ott: Absolutely. I mean,
absolutely.
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah. And then
you know, and it was a thing
that I learned. I definitely did
learn something there as well.
So I built something called,
well, it was, it was called Dog
Ears because I found this
picture of this dog I really
liked with droopy ears and I was
like, that's a good name for
this thing. So it was just a,
it's just a product that would
help you like search through
your, your Twitter likes and
retweets and whatnot, because
Twitter's interface itself
doesn't let you do that really
well. So I built this thing. And
my goal was just to like, see
how fast I could build this
thing. And it took me about
like, an hour a day. For 12 days
is what it took. And ultimately,
it failed because I was using
like a trial version of Algolia
and I realized that if I
had to pay for, like, it was
just not sustainable at the
price that I could charged for.
And so I just let it die. So the
website for that is still out
there, but you can't really sign
up. And, but I learned like a ton
of stuff. I learned about, like,
all the wrong things you could
choose. I learned about, like,
needing to make sure that
something was sustainable before
you, you know, spend time on it.
And the thing is, this wasn't
even a, you know, this wasn't
even like something that scratch
my own itch because ultimately,
I didn't care about this
problem, you know? So I
just let that one die. But I
learned a ton of stuff out of
it. I learned a lot of new tools
that I had not previously used.
So you know, I got something out
of it. And I consider that a win.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: For sure. I
think that the framing of what a
win is, is really important
there, right? Because you are
learning something, you can take
that to a different project,
maybe it's not going to be the
same product to that you're making.
But now you have experience that,
that guides the next thing
that's going to be better. And
if it's something that you're
interested in, then, great.
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, and I have a lot of things
like that, right? Where the next
thing I build, I'm not going to
be starting at zero, because I'm
going to take whatever, you
know, all the failed parts, all
the good parts of Dog Ears that
you know, didn't fail, I'll
probably start from like,
something where I already have a
site, I already have a way to
charge people, I already have,
you know, all of that going. And
then I saved myself a whole lot
of time. And I think it
definitely is helpful like that
way to have like a framework,
you know, a framework of how you
would do things because it means
you don't spend time chasing,
chasing, you know, shiny things
of like, oh, let me like build a
whole new framework of like how
to do this, instead of you're
focusing just on like, what
problem am I going to solve?
It's been helpful for me anyway.
I don't know if I, like, said that
clearly. But (laugh)
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I just
learned so much from everything
that you just said. I love that.
Like it's starting with, you
know, this idea of, you're not
starting at zero the next time,
right? Because there's this like
sense of like, oh, I failed at
something. And now I have to
start over. But you're not
starting over at zero.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I think another.
Sorry, I was gonna say I think another
interesting aspect of that is
that I mean, we can all agree to
not view this as a failure, or
at least as a negative thing,
right? But knowing when to pull
the plug or stop, you know, stop
putting effort or money or time
into a thing. I think
like a side project like this.
Do you have like a, you
mentioned you had sort of lost
interest in the problem itself,
which is, I'm sure a big warning
sign, but do you have like a
rubric that you use for your own
side projects of when to leave?
Or is it just like when it feels
like I've done this?
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, so this
is, that's a, that's a very good
question. And it's actually kind
of deep, right? It's, so I have
this problem. Had, have, I don't
know if I still have it or not.
But it's, it's this thing of
like, I like, I like starting new
things, far more than I like to,
so I like starting new things.
And that, you know, that's the
kind of like the most exciting
part of it for me, right? But it,
but it's, but it's a bit of a
like a negative addiction, right,
to start new things. But to not
actually like keep working on
them. So I have to kind of plan
for the possibility that I'm
going to lose the interest in that
thing. So the way that I kind of
work to mitigate that is that I
start to, I have to start
launch things as soon as
possible. And if I use the, the
preschool management thing as an
example, right? So the moment I
launched it, and rail people
started using it, it was no
longer a thing that I could just
say no one uses this, I can just
shut this down and move on to
something else. Now there,
now first of all, I have proved
that someone wanted to use it,
you know, and the real
consequences to me, I'd be
ending it and not working on it
anymore. And the fact that
someone was using it then made
it a lot more fun to like keep
working on it, so it kind of
like kind of, it kind of helped
that situation. But (laugh) not using
that example, when do I know
when to stop working on a thing,
when I'm not having fun with it.
Because if I'm not having fun
doing something, I'm not gonna
keep doing it. So people often
like talk about like, how do you
choose a problem to work on? And
so there's several schools of
thought on this. One is that, you
know, work on something that is
going to like, make you rich
for example. I don't know.
That's, that's a, that's an
actual rubric some people go
with. Or work on something that
like you're passionate about.
Maybe that works for you. Or
like work on something that, I
don't know, some other, some
other rubric for you. And I
guess if it's not, if you're not
having fun with it, if you're no
longer motivated to keep doing
that thing, that's probably the
time to move on. Or at least,
you know, pause it. If it's the
sort of thing that can like,
keep going while you can focus
on something else, then that's
good. If it's the sort of thing
that if you stopped working on
it will just die off, I don't
know. Maybe you should have
launched earlier or, I don't
know. It's totally fine, right?
It's totally fine to just stop
working on the thing. If that's
what makes you happy.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's, that's a
struggle that I have had with
things like this. It's sort of
guilt, you know, I mean, like
losing interest as a kind of
automatically stop working on
something if nobody else is
asked me to.
Vic Vijayakumar: My abandoned
projects need friends.
Dan Ott: Right? Like, I don't
know, or guilt or, I don't
know, shame even, you know, I
mean, it's not like deep, dark
shame. But it's still it's like,
I have these, like random side
projects, there's links to them
on my site, probably somewhere,
you know, from years ago. And
it's, it's sometimes it's hard
to not not feel bad, you know,
or embarrassed of a thing where
you can clearly look at this and
say, oh, this is a failed side
project, right? Like, you know,
I think that went nowhere.
Whereas the framing of this was
a side project, and it was kind
of fun. And I learned some
stuff. And you know, it, I think
it's a very healthy and good way
to frame things. And it seems
like you have, it seems like you
personally have that most of
that figured out pretty well.
Vic Vijayakumar: I hope so.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I want to
touch back on this idea of when
to launch, you said well like
maybe you didn't launch early
enough. So I know there's like
lots of different perspectives
on when you should launch and
how much you should have done,
what features you have planned
out? Or have you completed most
of the features on your list? So
I want to know, what is your
personal take on, on process and
when to launch?
Vic Vijayakumar: You should
launch as soon as you feel
ready. That's the thing. But
sometimes you have to force
yourself to, to accept that
something is ready. Otherwise,
you will keep waiting and
waiting and waiting. And it's
possible, you might lose the
motivation to launch it, right?
So, and the thing is, I think
when I say the word launch,
people often think like press
release, or like tweet about it,
it doesn't have to be that. You
could silently quietly launch
and tell nobody. But it might
just be a psychological win for
you to know that though, that
thing is on, you know, on
production on a secret URL, but
I can access it and it works and I
can log into it and I can use it
might be the psychological win
that you need to keep working on
it. And that's totally fine. Or
sometimes you can just launch
something with just a sign up URL
that says coming soon and sign
up for this, which is good
enough, right, for you to, for at
least like drum up some
excitement or whatever. But
yeah, I would say that that is
entirely up to you. But I like
to default toward pushing
something out early and then
iterating on that as opposed to
waiting a long time and then
like ending up with, you know,
bit rock or something like that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I feel that
also deeply I am the person that
creates things and then doesn't
put them out there. And I was
working on this project earlier
this year. It was a very, like,
deeply personal, but I had like
quietly launched it just so I
knew about it, and one other
person, and I had said like you
know, I'll probably put this out
to the public in about a month
or so. Well they missed that in
about a month or so and then
like posted about it on social
media as like okay, well I guess
somebody pushed me off the
diving board and and now I'm
going for this. Which in that
sense like was really good. The
project wasn't done, I scrambled
for a couple of days, but also, I
might not have launched the
project had somebody not been
talking about it.
Vic Vijayakumar: You know, if, if,
if you push something out and if
someone starts to use it and
their feedback to you is this is
good but it could use more,
that's good feedback. I would
rather that then no one use it,
you know? It's, yeah, I would
totally, I would totally get
negative attention then like
none at all for, you know,
something that I launched. But
I'm glad you were able to do
that. Like that would probably,
that situation would probably
stressed me out if someone did a,
an announcement about
something that I built but I
wasn't ready for it yet.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It stressed
me out. It did. (laugh)
Dan Ott: Can you talk a little
bit about, like some tools you
use to make, to make this process
easier, you know, when you're
working on side projects, things
like that?
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, so I use
a lot of no-code tools actually.
Low-code tools, I should say. So
I'm not one of those people that
like, builds entirely with
no-code stuff. But I do use
like, Airtable and Zapier are
probably like my two biggest
things where I just, you know,
duct tape things together when I
need to get them to work really
fast. So the other day, I had
this, I had this like, I don't
know, I, I thought of this joke.
And it was kind of a really
silly joke. And I, and I told
you, Dan, or I said, it's a, it's
a community for people who are
working from home to talk to
each other. And then there's
sweat pants, it can be called
meetsweats.com, and then I
laughed about it for so long.
Dan Ott: (laugh) Because Vic, Vic Slacked
me this on a Friday night, I was
watching TV with, with my wife,
with Emily. And she had to pause
what we were watching because I
was laughing so hard (laugh). And then I
shared it with her too, which she
also laughed, but I was just
sitting there on the couch, on
my phone laughing and it was
just about meetsweats.com
(laugh).
Vic Vijayakumar: And I was like,
surely that's already a website.
So I went there, and it didn't
exist, and the domain was
available. So I bought, you
know, meet, like M-E-E-T,
sweats, like, you know, sweatpants,
so I bought meetsweats.com
for $4 because I was like,
this is, like $4 is gonna be
worth it for me. And then I
think I spent like the next two
hours. So I put my kids to bed.
And I was still kind of giggling
about it while I was brushing
their teeth, and they're like,
what is it? I was like, nothing.
Nothing will get it. I put them
to bed and, and it feels like
forever, but it was just last
week. And while they were, while
they were, while they were
falling asleep, I just sat in a
room with my laptop and I built
out the site for this and
launched it. And it took
probably like, I don't know,
like an hour and a half or so.
And for that, so I just, you know,
I went on Carrd, C-A-R-R-D dot co, and I so,
that's a, that's a site that I
use for this, where I push out a
site, and I built a form on the
site, and it uses Airtable and
it like people can sign up to be
notified. And like all of these
are super helpful. And it's a
way to early launch something
right? While you decide if this
joke is forcing any more than
like the airtime we're already
got. And whether or not, the
thing is, the funny thing is like
something like 15 people signed
up to be early notified after
it's made up.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's me.
Number one (laugh).
Vic Vijayakumar: You were the
first sign up.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Founding
member.
Vic Vijayakumar: So this gonna be
a good example
of like, you know, or like, I
mean, I don't know anymore, like
is it a joke? Well, it's if it's
just a joke, you know, like, all
these people want to be want to
be notified of like when this
thing launches. And then a few
other people like, quote tweeted
it with their ideas of what it
should be. And, you know, I
think this is kind of a vote for
like building in public, right?
You don't really know what it
should be yet, but you take ideas
from the community. And you
know, this whole thing, so was
Carrd plus Airtable, and I think
that's pretty much all it was.
And it went out there. But a few
other tools I use are Zapier like
I said, and then I use you know,
things like MailChimp to, to
manage, like newsletters and
stuff. But otherwise, I have a
pretty traditional, just to, not
traditional, I guess. I should
say, I have like a skeleton, I
have a skeleton project, that
I just
spin up for everything. And that
way, I'm not spending my time,
you know, trying to figure out,
oh, what should I choose for
this project that I'm building.
And it's just something that
I've kind of forced myself to
not do anymore. Where I don't
like it. Unfortunately, it
removes the excitement of it.
Like, I used to be like, oh, I'm
going to do this thing. And then
I would spend the first week of
it just like building the
authentication and doing all
this little things. And now I
just know that I don't have to
do any of that. I could just
spin up the skeleton project and
just start off. And I know that
at like minute one, it can
already charge people, which
means that I focus on like the
actual problem instead of like
the distracting other parts of
it. So that's really helped me
out. It also means that I start
fewer things, because it means
that I have to like actually
come up with like what I'm going
to do before, you know, I start
on it.
Dan Ott: I think that, I think
that's great. I think that's a
great and sort of newer way to
think about a lot of this stuff.
And as a, I mean, I, you know, as
I've been a developer for a long
time, and it's natural to like,
you know, think of a problem and
say, okay, I'm going to start
writing React from scratch, and
you know, or whatever it is.
Because, because I don't know,
because that's what my job was,
you know, or is. And sometimes it's
hard to not do that. But making
it easy for yourself to, to get
going and solving the actual
problem is seems very, like a
very good way to do things like
that. Especially if you're
starting things from scratch,
often, right?
Vic Vijayakumar: This year, I
plan to do that many, many more
times. Like I was hoping to,
like, I was hoping to start a
new project every month. Or, I
don't know. I don't, I haven't
yet decided, but it's January 28th
that I think meetsweats so this is
probably like the project of
this one. But in February, I'm
gonna have to decide like, how
much more work I'm going to do
on that. Or if I'm going to pick
a new project. It's just, it's
just training, I guess, to like,
you know, to just push more
things out in public.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
really like that mindset. And I,
I've got 37 projects. So if you
would like one, I will let you
do it for February. Um, yeah.
The point Dan was making
before about using things.
There's a tendency to devalue
tools that make projects easier
if you could use something
harder, like React, right? Or
building a site from scratch,
rather than using a template.
And I wish that more people were
talking about how you can do
these things to spin up
projects, like what you're doing
or saying, like, look, this is
just as valuable as a site
that's done in React because
who really cares if they are
solving the same problem?
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, your
customer, your user doesn't know
what you did. I mean, they don't
care what programming language
you're using, they don't care
what CSS framework you're using,
they just care that you're
making their life easier. You
know, it does, I don't think, I
don't believe that, like, you
know, if you use something
easier, like, I don't know,
like, I mean, you, you know,
you're playing, you're playing a
video game, I guess it's
entirely only in your head as to
you know, what mode you were
playing it on. It really doesn't
matter ultimately. I think I
think I like just thought of
something a little bit more
insightful for the sake of that,
but that's all I can think of
right now. I mean, I use lots of
low-code or no-code things all
over the place. It's, and you
know, it's not even just for
starting, right? Sometimes, so
like that, that beer festival
that I that I talked about
earlier, you know, I don't
remember what it used to be at
the very beginning, but it's
been running on Airtable for
like, I don't know, like four or
five years now. It works just fine,
you know? I, and I will
never replace it. I'm not going
to, you know, spend a bunch of
time moving it over to Postgres
or whatever. It works.
Dan Ott: Yeah, absolutely. We,
we, in Virtual Coffee, one of
the Virtual Coffees last week,
or maybe Tuesday. We were,
somebody was asking about, like,
if, if they were freelancing, and
somebody asked them to make a
site, you know, like, what,
what, what they should do,
right? And, and some of the
answers at the beginning were,
oh, just write it in, you know,
I don't know, React or Gatsby or
something, or, you know, even
11ty and, and then we kind of
were talking about it for a
while, and especially if
somebody's paying you to do it,
they also probably don't care
what technology it's written in
or what you use. And if you are
able to stand up a site, like
you have that like using Caard,
for example, right, for a
Caard is a service that is
basically a landing page
service, right, and you can add
a form to it, I think, and maybe,
maybe something else?
Vic Vijayakumar: So I have
an example about this, actually.
Where, so when I started Everyoak,
it used to be just in the
Airtable form. Where, so it was
just, it was a, so it was a React
page. It was a, it was React form,
but then it's submitted to
Airtable, and that was actually
it. Because it, there was no
login or anything like that, you
know. Parents would come like
fill out their application. And
then the rest of it kind of got
built around that. And like it
ran that way for two years,
where all it did was submit to
an Airtable. Like I didn't move
it over to like MySQL or
anything like that for a good
solid two years, and it would
work just fine, you know. The
parents don't care, it still
makes their lives easier. And
then the reason why I moved it
was ultimately because I
exceeded Airtable like free
limits. Not because I thought
like, oh, I'm like, I'm doing
something that you know, like,
you know, really good
programmers don't do or anything
like that, you know. I moved it
because I just didn't want to
pay money for, for what I was
doing. That's fine with it. And I don't
think people should be like, oh,
if I use a, you know, low-code
or no-code tool, I'm not a good
programmer or something like
that. That's, if, you know, if
someone is telling you that, they
don't know they're talking about.
Dan Ott: Yeah. I mean, I agree.
And the framing of, of how a
person values themselves and
their abilities, I feel like is
either starting to shift, or
maybe I'm just like finding
better vocabulary, you know,
vocabulary about it. But that,
like, if a client, for instance,
I mean, I'm independent
developer. So clients are the
way I think about a lot of this
stuff, right? But if a client is
paying, like is paying you,
they're not paying you for code
or, you know, React or whatever,
right? They're paying you to get
the thing that they want, right?
They're paying you to have the
daycare, like management
software done, not to do it in
the most, you know, detailed way
that some other judgy person
will judge you for, right? They
don't care. And so, you
know, my point is just like to
provide value is the thing, is
the thing that you're working on.
Not, not that you're working on
becoming like a great expert,
or whatever, you know.
Vic Vijayakumar: Right. And, you
know, it depends, of course,
whether you are doing this in a
job or, but actually even at my
day job, we actually use a lot
of Zapier and Airtable. Like
we had, we're on the enterprise
levels of both Zapier and Airtable,
because like, you got to maximize,
you know, your value.
And we don't want to be building
all these. So this is just going
to come off as like product
placement for Zapier or Neotel
but there's so much stuff that
we just don't want to all this
duct tape we just don't need to
do. Because it's like it's
cheaper to pay for, for those
tools on a monthly basis than it
is a spent any amount of time
like building all the plumbing.
That's all I'll say about
that. So this doesn't become a
huge, like, endorsement or
Dan Ott: No, it's true though.
And cheaper. Like if you build
for the hour or if your employee
or whatever, like your, anybody's
time is worth money and
somebody's paying for it
eventually, right? So anytime
you can save yourself time and
you know, a productive way that
it's like easy to, it's an easy
win. It's an easy decision. I love
it. I, Zapier for like, I have
just started scratching the
surface of Zapier over the last
couple months. I think based on
your recommendation. But it's
just been, I don't know, it's been
a revelation.
Vic Vijayakumar: I kind of use
it all over the place. I have
some zaps that just told me like,
okay. So this is a pre-2020
story. But I have some zap
that's that just tells me like
it monitors there is like
races that I used to run, like
road races. And it just tells me
when like registration opens up
for those races, so I could
create a certain good bid number
one. So I just have like
a bunch of random automations
like that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Um, can you
or one of you explain what
Zapier is?
Vic Vijayakumar: Sure. It's
plumbing. So okay. So, let's see.
What's the best way to describe
Zapier? So let's see. So I
have a, it ties together various
services. It takes events from
one service and kind of like,
pipes them into another. So as
an example, let's say that I
have, okay. This is a real one.
So anytime an event starts on my
calendar, I have Zapier watch
for that. And three minutes
before that event starts it
marks me as Do Not Disturb. And
like and then three minutes
after the event ends, it like
changes my status back on Slack
to you know, to clear. I have
some like a lot more complicated
ones, where like I have, you
know, I run a little script that
watches the, the, the race
website, and it looks for like a
specific word on that website.
That word was found. It sends me
a message on Slack and sends me
a text message and lets me know
that I should go register. But
you can like have this, you can
have it like send emails, or I
can have it say that anytime
someone fills out this form and
a new record appears in an Airtable,
I want you to do like these
15 other things like maybe
fill out an invoice or send out
an email or like you could have
a do a bunch of different
things. And it can be many many
steps it can run like every five
minutes or something like that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So it is a
time saving superpower?
Vic Vijayakumar: It is 100% a
time saving superpower.
Dan Ott: Yeah, and the, for me, I
found that once I started like
using it because I read about it
and been like that sounds cool,
but you know, not really dug into
it. But once you start using it,
the ways that you can use it
like it changes how your brain
thinks about everything (laugh). It's
really, it's, it's pretty crazy to
think about the, what we're
using on Virtual Coffee, Virtual
Coffee's site, we have some random
forms that collect information
in various places for example.
And those forms are submitted on
Netlify, and so now Zapier is
getting notified when that
happens, right? So the form
goes to Zapier, and then, for
instance, we are saving the
record in a right now in a, in
a Google sheets row, and also
submitting an issue on GitHub
for it or whatever to. That,
like, that's just one way that
we're using those. We're using
Zapier right now. It's, I don't
know, it's very cool. Could you
tell us about Airtable as well?
You've talked about it a lot.
Vic Vijayakumar: Airtable is
just, I mean, it's it's very much
like Google sheets or any other
spreadsheet, you know, there are
rows and you can group them and
sort them. But once again, it
allows you to like do things
based on row's changing. And it
has a really, really nice API.
So I, you know, I've used I've
used it as kind of like a back
end for a lot of stuff. There's
a site that I built recently
like to allow parents to buy t-shirts
for their kids, and then
pay the invoices, and then I was
using the Airtable for that.
Yeah, there's not really much of
it. It's very simple. A lot of
people use it, I think they're
like a, they're one of those
like, big billion dollar
companies.
Dan Ott: So if you were building
a service where you had to store
content, basically, in any way,
at the beginning of it,
it's the first thing you reach
for? Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Can we jump
back to indie hacking for a
second? Coz I want to talk a little
bit about what the community is
like, and the kind of how you found
a place in that community?
Vic Vijayakumar: Sure. So I
guess it probably starts when I
like started to follow various
people on Twitter. And I
realized that, oh, there is a
name for this thing. And like,
oh, it's like, I shouldn't just
like, hide the things that I do.
Like, it's actually good to, you
know, like, share it in public,
right? Then I found indiehackers.com,
which is probably
one of the largest of these, and
I'm in a few other communities
like that. They're all like
Slack communities. Let's see.
Wait. (laugh) What was the rest
of your question?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's just
kind of like how you found your
place in the community, or like,
what the community is like?
Vic Vijayakumar: It's, I find it
to be like, very welcoming
honestly. It's, there, there are,
of course, a lot of very very
successful people in these
communities. And you gotta, you
got to make sure that you follow
people that are, you know,
slightly out of yours, slightly
below you, as opposed to just
the people that are like wildly
successful, because then you
kind of experience this like
survivorship bias, when you
follow people that are just, you
know, making tons of money or
have very very successful
products, and you don't really
learn anything from them,
because I don't know, they've
they've kind of, you know,
they're they they paint a much
rosier picture of their success
than, than perhaps what is like
real. So, I find that it's
important to follow people in
these communities, like Twitter
is probably honestly the best
place for this. You know, find
someone that has like, under
1000 followers under 2000
followers, and he's like, you
know, posting daily about their,
you know, what it is they're
building, and a lot of them
share their learnings like
successes and failures, and you
learn so much about it. And, and
I get so much value from reading
about people's failures. And
knowing you know, you know, I
should not do that. And
similarly, when I find people
that are maybe, like, still just
starting with it, and I'm able
to share, like my successes and
failures with them, I really
enjoy doing that. So I'm in the
Slack community called Micro
B2C, where it's a bunch of
people that build micro business
to consumer products. So, let's
see. So they like, you know,
Lunch Money as an example there,
like, GG app is another example.
There's lots of
different ones there. And it's
just, it's just great to, like,
it's great to be able to post
questions to them for example,
like, oh, the Apple store has
changed some policy, like, you
know, and they say, oh, you need
to write your terms of service
to be like this. And you know,
it saves you from going through
the hassle of discovering all
this stuff on your own. It's,
they're good places. They're
also some paid communities. I'm
not really a part of any of the
paid indie communities.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
love this idea of learning
through failures because I know
we grow so much, but also, it
helps with our time saving
superpowers, right? Like you (laugh) get
to, I don't know, you get this
knowledge and understanding that
you might not get in any other
place, right? And so, some of my
favorite conversations recently
have been from people who have
been there before and can share
those. That's one of my first
questions like, okay, can you
talk about like your failure
and, and failures and what
you've learned? Because then,
you know, like, I'm a step ahead
of where I was before. And I
don't have to go through that,
like, really painful process.
Vic Vijayakumar: Exactly, right?
So I, I love those people who
share immediately, like, very
forthcoming with you about what
they failed it, that that's just
like such good vulnerability,
and they don't want you to go
through like, the stuff that
they've gone through. And I'm
not a fan of the people that are
like, oh, you'll find out. No, I
don't want to (laugh). I want you to
tell me, I want, and so I
bias a little bit towards the
oversharing and failures.
Dan Ott: One of the one of the
things that you said, sort of in
the same realm of following
people that are on your,
basically, on your level of
learning in indie hacking, I think
is really good advice.
Vic Vijayakumar: I mean, that's not
to say you shouldn't follow wildly
successful people, right? You
just have to take their
learnings with a mountain of
salt. And like, I don't know,
maybe aspire for their success,
but not necessarily their
journey, because everyone's
journey is completely different.
Dan Ott: Oh, absolutely. I, I
was going to say, it, I feel like
it's very good advice. Just, I
don't, learning anything really,
or not just indie hacking, right?
I mean, I would give you the
same advice to developers, I
don't think I had framed it that
quite the way you did. But it
made me, it made me think that I
should start framing it that
way, right? Because when people,
when people are in a different
phase, their perspective is
different even, you know? So if
somebody, it's not just that
they have forgotten about the
failures along the way, and they
happen to have a successful
product, you know, but they're
the things they're thinking
about are different if they're
managing a successful product,
versus trying to learn how to,
you know, try to try to learn at
the beginning. It's something
I've been working on a lot with
Virtual Coffee, you know? And
one of the things I've enjoyed
the most is becoming close with
people, you know, at different
different phases of the
developer journey, that career
journey, like, you know,
everything. And I just think
it's such good advice, you know.
It's don't just always pay
attention to the people with the
million followers, you know, in
whatever.
Vic Vijayakumar: I mean, they
probably have valuable things to
say. It's just that not all of
it is going to work out for you.
But the person that is like,
closest to you has actionable
advice right now that, you know,
that is applicable and timely.
Dan Ott: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. We talked about that in my
breakout room today in Virtual
Coffee, this idea of processes
and growth and how so many times
you might have a blind spot,
especially like, you know, if
you haven't been there recently.
And so, you know, being able to
fill in those blind spots are
probably the person who is
closer to the problem or your
stage in the journey. And that's
incredibly valuable.
Vic Vijayakumar: Totally agree.
Dan Ott: I mean, I could talk
about this, the low-code, the services
stuff for hours. This is just
one of those,
Vic Vijayakumar: What services?
Dan Ott: The low-code services. Airtable and Zapier,
and just like the way different ways to hack like hook
all this stuff together. Are
there any other notable low-code
services that you like to use
besides we have mentioned so far
Caard and Airtable and Zapier?
Are there any, any other
interesting or cool ones that
you like, like to use?
Vic Vijayakumar: I think I
probably use those more than
anything else. Trying to think,
but I mean, let's see. No, I think I
think those form a bulk of my,
like, I think I can build
anything with like, just those
three things. I mean, plus, you
know, I don't just use that
there are there people that use
like, you know, something like,
I think it's called Bubble or
any of those other like, things
that let you like, build a whole
app with just like, you know, in
no-code local stuff, but I
actually have them as part of my
React app. So I'll do like, you
know, a NextJS page that just
happens to use, you know, Airtable
as a, as a thing. And I actually
have a, have a lightning
talk on, you know, building an
Airtable backed app next month in
the Virtual Coffee.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Oh. This will
probably drop in February, on
February 26th.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I'm looking
forward to that talk. And
learning more about how you like
hook up next. And you know, that
side of it as well. Again, I
could talk about this stuff for,
for hours.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So we
talked about having community
members around your space and
the journey that you can learn
from too. And so I'm curious to, you
know, how close to your projects,
are they in terms of the things
that they're making? Like, so are
you just mainly focusing on
people who are doing things
similar to you? Or, you know,
how do you kind of learn from
the people around you?
Vic Vijayakumar: Oh, you mean,
like, the specific niche I'm in?
Nich? Niche? I don't know.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
know. I say it both ways.
Vic Vijayakumar: They're kind of
all over the place. Actually, I
follow several people that are
like, making candles, you know?
Or, but like, you learn
something from that too, right?
So this person makes candles,
and you know, they happen to
use Caard and Shopify to put
together a site really quickly.
And, you know, it's once again,
example of like, shipping
quickly, right? And I don't
mean, like literally shipping
the candle. But like, actually,
like the, I think the process
for a lot of bootstrap founders
is very similar. So like, in the
candle making example, you could
decide to build a whole business
and, you know, build an
elaborate site, and then like,
you could release it and find
out that no one cares. Or you
could announce that, hi, I a small
business solo founder, I'm
thinking about, you know, making
hand pouring candles. And it
turns out that 100 people, and
then you know, you launch a
little site on like Caard, or
Shopify or whatever, and 100
people have pre-sign up, and
it tells you that this, you
know, there's interest or this,
and that, you know, it's
something that you want to do,
and this particular one, so,
Terra Simply is the candle
company I'm talking about, but
it's just like Shopify, and she
just pours candles, and, you
know, in her house in Missouri,
and it's like, really, really,
so, you know, I learned a ton of
stuff from this. Even though it
has nothing to do with, with,
like, building software
products, right? And I follow
like, some people that, that
like, you know, have other like,
direct to consumer stuff, like
printing t-shirts on demand, you
know, and I learned, you learn,
you never know what you're going
to learn when you start
following someone. And then you
do when you realize that, you
know, this is like something
that actually is really useful
to you. I mean, I just learned,
I just like learning random
things. Like I'm super good at
triage if you [unintelligible]
your team. I just know,
random factoids that I shove in
the back of my head for like,
someday when it's going to be
useful. And, and I find that
just falling like kind of this
diverse group of people, the
only thing in common between all
of them is that they are solo
founders, you know, is actually
really useful. I listened to a
bunch of podcasts that I learned
a lot of stuff from.
Dan Ott: that's a great point,
and just the diversity of since
it's not all around a
technology, right? It's not,
you're gonna have diverse
solutions and all the different
problems, you know? It's, that's
seems like a very cool community
to be a part of.
Vic Vijayakumar: Yeah, and
you're gonna learn about, like,
some tool that someone's using
that like, you'd never even
thought of like, oh, wow, that's
gonna be useful for me and my
preschool thing, or whatever.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Alright,
Vic, I think this is been a
fantastic conversation, and I am
so glad that you came here to
have this with us. Where can our
listeners find you?
Vic Vijayakumar: You can find me
on twitter at twitter.com slash
Vic, V-I-C, Vijayakumar,
V-I-J-A-Y-A-K-U-M-A-R. Or you
can find me on my site where I
blog about the most random
things. So vicvijayakumar.com
once again, spelled the same
way. And yeah, and I'm going to
be sending out my first
newsletter this month, I think.
A bunch of people that
have signed up. I don't know
what I'm going to write about
yet, but it's going to be
interesting.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Listen, I
will let you know I sign up for
everything that Vic does,
because he's super awesome. So I
can't wait until meetsweats drops.
Because you know, it's gonna be,
gonna be life changing. Doesn't
matter. You made it. I'll be
there (laugh).
Vic Vijayakumar: It's gonna be
the Fire Fest of our day.
Dan Ott: (laugh) Amazing.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, well,
we'll have all those links in
the show notes and you can find
Vic and all of the very, very
cool projects that he is working
out there.
Vic Vijayakumar: And at the
Virtual Coffee Community
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And at the
Vic Vijayakumar: Bye, y'all!
Thanks for having me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Bye!
Dan Ott: Thanks, Vic.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
any questions or comments, you
can hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or you can
email us at podcast@virtualcoffee.io
You can find the show
notes at virtualcoffee.io.
Plus, you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
we've been up to.
Dan Ott: Please make sure to
subscribe to the Virtual Coffee
podcast if you haven't already.
And if you feel like writing a
review, we'd love to hear from
you. Next week we'll have
Cameron Bardell and Rahat
Chowdhury on the podcast to talk
about mental health and tech and
the intersection of the two.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week.