Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season 1, episode
5 of the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Today on
this episode, you'll hear from
Rahat Chowdhury, and Cameron
Bardell. Rahat is a
second-career developer, mental
health advocate, live coding
streamer, and a rapper. He is
also the founder of a mental
health startup called Whimser,
which is aimed at providing
tools to help keep up your
mental health. Cameron is an iOS
developer in the healthcare
industry from Waterloo, Ontario.
He is also in the final stages
of an undergraduate degree in
physics and computer science. In
this episode, we talk about
building mental health projects
balancing mental health with
careers and life and how mental
health recovery isn't linear.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee. We introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random check
in question. Today's question is
if you had to choose one
song for karaoke, what would it
be?
Hey, I'm Bekah. I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could sing one
song for karaoke, it would be
"No
Time Left For You" by The Guess
Who?
Dan Ott: Nice. Hi, I'm Dan. I'm
a front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio. I would, if I
could sing any karaoke song, I
think anything about Cake is
like really in my wheelhouse.
Both, you know, I like the music
and his register kind of matches
mine. So I think pretty much
anything by Cake. And I would
just see what they have and pick
one.
Rahat Chowdhury: Hey, I'm Rahat,
a software engineer from New
York. If I had to pick one song
for karaoke, I guess it would be
"I Don't Want To Miss A Thing".
Because I am a new dad, and I've
been obsessed with my daughter
for the past month. So yeah.
Dan Ott: That's a good one.
Cameron Bardell: That's better
than what I got (laugh). I'm
Cameron.
I'm an iOS developer from
Waterloo, Ontario. And my go-to
karaoke song is "Smile" by Uncle
Cracker.
Dan Ott: Nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Awesome.
Well, thank you both for being
here. We're very excited to have
you on today to talk about
mental health tech. Both have
been working on some really cool
projects that we're excited to
talk about. But before we get
there, I always like to do a
little bit of the origin story.
And so can you talk about that
maybe Cameron, if you want to
talk first and tell us how you
got into tech and then Rahat.
That would be awesome.
Cameron Bardell: Sure, yeah. I
was always like, it's kind of a
techie kid. And then, but I
didn't do any real programming
until I got to high school. So I
think it was in about grade 10
when I took my first, you know,
intro to programming course,
which was
all in Python. And my, my
teacher, that course, who was a
really good guy who I still talk
to sometimes, he was my
computer science and physics
teacher in high school. And now
I do computer science and
physics. So you can see where
that came from. He just noticed
that I was taking a bit of extra
interest, then he pulled me
aside and said, would you like
to find
some extra projects to work on?
And I said, yeah. So he sent me
down to the like center for
extended learning, I think it
was called there in high school.
And they were started, got
started with a
project building Flash games and
action, and ActionScript
(laugh).
Educational, yeah, RAP Flash,
educational games and
ActionScript for students, and
that was my first, I don't know,
the first thing I
ever programmed that anyone else
ever looked at. And you know, I
just took it from there.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
awesome.  I always love those
stories when you have good
teachers who kind of, you know,
notice that in you and, and
they're able to cultivate that.
Cameron Bardell: That's a big
thing what he does at that
school with me. He always like
kinda gets identifies the kids
who
are, you know, do a little extra
just because they're interested
in any tries to take them under
his wing. Just super great.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So great.
All right. Rahat.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, so I got
into tech a little bit later in
life, I guess. So I had a built
up a career kind of in like
customer support. And I was
managing customer support teams
at different tech startups. And
I got to like work with a lot of
the engineers just seeing like
different bugs kind of get fixed
whenever a customer would like
complain about things, I guess.
And that's what kind of got me
interested into the whole thing
at first. I wanted to see if I
could be the one actually fixing
stuff. So my wife is really
supportive. She helped me
through a lot of things and went
to a bootcamp and yeah, now I'm
doing fixing stuff.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That is
awesome. I love it. And so you
both also have different
histories with Virtual Coffee.
Cameron, I feel like I've known
you forever. I remember you
first joining Virtual Coffee.
But I always like to ask to
you, how did you find Virtual
Coffee?
Cameron Bardell: Yeah. So
someone retweeted I think it was
in June, you guys there in
April, right? Then somebody
retweeted your invite link in
June. And I think I just
replied to the tweet asking you
if it was public, or if it was
like, kind of close thing? You
said, yeah, it's public. Come
join. So I did. And I've been
coming ever since then. It was
probably, it was really, you
know, in the midst of the
pandemic, and, you know, talk to
anyone that it wasn't directly
related to a month. It was a bit
of a savior for me.
Definitely one of the best
things I did in all of 2020.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, and
now you are, you're growing our
iOS, our mobile group of
developers, because people see,
and they come for Cameron.
Cameron Bardell: Yeah. I was the
only one for a long time
(laugh).
I was only one for a few months.
Now I think
we're up to four or five. You
know, we're still, what is
that? 2% of all the people who
attend (laugh), but still.
Dan Ott: Also a strong member of
our Canadian contingent.
Cameron Bardell: Right? Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah.
Cameron Bardell: Like, I'm
meeting some niche groups.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: (laugh) And
Rahat. How did you find Virtual
Coffee?
Rahat Chowdhury: Um, I think
I've seen it a couple times on
Twitter.
And I didn't join at first,
because I'm not 100% know what
it
was? And then I think it was
Andy, from protege.dev, told
me a little bit about it. And
yeah, joined in into one of the
meetups, I guess. And then,
yeah, from there just really
loved the environment and vibe.
So kept going.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, nice.
I remember, I remember that
conversation now. Because we
were talking about working on
Epic React.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And we have
a channel for that, which is not
that active. (laugh)
Rahat Chowdhury: (laugh) Came
for Epic React, stayed for
everything else.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: There you
go. It's our new tagline.
Okay, so both of you have
projects using mental health
tech, and I'd love to talk a
little bit more about those. So
can you just kind of give an
overview about the projects that
you started?
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah. So
there's a couple, two things
that I'm
mainly working on. One is an
open-source project. It's called
The Sylar Project. So that is
sort of like a database of
different mental health
resources in the US. What I'm
hoping is to kind of like, get
people to help me add more and
more resources to it. And either
in their own states or cities.
So there could be like more
stuff for people to look up. The
reason I kind of started it is
because, you know, taking that
step into, like trying to find
help or find resources that will
help you is like a pretty big
one. And I wanted to make it as
easy as possible, like once you
did make that step to find
something that could be helpful
for you. So having it all kind
of like in one central place
would be, you know, probably
ideal for that. So yeah, I'm,
eventually I'm going to turn it
into like an API that other
developers can like, build stuff
off of. But for now, yeah, it's
just kind of a list. The US,
hopefully, maybe in more
countries soon. And yeah, the
thing is a startup, I'm hoping
to launch very, very soon. It's
called Whimser. And it's all
about cognitive-behavioral
therapy, and kind of like
journaling and voice note
journaling, and kind of getting
reminders of like, the good
things that happened over time
and challenging those negative
thoughts and stuffs.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
awesome. I love that. I was
working on this postpartum app.
And I kind of just went into it,
working on it by myself. But I
reached out to a group of moms
and I said, like, what would you
like to see in something like
this? And one of the top
responses was resources for my
area. And I didn't have anything
about that there. But also, it
was really hard to find that
online, too. And so I certainly
think that that's really, really
valuable. Along with, you know,
all of the other things,
anything that can benefit mental
health is super important.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I think
there's like a lot of, I guess,
niches in mental health that
aren't really covered in some of
the general labs. So there's
definitely a lot of things that
we can do in this space.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I feel like
I could talk about it for seven
hours. So try and stay focused
here. Um, Cameron, what about
your project?
Cameron Bardell: Sure. So my
project kind of grew out of my
own personal journey with mental
health, I was doing lots of
research on how people track
their mental health over time
and how you can do, there's
various different methods to
like check trends and mental
health, whether it's like, like
CBT, like Rahat said, or just
like doing daily journaling, or,
and I found that a lot of these
clinical studies use these super
long surveys that can take up to
like, half an hour to complete,
and you're supposed to do them
every day. And that's
exhausting. And it was a time
for that. So I dug a little more
into that, and found that those
studies who use those, I would
certainly have their place and
not saying they should be
replaced in anyway. But they can
often get similar results to
these other smaller scale
studies that use really simple
measurement systems and the one
I found that I really liked was,
so it's just really simple, all
you do is you get yourself, your
mental well being whatever is
most important to you, on a
scale of 1 to 10, once in the
morning, and once in the
evening, and you do that twice.
So you do it kind of for your
general overall well being, then
you pick another thing that's
important to you, whether
that's, you know, your sleep, or
your anxiety or your nutrition,
and you rate that in a scale of
1 to 10 along with your general
wellness. So you're
basically doing four readings a
day. Two in the morning, two in
the afternoon. It's super easy
to do. You, I, you know, you
open
after 10 seconds a day and do
your reading, and then you go
about with your day. So I
started building an app for
that. And I've had to kind of
shell that a little bit because
I recently started a new full
time job, hoping to get back to
it soon. But yeah, I think a lot
of the solutions out there
really intensive and
time-consuming. And you're meant
to
open the app and kind of spend
some time in there. But I think,
you know, the goal for my app
would be to spend as little time
in it as possible.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
like that approach. Some of
those, you, you look at in it,
it's so complicated, it that it,
it's an
automatic like, I'm done. I'm
not gonna sit here and go
through all of these things. And
watch all of your screens give
me messages and positive things
like I want to feel where I
wanna go.
Cameron Bardell: It feels like
you're supposed to live in the
app, sometimes. Like they have
common videos to watch, and you
know, like maybe guided
meditations, or some of them are
like gamified, where you can
like earn awards and stuff. And
sure, yeah, those work for tons
of people get great reviews and
works a lot. But it doesn't work
for me (laugh). I want to, you
know, I
want to spend as little time
thinking about it. So, and there
was no solution out there. So I
built it.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. I was
going to say something about
the,
oh, the cognitive therapy, yeah.
Rahat, you had mentioned that
with your, with your startup
that you're working on. The,
that area
of like therapy has been very
interesting to me. And at some
times, it's been successful, but
a lot of it with, I mean
personally,
when, I mean it's just my
personal experience, my problem
with it
is sort of getting myself to do
anything about it. And this is
sort of applies to what Cameron
was saying to you. But like, the
exercises that a therapist
would, would give me would be,
you
know, these things that I have
to both remember how to do,
remember to do them, and then
also, I don't know, do them at
the right way, or whatever. Or
maybe there isn't like a right
way. But it's like there's full
of doubt, you know, like,
wondering if I'm doing it the
right way or not. So I was, I
was
wondering if there's, if you
have some plans with cognitive
therapy, like specifically
about, you know, I don't know.
About how to approach like, sort
of things like that?
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I think
in our case, probably, cognitive
behavioral therapy is probably
just kind of in the MVP, or the
beginning stages. What we're
kind of planning to do is like,
have it
be a little bit of a guided sort
of prompt thing, but hopefully,
with not too many prompts, like
Cameron mentioned, which is
definitely an issue in a lot of
apps. So it's kind of like,
choose your emotion. You can
write down something, record
something and be done with that.
Or if you want to, like, get
more insight onto things and
challenge some of your thoughts.
It'll then take you on, like,
guided like two more questions
of like, what's a cognitive,
like a cognitive behavioral
distortion
that you're facing right now.
Gives you some info about what
those are, and asks you to kind
of challenge the thought in some
way. And, you know, if, and
that, that journey, I think is
more
optional. And sort of like, if
you just want to record, record
yourself an event, it's kind of
like, that's an option too.
And if you do want more, more of
that info and more like, I guess
more deeper CBT stuff, then it's
a little bit guided scope and
more questions on that. Our
eventual hope is that the app
kind of becomes a sort of like a
custom journey based on like
your work with like your
therapist or psychiatrist, or
whoever. We're hoping that like
health professionals can like
prescribe a journey for the app
that's tailored towards the
user.
Dan Ott: That's really
interesting. Yeah, that, I
hadn't
really thought about, I mean,
they don't always like, there's
a lot of apps out there. But not
always connected, you know, to
like, to therapy, right? And
it's kind of okay, therapy is
either
not doing it for me or, you
know, something like that. And
people are kind of going on
their own to like, onto the App
Store, you know?
Rahat Chowdhury: I think CBT
definitely doesn't work for
everybody. So, yeah, our goal is
just to like, while we're
starting there, we just want to
figure out like, something easy
and simple for people to do that
is helpful for them. And just
based on stuff that an actual
therapist would recommend for
them to do on their own time.
Cameron Bardell: Like Rahat said
earlier, there's tons of room in
the
space very, like very individual
responses. I mean, that's the
whole problem with mental
health. It's the problem and
the solution, I guess. Is that
it's so varied for an
individual,
for everyone. So yeah, there's
just tons of different ways to
build tools like this. And each
I know, part of figuring out how
to control your own mental
health is you might have to try
a lot of these different things,
and most of them won't work. And
that's really hard and
frustrating. But, you know, it's
part of
the journey.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, and I
think, you know, they're all
valuable. Because everybody
approaches it a different way.
And I think that technology is
really changing the face of how
we view mental health. I mean,
even openness to talking about
it, and having these
conversations. I know like in
my mental health journey, it
would not be nearly as
productive as it was if I didn't
talk to other people who
I never would have met on, if I
weren't on Twitter, or online,
or whatever, you know? So
hearing other people's stories
kind of guided my journey and
where I was going, but it looks
different for every person. And
the more we learn about it, I
think using technology also
helps us better identify the
problems and the solutions that
will work for different people.
Cameron Bardell: And the good
thing about using technology for
that kind of things, it's
impartial. Like a big part of
the reason why I built what I
built is that like uncompress
new
things and graphs and numbers.
And so I wanted to see like,
kind of the true history of, of
what I was feeling. And so I
looked, and when I was doing
this research, I found out that
there's a lot of studies that
show that if you ask people how
they're feeling, at a certain
time, and on a scale of 1 to
10 like I said, like say, they
get a text and they have to say
how do I feel right now? And,
and you do that multiple times,
maybe throughout a day, or
throughout the week, and then
you ask them
later on, looking back, how did
you feel on average in total?
Those two numbers almost never
lined up. How people say they
feel at the moment is not how
they say they felt later
(laugh). So
that was one of, of another one
reasons why I made this thing
that you have to do. Well you
don't have to, you can do it
as many times as you want. But
you know, ideally twice a day,
and you do it right in the
moment really quickly. It's just
really important to have that
kind of self-knowledge and be
able to look back and see things
trending up or down in different
directions. Like my app doesn't
offer any kind of therapy or any
information other than what you
give it. It's just, it's just a
personal record.
Dan Ott: Yeah. That's really
cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I,
Cameron, I wanted to talk about
something that you said in Slack
the other day, too. I
think it was somewhere near you
is trying to help people feel
connected during the time of the
pandemic. And I'm always, you
know, found that community is
the most important part of
growing through mental health
challenges. Can you just talk a
little bit about what they were
doing there? Because I found it
like, this really kind of
simple, but beautiful way of
connecting people.
Cameron Bardell: Yeah, that was
a really interesting project.
Um, so it's called, I go to
University of Waterloo, which
is, like common engineering and
science-based school in Ontario.
And so I just saw on Twitter
that a couple of engineering
students put together this
project, and it's basically a
heat map of the university
campus and where people report
they've cried on campus, which
sounds kind of funny. I think
it's really interesting because
their, their stated goal is just
to show people, like when you
get, you know, into kind of
worked up emotional state like
that, I think it's really normal
to kind of want to hide
yourself, you know, you want to
make, you want to go be alone
somewhere, and you kind of
experienced that on your own.
But, yeah, they just put
together this map just to show
that, you know, if you've done
it, if you're struggling with
it, then someone else's too. And
they've got it's a heat map,
like I said. And then there's
also just kind of some people
did more personalized stories.
So I thought that was a really
interesting project, especially
during a pandemic and we're all
more isolated than ever.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, that
idea of, of connecting people
is,
is really important. I think
that, you know, you do sometimes
get in that moment where you
think like, well, I'm the only
one that feels this way. But
just like having a simple visual
of like, oh, I cried, but look
at somebody right over there did
too.
Cameron Bardell: I'm looking at
the map right now and I'm like,
oh look, at the engineering
building. I've had long nights
there too. (laugh)
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
think that's really, really
great. Okay, so I would love,
you talked a little bit about,
you
know, how you kind of got into
pursuing these. So it sounds
like for both of you, there's
some type of personal component
to this. And I'd love to know,
or if you are up for talking a
little bit more about, like the
inspiration behind this. And if
you learned anything new about
yourself, or, you know, what you
were doing through, through this
journey, that would be awesome.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I think,
for me, so the idea for this
kind came out of like, some of
my own personal experiences.
Going to
therapy, trying to take care of
my own mental health and all
that. And, like, the one of the
main things was like, therapy is
helpful. But it's only 45
minutes, once or twice a month,
or every other week, or
something like that. And there's
all this other time in between,
where just like, I, I'm not
sure, sometimes, like, I guess,
how to take care of myself for,
you know, try to, I guess, make
my mental health better in some
way. So that was like a large
part of the conversation that I
was having with my therapist.
And she would give me like
different prompts and stuff. And
like, sort of like CBT based
things to try out on my own is
writing stuff out. And it was
pretty helpful. And the thing
that I realized was really
helpful for me was like, when I
in those moments, when I was
able to remember back to like, a
positive thing, kind of related
to whatever I was doing. Like,
if, like, if I was having a
crap day at work, but then
thinking about another time
where, you know, something went
right at work, that was
sometimes pretty helpful. So
that was kind of like a lot of
the basis for the app itself of
like, having some positive
reinforcement in those negative
times.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's really
cool. I have, I also have
trouble
with it. The connection between
like, different appointments and
and just sort of everything, it
seems to make sense, you know,
when you walk out of an
appointment, and then a week
later, you're like, I don't
(laugh), I don't know. I don't
know what
I'm doing. I don't know, you
know? Like, all the, all that
stuff. I
guess a place where like
technology can, you know, like,
really shine? I think if you
know, if applied correctly.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Cameron, I
don't know, if you want to
share. You don't have to, but
Cameron Bardell: Yeah, no,
totally. Yeah, part of my like,
journey with my personal mental
health, I guess, I started
struggling with anxiety in my
pre early teens, and kind of
kept them to myself for a long
time. So like, I feel like most
of the last several years for me
has been a process of opening
it up to slowly, like, wider and
wider circle of people. So it
started eventually, like, you
know, talking to my parents, and
then they helped me a lot. And
then you know, from there, I was
like, okay, that worked out
pretty well. And then I, you
know, started talking to a
doctor, and then I do even more.
I said, wow. This seems to be a
trend (laugh) if there's
anything. So then, you know, you
start opening up to a wider
circle of people. So my friends,
you know, you guys eventually.
And now here I am on a podcast
talking about it. That's been a
really important part of the
process for me. We have a Slack
channel in, in Virtual Coffee,
where we talk about these sorts
of things. And, you know, people
have been, you know, pretty
open. And, you know, not
everyone has to be open, and
just something that happens to
help
me personally. I would never say
that, like, I don't even know
how to phrase this. Like, I
would never tell anyone that
they should go and talk about
their experiences, because it
will definitely help, you know,
it might not (laugh). Depends.
It just
happened to help out for me. And
I only came to that realization
after
like several years of
struggling. So yeah. That's,
that's kind of been an ongoing
thing for me.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's actually
been a trend we've noticed with
Virtual Coffee. And not just
with mental health, although
definitely with mental health,
and even just being becoming a
developer or learning, finding,
you know, finding a job, all of
these things that, over and over
again, we have people that come
in or just feel alone, you know,
feel like they're the only
ones are feeling something's
wrong with them that because
they are struggling finding a
job or struggling learning, you
know? Anything. Learning
anything in tech and is or
struggling with, you know,
mental health things and finding
other
people that are also, you know,
going through a lot of the same
things.
Cameron Bardell: And I would
encourage you to say like, you
don't even have to say anything
when you're in these spaces.
Like you can just go and be a
lurker until you feel
comfortable. I mean, you'll
never feel comfortable sharing
yourself that you can go and see
what other people are saying,
you know, maybe that's something
that
could help. Like, that includes
like, you know, mental health
stuff in
the job search and I know
Bekah's been and several other
people in the Slack've been
leading the way on like a
neuro-diversity channel, which
is really great to see. So all
those kinds of things. You can,
you can reach out and find these
spaces and you don't have to be
sure if it's right for you to
share. You can definitely kind
of hang out for a while and it's
take your bearings, and maybe
decided that it's not for you,
and
that's okay, too. But yeah, you
don't have to feel pressured to
say anything.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I think a
pretty good other benefit that
comes from that is like, just
knowing that you're not alone,
sort of. There's other people
kind of like going through
similar stuff. I think there's
definitely just like powering
as like not feeling as alone.
Like, for me, especially when I
start doing talks on it, and
kind of like openly talking
about it, so like, other people
responding by like, hey,
I, you know, I go through this
kind of similar stuff, too. It's
just
like, it was kind, maybe not, I
don't know, good is the right
word to say, but more like just,
it doesn't feel as bad
going through it, knowing that
you're not going through it by
yourself.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: For sure.
Cameron Bardell: It kinda like,
it kind of shows how like, the
progress
isn't linear, either. Like it's
normal and honestly in some
ways, kind of important to have
back slides. And then, and then
show yourself that you can get
through them, you know? If you
feel like you've made progress,
and then you revert back for a
little bit, that's a normal part
of the process. And you
shouldn't, you know, something
that I like to say is you
shouldn't feel bad about feeling
bad. Like, you don't have to
beat yourself up over your lack
of progress over thing, you
know, any of these
areas. So again, it's, the
recovery, like showing you that
you have, showing yourself that
you have the strength to recover
from something like that is
really important as well.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I,
um, so my journey into tech
started
with a trauma that I went
through. And so I talked a lot
about it about having anxiety,
depression, PTSD, but like one
of the most pivotal moments for
me was when I was in bootcamp,
my educational coach, who was
assigned to me and she said,
hey, can I share a story with
you? I said, sure. And she said,
I went through trauma, too. I
was run over by a semi truck.
And that was the first person I
had ever talked to about
trauma. And our traumas were
very, very different. But all of
the words that she were saying,
they were the words that had
gone through my head so many
times. And I finally realized
that I wasn't alone. So I had
spent so much time alone in, in
that, that, that just moment of
connection was enough to like,
give me hope to keep going. And
that was, my trauma was four
years ago. And I gave a talk
about it the other day. Told the
story many, many times. And I
just started crying and I don't
ever cry. So it was like on a
screen full of people, just
crying.
Couldn't get it, couldn't get it
together. And it was that
feeling of like being super
frustrated at myself. Like why,
why is this happening now? And
the talk, that's recorded.
That's
gonna be on YouTube, right? And
so like I wrote a little post on
my
trauma blog about it. And
somebody messaged me, and she
said, this is what I needed to
hear in this moment, because she
had also gone through a trauma
in a couple of years ago. And
suddenly, she was like, hit with
that moment, too. And just felt
like very frustrated with
herself. And so it exactly what
you're saying, Cameron. It's
like, it's not linear, right?
Like, there's gonna be waves and
somebody once said, like, it
doesn't go away, but it gets
different. And I think that, you
know, that might be specific to
trauma. But, you know, we find
these moments in our lives,
where we're like, man, I really
thought that I was passed this.
And that can be hard. But when
you connect with somebody else,
and you can kind of talk about
it together, then you realize,
like, okay, you know, like, we
we've got this together.
Cameron Bardell: It can be
helpful, too, if you've been,
like you said, you've kind of,
you hear your own words in your
head so much. And
maybe you don't know if it makes
sense. Because these things can
often be really hard to put
words to, because it's not
something that necessarily has
like a physical analogy for
everyone. So if you can, like
kind of, say these words out
loud, and someone says, yeah,
no, that makes sense. That makes
you feel a little less, I don't
know, lost sometimes. So.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, also,
I think, you know, if we're
talking technology too,
sometimes, sometimes you can
deny things to yourself, right?
But if the data is in front of
you, like, okay, I've been
tracking my mood for this long,
for the last, however much time.
Maybe, maybe I'm not being
honest
with myself about how bad I feel
right now. Or good. Maybe you
feel good, hopefully. (laugh)
Cameron Bardell: People aren't
good at, um like, I don't know,
maybe you're not, it's not that
you're not being honest with
yourself. People just aren't
really that good at
self-evaluation.
It's just how human brains work.
So it's not, it's not
necessarily like intentional or
otherwise, like deluding
yourself or lying to yourself,
or whatever you want to call it.
It's just not an easy, normal
thing to do.
Dan Ott: Mm hmm. Yeah. And that
kind of circles back to some of
the cognitive behavioral therapy
stuff is your brain like, will
actually actively lie to you
about al of things. Is, yeah,
well,
like we said at the beginning,
we could probably all talk about
this for (laugh) a long, long,
long time. Kind of moving,
moving on.
So you're both pretty busy, you
have a lot of side projects
going on and along with, you
know, career stuff and family
stuff, school. So we were
wondering how each of you sort
of balance your, your own mental
health, like with, with work,
and
with side projects, and
everything else that goes along
with being,
you know, a human in the, you
know, in 2021. Rahat, we'll
start with you. At a talk, one
of our lightning talks last
year was sort of about some of
this. So, I start with you, and
see what your thoughts were.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, for me, I
tend to forget a lot of times to
really stop and just like, not
work on all the different things
I'm working on for a little bit.
So the way I've recently been
managing it is just like, trying
to remember that, you know, I
have a daughter now. I need some
time for her, I need some time
for myself, I need some time to
just like unwind from
everything, because there is a
ton of stuff I'm doing right
now. And it took, it takes a lot
of work for me to like, get past
my own, I guess, self-imposed
deadlines on things that don't
actually mean anything. And the
way I had sort of tried to
accept a little exercise I do
just in my head is like pretend
that like I'm a stakeholder in a
meeting, and I'm like pushing
the state back a little bit
like, hey, we don't need it till
this time. That's kinda, that's
something that kinda works for
me a little
bit. And then those moments,
I'll try to let go and like
just take a walk or play some
video games, anything like
that, and just try to get away
from what I'm working on. And
just like, also trying to remind
myself that if I wanna work
quickly through things, then I
need to take a break. Because
I've like gone through burnout
before, like, not being able to
do something for a couple
months. And just kind of like
getting it down in my head and
it was like, if I don't stop
sometimes, and just
like take a breath, I won't be
able to continue doing as much
stuff as I hope to do.
Dan Ott: Yeah, totally. I think
that's, I mean, we've sort of
talked about this before, but I
think that, that's like a great,
a great thing to do consciously
is sort of try to jam, like not
jam those breaks into your
schedule, but like actually
schedule, you know, breaks in
and make sure you're taking care
of them. Cameron, do you have
anything like, I don't know,
specific thing you do, to try
to, you know, take care of
yourself
or, you know, getting everything
done. And, you know, side
project thing and all that?
Cameron Bardell: Yeah,
[unintelligible], I guess. I'm
coming out with a bit of a
period where I've like been
bouncing around on a lot of
different things. Because about
a year ago, for a long time, I
was kind of torn between whether
I would do like science and
research or just go into tech.
And about a year ago, I finally
decided, okay, tech can be the
thing. So at that point, I
started doing like a bunch more
freelancing and did a couple
internships and side projects
and stuff, so it was like, okay.
Here's what I need to do again
to get into the tech industry.
And
then, you know, a couple weeks
ago, I just got hired full time.
So then that period of like
doing a whole bunch of stuff and
bouncing around is kind of
settling down now. So in back,
it's like reevaluating and
focusing on, okay, here's the
main things I need to do. Like,
I need to do like this much.
Well, I need to work, you know,
40 hours a week, and I need to
do this much school, and then I
also need to exercise. So I've
been coming out of kind of a
chaotic period and settling into
more of a routine the past few
weeks, which isn't really nice
(laugh).
Yeah, but I still think that,
that period of working hard was
important, because I ended up,
you know, in a place that I
really wanted to
get. And yeah, it was hard for a
while. But here I am.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think,
too, when you can see, this
isn't a forever thing, there,
this is going to end then it
makes it feel a little bit more
doable. But there's also this,
like natural tendency in tech. I
think tech just moves so
quickly, right? That people feel
this, this need to hustle all
the time. And that's like, I
can't stand that word, hustle.
But like to continue to keep
doing stuff all the time. And I
find that as much as I don't
like that word, I have a really
hard time turning off my brain
when there's always something to
be done because, you know, like,
tech moves fast and so do
people.
So, (laugh)
Cameron Bardell: Yeah. I really
kind of like, it's kind of a
strong
word, but I kind of detest that
part of Twitter's like, I don't
know. Silicon Valley, like VC
hustle porn kind of like, if
you're not working you're losing
money. I don't know. Everyone
should be the
founder kind of thing which is
not true. Not everyone should be
a founder. Being a founder kind
of sucks (laugh). Yeah. And,
yeah, I don't
know. I just like, what you said
about having a deadline was,
was really stood out to me
because yeah, like I had, so
when
I made the decision to go into
tech, I had a year and a half
left in my degree. And I was
like, okay, so I'm going to work
really hard for
this next year and a half, and
then I'm going to be settled
into a career hopefully. And
having that deadline really
helped. And then when I got
hired full time, I had four
months left in my undergrad
degree. So just to make the full
time work, I stretched that out
into eight months. So starting,
you
know, in August, I'll be done
with school and just working.
And
then I feel like then, you know,
like I said, even now, I'm
working less hard than I was
three or four months ago, but
even past the summer, I'll be
pretty fully settled in just
having that in mind really
helps.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, and I
know Rahat too, you have been
working on a book. And at some
point, you tweeted that you were
talking about like building a
mental health breaks, which I
just really loved that idea.
Because we're always focusing on
like, you've got to learn,
you've got to learn fast,
bootcamps
are moving people through
quickly, everybody's looking for
jobs. And that idea of like,
okay, you can learn, but let's
pause and take care of you. And
I just found that concept
really, really fascinating. Are
you, is that make it, does it,
did
it make a place in, does it have
a place, oh my gosh. Does that
have,
did, I can't do it (laugh).
Dan Ott: (laugh) Is that in your
book?
Rahat Chowdhury: (laugh) Yeah.
So I've definitely built it into
the chapters
I've been writing recently. Like
at the end, depending on like
what subject I cover in that
specific chapter, like, there's
one where talking about like,
trying to find other people
similar, like in the same
journey as you are going into
tech and seeing like, you know,
if you can band together to work
on some stuff. And at the end, I
kind of like, I want to have
like a sort of like a norm-,
kind of like an alert box type
thing at the end of like, hey,
you know, reaching out to people
can be hard. Talking to people
is pretty hard. Especially if
you're like me, have some social
anxiety and stuff. And, you
know, if you've talked to a
couple people, great. You don't
have to keep doing it. Take a
break, just remember to take
care of yourself stuff like
that. And that, there's a little
like alerts, like at the end of
each chapter like that, based on
whatever we covered. It's just
like, it's awesome that you're
doing this, but you should also
be taking care of yourself as
well.
Dan Ott: That's really cool.
Cameron Bardell: Now that I
remember what Bekah said, sorry,
just to jump in quick. Bekah
said something that stood out to
me.
I guess it's like these
bootcamps and online, different
online, you know,
learning platforms, whether it's
Udemy, or like something
self-directed
like that, they kind of try to
push you through, like
you said, and finish quickly.
And that's, they present it in
ways if that's good for you, and
it's not as good to them, then
they can get more people in
(laugh) and charge more people
more money.
So yeah, of course, they have to
present that in a way that makes
it seem like it's for you, but
it's not.
Dan Ott: Yeah, it seem, that's
actually, that's an interesting
point. And in the bootcamps,
from what I've heard, it seems
like they're either in a like,
kind of class, like they're
where people are pushing and
pushing, or it's either that,
or you're in the self-guided
path. And it, from what I've
heard, and
I don't have full experience
with this, but from what I've
heard, it's sort of like very
much on your own in a point, you
know? And so you can go, try to
go faster, or you go slow, or
you lost or whatever, but you're
sort of like drifting off on
your own. I think, yeah,
getting, getting some, some of
that
thought into learning, like
learning materials and learning,
you know, courses and programs.
It seems very important. A lot,
a lot of people struggling in
bootcamps. From what I've
learned over the last, over the
last year.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I think
that's definitely like a culture
and a
lot of bootcamps that needs to
change. Because, yeah, we're
just kind of pushing and pushing
and not reminding people to just
take a break. Like, I also do,
I'm a TA at a bootcamp,
part-time.
And like, one of my students was
asking me, like,
how do I get better at
JavaScript? How do I like, do
more stuff to,
you know, keep, keep building. I
tried to work on things every
single day, for X amount of
hours. And I'm just like, take a
break sometimes, and just let
the information kind of sink in.
Because sometimes you just need
to walk away from it to like,
let yourself absorb it.
Sometimes just like walking away
is like one of the best things
you can do to like, solve a
problem. Like there's countless
sign I think a lot of people
talking about it of like, you
know, you're going through
trying to fix a bug, you don't
know what's going on, you walk
away, you come back and you know
what's going on now. Because you
need to refresh or you need to
just like step away sometimes.
Dan Ott: Absolutely.
Cameron Bardell: Yeah.
Motivation is like a finite
resource (laugh).
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah. I feel like
that, that go take a walk is, is
gotta be like, when people are
having a, you know, when people
are like, I can't figure this
thing out, you know, it's like,
when you're doing tech support,
you need the first question is,
when did you turn it off and
turn it back on again, right?
And so
when you do like bug support,
you're like, okay, did you, did
you take a walk? Have you
stepped away from the computer,
yet? (laugh) Step away from the
computer and come back. And then
let's
see if you're still having the
same problem (laugh).
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's so
hard to, I think, in bootcamps,
there's that sense of loneliness
and lack of community,
especially for online bootcamps
with self-paced students that
don't prioritize community. And
then you, you find that problem.
So you can take a walk and come
back and have nobody to ask,
right? And so that's like,
bootcamps come with built-in
loneliness, like, I don't know,
that needs to be (laugh)
advertised or
something.
Cameron Bardell: Yeah. Meg, in
our Slack at VC, Meg was talking
about that a lot. How she's
doing the self-guided bootcamp.
And that she can't
do it as fast as some of her
peers because she's working at
the same time. So she's kind of
fell behind like the people she
started with just for lack of
time. And then I think that
contributed to some of your
dissatisfaction.
Dan Ott: Yeah, absolutely. Um,
she's one of the people I was
thinking about. Marie was, while
she was on the podcast a couple
episodes ago, but was talking
about, she did a, like the
scheduled one, right? But they
didn't have a lot of support.
And she was struggling. And so
she basically strong armchair
class into doing study groups.
And they all found it, you know,
I mean, they all found it very
valuable, you know? But it was
not a program thing, you know?
It was, it was Marie, doing it,
because she wanted the support.
And it turned out other people,
you know, found it valuable,
too.
Cameron Bardell: It's the same
way I pass like undergrad.
(laugh) Just
having groups of people to study
with, um, you know, that went
away for a lot of people in the
pandemic, and I can't imagine
what it would have been like, as
the first year you're going into
do that, you know. And the only
way I passed, you know, second
year
calculus is because I was doing
it with a group of friends
(laugh). So
yeah, I definitely feel bad for
those people.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I was
talking to a mom recently, and I
don't remember she's going
through a bootcamp or a
self-taught,
she's doing like a guided, can't
talk today (laugh). Can't
remember if she is self-taught
or doing a bootcamp. But one of
the things she was saying was,
it's just so hard to find time,
you know, a lot of moms are at
home with kids right now
because of the pandemic, and
there's no childcare. And so
she's saying, yeah, you know,
like, I guide my students do
their schoolwork all day, and
then I stay up from like, 12:30
until 3:30, and then I've got to
get up at 7, you know, and
it's like, okay. Let, let's
break this down a little bit and
figure out something that's,
that's doable, and maintainable,
and that allows you to get rest.
Because a rested brain is going
to absorb the material more.
But, you know, there's this
pressure to continue to go all
the time, despite everything
else. And you, I don't know, you
can't really strong-arm your way
through, well, I was gonna say
through, through lack of sleep,
but parenthood that kind of
makes you do that. So maybe you
can (laugh)
Dan Ott: (laugh) Anyway that
also, you know, confirms that
it's not a good
idea by the end of the choices
you're making after four weeks
of not sleeping. It's good stuff
though (laugh).
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So I've
been doing like a deep dive into
deep learning and mental health.
And I've been like, very, very
fascinated by all of the
different ways that they are
approaching mental health with
technology and how I think
that's gonna provide more
individualistic care for, for
people and address like, I
think, you know, really
understanding what mental health
looks like. And so I think that
that's really exciting. But I
also feel like, you know,
there's this, this tendency,
like, I'm so excited about this
thing, but you're gonna have to
wait forever for it to come out
and to apply, to apply it to
your own life. But I think that,
you
know, all of these little things
that bring us hope can be really
useful. I don't know if there's
anything that you found that
you're like, yes, this is really
helpful, whether it's for you,
or someone you know, or for your
projects in terms of tech and
mental health, but I'd love to
hear about it.
Cameron Bardell: I don't have
anything, you know, anything
like deep learning or AI or
anything like that. I did take
some of my own trend data and
kind of feed it into a
prediction engine in a
classification engine, just to
see if I can find, you know,
anything. I didn't find anything
that's
useful, mostly because my data
is like, pretty one dimensional.
But yeah, I don't, nothing that
I've used personally comes right
to
mind. But like you said, you
know, we're kind of using our
own experiences to look at these
things. And you said, well,
maybe it'll take a long time for
these to come out and be
available to use ourselves but
or, we could use our experiences
to build them for, you know, the
next group of people. And they
can improve
upon what we build. I think
that's kind of the dream of the
tech industry is that things
keep improving. So, (laugh)
hopefully. We'll
see how it goes.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, deep
learning stuff is cool. We
actually, like one component of
our app is like the whole
reminder of something, you know,
relevant to what you're going
through right now. And we're
building this with like, AWS
Amplify, which gives us access
to a couple cool like machine
learning stuff that they have
kind of built-in. And right now,
we're kind of like trying to
figure out the best way to kind
of compare one entry that you're
not having a good day on
to something that's like,
relevant, but you did have a
good day on to remind you of
stuff. So while we're kind of
like using that, I guess API for
now, what we kind of want to do
eventually is probably build
something of our own based on
like, what our users are
actually going through. So we
have someone on board who's kind
of like leading that a little
bit. And, yeah, I think there's
a lot of room to do some cool
stuff with deep learning and
mental health.
Dan Ott: That's pretty
interesting. I know, I keep
coming back to the cognitive
therapy stuff, but like yet,
like adding that little aspect
into it. And you're saying,
like, for example, you're like,
you're really upset, because you
feel like you can't do a thing
or something. And then the app
can be like, well, here.
Actually, here's proof that you
have done (laugh) a similar
thing, you know, like six times
in the
past, like, since we've started,
you know, working together, or
something like that, that could
be really, I don't know. Really
valuable.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah,
definitely.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Always, um,
you know, like, after I finally
felt like I was a, had my trauma
under control, I always
would talk to people about this
idea of like, having this
experience in your back pocket,
like, look, I was able to make
it through this. And it was
really challenging for a period
of time. But I've developed
these tools, or like, I know
that I need community, or I know
that this is going to be a
trigger for me to predict some
of those things. But at the
beginning of the pandemic, I
found myself, again, frustrated
with myself, because I thought,
you know, so much of what I feel
like I'm going through, like, I
lost my job, my kids were at
home, and I was supervising
their schooling. And I just felt
like really isolated and alone.
I'm like, I have navigated
through this before. But I'm
crying every single night. Like,
what, what, why, why can't I
make it through this and, and
like, ultimately, what I
remembered was, hey, community
plays
a really big role in that,
right? And so that's, that's how
Virtual Coffee was started.
Because I was like, hey, anyone
want to get together because I
feel really lonely. But then
also, recognizing that I wasn't
the only one going through the
experience of the pandemic, and
the effects of it. Like,
everybody was experiencing it.
And that's very different from
navigating your own situation.
And so, you know, I think, for
me, at least, I have this
tendency to be really frustrated
with myself when I think like, I
should have the skills or the
tools or whatever to make it
through this. But also, not
every experience is the same.
And that's gonna vary from time
to time. So there's learning new
things, and there's growing as a
person. And I think that, you
know, being able to share those
things, and the first couple
Virtual Coffees, that's what
they
were, it was like, I'm
frustrated, there's a pandemic,
and I'm very sad about it right
now. But that's what creates
that like closeness and that
ability for vulnerability and,
you know, for, for other people
to be able to share their
stories as well.
Dan Ott: Word. (laugh)
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: (laugh)
Sorry. I feel like I did a
monologue. You
can cut that.
Cameron Bardell: No, don't cut
that.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, that was
awesome.
Dan Ott: No, I think it was
great. I just didn't have
anything really to add.
Rahat Chowdhury: And not to add.
Yeah. (laugh)
Dan Ott: Okay, so wrapping up. I
guess just the last question
that is a little more general.
We, in Virtual Coffee, talk a
lot about you know, finding
teams and you know, find a job
and stuff like that. So when
you're thinking about either
joining a company or creating a
team to work on a project, what
is, what is like a
characteristic, what just, just
like pick one,
but what is one characteristic
that you value in people, in
people you work with? We'll
start with Rahat.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah, I mean,
I've been recently applying for
jobs and stuffs. So one thing
I've been kind of like, asking a
lot about is like, how the
culture is in terms of like pair
programming. I love like
learning things from like my
experience steps. So if there's
like a environment for that,
that's definitely something
super important to me. I've had
a couple of companies tell me
straight up that, yeah, we don't
really have time for that, like
hmm, probably don't want to
continue
with you then. So, yeah, I mean,
I feel like that kind of like,
shows you a little bit about
how, you know, senior devs kind
of like support the more junior
ones. And I guess the overall
team dynamic of like, having
that willingness to just like
hop on a call or something with
somebody and help them through a
problem.
Dan Ott: Yeah, absolutely. I
found with pair programming,
too,
it's, it's sometimes, it's a top
down issue, right? You know? So,
so like, you could have a senior
developer, be willing, or you
know, willing to talk and
willing to do stuff like that.
But when you phrase it as like
pair programming, then
management gets jumpy, because
two people, like in their mind,
two people are
working on the same problem or
whatever, so, yeah. I think
that's, that's really important
to think about when you're
finding people to work with.
Cameron, what about you?
Cameron Bardell: Yeah, that was
a good one. One thing I noticed,
I was doing a bunch of
interviewing. I interviewed at a
lot of places, even something
like that, I was pretty sure I
would take a job just to kind of
find out what the tech industry
was like, because I didn't
really know. And one thing I
noticed was, that kind of stood
out to me with some places don't
ever talk about like, the
products they're building. And
if you (laugh) can't really tell
if they care about what they're
building, or if they want to be
good. And yeah, I just
really wanted to build something
where like, everybody wanted to
actually make it good. You know,
even if it was something that
would have just be an internal
tool, or you know, something
that's in
kind of like a boring industry,
like, I still want to make
something that's nice to use and
looks good, and supports
accessibility and all these
things. See, I kind of, I was
definitely more willing to talk
to people who seem to care and
know a lot about the product and
want to continually improve it
instead of just, I don't know,
make it good enough.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I think that's, I
think that's great. I feel like
that's usually a good sign that
like, people are invested in it,
too. And don't have a lot of
turnover, you know, if you have
a new, new people that are
coming and going all the time,
then you
can't like build any connection
to it, right? So,
Cameron Bardell: Yeah. It's
kinda surprising you. Especially
a lot of the startups
was working at, I thought they
were all like, deeply care
about,
like the thing that they're
building, but they didn't.
Dan Ott: They deep, deeply?
Yeah. Maybe deeply care about
the project, but,
Cameron Bardell: Maybe they
deeply care about the money they
were making? Yeah. (laugh)
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Awesome.
Thanks for being here. We really
enjoyed having this
conversation. But before we
leave, can you let us know if
there's anything you're up to?
Or how our listeners can find
you?
Cameron Bardell: Sure, yeah, you
can always you can find me at
Virtual Coffee, obviously, twice
a week. You can find me on
Twitter, @CameronBardell. And
that's where you can see me
doing most of my stuff, kind of,
I don't have a lot of time for
doing like open-source work
right now. But I hope to get
started back up in the next few
months. So yeah.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah. You can
also find me on Virtual Coffee.
I usually come to the afternoon
meetings. And yeah, I'm on
Twitter, @Rahatcodes. And if
you're into open-source and
stuff definitely looking for
some contributors to my mental
health
project. So. Definitely check
that out.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Awesome.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. Well,
obviously the link of all that
in
the show notes. Okay, well,
thank you both for joining us.
And we will catch up with you
guys on, on Virtual Coffee.
Cameron Bardell: Thanks, guys.
Always great and fun.
Rahat Chowdhury: Yeah. Thank
you.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO. Or you can
email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes. Plus
you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee's been up to on
our website at virtualcoffee.io.
Dan Ott: Please subscribe to our
podcast and write a review. Next
week we'll have Drew Clements on
the podcast to talk about
building a career and a
community. Thanks for listening
everyone.