Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 1, Episode
6 of the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here, on this
podcast,
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. In this
episode, you'll hear from Drew
Clements. Drew is a career
transitioner, a father of two
and full time developer. And he
spends his spare time building
protege.dev and hopes to become
a strong advocate for junior
developers everywhere. In this
episode, we talk about building
a career, and also Drew's
experience building protege.dev
the platform curated with remote
jobs for junior developers. Drew
talks about the struggles of
junior level job searching, the
importance of supportive company
culture, and learning in
public while building Protege.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee. We introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random
check-in question. Today's
question is, what is the most
beautiful place near where you
live? We hope you enjoyed this
episode. Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a
front-end
developer from a small town in
Ohio, and the most beautiful
place near me, I don't really
know. But it snowed a lot last
night. And so all of the pine
trees look really, really
beautiful. So I'm just gonna go
with pine trees covered with
snow.
Dan: That's awesome. I love how
everything looks with snow
on it. Hi, I'm Dan. I am a
front-end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio. I say Cleveland
every time. I'm actually from
Lakewood, which is first city
West of Cleveland. And so there
is a
park called Lakewood Park that's
on the lake here. And it's very
beautiful. There's lots of--
it's big, and there's lots of
cool little spots to hang out.
So that's that.
Drew Clements: I'm Drew. I'm a
front-end developer with Foster
Commerce. The most beautiful
place near where I live. I live
in the south, so my options are
limited here. So, I'm, like,
five minutes from St. Simons
Island. But the beaches aren't
necessarily pretty. They just
have expensive resorts. And I'm,
like-- I'm just out to Savannah.
So they have a pretty rad
downtown. But-- okay, I got one.
I got one. On the other side of
the state from me, which is
still relatively close compared
to you
guys. We have-- they call it the
little Grand Canyon. It's a
little hiking trail. It really
does just look like a miniature
version of the Grand Canyon.
Dan: Nice. That's cool. That
sounds cool. Yeah.
Bekah: Vacation 2021. Well,
welcome, Drew. We
are very happy to have you. And
fun fact about Drew, he designed
the Virtual Coffee logo. So,
thanks for that.
Drew: I do what I can [laughs].
Bekah: We always like to start
off with the
origin story of how you got into
tech. So, can you give us a
little background?
Drew: Yeah, that's-- I feel like
my story into tech is
like a story linked to a story,
linked to a story. So, growing
up, I played in bunch of punk
rock bands. One of the last
bands I played in, I met a guy
from the local music scene named
Sean. Sean moved away to
California and became a
developer. Right before he did
that, I tattooed him. Me
tattooing
landed me in apprenticeship as a
designer a few years later,
which then led me-- that's where
I was kind of introduced to,
like,
HTML and CSS. So I was like,
"Hey, I'm learning this stuff."
I remember Sean was doing
something like this. So then, I
reached back out to him. Me and
him started kind of talking
again. So from there, I was able
to kind of work into a developer
role with that same company and
left tattooing. So it's- it's a
guy I met through the local
music scene in 2010 ended up
getting me into developing a
decade later. Yeah, so I spent
seven years as a tattoo artist,
transitioned to graphic design.
From graphic design, I used to
know that Sean—the old
connection—to get my way here.
And I don't think I could have
made that happen if I had all
the money in the world and 10
years to plan it, but here I am.
Bekah: That's awesome. So, if we
ever have a
Virtual Coffee on-site
conference, are you going to
offer tattoos? All Virtual
Coffee logos?
Drew: [Laughs] Yes, I will do
that.
Bekah: All right, we have it
recorded. So now you
can't back out. Okay. So, I'm
also want to know about how you
found Virtual Coffee. I feel
like I have known you longer, a
lot longer than Virtual Coffee
has been going on. So-- but how
did you end up at Virtual
Coffee?
Drew: How did I end up with
Virtual Coffee? It's funny
enough that we're recording this
on a podcast, because I met you
through reaching out to find
people to interview for a
podcast I was going to start.
So- so I have the recording
actually. I don't know if it- I
don't know if it ever got
editing. I don't [laughs]. I
just had it right here on the
desk. No. So, I guess in 2019, I
was going to start a
podcast, I reached out to you.
We connected on Twitter. That
never ended up happening. But
we-- when
I saw you posting-- so, at the
beginning of 2020, I was- I was
working two jobs. I was working
full time as a designer,
part-time as a developer. An
awesome-- both of those job
within, like, 24 hours of each
other. And with a wife that was
five months pregnant, that was
kind of like a gut
check. But around that same time
was when you'd posted about
Virtual Coffee. So, like, you
know, I have a lot of spare time
on my hands, Bekah posts a lot
of awesome stuff, we had a great
conversation when we recorded
our podcast episode together. So
I was like, "Yeah, let me- let
me check this out and see what
happens." And now, you can't get
rid of me [laughs].
Bekah: I think that podcast
episode that I
recorded with you, I had just
been working with Dan for a
couple of months. And I, like,
was still trying to wrap my head
around things. And I remember
you asking me questions and I
were like, "I don't even know
the words that I should use to
answer those questions." So
[laughs]--
Drew: If it's any consolation,
there's still a lot
of times I don't know the words
I should use to answer
questions [laughs].
Bekah: Yeah, that's for sure.
Same.
Same. [Laughs] But it was- it
was, like, it was really great
podcast
interview because you're just
some fun to be around, I guess.
So, I'm happy that you are here
with us today. And at Virtual
Coffee.
Drew: Happy to be here. Like I
said, you can't get rid of me.
Bekah: [Laughs] Okay. So fast
forward a little bit,
you got another job, you're
career changer. And you're like,
"Oh, hey.
I bought this domain called
protege.dev. So on top of all of
the other things that I'm doing,
I'm- I'm gonna start this
community building project." So,
why and how?
Drew: Why and how? Well, so, I
originally bought the
Protege domain-- to the back up
just a little bit. I had an old
side project called ColtXP. It's
a really bad name. Never name
anything that, ever. But that's
what the original podcast that I
interviewed you for was going to
kind of be in parallel with
that. And so I- I knew that it
was a bad name. So I was trying
to think of something- something
else I could call it. The idea
of that project was that-- it
was gonna be pretty much a place
where people could connect to
work on open source issues
together, kind of like a junior
finding a senior willing to, you
know, give them some time. So I
was just trying to think the-
the name ColtXP-- I think I just
used, like, a Thesaurus or
something. Like, what's another
word for someone that's learning
something or something like
that. And Colt was somehow on
that list. It was like an
inexperienced person or
something like that. Again,
horrible name. Don't ever call
anything yet. So I came across
the word protege, you know,
pretty obvious. I don't know why
I didn't think of it in the
first place. So I was looking
around on different domains.
Actually, no. I went to Netlify.
And I was like, "Let me see if
protege.com is available."
Obviously, it wasn't. So I was
like, "Let me see if protege.dev
is available." It was. For 15
bucks. I was like, "That's not
bad at all." So I hit the next
button,
expecting there to be, like,
insert payment information. And
it said "Congratulations". I was
like, "Okay. I guess this is a
thing now. So I kind of went
back and forth on, "Do I want to
make that something new with
that name? Do I want to rebrand
the old project under
Protege—which was the original
idea?" But
then- but then COVID happened,
and I lost- I lost both of those
jobs. So I think- I think I
accidentally bought the domain
in February, and then in March
was when I lost work. So, you
know, I was looking-- I lost
work, so I was looking at all
the job boards all the time. And
it was, you know, you see
senior, senior, senior lead,
tech lead, bla bla bla. And
I was like, "There's, like,
there's nothing-- it's so
hard to find anything for
someone at my skill level." So I
was like, "You know what? I'm
just gonna build the job board
that I wish I had." And that's-
that's kind of how it ended up
getting started. I lost- I lost
my job and gave myself a new
one [laughs]. A new one that
doesn't pay anything.
Dan: I love that. I love the
idea of, like, you just-- you
have
a problem, you know, and so you
just decided to fix it [laughs]-
to fix it yourself, right?
Drew: That's- that's pretty much
what happened.
Dan: Yeah, it's amazing. And
then, on top of that, you know-
you know you're going to gain
experience for yourself, you
know? And building it, right? We
were just talking to Vic. And
he's talking about a lot of this
sort of the same thing, right?
Like, the-- he frames it a
little differently. But the
indie, you
know, indie hacking mentality,
right, of you have a problem.
And so instead of, I don't know,
wandering around or just being
sad, you know? Right? Like, you
just kind of go and- go and dive
into it, right? And hopefully,
it becomes a successful product.
And also, you know, you're
giving yourself, like,
experience,
and scratching your own itch,
and all that stuff. That's
great.
Drew: Yeah, the-- when I first
started out on Protege, my
mindset was, you know, "I'm
going to build this thing in
React. I
need-- I needed a React project
on my portfolio." So I told
myself, like, "I'm gonna- I'm
gonna build this out. And if it
works, awesome. If not, then I
have something on a resume that
will maybe at least helped get
me hired," which it actually
did,
fairly- fairly early on. So I
think I started building it in
March. And either at the end of
March or early April, I was
connected with a company called
Layer Frame out of Florida.
Super awesome team. And the
workout done on Protege, even at
that point, before it was even
done. Just the fact that I was
doing that, you know, building
that product, but also the work
I'd put into it myself, pretty
much jumping in blind was one
of-
one of the reasons that they can
even consider to bring me on
the team. So it saved me almost
immediately.
Bekah: I think that's so great.
I think there's
a tendency when you are starting
out as an entry level dev to
just keep going through the
tutorials, right? And there's
nothing wrong with that. But
there's so many different people
that are doing those same
projects. So if you're able to
do something where you're
building something that you're
interested in or something that
solves a problem for you, you're
a little bit invested in it, but
it also shows that, "Hey, look,"
you know, "I tackled this
problem, and I kept adding to
it,
and growing with it." And I
think that really shows, you
know, a
really good representation of
who you are as a coder.
Dan: Yeah, you mentioned, like,
when you were describing
talking to the company who hired
you after that, that you went
into
the- the Protege project going
in blind. And I was- I was
wondering, like, what you--
like, in hindsight, like, what
do you
think of when you say that?
Like, what pieces were you
missing, you know? Now that
you've gone through the whole
process, and it's been a
product, you know, for however
long, I just looked at my watch
to see what month it was. I
don't know
what I'm doing. But, you know,
it's- it's been a, you know,
it's been live for how many
months?
Drew: Coming up on a year. I
think March will be a year.
Dan: Okay, yeah. So, I guess, my
question is [laughs]- my
question is, like, what- what
do-- you know, now that, like,
would
change your approach, if
anything-- you know, if you
would
start-- if you were starting
protege.dev right now?
Drew: How much time do you have?
[Laughs] It was-- so,
the initial
build was just a regular Create
React App. That was intentional
because I wanted to force myself
to learn some of the lower level
plumbing. I wish I would have
known more about state
management in React. Like, I
kinda-- so, right before this
episode, we were talking about
how some of the- some of the
parts of it are really just a
juggling act until, you know, it
either dies or does what it's
supposed to do. So, I think, if
I would have known a little bit
more around that, that could
have been-- I don't think it's
an unstable system. But it's not
as
good as it can be. And I'm
actually in the process of
rewriting some of that work now.
And I expect I'm going to be
able to eliminate probably about
40% of what's there now, and
have something that works better
in, you know, with better
practices in place at the same
time. Also, I didn't really know
much about, like, component
systems. Like, I knew what
components
were, but I didn't really have a
good idea of how to utilize them
correctly, which is another
thing I've been kind of cleaning
up as I've been doing this
rebuild. We're converting from
React-- Create React App to Next
right now. So, I mean, even just
last night, I was looking at
some stuff, like, why didn't I
just make this a component
rather than pasting it seven
times in the same place? Yeah.
So, just- just little stuff like
that.
Bekah: It's interesting. I used
to write
screenplays with my brother. And
one of the first bits of advice
someone told me—or I heard—it
was, "Write your whole
screenplay,
and then cut 50%, and then
rewrite it." And, like, as
you're
talking through this, that kind
of makes sense to me in terms
of,
like, okay, you have something
down and you learned a lot in
that first process. But what you
learn should enable you to
really tighten things up and
getting it working efficiently
or- or making it an effective
story. And codes not that
different from that.
Drew: Yeah, that was what
Andy's—the co-founder—he
came on really early on with me.
One- one thing we were very
adamant about when we were
starting up was that we're going
to try to build as much of this
as possible without a library
if we can. So that's why- that's
why a lot of the state
management with some of the
forms are a bit of a juggling
act, because we knew there was,
you know, Redux and other things
like that out there. But we
wanted to kind of put ourselves
in the uncomfortable position of
having to build it, the only
having to build it with whatever
we had available to us then
without grabbing something off
the shelf. And-- I mean, he
would probably agree, we both
probably-- we learned- we
learned
a lot of wrong ways to handle
state React. We learned a
lot of ways that you can do it,
but probably aren't ideal. And
now we're- now we're getting
into the phase of, you know,
now- now
we can do it the right way with
an understanding of why it's the
right way.
Dan: Yeah, that enable that-
that agreement at the beginning,
and between you and your partner
was-- is, like, a very, very
cool
thing to do. Especially, you
know, it's nice to have
alignment and that sort of
thing, you know? But I mean, I
always-
always- always say the best way
to learn anything, on any sort
of deep level is to do it, just
like you guys have done. And
state management in particular,
I mean, like, a lot of things
are like
this. But state management is
one of those, where there's a
million
ways to do it. None of them are
right or wrong, really. And
the--
but you never really-- you never
gonna have actual full insight
into why you-- why to make one
choice or the other. Why to use
Redux versus, you know, anything
else. It-- by reading tutorials,
you're never gonna figure it
out, right? Like, you're never,
like, somebody could say, "Use
Redux for this x, y and z," you
know? "Don't use Redux here,"
you know? And you could sort of
try
to follow them. But you're never
gonna-- you don't understand why
until you've gone down the road
of hacking it together, and then
getting to the spot where you're
like, "Okay, this-- I see now."
Like, "This is not working out,
or this is like more of a pain
than it should be, or," you
know, or whatever. Or, "I don't
trust it
as much," which is- which is one
of the-- like, one of the- one
of
the things that's hard to
explain until you feel it,
right? So you have that-- you're
talking about that form state.
And just not, like, you know, it
can be better, you know? Like,
it's working and stuff, but you
know, like, there's some-
there's some area where it's not
exactly sure what's going on or
can't track, you know, all the
different pieces of state or all
the different, you know, figures
[??] that go on. Like, that's
really great.
Drew: Yeah. And even when
we're-- even while I'm coming
through it now, I'm realizing,
I'm kind of reflecting back on
where I was last year, and,
like, I can kind of like see the
growth that I've had over the
last year. It's, like, as I'm--
as I
rebuilding part to this, I'm
looking at- I'm looking at some
of the state, and I'm like,
"Okay, this- this definitely
needs to
be, you know, handled somewhere
else in a more safer way. But
this is actually perfectly fine
to just be, you know, in this
one component, and that's all it
needs." And it's-- I don't know.
I--
me, a year ago, would be, like,
so jealous of me right now
[laughs],
that I'm, like, able to set them
in a position to, like, to
know the difference of one and
why.
Bekah: I think that's a really
good point too,
because there's always this
tricky thing where you feel
like, "Oh, I have not-- I
haven't grown enough." But look,
you're
talking about this one year
journey and how much you've
learned, you know? You've grown
a lot through that. And
sometimes, it feels very slow.
But really, you're- you're
moving a ton.
Drew: Yeah. And this is actually
my-- this is my first
year as a full time developer.
So before this, I was either--
I was working part-time, which
was, you know, like, maybe 15
hours after I got done with a
full time job. So, like, you
know, I was already probably
coming in at, like, 60% mental
[??] capacity. And then, the job
I had in the agency before that,
it was a developer role, but it
was- it was with a bunch of
proprietary stuff, and some
older languages. So, like, a lot
of it didn't really-- so, I
mean, a lot of it was just
customer
support to begin with. And the
smaller majority after that was,
you know, it was in- in such a
sandboxed and specific place
that a lot of it couldn't really
translate over. What I-- one
thing I wanted to double back on
you said there, the- the
alignment between me and Andy, a
lot of that was able to happen
was because-- I mean, I was- I
was very junior when I just
decided
to go full tilt on this, but
Andy was the same way. Andy
was working full time as a
project manager, you know? He
had written some code before. I
don't know the full extent of
his- of his experience before
that, but when he approached me,
he was like, "Hey, I've had a
similar idea. I'm kind of in the
same spot." So when- when we
were kind of like spitballing
ideas,
we were like, you know, "Let's
keep it simple. Check. Let's
build as much as we can without
libraries. Check." So I think- I
think part of the reason we were
able to align on so many things
in the beginning is that we
were—for the most part—in
pretty much the exact same spot,
career wise. Shoutout to Andy,
by the way. He just started full
time as a developer, I think,
within the last few weeks. So,
congrats on that.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure.
Dan: Congrats to Andy.
Bekah: Andy is also very
awesome. Okay. So,
simultaneously, you are
establishing a career as an
early career developer, and you
are tackling a big problem in
the industry, right? So, can we
talk a little bit about the
challenges of balancing both of
those things?
Drew: I don't know if there's a
balance as much as I just
put as much weight on both all
the time [laughs]. Which
is why
I'm probably on, like, a beeline
to burnout at some point
[laughs]. I
don't know. It's-- I don't know.
I haven't really thought about
it. There's not much for
balance. Or I guess, I don't
really have a process for
balancing it. So, like, I'm
really bad about saying yes when
people ask me for stuff. So,
like, I joined up with Layer
Frame. And then—thanks to a
tweet that you sent out, Bekah—I
was propositioned for some other
contract work that ended up
happening, like, right alongside
that that turned into the full
time role that I have now. So,
I'm like, "Okay, cool. I won't
have two jobs anymore." Like, a
month after that, someone else
was like, "Hey, I got some
contract--
or do you want to jump in on?"
I'm like, "Absolutely! [Laughs]
Let's do it."
So, I've had a bad habit of
keeping two jobs.
Bekah: Yeah. It's so hard to
balance. I'm not-- I'm
certainly not good at that
either. And that's one of the
things that I'm working at,
figuring out I like go through
these cycles. I'm, like, all in
for six weeks. And then, for an
entire week, I feel like I can't
move. And that's obviously not
healthy [laughs]. I'm trying to
find better ways of doing that.
But
also, there's just this weird--
I don't know. Tech just move so
fast all the time. And you want
to level up as a new developer.
And at the same time, you're so
aware of the problems of, I
don't
know, like, being an entry level
developer position that you want
to tackle them when you have
that passion. So there is this
weird, you know, how do I do all
of these things and still take
care of myself.
Drew: That's- that's one thing
I've planned to focus
on this year is getting the
stuff done that I want to, in a
healthy way. I will say, one
silver lining to taking on all
that extra contract work is
I've- I've walked away with
probably
at least two to three things
that I didn't know before I
started the project. I really
forget where that sentence was
going [laughs]. That was gonna
be a good one too.
Bekah: [Laughs] And that's we,
all the time.
Dan: Yes.
Drew: Oh, no. So, it allowed- it
allowed me to work
with a couple
of different-- or, you know,
just developers with different
styles. So, when I was with
Layer Frame, I was working with
Rob.
And I feel like Rob was just,
like, a mastermind with
everything. So, like, anytime I
had a- anytime I had a problem,
he had a solution for it. And he
was really good at walking me
through how he got to the
solution. So I walked away with
some really good troubleshooting
skills from that.
And then, when I-- on this last
contract role that I just-- at
the end of last year, I was
working with a guy named Nick.
And he's just- he's just super
knowledgeable around React. And,
like, some of-- there's, like,
so many tools and methods in
React
that I didn't even know were a
thing until I was able to work
with him. So it-- I overload
myself a lot. But so far, I've
walked away- I've walked away in
the green from it.
Bekah: I want to come back to
this idea of
talking about Rob, and one, just
like, learning in general. So,
do you have a measure or a point
where you think, "Okay, I have
been trying to figure out this
problem. And I know that this
other person knows the answer."
So, at what point do you ask?
Like, how far down the rabbit
hole do you go before you ask
for help?
Drew: So, at my full time job,
we have a one hour
rule. If you get stuck for more
than an hour, then reach out to
someone. And I think that's kind
of been rubbing off on me for
my side projects. I'm in a
couple of different communities
that I kind of know which one
will probably more than likely
have the answers I need or will
be—dependent on the time of
day—may just be more available.
So I usually try to hit it if,
you know, right at the one hour
mark, depending on how hard I'm
spinning my wheels. Some--
sometimes, I know there's been a
few times, like, I just-- I hit
a wall and, like, I don't even
know
how to start scaling this thing.
So I'm just gonna immediately
reach out. But then, there's
sometimes, like, you know, I go
through- I go through my
troubleshooting process. And if
I still can't really get
anywhere, I have a couple
different places I can reach out
to the-- what I love about the
communities that I'm in is that
in most cases, it's rare that
they're just gonna give me the
answer. But they're more so
going to work through it with me
and almost kind of rubber
duck me to the answer. So that's
always super awesome.
Dan: Nice. Yeah. Like, I mean,
that one hour mark? Seems
like a good, like, rule of
thumb, you know, for that sort
of thing. That question comes up
a lot, you know? And with- with
newer-- early career developers,
you know? I mean, that exact
question comes up a lot. A lot
of people are wondering it, and
it's hard to sort of baseline
it. I feel like the answer can
sometimes change depending on
the company, if you're-- I mean,
if you're working-- like, this
is not for side projects, but
you
know, at a job. And I've been
finding it very-- like, it seems
like a good thing to have an
actual rule for—like you said—
that.
That's where you learned it
from, have it written down,
you know, and make it-- make
sure it's okay for early career
developers to ask questions, you
know? And, like, let them know
when to do it, right? Because
you know what? I mean, nobody
wants to ask a question right
away every time they don't know
anything, you know? But it
always is going to be like-
like doing the rubber ducky
thing is just, like, such a
useful
tool for any developer of any-
any skill or, you know, learning
level. It just that one hour
mark seems- seems cool. I don't
know.
Drew: Yeah. Speaking of rubber
ducks, my-- we did-- two
years ago, we did Secret Santa
for the family. My sister got
me-- she didn't know what- she
didn't know what to get me. So
she just googled, like, coder
gift ideas. And she got me this.
It says- it says, "Hi! I'm Stu,
your debugging friend.
Tell me your steps, and we'll
find the bug together!" It's-
it's right here, on my desk. And
he does exactly that.
Dan: That's amazing.
Bekah: I- I have a problem of, I
think, early in
my career. It was I don't know
if I should ask a question. And
now that I'm a little bit in,
it's the stubbornness in me that
I have to tackle, like, "I can
do this," you know? [Laughs]
Like, "I
don't
have to ask a question." This is
a real check of, I don't know,
what does
that, like, hubris or something?
[Laughs]
Drew: [Laughs] Yeah. No, I
have-- the first kind of
developer
role I was in, the senior dev I
worked with, he was- he was very
much trained the old-school way
and brought up with the
old-school mentality. So, any--
anytime I would come to
questions with him, he would
assume that, like, I got to the
question or I got to the problem
and immediately ask the
question. And that's kind of how
he would react to me. Like,
there's a lot of tension there.
Like, it got to the point where
I
didn't want to ask him a
question because I knew what-- I
knew the vibe and what the
response was going to be. What
was actually happening is, like,
I was spinning my wheels for,
like, two hours trying to not
have to ask him a question. And
then, when I did ask the
question, it was, like, you
know,
grief conflict? A whole bunch of
tension. So it's-- I don't know.
It's- it's been like a breath of
fresh air slash a huge relief
that,
A, I've found the communities
that have found and have places
that I can ask questions, but B,
now, with a company that, like--
that had-- that has their own
rule for when you should ask
questions, and a lot of times,
they're- they're gonna chop that
hour down to, like, 30 minutes
or, like, any time I'm on a
project, they're like, "Hey, one
hour rule is actually 10 minutes
here,"
when our rules actually 20
minutes here. And they actually
want you to ask questions. They
have-- we have an entire thread
[??] in basecamp where it's just
different developers asking
different questions. And
there's-- it's just super
awesome thing to be a part of.
Dan: That's really-- that's
cool. That's really cool to
hear. Like, the-- per project or
something, they'll- they'll just
say, "Okay, for this project, we
know it's, like, new or
something,
or a lot of moving pieces. So
change the rule," you know?
Based
on that.
Drew: Yeah. And they-- they're-
they're really aware of,
like, skill level and expertise
with the different-- with
different tools and stuff. So if
they're bringing me on to a
project that uses, you know,
like, a legacy build that they
know I
haven't really seen a whole lot,
then- then that's when they'll
say, "Hey, your- your window's
15 minutes for this." Or if
they're
moving, in some cases, even some
of the more experienced devs on
to something where it's a little
more intricate UI work, where
they're mostly, you know, data
back-end stuff, like, "Hey,
okay.
Well, now your window's 10
minutes," and met-- but mine
will
still be the full hour so that
they're- they're really aware
of,
like, where everyone's at. And,
like, adjusting their windows
accordingly.
Dan: That's really cool to hear.
I feel like asking
questions is almost a skill to
learn as well. Sort of similar
to googling [laughs] is a skill
as a developer, you know? It
sounds
everybody who is been a
developer for long enough knows
what that means, like, knows
what a person means when they
say that googling is a skill,
and you have to learn how to
google. Do you feel like you
have become better at asking
questions? Once, like--
especially once you start
working with
maybe a company that value that,
you know, value that
interaction?
Drew: Yeah, absolutely. And- and
I would even say, I got
better at asking questions, even
while I was in that environment.
Because-- well, first, I want to
say, like me and that
developer,
we-- it was a really strange
relationship. Like, every- every
Friday, we would go grab lunch
together, we were best buds. And
we liked the same music. We were
both guitarist, and we would
sit-
we would sit there-- you know,
we shared an office. It feels
weird
to say that I shared a room with
anyone right now [laughs]. But,
you know, the
entire day, we would just sit
there and talk back and forth
like it was-- we really were
just friends. Friends inside-
inside
the company. But when it- when
it came to that, that- that was,
like, that was the only point of
friction in that relationship.
Which was- which was really
strange to me. But I think,
it's--
the only thing I can chalk it up
to is that that's just how he
was. That was the company
culture. He was- he was trained
in and brought up in himself. So
that's the only way he knows to
try to help others learn. But,
yeah, I think even in that
environment, I think I got
better at asking questions.
Because I would- I would ask
something, and his response
would be like, "Well, what is-
what is x mean? What is y mean?"
I would use the wrong words all
the time, which is very
frustrating.
Dan: Can you give an example of
that?
Drew: So, like, I would say
something like, you know,
"The-- this-- I'm passing this
argument, but it's not coming
out the right way," when what I
meant was the method, but I was
using the word argument. And his
response to be like, "Well,
obviously, that's not gonna
work. You don't need an argument
there." "That's the--" I'd be
pointing at it on the screen,
like, "That, right
there. That's what I'm trying to
do." He's like, "What? That's
not
an argument." I'm like, "Okay.
Fair enough." So [laughs], like,
that kind of stuff.
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. You know, we also
see, like, the issue
with entry level devs and the
problem of comfort level with
whoever they're working with.
And I have a lot of feelings
about that. But one of them also
is that not everybody is meant
to be a mentor, right? You know,
some people have, like, a
natural
ability, some people can have
training and get good at it. But
some people, you know, they
don't desire it or they feel
like it takes away from their
experience. And so, they're
aggravated by it. But a company
not only has to make a space
welcoming for new developers,
but it also has to support the
upper level devs who are
providing the mentorship and the
guidance, and making sure that,
you know, that culture shows
that how you treat people and
talk to them.
Drew: Yeah. That's the-- so, one
of-- Sean, the guy
that I mentioned
earlier, he was always really
good at. If I ever came to him
with a question, he was-- his
response was always, you know,
"Well, let's look at it
together." Or, you know, "Let's
talk me
through the steps you're trying
to do, and let's see if we can
find the hang up there." So I
think, he's one of those people
that just naturally has, like--
well, I mean, he's-- I know he's
been a
guitar teacher for a while. So
maybe he's just developed those
teaching skills.
Dan: Yeah. Going back to having
a company support the
senior devs in those roles, I
feel like that's an important
thing. I guess tying it back to
the framing of making it a rule,
like, having the rule of the one
hour thing, for instance, right?
That gives the younger
developer-- younger-- the-- you
know, early
career, newer developer a
guideline to follow, right? But
it also implies that the
question should be asked, you
know? And that- and that the
question also should be, you
know, answered or whatever. So,
again, that has to become-- I
mean, you can just hope that the
senior developer in whatever
position is good at it and
everything, but having it be
part of the company culture,
having it be expected, you know,
that's part of a developer's
role is supporting a junior
developer or however it works
out. But that part of the
developer's job is doing that.
Not that answering a question
or helping a developer through a
problem is taking time away from
doing your job, right? I feel
like that can be something that
can come up, right? Where—if
it's not framed correctly—maybe
when you were asking a question,
he was just feeling like he had
stuff to do. And this was
getting in the way of doing his
stuff or something, you know?
And which is not actually
correct, right? Like, it's part
of his job. I mean, I don't know
what the exact situation was
there. But, like, it should be
part of--
Drew: There was definitely a
lot- a lot of moving
projects with only one
experienced and one learning
developer.
Dan: Right. Right. Right. You
know, and not having it
explicit is a recipe for that
sort of thing to happen, you
know? You could maybe have be
lucky. That's what I mean,
like, depending on just hoping
[laughs]- hoping that it works
out. It
doesn't-- that doesn't seem like
the right call. And hiring
junior developers is important.
But they need-- like, the people
hiring them need to be, you
know, prepared, right? Need to
be prepared to support them, but
also prepared to, you know, have
a plan for the senior developers
too. Because it's hard. It's
also
another whole skill to learn.
And, you know, having some
guidelines like that, I feel
like is such a good- such a good
thing to, and sort of almost
easy thing to pull off, right?
Like, an easy way to really
improve the situation is just,
like, this is how it works. Ask
a question, you know? [Laughs]
Like, ask
a question after an hour, you
know? Answer the question after,
you know, that when the junior
developer helps like it or
asks, you know? I just like
that. I like the clarity of
that, you know? I think that's
really cool.
Drew: Yeah. And that actually
reminds me one- one
thing—before I knew about the
one hour rule—one thing Sean
always did to me that I didn't
know until I-- you know, months
and months later is that when I
would ask him a question, he
would- he would- he would set,
like, a timer, like, he'll reply
within
one hour if he doesn't hear back
from me. And I didn't know
that was the thing. So, like, I-
I just asked him a question, I
keep trying to work on it. And
then, there were a lot of times
where like, "Oh, nevermind. Got
it." And then, like, at-- what--
I think it
was after I'd left the contract
role with him, he's like, "Yeah,
I used to give you, like, an
hour anytime you ask a question.
And
towards the end, you got to
where you were responding back
within,
like, 10 minutes that nevermind,
you found the answer." But
touching back on what you were
saying about companies needing
to, you know, like, proactively
support junior developers.
That's one of the things we're
doing on Protege. So, all of
our--
all the listings there are
curated and, like, approved by
us. That's one thing-- when-
when a company lists with us,
one
thing we gotta do-- one thing we
do is, you know, first, we read
through the listing and make
sure it kind of lines up with-
with the goals we have for
Protege. But then, we also kind
of like dig into the company's
website, and, you know, maybe
their LinkedIn, to try and get
an idea of the company culture
like. Are- are they posting this
role because they just
want to pay someone cheap? Or
are they posting this role
because they genuinely want to
find someone to build them up
into the best version that they
can be? And we try to- we try to
make sure we have a good idea
of- of- of the answer to that.
For- for every listing.
Dan: That's really cool. I
mean-- and that's, like-- I feel
like one of- one of the things
that makes Protege, you know,
special is the curation and the
sort of insight into the- the
junior developer mind, if you
will [laughs], you know?
It's—like you
said—it's not just a-- I don't
know, collection of- of things
that people want to find cheap
worker, you know, something like
that, right?
Drew: Yeah. I'm a--
Dan: It's really cool.
Drew: I will always refer to
myself as perpetually-
perpetually junior developer.
So, hopefully, I will always be
able
to keep that mindset. But we
have-- I was actually just
talking to some people in the
Virtual Coffee group not too
long ago about- about some tools
and features we can add to,
hopefully, help empower both
sides of the process in our
interface to build.
Bekah: So-- okay. So, if you had
a magic wand, and you
could get everything you want
for Protege, what does it look
like?
Drew: If I get everything I
want, in terms of features or
success?
Bekah: Whatever you want. Let's
do it all.
You've got a magic wand. It's
your choice.
Drew: If I had a magic wand,
there-- there'd be accounts for
both candidates and companies,
there'd be- there'd be tools on
both ends to do both empower and
protect both sides. I don't
really feel like the companies
would really need much
protection. But in some cases,
like, maybe the candidates do.
Especially from, you know, like,
ageism, or- or something like
that. Yeah, so some- some tools
around, like, empowering
candidates against
discrimination. So, like, maybe
there-- maybe only-- like, their
work history and, like, some
kind
of like generic questions they
answered are available. And the
company can't really see what
their, you know, name- name,
gender, age, or location, or
anything like that is until, you
know, they schedule an interview
with them and have something
kinda like on the books or
something like that. Or even-
even a tool to where maybe
candidates can say, like, you
know, "I'm in this time zone,
but I'm willing to work in up to
these," are-- you know,
different stuff like that. I
haven't
looked at the, like, the company
side of a lot of the job board
competitors—which I don't really
consider them
competitors. Because, like,
they- they have their niche.
They're
doing their thing, we're- we're
trying to solve a completely
different problem. So we'd
really just, like, all the tools
for everyone [laughs]. And
that's it.
Bekah: All right, excellent. I
mean, it is so hard
to search for a job as an entry
level or junior developer
because they don't make it
clear. Or you do have those
problems where they're like,
"Yes, we want an entry level
developer, but you have to know
all of these things," just
because
they want to get you to do work
for less money. And that's such
a problem. And we see people
over and over going into those
environments and just being, you
know, totally frustrated, and
it's affecting their health
because it's such a terrible
place to work. But then, it's so
hard to find another job. But
it's just-- I don't know. It's
just this- this huge problem.
Drew: Yeah. Ideally, we want to
build a network of
companies that we know without a
shadow of a doubt, like, just
support juniors, like, from the
ground up in every direction.
And that's- that's really what
we want for it is just, "Oh,
you're- you're a new candidate,
you're looking for a job. Okay.
Well, we know these 15 guys or,
you know, these 15 companies
are- are hiring, and we have a
good working relationship with
all of them. And we know
regardless of where you end up,
any of them are going to take
care of you."
Bekah: Yeah, that's so awesome.
And it's nice
to have connections with
communities where you can see
junior developers who need jobs,
and you know that you can vouch
for them too, right? Like,
there's a difference. You'll get
the-- I'll get those Twitter
messages like, "Hey, I saw you
asked about your friend wanting
a dotnet job. I want one too.
Can you recommend me next?"
Like, "No [laughs]. I don't know
you."
Drew: [Laughs] I actually just
had a-- I guess was kind of a
screening call last week with a
company that they just,
like, they hit me up on Twitter,
like, out of nowhere. And I
spent, like, the last 10 minutes
of that interview, like, talking
someone up from Virtual Coffee
because that referred them to
apply to the application. So,
like, the lady I was
interviewing
with, she's like, "Okay," she
was about to do, like, her
little goodbye speech. And I was
like, "Wait, before you go. Let
me tell you about this person."
And I was like, "They do this,
they do this, they have this
experience. Look at their
application. Forget about mine."
Dan: Nice.
Bekah: Okay, so another thing I
want to talk
about-- because you are just
doing, like, stacks on stacks of
things. Okay. So, you're
building a career, you're
building a
community slash movement. And
it's an-- also an open source
project, and you're streaming
some of this. So you're, like--
okay, let me make this even more
difficult [laughs]. So, I'm
going to add
the open source maintainer
thing, and I'm going to stream
it. So what was the idea behind
adding those components? And,
you know, I-- both I'm
interested in, like, how has
that been
challenging? But also, like, how
has that helped you as well?
Drew: Well, we decided to make
an open source because
we wanted a way-- well, one of
the questions we kept asking
ourselves early on was, like,
what can we do to let the
companies know that the
candidates they're considering
here are, you know, worth- worth
the hire. And one of the ways
we thought we can do that was
make it an open source project
to where those candidates can
actually contribute to the
platform itself, you know? We-
we display anyone's who's
contributed to the project is--
on our contributors page. And
the idea behind that was that
companies could-- ideally, in
our heads is that played out,
companies come here, they- they
want to post a job. And then,
they see it on the contributors
page that, "Oh, so there's
actually six applicants here
that have actively helped to
build the platform I'm listing
this job on," you know? Maybe-
maybe that'll help give them
some preference or something.
And even if it doesn't, then,
you know, we're doing our best
to- to help junior developers.
So even if it doesn't help in
that regard, it gives them the
opportunity to work on a real
world app that they can add to
their resume. I mean, even if
it's just, you know, I think
there's been some contributions
that were just accessibility
fixes. But, you know, that may
have just been, you know, from
code perspective, all they did
was changed the Tailwind class.
But,
you know, they also set up the
project locally, they also- they
also, you know, at least have an
understanding of Git and how
that whole process works. So
that was- that was a lot of the
reasons why we decided to do
that. I decided to stream it
because-- partly because I was
unemployed and bored, partly
because I wanted to force myself
into some accountability. So,
like, now, there's a lot of
people out there that know this
is a thing, so-- I don't want to
say they're depending on me, but
they know it's a thing. And if--
I'd feel really bad if I
started
building this thing that was
gonna help the community and
then just, like, let it go. So
now, I have all these people
that
know it's a thing, and they can
just say, "Hey, how's- how's
that
going?" And my response can
never be, "Oh, I turned it off."
So,
that-- that's- that's never
gonna be a thing.
Dan: I like that idea of the
streaming for- for
accountability, you know? I
mean, the side project issue,
you know, of abandoning in or
not, or whatever. And you're
right. You're-- you already
have-- you have an audience of--
you
know, you have people coming in,
but that-- the- the streaming, I
feel like is- is a interesting
bit to add, just for, like, the
accountability part of it, you
know? I think that's really
cool.
Drew: Yeah, and there's- there's
actually parts
of the application now that
wouldn't exist if it wouldn't
have been for- for streaming
because I'd hit a bug or get
hung up on something that I
probably would have never found.
But there have been-- there been
people in the chat that were,
you know, helping me debug some
stuff. And if you look on the
contributors page, the last
three entries on it, it actually
just says special commit. Those
are there because those are-
those are three people that were
consistently there for, I think
the first two months. I was
working on building a stream to
pretty much every day. So those
three people were there for
probably 85% of that streaming
process. And we're doing a lot
of, like, you know, coaching or
problem solving with me through
the
chat. So that's what-- that's
why we put them up there. Yeah.
And
we've had-- we haven't really
done much marketing for Protege.
I feel- I feel weird trying to
market a thing I built, but it's
kind of- kind of through
Twitter, and through streaming,
and through a couple of other
communities. We-- we've somehow
managed to-- we average around
400 users per month, which, you
know, in the- in the larger
scale of Google Analytics
probably isn't a whole lot. But
for- for something I started
building out of nowhere last
year with no marketing, I think
that's pretty good numbers. So
we're really-- we have a phase
two. We're kind of like ramping
up for now, which is part of
next-- the next migration as
part of that. So we want- we
want to
get those numbers up not because
we want, you know, good
analytic points or whatever the
business side of that is. But if
we can get that number up, then
that's more people that are--
that's just more people we're
helping or, you know, maybe it
at least giving hope that, you
know, someone's out there doing
something on- on the behalf of
them.
Dan: Absolutely. And, you know,
the bigger community gets,
like, around that or audience or
whatever, you know? The more--
it's sort of exponentially
increases the exposure without
even doing ads or, you know,
anything specific did grow
it, you know? Yeah. That's
really cool.
Bekah: All right, Drew,
thanks for being here with us.
We really enjoyed having you.
And congratulations on
everything that you've done with
Protege, and for your one year
anniversary, or birthday, or
whatever you want to call it
going up. So, where can our
listeners find you?
Drew: You can find me on Twitter
@drewclemcr8,
drew-clem-c-r-8 because, you
know, all the good handles are
taken.
You can find me-- I haven't been
streaming a lot lately because
of, you know, work and two kids.
But I'm on Twitch at
twitch.tv/ducky_87. I used to do
some gaming
streaming, like, four years ago,
and I just never changed the
handle. And now just kind of
like it. So-- and you can also
find me-- you can find me in the
Virtual Coffee sessions. Do you
ever want to pop in and join one
of those? Usually on Tuesdays. I
can't make-- I usually can't
make Thursdays.
Bekah: Yeah. And also there's
some open issues on Protege.
So, if you're interested in
contributing, it's a great
project. It's got a great
community behind it. And there's
lots of people there too,
willing to help and answer
questions. So, we're very glad
that you came here on this
podcast and that you've been
working on this project. So,
thanks, Drew.
Drew: Thank you.
Dan: Thanks, Drew.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO.
Or you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes.
Plus, you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening,
and we'll see you next week.