Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season one, episode
seven of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. In this
episode, we talked to Colleen
Schnettler. Colleen is a Ruby on
Rails consultant who recently
launched her first product
called Simple file upload. She's
also a career changer. And we
discussed the challenges of
being a woman in the workplace,
the benefits of working for
yourself, and how difficult it
can be to learn to code in the
first place. It can take time
and commitment, but when you get
there, it will all be worth it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random check
in question. Today's question
is, "what movie can you watch
over and over without ever
getting tired of?" We hope you
enjoy this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could watch any
movie over and over, it would
depend on my mood and the genre.
But The Sandlot and The Princess
Bride are solid choices.
Dan Ott: Oh, yeah. Princess
Bride. It's really good.
Sandlot, I've never been a huge
fan of which is like I know, I
know. I know. But it's just like
there's a mean dog. And I don't
know, it's just too much for me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: The dog's
not really mean. Spoiler alert.
Dan Ott: All right, well, maybe
I should watch it again.
Hi, I'm Dan, I do front end
development from Cleveland,
Ohio. My movie that I watch can
pretty much watch anytime is The
Matrix, I guess. And also, Thor
Ragnarok. More recently, but
I've that movie came out, what,
four years ago? I don't know
when it came out. Exactly. But I
think I've watched it like 20
times. So that's, I mean, it's,
I don't know, like watched every
second of it. But I like it.
Colleen Schnettler: I'm Colleen.
I'm a Rails developer. I am
right now on the East Coast, but
about to move to the west coast.
And a movie I could watch over
and over would be Moana. I mean,
it's just like the perfect
movie. The music is amazing. The
story is amazing. It's funny. I
know. I'm giving myself away as
like having to have watched it a
million times. But I never get
sick of it.
Dan Ott: It is the perfect
movie. My kids have gotten sick
of it. Because I'm and yeah, we
could have a whole podcast about
movies that I've unwillingly
watched a million times. That's
a whole separate separate
question. But Moana is awesome.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I feel like
I need to go back and watch
Moana again, cuz I think I fell
asleep or got bored.
Dan Ott: It's just so good. And
you know, happy and I don't
know, it's good. I like it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I like the
soundtrack. Okay, we can cut
that. I'm not gonna sing.
Anyway, thanks for being here.
Colleen, we are super happy to
have you on the podcast. And,
um, when we start off the
podcast, we just always like to
get the origin story of our
guests. So you have quite an
origin story. You're a career
changer as well. But let's just
kind of start there. How'd you
get into software engineering?
Colleen Schnettler: Sure. So my
background is actually in
electrical engineering. So very
hard work hardware focused. And
the first half of my career I
worked at the shipyard at a
shipyard in Newport News, where
we were working on some of the
electronic systems surrounding
naval aircraft carriers. And I
ended up leaving that job to
stay home with my children. And
then I stayed home with the kids
for three or four years. And it
was around that time when I was
staying home when I was getting
ready to go back to work, that I
really, really wanted flexible
and remote work. And it's so
hard to find that even with an
engineering background. My
previous work had been so hands
on that there was no
opportunity, especially in
defense contracting. There was
no one opportunity for me to do
that work remotely. And so I
started looking for other
opportunities. And I started
trying to teach myself to learn
to code.
I released an iOS app, which I
don't know that I've mentioned
before, maybe I have anyway in
like, 2012. And it was a
disaster and like, the thing
hardly worked. I mean, you have
to pay Apple $100 a month to be
in their developer program. So
yeah, it was, um, it didn't work
out the way I had hoped. I did
everything wrong. Like I did
everything wrong with this iOS
app. But what I realized what
was, there was a way I could
stay in my house and work and
get paid. And so the process
took many, many, many years to
get where I am today, but I just
kind of started chipping away at
learning web development,
because I saw that as an
opportunity for flexible remote
work.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, that
is awesome. And I think the
first CodeNewbie podcast I ever
listened to was your episode.
And it was so great, because I
was like, okay, like, Look,
look, she did this. And I don't
know, it gave me a lot of
confidence to keep moving
forward with my journey. So very
much appreciate you sharing your
story and being willing to talk
through that journey. Um,
Colleen Schnettler: That's
awesome. I'm glad you got
something out of it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I also like
to ask everybody, their history
with Virtual Coffee. So how did
you come to Virtual Coffee?
Colleen Schnettler: So I have
forever been looking for a
community, with, with people on
the internet, right? Like, I'm,
I'm not great in big groups. I
love people. And I love
interacting with people. But
like, if you put me in a Zoom
Room with like, 10 people or
more, I'm out, like I'm mentally
checked out. Like, I just can't
really wrap my brain around
that. And so I've actually
joined several groups. Internet
internet groups, are what you
call is... community is a better
word. I've joined several
communities. But the ones I've
joined, I've had two really
distinct problems. The first
problem is that it's just so
hard to foster authentic
connection on the internet with
large groups of people. It just
is like, if you don't get to
know someone, it's just I really
struggle with that. And the
second thing is I have joined
some paid communities. And
they're paid for like, because
I'm trying to, I'm starting a
business. So I've joined some of
those communities. And those are
more like highlight reels of
everyone's success. So it's
almost like people are just
like, dropping in to tell you
how awesome they are and to
promote their product. And, and
of course, we're all trying to
protect ourselves, right? I get
it, but it doesn't, that doesn't
do anything for me. I'm sure
you're doing great. That's
wonderful. But it's hard for me
to find, really until I found
you guys. You know, it was just
I didn't find a community where
people were honest. And I think
we have pandemic. We're all at
home. We got our kids running
around like, we need a space to
be honest.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. And I feel like I also
recruited you. I was like, Oh,
you're super cool.
Colleen Schnettler: You actually
did like it. I hate that I'm so
high maintenance that you had to
recruit me. Like, like, I saw
you on Twitter talking about it.
And I was like, I should do
that. But like, I was just so
overwhelmed by the current
demands on my time. Like, it was
just like, I cannot, I can't do
another I was like, I can't do
another slack group. I can't do
another fake community. No
offense. I didn't know at the
time, it was like, I can't do
another group of people that
don't really like, like,
connect, and you did you sent me
a message and asked me
specifically. So again, I'm
sorry, I'm such a pain that you
told me in. But after you did,
it's been really great. And I
really appreciate you reaching
out and inviting me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, no,
I'm very glad you're here,
obviously, because I reached out
and made sure that you came
because I wanted you here too.
So yeah, I'm glad that I did
that.
Dan Ott: That's, that's really
interesting. The point you were
making about there was the
private community where, you
know, the highlight reel thing,
you know, as you termed it,
right, the everybody's always
the motivation for sharing your
successes is I suppose fairly
clear, you know, but the you
know, I found I found similar
I've found that I've had similar
issues with community online
communities where I've just
never really connected you know,
as well. And the highlight reel
thing is aspect that I--I've
never liked, framed it that way.
Like the you want to be able to
share your wins you know, and
get high fives or whatever. But
but the fact that like you'd
like being very honest and
shared, being able to share, you
know, I don't know, I don't like
saying failures, you know, but
like, not wins, you know,
hardships and struggles, you
know, things like that is
something that sort of happened
naturally here. But it is, I
mean, it is one of the like,
things that we we very much
value and I think, really does,
you know, make Virtual Coffee
unique.
Colleen Schnettler: Well, I
think the thing that's, that's
important to remember is it's
because of the leadership team,
which is you guys, I mean,
Bekah'll drop in some like super
personal stuff. And I'm like,
Whoa, like your midweek check
in, it was like, a couple months
ago, you like drop this, like,
super personal midweek check.
And I was like, oh, like, this
is a real midweek check in like,
we're actually gonna be honest,
okay, I can do that. But I'm
just not. I think guys too, for
me, like, I've been a woman in
engineering for like, 20 years
now, minus the four years I was
home. And so I am super super,
because the way I've been
treated in the past, like, just
honestly, I'm super protective
of myself and my abilities. And
I think that mostly I, because
of that, I always try to present
myself a very specific way,
because I feel so judged all the
time. And that's just a
culmination of 10 years working
in an office. And just having to
deal with that. And so I have
this really like, I don't have
to say chip on my shoulder, I'd
rather say defense mechanism.
But I have this like, really
serious shield in front of me.
So I'm not going to go into a
group. And these groups I'm in
are all men to mostly like the
paid community I'm in, there's
like, maybe five other women.
And so, you know, I really
always have those shields up,
because I feel like I'm just
judged differently. whether it's
true or not, I don't know. But
it's just my perception.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: No, I feel
that so much. And I think, for
me, this is a very new
experience sharing very open
things about myself. Because I
spent a lot of years like with
the shield up and doing exactly
what you're saying. And then at
one point, I just I couldn't
anymore because of what I had
gone through, like it was a
breaking point. And so I was
like, Well, you know, I went
from sharing nothing to like,
here, here is everything, like,
I will just hand you my heart
and do what you want with it.
And I'm gonna keep moving on.
But, you know, you said
something to about, like,
communities can be really
exhausting online as well,
right? Like it's one more thing
to do, right? And I think that
you find the good community when
you are like, "Okay, this isn't
these are, these are people who
support me as a person." And
they, they are interested in me
as a human being not as like a
possible consumer, or, you know,
as this this one thing that
separates you from your
humanity. And it's really hard
to find, but really great when
you do find it. And kind of like
you touched on some of the
things I wanted to get started
with too. It's like the, you're
doing a lot of things, right?
You are an independent
contractor, you're a podcaster,
you're building this, this tool,
you're a career changer. You're
a mom, like, first of all,
that's amazing. Second of all,
how do you stay motivated to do
all of these things?
Colleen Schnettler: Well I don't
know, honestly, I don't know if
I'm doing the right thing. Like
I wonder about it all the time,
a different community I'm in
which is has been great as a
group of consultants. And we
talked about this a lot, because
there's a lot of consultants who
have moved to full time
employment, because I'm sure you
guys have had this experience as
well, like you contract for
someone, and then they offer you
a job. And every time I'm like,
do I want to take it or not want
to take it like it just seems so
comfortable to have a regular
job? And then I'm like, oh, but
flexibility. And so I you know,
I do question these decisions. I
think about a year ago, I really
got focused on trying to figure
out what I wanted, like long
term. What do I want? Not what
do I want next year, but like
what do I want for the rest of
my life as a career. And when I
go back to wanting that flexible
remote work? The real reason I
started coding, flexible, remote
work, obviously, but I've always
wanted my own business, like
I've always wanted to be
completely independent. So the
starting a product is really
hard because it's slow and you
don't know what you're doing and
like, it's just a whole thing.
So I have one
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: you have a
podcast on it.
Colleen Schnettler: Literally
the reason we started the
podcast was so I would not quit
like but that's always been my
goal and I know why I want that
and once I was able to really
be, to find for myself, what my
goal was it made staying
motivated so much easier.
Because before my goal was kind
of nebulous, it was like, "Oh, I
just want to work flexibly and
remote." Okay. And then it was
like, "Oh, I just want to, you
know, make money." And something
Saron Yitbarek, the founder of
CodeNewbie, said to me once was,
what are you optimizing for? And
that's my favorite question.
Because like, long term, this is
our life. So what are you
optimizing for? So I know that
my goal is to get a product off
the ground, I know, the only way
to get a product off the ground
is to do all these things. I
mean, obviously be great. If my
product made enough money, I
didn't have to consult, but
that's like many years off. So
just trying to get through it.
Dan Ott: That that idea of
optimizing, thinking about
things and in that, in that
framework, is something that I
came across, I don't know a
while ago, but it helped me the
same way. I've been independent
for a long time. And there have
been times there have been times
where I've considered either
applying or taking jobs. And
it's the same thing, I'm not
optimized for making money. You
know, like, for instance, right,
that is not my main, I need to
make money, like, I need to
support my family, you know, I,
you know, help support my
family, and I need to pay bills,
and things like that, but but
the, the main thing I'm
optimizing for, is that making
money, right? Otherwise, there's
other decisions, you know, I
could have made right. And there
was there came a time in my, I
think, in my mid late 20s, or
something where I had one of
those, what am I doing with my
life? You know, what am I doing
with my career moments? And I
think that, that question helped
me a lot to help me become
comfortable with staying
independent, you know, keeping
the flexibility. I like, the
flexibility and the, you know,
both in in time and allow me to
follow my nose sort of service
strange phrase, but like, you
know, a lost track of what I was
saying, the, what are you
optimizing for is a great
question to ask yourself,
though, in pretty much any any
decision you're trying to make,
I think it's a great way to
think about it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And that's
where I'm going to be the rest
of the day trying to figure out
what I'm optimizing for. What am
I doing? Can we even do the rest
of the podcast now? The other
thing too, about being
independent is it allows you to
avoid some so many workplace
challenges, right? Like, I don't
know, I don't really like
playing politics in the office.
That's been a challenge for me
in past jobs. And it's been nice
to not have to deal with that
kind of stuff. So have you found
that as a perk?
Colleen Schnettler: Oh, yeah, I
have so much to say about this,
okay. I promise I won't bring
it, I will. I won't go too long.
But so when I was young, so I'm
at a college, you know, I'm the
only woman working at this
company. I learned quickly that
at at any big business, this was
a fortune 500 company. So a big
business, there are people who
get the good work, and people
who get the crappy work. And the
people who get the good work are
typically the people who are in
the in-crowd, right, there's all
there's all this, like the
in-crowd of the smart people,
and then the hanger-oners. So I
quickly learned, like, the way
to get into the in-crowd is to
be liked. And this ended up
serving me poorly for like, the
next 10 years. Because somehow
throughout my career, I learned,
okay, so my goal is to get in
the in-crowd, so I get the good
work. But there was a lot of
other weirdness that came with
that being the only woman on my
team. Just a lot of weird, you
know, uncomfortable things that
came with that. Trying to always
be nice. And trying to laugh at
like the microaggression. I
didn't even know those were
microaggressions I don't think
we had a word for it. 15 years
ago, yeah. But like, just so
much of that. And what I didn't
realize while I was going
through this, like playing work,
politics, trying to be like,
laughing at the joke that you
know, about some woman who got
promoted, cuz she was a woman.
Like, what I didn't realize is
that was slowly chipping away at
like my self worth. And I
didn't, I didn't even realize
that until until now. Like
looking back like 15 years
later, right? And so I really
think I hate office politics.
Like so I'm out. Like, I'm not
doing that anymore. If I went
back to a job, like, I would
never put up with that now.
Right? Like, I would never laugh
at those jokes. I would never,
like take not respond to some of
the ways I was treated. Now, you
know, when my late 30s, but in
my 20s I just didn't know. So
this combination of like office
politics and gender politics is
like oh, it was awful, and I
hope it gets better. But I think
it probably depends on where you
work. You know, in terms of how
that how that goes,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Oh, for
sure. Got so much to say about
that too. But that is, you know,
that's super frustrating, and
you're younger coming into this
industry as well. And I know
like, that was also an issue.
Being a young woman in an
industry, it can be really
challenging. I don't know how
many times I got comments that
were super inappropriate, you
wouldn't say to, man, in that
same situation, but I always had
to do with, you know, me being
young and me being a woman. And
that was just for a long time.
It was well, 'that's just the
way things are.' So you do kind
of laugh it off or whatever. But
now, yeah, there's, there's no
way that I stand for that now.
But also, I've been through
enough situations where I feel
like, you know, what, I don't
care. What happens if I respond
to this strongly? Because I'm
done. And it, it doesn't matter.
But certainly 10 years ago, I
was not nearly in this place.
Yeah.
Dan Ott: Yeah. That the the
question of, like, how to
respond with things like that.
What I was gonna say was the
advice, like, if you have advice
for somebody who is young, new
career and can't afford to maybe
burn bridges, not burnt bridges,
but can't afford to just quit
their job, right? Because
they're supporting their family
or their, you know, the only one
making money, you know, with
their family and stuff like
that, like, What? How do you,
how would you try to give your
past selves advice, I guess,
maybe in this in this situation?
Or how would you give somebody
who is coming out of college,
and joining the industry here,
or coming out of high school,
even, you know, as a young
woman, like entering this? And
if they have these? If they end
up having experiences like this,
you know, because I'm sure that
plenty of women still are I know
that plenty of women still are,
what would you tell? Like, what
would be your advice to to
somebody who's found themselves
in a situation like that, as a
young as a young developer? If
anything.
Colleen Schnettler: I don't
really know, honestly, which is
terrible. Like, you know, I just
feel like, my thoughts are, if I
could go back and talk to
myself, right? Like, you think
it's okay, like you think these
are small, but like these, these
micro aggressions, like they
compound, and they will impact
you long term so much more than
you can realize now at 22/23
years old. So, you know, you're
not going to get fired for
standing up to that person, it
could end. I mean, it could not,
it might not end great for you.
I ended up in one job with a
company I will won't name I
complained about my mentor,
mentor, who was treating me
poorly. And I got reassigned,
and he got promoted. Like it was
terrible. So, you know, when I
finally stood up for myself,
that's what happened. And so
that obviously left a terrible
taste in my mouth. But I would,
I would also say that like you
think it's okay to let them go,
don't don't let it go. Because
it's gonna compound and it's
gonna come back to bite you and
you're not gonna get fired.
Like, you might have something
like happen to me where you
might get reassigned. Look for a
new job, like, keep looking
like, don't give up. And just
just fight back because that bs
is exhausting. And it will just,
it will just eat it you over
time.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. I would. I totally agree
with that. And I think that, you
know, that look for a new job
thing is super important.
Because I know people that Well,
it wasn't that big of a deal, or
these other things about this
company are good, or it's hard
to find work. But like, the
minute that something like that
happens, and if you reported to
HR to a supervisor, and they
blow you off, then you know what
kind of company you're working
for. Right? It's not just one
thing. This is a company
culture. And so it is definitely
time to start looking for
something new. And I don't, I
think I have a couple of
thoughts too. But, um, one is
having somebody who is an ally
or a support person at your
company can be really useful.
So, you know, I was on this
committee and I every time I
spoke, I was interrupted by one
of the older men in the meeting.
It was frequently happening, and
I didn't even realize that it
was happening. And then somebody
else pointed out to me that,
"hey, he doesn't interrupt any
of the men when they speak, he
only interrupts you and the
other women" and having the the
man who pointed this out to me
say something. Then it was
recognized, right, and it's a
shame it should not have to
happen that way. But definitely
having like allies who can stand
up for you and say, like, let's
not do this is really, really
important too. Yeah.
Dan Ott: So you have been--I'm
sorry, can you remind me how
long you've been--you've been
independent now for--
Colleen Schnettler: four years,
Dan Ott: four years now? Have
you run into any, like similar
issues? Since You've been
independent? or Yeah.
Colleen Schnettler: So that's
one thing I have to say, that is
awesome. Yeah, I have had no
problems working for myself. I
think it's a combination of a
few things. I think, you know,
the world and the conversation
is changing around this issue.
I'm in the rails community. And
I can't speak to the other
communities, but like the Ruby,
and the rails community is
spectacular, just the most
inclusive, welcoming community.
I mean, I will never forget, I
went to my first rails meetup
several years ago. And the guy
who was running the meetup is
like a super senior developer.
And I was coming off of my
previous experience. So that
story I told you about the guy
getting promoted and me getting
reassigned. That's when I quit
my job to stay home with my
kids. Cuz I was like, I'm done.
I can't do this anymore. So I'm
coming off of, you know, that
bad work experience, I was
coming off of being a stay at
home mom, I was really like,
just struggling. I didn't know
what I was doing. Self teaching
is hard. And I remember I met
him and he's like, super senior,
like, kind of well known in the
community. And like, he treated
me like an equal. And that
hadn't happened to me in so
long. And then people just kept
doing that to me. Like, they
just treated me like a human.
And it was this. It was it was
like, it was amazing. Like, it
was just so amazing. And that
community is amazing. And I
think also being independent.
Like, I don't have to work on
your team if I don't like you.
So that's been really great. So
yeah.
Dan Ott: Yeah, just another
another bonus for being
independent. Right?
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, you
have so much freedom. You can
pick your clients, you can pick
your teams. I mean, I've worked
on some spectacular teams. And
it's because I have a lot of
choice. I can hire people or I
can work with my friends who are
hiring people like it's a win
win.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, so
you mentioned Saron earlier, and
I had a tweet from her pulled
up, because she said something.
She tweeted this recently on
February 1, but she said, "I was
reflecting on my experience," I
shouldn't even read this aloud
because she's got such a great
voice. And I hear it in my head,
and I'm gonna read it. Anyway.
I'm not gonna read them to
summarize. She was reflecting on
her experience in tech and
saying how positive it's been
right. And she knows that
there's toxicity and problems
out there. And then she
realized, I've spent most of my
career working for myself is
what she said. And I think it
does make a huge difference.
Because you, you don't have to
play those, those politics, you
have the ability to be flexible
and to change things. And I
don't know, I I have this
feeling when something is
unfair, or unjust. At this point
in my life, I like to just like
yell about it really loud until
like, somebody responds to me.
And I know people feel weird,
like, well, you shouldn't name
names or whatever, like, I have
the, I have the ability to name
names. And and I will, you know,
it's not. And I think that also,
you know, people who have that
ability and can do that. And
that's also really helpful for
everybody else trying to, you
know, make their way and falling
into these situations.
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So I think,
can we just jump back a little
bit to your career, so you've
worked into male dominated
industries. And that's got to be
a challenge. Like, did you think
about that at all, when you were
moving from engineering to tech,
like," Oh, well, I'm moving from
this industry, and maybe the
experience will be similar in
this other one."
Colleen Schnettler: So there is
no other job where you can make
the kind of money we can make, I
mean, think of what we do guys,
we have paid like a kind of
absurd amount of money to like
work six hours a day in our home
office. You know, like when you
hit this point, it is just like,
I cannot I remember trying to
build so I tried. I didn't ever
get a job. So I was self taught.
I applied for that flat iron
scholarship. like three years in
a row. I never got it. I still
love you, Bekah. Even though you
got my scholarship, it's fine.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Sorry.
Colleen Schnettler: I remember
when I was trying to get
started, it was just so hard.
And then I remember talking to
people and they were like, you
should get a job before you go
independent and they were
totally right. My advice would
be whether you're a bootcamp
student, or you are self taught
your number one goal should be
to get like a real a real job,
get a full time job, because
that's how you're going to get
the growth and the mentorship.
But I was never in a position to
do that, like, my husband's gone
all the time, I have three
little kids, like I have to be,
I have to be available. I didn't
have 40 hours a week to work. So
trying to like build, build this
business to where I am now,
like, was so hard. And if I look
back to like, five years ago,
like I literally cannot even
imagine myself in this position.
But despite it being a male
dominated field and like it, you
know, I like men just fine.
Like, I don't mean to like hate
on men, I've just had some
really bad experiences. I mean,
our job is amazing. Like we we
can work from home, we get paid
really well. We do things that
like, like impact the entire
world like not to sound cheesy,
but like the internet runs the
world. And we control the
internet. It's amazing. Oh, my
gosh, I showed it like so my
family is not at all excited
about web development. I don't
know why. But I showed I showed
them the other day, like one of
their one of their friends was
having a problem with his like,
e commerce site or something.
And like, I just pulled up a
console and change the CSS like
in the console so they could see
it live. And they were just
like, "Oh my gosh, this is
like!" You're welcome. Like,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I felt like
I made it once when my dad
called me and he was like, is
this the expected behavior of
this form? That is not that
should not be happening.
Validated.
Um, yeah. Okay. So you have this
really long process that you've
gone through? And it sounds like
you're you're, you're happy with
where you are. But, you know, is
it worth it for such a long
process to get there?
Colleen Schnettler: I just wish,
okay, so my thoughts on this, I
just was wish the messaging was
better on how to become a
software developer. I think that
I'm going through the same thing
now that I'm trying to start a
software business, like the
messaging is just bad on the
internet. And I feel like five
years ago, like it was the same
way when you're trying to learn
to code. So yes, the answer the
TLDR is yes, it's 100% worth it.
But it is a slog, like when you
are either working full time, or
whatever you're doing, like,
especially if you have kids at
home, and of course, we're in a
pandemic. So that makes it all
the more complicated. It's just
a slog, I used to have this
process where while I was doing
the dishes, I would listen to
the code, newbie podcasts like
to get me pumped to go work all
night, right to try to learn
something. And I like I was
trying to learn something. And,
you know, I thought I was good
enough. And then I tried to do
open source, and I realized I
was not good enough. And you
know, what happened to me is I
just like there was this one
issue, I could not sorted out
and I probably just just like
sat on it for like six months,
like, I just stopped and like,
didn't you know, it's open
source? No one's asking me. And
this guy, like, who was one of
the maintainers just all he did
was send me like an email. And
he was like, hey, do you need
some help on this issue? And
that, that changed everything
for me, like one person reach, I
would not have made it like I
was I was out, like one person
reaching out, like, change the
trajectory of my whole life.
Like, it's so cool. So I'm
ranting a little bit, but I
guess my, what I'm trying to say
here is like it's a slog. So
don't believe there's so many
stories on the internet that are
like, I learned to code in six
months, and now I make $130,000
a year. No lies, it's like, no.
It's a slog. It takes a long
time. But when you are on the
other side, like it's amazing,
because we are we have I can
work from home, I can. Back when
there was a bus, I could take my
kids to the bus, like, I can
pick them up, like I can do all
those things. And, you know,
you're gonna make pretty good
money doing it. So absolutely
worth it. But be prepared for it
to take years.
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah, that's, I
mean, the the self taught path,
you know, that's always when I
say to you, it's really hard to
say I think out loud. It's nice
to hear you say that. It is
hard. It's hard, no matter what
path you're taking, and if
you're not doing it full time,
like you know, if you have kids
or another job you trying to
change. It does. It takes a long
time, but you'll get there And
then it's like, once you get to,
I don't know, as I imagined the
time is different. But there's,
I feel like one spot. When
you're becoming a web developer,
I guess, where everything else
becomes much easier. Like, it's
like, there's this thought
process, you have to, like,
change your brain to like, learn
how to code almost. And that's
like, hard. And I think it's, it
doesn't really matter what
language you pick, or what, you
know, if it's web are probably
the same for not web stuff. I
don't know, I can't even think
of c++. That was what I learned
c++ in college for a little bit
before I dropped out. But once
we learn how to become a
developer, you know, then maybe
I'm making this up. But I feel
like everything else becomes
easier. Like it becomes easier
to jump, like from different
languages, you know, the, oh,
yeah, if you're moving, you
know, if you're moving from
JavaScript to Ruby, you know,
that there's going to be like, a
bunch of differences, you'll be
confused for a little bit, but
like, it'll, it'll click a lot
faster, you know, you'll ask the
right questions you like, "Okay,
I know how to do this." And, you
know, I know how to do this. But
that approach doesn't seem to
work, you know, in Rails, so
here's, you know, okay, well, I
can Google for that. And
probably there'll be an answer,
you know, like, that kind of
thing. The The, the hard part,
the beginning is just like, I
know, re I don't know, resetting
all the, you know, the paths in
your brain, you know, I feel
like--
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, and I
think once we've come through
it, it's hard to remember how
hard it was. Yes. Like, now,
it's like, like you said, Dan,
like taking on a new language.
Yeah, it's kind of hard. And
it's like, I gotta learn all
this new stuff. But you mostly
get it, right. Like, you can
mostly make it work. But like, I
think it's, it's hard to
remember, like, it's really hard
when you start, like, with no
context, like, it's really hard.
Dan Ott: Yeah. Yeah. No, I
totally get it. I was. Sorry, I
was just gonna say that that was
something that, um, actually,
Virtual Coffee helped me
remember or realize, you know,
because it had been a long time
since I was there. But I do. I
mean, I, I remember struggling
and having no idea, you know,
what I was doing? But it is it's
hard. Like, the kind of
questions you ask are much
different. And when you're
starting out, versus one year,
whatever, a year or two under,
you know, under your, under your
belt. And hanging out with a lot
of people who are learning for
the first time is is
instructive, you know, and cool
to see.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
don't know if this if this
tracks, because I'm not really a
musician, but we see a lot of
musicians moving into tech. But
I know, I know, my brother plays
a lot of instruments, right. And
learning to play an instrument
can be really hard. But if you
get a good understanding of how
to play that instrument, and a
good concept of music, then it's
easier to pick up the next
instrument and to learn that one
too, right? Because there's this
idea of like, how you approach
it, and the pattern matching
that happens to and there is
going to be some overlap with
these different things. And in
your brain is kind of like,
Okay, I see that there's a
pattern here. It's not exactly
the same, but I can get there a
little bit quicker.
Dan Ott: I think that's a great
metaphor, or is it an analogy?
What is difference? Doesn't
matter? Oh, well, all right. Are
we in a metaphor right now? Or
are we in an analogy?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
we're in an analogy.
Dan Ott: Okay. Cool. So that's a
great analogy, Bekah. And I
think that kind of ties back or
in my head, it's, it's time just
what I was, what I was saying
was, was the thing that you're
teaching yourself is music,
your, your asset, like you have
to be teaching yourself piano or
x at the same time, but really,
you're teaching your brain how
to music, you know. And so,
moving from instrument to
instrument, you don't have to
relearn how music works, you
know, you have to learn, you
know, you have to learn some new
intricacies or whatever. Like,
I, I played a lot of
instruments, but I never really
played any string instruments,
because they're different, like,
you have to use two hands be
used in different ways, you
know? And, I mean, I'm sure,
probably could have, but you
know, I played like, every
single brass instrument, and
could just pick them up because
I don't know, it's like, it's
like all and when you're in
JavaScript, you know, like,
React, Vue, and all these things
are much more similar. But even
if I jumped to violin, I, my
brain still knows music, you
know, you know, so I don't know.
I like I'd very much like that
analogy. We're collecting a
series of like, really good,
developed like
programming-developer -journey
analogies. So because Marie had
the really good one about about
cooking, you know about being a
chef and recipes and stuff like
that. So I like it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, so
you're doing consulting. And so
you're primarily a Rails
developer, right? But then
you've decided to tackle React,
and you're building this
product, right? And so trying to
balance all these complicated
things much.
Colleen Schnettler: So, yes, so
first things first, I am
committing to taking, okay, I
didn't take this Sunday off, but
I am committing to taking
Sundays off. And I started doing
that a couple months ago. And
that has been really good for my
self. So basically, I'm trying
to, I'm trying to commit to
balancing these things in a way
where I can take the weekends
off. And it's funny. So I've
started like, this is so sad, I
have to do this guys. But on
Friday, I delete Twitter. Like I
just delete it from my phone,
it's like, because I can't have
it on my phone, I just can't
like it's terrible. But then,
and so I don't have slack on my
phone, I don't have Twitter on
my phone, which is really good.
So I think that's been really
good at helping me balance. It's
just like finding the time like
trying to really take a step
away on the weekends. But then I
come back on Monday, and
everyone's been hanging out all
weekend. And I'm like, "Oh, I
miss all these things." But for
me, like balancing these things,
so the consulting, I have one
kind of long term client, which
isn't too bad. It's like
maintenance. And that right now
I have a pretty intense project,
which is taking up all my time.
But it's nice, because I can do
it in short bursts. So I can
work really hard for three
months, have enough money for
six months. And then for the
next three months, focus on my
product, or at least that is my
master plan.
I started to learn react, and
then I just stopped because
like, I ain't got time for that.
So maybe in the future. I'll
sort that out. But uh, yeah, the
reason I started to try to learn
react because I'm building this
product, and I was getting a lot
of requests for a react
component. And then one of like,
my internet friends built a
react component because he
wanted it, which is awesome. But
I tell you what I shared, I know
how to maintain it. And now I'm
trying to make changes. And I'm
like, so yeah, that's a bridge,
I'm going to cross in the future
like that. That was just too
much like trying to learn that
and try to do the product and
trying to work and do the
podcast and all the things was
too much. So I'm tabling that
till I have some more time. I
mean, this is like a life like,
as we talked about earlier,
like, this is our life. So if
we're constantly in sprint mode,
like how are we going to
recover? And how are we going to
like, this is my life. Something
that occurred to me, like when I
was starting the product, and it
was really intense. It sounds
like like, what is my goal here?
Like, yes, I want to have a
product. But if I spent the next
10 years, like heads down on
this product every weekend, like
the reason I want to have a
successful product is because I
want to buy a house. Like it's
real simple. Like I want a house
with a backyard and I want my
kids to have their own bedrooms.
Like that's, you know, this.
That's why. And it occurred to
me, I was like, if I spent 10
years, like heads down on this
product and then sold it, even
if I sell it for $10 million, it
doesn't matter, because my kids
will almost be out of the house
by that point. And I'll have
missed what they really want
more than a house, which is to
hang out with me. So I know
that's like kind of cliche to
say, but it's true. Like it just
kind of hit me like, even if I
make $10 million. And it takes
me 10 years, it does not matter
because there'll be teenagers
and they won't wanna hang out
with me anymore. So hence the
I'm always taking weekends off.
I'm always gonna focus on my
priorities, and I'll fit in
everything else as I can fit it
Dan Ott: I think that's awesome.
I it's so hard to do, too. I in.
mean, I'm, it's really hard. I
was jealous, like of your I
don't know, it seems like that's
the right word. There, it seems
like you're doing it, you know,
like you're doing the weekends
off. And you know, everything.
And I know jealousy is a silly
word. Because I know that I
could just say, oh, I'll just
take weekends off. Right, you
know? Yeah, it's hard. It's hard
to it's hard to like let go. I
also started with the like the
like everything said, come back
on Mondays and everything.
Everybody was hanging out, doing
cool stuff. Also, like, it's
like, I got a bunch of stuff I
want to do you know? And it's
hard to tell myself not to. You
know, that's really awesome to
hear you talk about that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, it's
my husband was talking to me
this morning. And he was like,
"You can't just," I can't--I
don't know how I put it--but
"you can't just sprint all the
time." Right? Like you need a
rest. Everybody needs to rest.
But no, I don't, just keep
going. I can power through it.
Right. Eventually you get a
second wind but how many times
you get a second wind. I mean,
you don't, one, one you can only
have one second one.
Colleen Schnettler: And then you
collapse from exhaustion. That's
how that goes.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. It is
like, what the kids to you know,
it's there's just so much to try
and figure out and you want to
stay up on things, you want to
learn things and you want to do
work and you want to grow. And
then you want to hang out with
your kids. And it is just
really, really challenging to be
able to do that. And like you're
saying, You miss out on what
people are doing, or somebody
like I learned 17 languages
during the pandemic, what did
you learn?
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, what I
started doing react, I bought a
book and I know the author
really well. So that's cool. So
I literally have the author on
like, speed dial. And one of my
friends was like, Oh, I bought
this book. And I read it in a
weekend. And I was like, I don't
want to read a react book all
weekend. Like, I just don't.
Yeah,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I got that.
I can. Yeah. Maybe that's how
I'll start putting myself to
sleep. Sorry, I just coding
books are not my, my thing.
Dan Ott: I stopped buying them a
while ago, I have like--Oh,
yeah, you can see some of them
behind me. But I have like, 12
books and I, I can never get
through them. You know, it's
like my free time. If I'm
actually having free time. I
don't want to be doing anything
related to my computer anymore,
or development or, you know,
it's like, there are all this
stuff, books and podcasts and
everything that I want to
consume, because I want to know
them and, you know, know, the
material and all this stuff. But
it's just so hard. It's there's
not enough hours, really in the
day, you know?
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, well,
I think we're socialized to want
to work all the time. So we
should figure out a way to
socialize like, like gold star
every Sunday, you don't work.
And then you can like move it to
Sunday and Saturday, double gold
stars. Like, we need to find a
way to incentivize ourselves.
Not to work all the time,
because there's so much pressure
to work all the time.
Dan Ott: That's, I like that
idea that gold stars in your,
yeah, the the like, incentives
are your health, but it like
it's like a long term thing.
Right? So you're never gonna
know until the incentives until
until much later. Yeah.
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, you're
totally right. Like, it's, you
really won't know until it's too
late, right? Because then you'll
just get a pass out from
exhaustion or whatever. However,
everyone deals with a different
way. Right. But I'm sure we've
all done that, where we work way
too much. And then, you know, we
have to deal with the
ramifications of that.
Dan Ott: Yes. Yes, that sounds
familiar. vaguely.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I want to
jump back just for a second. So
you know, we talked about like
the benefits of working for
yourself and community support.
But also so I'm like, interested
in this question of what
qualities are important in the
people that you work with? So
you know, it might be your
clients? Or if you can reimagine
yourself going back into the
workforce, like, What? What are
those things that make you want
to work with that person? Or
make it a safe space, a safe
environment for you?
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah, sure.
I've worked with a lot of people
doing that, because I do like a
combination of contracting and
consulting. So I'll drum jump on
and augment a team for six
months to a year, or I'll work
you know, in a smaller group. So
what I look for, in people I
work with, I really, like people
who are honest, obviously, who
are, I don't want to say, well,
like empathetic and
understanding, like my very
first contract job. And it was
like, really exciting to get
this because I was like, really
new. It was a team. They were VC
backed. So they had a lot of
money. It was a team of like, a
bunch of like 22 year old guys.
I mean, guys, this was like me
coming off of being a stay at
home mom, I'm what like 32. And
they're like, on Slack, and they
would type things like, like,
they would just type all these
acronyms I didn't even know. It
was hilarious. But okay, so
these guys and these guys did
work all the time, which was
negative. So things I look for
my point of bringing these
bringing this up is despite the
fact that like, they were kind
of young, and they were really
excited, and they had money,
they were also like, really,
okay, and kind of empathetic to
the fact that like my life
situation was really different
than theirs. And so when I
couldn't turn around a feature
superfast, or like when I wasn't
online on the weekends, like
they got it. And so that's
really important, like, like the
people you work with don't have
to be in the same life stage
you're in. But if they can at
least understand and not
penalize you for having to stop
work because you got to go pick
the kids up from daycare or
whatever it is. That's really
important.
I just like people who are
honest and You know, really open
to learning, I think no matter
where you are in your coding
journey, you can, there can be a
lot of give and take. I worked
with someone else who was like,
really militant, I don't know if
that's the right word about a
specific style of coding. And I,
if I were to work with that
person, again, I would push back
a little more on that even the
way, you know, when people
review prs, like, there's so
much you can tell, by the way
people review your prs. But um,
yeah, I mean, just people who
treat you equally and fairly
like part of the team, and there
doesn't have to be a team
hierarchy and our, you know,
give and take, like, you can
teach them something, and they
can teach you something.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah,
that's so great. I think, in one
of my previous jobs, I was there
for many, many years. And I
don't know that anyone ever told
me "Good job." And I don't think
I ever realized it until Dan and
I started working together. And
he said, "Good job." And I was
like, "Oh, nice!" right. Just
feels good to know, it's an it's
an acknowledgement. And it's
simple. Right? And, um,
Dan Ott: Yeah, I think I think
one of the things I tried to
look out for is yet the sort of
a two way communication, you
know, like, that's something I
value personally, it kind of
ties into everything you were
saying, but you know, being more
of an equal footing, even if it
even like, yes, there's a
client, you know, relationship,
you know, I'm doing work for a
person, you know, like, I don't
know, the clients always right,
or whatever, you know, but it's,
like--
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah I've
hired. Yeah, I've hired a
contractor who's a better
developer than I am. I hired him
to review my prs. And like, I
loved his style, because he
would pull out something. He'd
be like, Hey, this is really
cool how you did this, or I
really liked the way this is
structured, and then he would
bring in, but did you know about
this resource? Have you read
this article, like, and it was
just so cool, like, Yay.
Dan Ott: So I mean, that is
awesome. But also just the idea
that I'd be uncomfortable with
hiring somebody that you know,
is very much better than you or
whatever, like that situation,
like the fact that you did that
is, like just such a cool thing
to me, just as a business owner
and as like a developer and
somebody who you know, wants to
keep learning, but maybe this
is, um, mmm, maybe it's only
strange to me. I don't know.
That's strange, but like,
surprising, or that's not even
the right word. But the that
like, you did it on purpose,
right? Like that tactical thing.
You're like, I want to go hire
somebody to that is like much
better than me to help me and my
business. And that's also I just
think that's so cool.
Colleen Schnettler: Yeah,
honestly, it went so well. Now
I'm looking for like
opportunities to do it again.
I'm like, how can I hire him
again? How do we do this again?
Dan Ott: That's really cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, that
is super awesome. Okay, Colleen,
it's been really great having
you here. And so we really
appreciate you talking about
these things. And where can our
listeners find you?
Colleen Schnettler: I am on
Twitter. My handle is
@Leenyberger. You can also check
out my podcast, the software
social podcast available on
iTunes and wherever you get your
podcasts.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Like and
hit subscribe. I think actually
the first time I ever met you.
We were doing like co working
with the moms can code and your
handle was leenyberger and I'm
pretty sure I called you leeny so
Colleen Schnettler: --terrible
handle. Like, I had no idea that
like Twitter was a real thing
when I signed up. And now it's
like I'm stuck with it for life.
So
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: you can't
get away from it.
Dan Ott: I think it's great
handle by the way.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I'm sorry.
I called you Leeny
Colleen Schnettler: I don't even
remember. I do remember you were
like on the treadmill or
something while we were we were
co working.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Exercise
bike. Yeah,
Colleen Schnettler: I was pretty
impressed. like Oh, nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Trying to
try to get it all in.
Colleen, it's been great having
you here. And we're really
excited to see what comes next
and to listen to your podcast
episode. So we'll talk to you
soon. Bye.
Colleen Schnettler: Bye.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO. Or you can
email us at podcast at
hello@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes plus you can
sign up for our newsletter to
find out what Virtual Coffee has
been up to on our website at
Virtualcoffee.io
Dan Ott: please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.