Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season one, episode
eight of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Today,
we are joined by none other than
Kirk Shillingford, a software
developer from Dominica, who in
his words has been haphazardly
writing code for about seven
years. Kirk is also one of
Virtual Coffee's Community Ma
ntainers and a good friend to us
both. We talk about making mi
takes, empathy and developer te
ms and the importance of ha
ing a supportive community.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee - we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from
what we do and a random check in
question. Today's question is,
what is your favorite geometric
shape? And why? We hope you
enjoy this episode.
I'm Bekah, I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And my favorite geometric
shape is it's either a triangle
or a Pentagon, and probably
because they are single digit
odd numbers. And that makes me
feel happy inside.
Dan Ott: Hi, I'm Dan. I'm a
front end developer from
Cleveland. And my favorite
geometric shape. I don't know I
don't think I have one. I i've
been I like a hexagon. Because
it sounds cool. And octagon
because I my my favorite
transformer was Optimus Prime
when I was a kid. And I mean
still obviously. But I named my
hamster after him. But was
Didn't you know actually know
what his name was? So I call
them "octomus", you know? And
then we just call the hamster on
octo all the time. So right. Cuz
I am awesome.
Kirk Shillingford: Hi, my name
is Kirk. I'm a full stack
developer from the small island
of Dominica. And my favorite
geometric shape is the
dodecahedron. And obviously,
that needs no explanation.
Dan Ott: So that's a 20 sided
right.
Kirk Shillingford: It's the 12
sides, sir,
Dan Ott: well, what's the 20
sided one?
Kirk Shillingford: Oh, icosagon.
How could you confuse those two?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think you
two are making these things up.
Kirk Shillingford: If we want to
make this entire podcast about
geometry, I can totally do that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I like
math, but geometry is my least
favorite. So we're gonna pass.
Kirk Shillingford: You're
probably like one of those
people.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Spatial
spatial things are not they
don't work in my brain. Okay,
Kirk, we are super happy to have
you actually back on the podcast
because you co hosted one of our
episodes, the one with Marie
earlier in the season. So it is
good to have you here with us
today. And first, we'll start
off with your origin story. For
those who don't know. So tell us
a little bit about how you got
to where you are as a developer
and how you came to Virtual
Coffee.
Kirk Shillingford: I thought
this was a whiteboard interview.
That changes everything about
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: About
geometric shapes? That's why you
knew that, you were prepared.
Kirk Shillingford: People take
the strangest Google questions,
you know. Yeah. Okay, let's
let's talk about how this all
started. picture it. Dominica
2014-15. I was in fourth form.
You guys, you know, fourth form?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: No.
Kirk Shillingford: Okay.
sophomores, sophomore, junior
high school.
Dan Ott: Got it.
Kirk Shillingford: And back then
my school had there was
information technology and there
were contracts, information
technology, technical and
information technology in
general. These names are
relevant because they are not
they have absolutely nothing to
do with anything. The technical
was like all Microsoft, it was
like, Word, Excel access. That
whole thing, publisher, all that
stuff. And general was the one
that had like actual programs.
And I had no idea what that was
even about. So I'm like, okay, I
should do this one. That train
of thought would like, be the
next 10 years of my life. So
yeah, we got into it, and it was
purple pascall which for some
reason, the Caribbean
examinations Council was like,
this is a relevant language that
people should learn. And I heard
that they still use the real
basketball, like, you can still
submit projects into a
basketball, which is terrifying.
But yeah, so we were in this
class, and it was like, 10 of
us. And the teacher was like,
I've never done this before. So
you know, go for it. And that
was like the most, it was like
one of my most fun classes is
because like, we were just
learning and like, I think the
internet like we get like search
stuff. But obviously, it wasn't
like now. So you're just like
finding like weird stuff in
forums. And we were just like,
messing with the code. And like,
nothing, nothing was like clever
back then. So you could not
enter for loops and just like,
eat up all the ram on the
machine, and just crash
computer, which we thought was
hilarious. And then somebody
figured out how to get the code
to, like, produce sounds. So you
could like, do the Star Wars
Darth Vader theme, just using
like computer beeps. And that
was like, really fun. And I
remember my final project was
BMI calculator thing, like the
project didn't have to be
complicated. And, you know, I
don't stand by that code. Nor do
I stand by BMI. But it was like
my first time actually doing
that. And that was pretty cool.
And then I didn't touch code for
like, three or four years.
Because in my head like I would,
that was not my thing. My thing
was maths. So I take our math,
and that that became
engineering. And still, it was
very much like, there's no
concept like I liked it, but it
wasn't like, Okay, this is not,
there was no point where like,
this is a career until two years
into my environmental
engineering degree. I just was
at a conference, and I saw like
a bunch of people in T shirts,
whereas everyone, every other
person in this conference is
wearing a suit. And they're just
some company wearing like blue t
shirts. And I'm like, Okay,
let's find out what these folks
are about. And of course, they
were software consultancy, and
they're like, Hey, you want to
take our tests, and they gave me
like this logic test. This is
pretty neat. And then they put
me through way too many
interviews. And then I got an
internship with it. That was
kind of like my segue back into
programming. Like, oh, this is
pretty fun. And it was like,
helping me with, like,
traditional engineering stuff.
And then that just became like,
okay, just want to do more of
this and less of the other
stuff. And then that just
became, oh, I guess I do this
now. So now I am here at this
podcast.
Dan Ott: That's pretty crazy.
That's awesome. That it was
like, sort of a random happening
that you you know, you ran into
those people at that at that
conference, you know, do you
think you would have not like,
not found your way to or back
to, you know, developing, if
that hadn't happened?
Kirk Shillingford: Um, I'm
pretty sure. I mean, and it's a
weird thing now. Like, I still
don't feel like there's a
difference between the stuff
that I like, and the things that
I think that I'm actually good
at, like math, and I guess
programming or things that I
like to do, I don't necessarily
feel a particular aptitude for
them, like, ah, like, this is
what my brain is supposed to be
doing. But in a weird way, it's
been more things like writing
and just just like a different
style of a different style of
communication. But when I found
them, it was just like, an
interesting alternative. Because
I spent two years in this world
of these, like very, very
serious engineering people, you
know, like, they wear ties to
work, and they build like
structures and like, everything
is super critical. Like if you
don't do this, you will poison
the town's water supply, you
know. And then I meet these,
like, sort of strange people who
are like, Oh, yeah, we don't
like we do work. But like, all
the sort of like trappings and
structure that I associated
with, like professional
environments, which is
different. And I found that
really appealing, like, okay,
these people just like, they
just want me to do the work.
They don't have to, like, put
myself in this cookie cutter
sort of template to do it. And
yeah, so I don't know if I
hadn't meant that. I might still
be just a traditional engineer,
I guess. And to be fair, like, I
didn't changed my major, like,
once I met them, who's like,
okay, I realize like, oh,
software is more than just this
fun thing that I did in high
school. It's actually this
pretty useful and important
tool. And I'm not terrible at
doing it. So that was fun.
Dan Ott: That's really cool.
Kirk Shillingford: I think it
was cool. Also, they paid me way
too much money. Like as an
intern, they never had interns
before. So they just like gave
us like regular dev salaries.
And I'm like, Okay, this can
work too that was also quite
nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. Okay,
so I also want to talk a
little bit about how you came to
Virtual Coffee. And you've been
hugely involved in what we're
doing, and helping support the
community for a while. And we'll
get to that a little bit later
on. But just how did you
discover Virtual Coffee? And do
you remember the first time you
came
Kirk Shillingford: This is my
favorite story because I want to
make this clear. I knew Bekah
first, I knew Bekah before she
grew up. All right, way back,
was still underground. Okay, at
some point, I want to say, like
very, very early on, we you were
still in flat iron. He started
tweeting about coding. And I
have started following you.
Because I remember I was on this
like, very determined thing to
not follow people who had like
10s of 1000s of you know, like
these sort of like big tech
things like these people not
relevant to my life. And you
just posted a tweet saying like,
Hey, I'm trying this thing, and
I don't know if it's going to
work out. That's how I feel.
And, you know, then you do that
thing where like your Twitter
friends or someone like you see
them post and you just like,
hey, support, encouragement, and
kind of did that for a while.
And then I remember you started
posting about PC. And I was
like, that's during work time. I
can't do that. So I think I
missed maybe like the first
month or two. But eventually,
you know, just like, this sounds
like a lot of fun. Like work
stopping right now. So I think,
When was the first time it came,
I want to say it's May or June.
Okay. Yeah. And I definitely, I
came once and I didn't come
again for like a couple months,
but I joined the slack. And like
the slack was a big thing.
Because even like when I was
working, like I could still like
hang out in slack kind of see
what was going on. But I would
also see people like Ah, the
meeting was so great. And that's
that's kind of just how it
happened. Yes, I want to make it
absolutely fundamentally clear.
I knew Bekah first.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I want to
say it took me a long time to
realize who you were because
your Twitter picture was not a
picture of you. It was his it
wasn't green. Okay. It was
something so that it's always
funny to see people who their
Twitter picture either doesn't
look like them or something
totally different. And then it
takes me like a really long time
for that to click and like, Oh,
that's that person I've been
talking to for all of that time.
So that was also you I did not
recognize you because you are
not a Pokemon in fact.
Kirk Shillingford: Debatable.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That should
have been our question if you
could be a Pokemon which one
would you be and why?
Kirk: Oh, my answers. I just
gotta check my Twitter. But
yeah, I mean, I remember like,
we had the whole like, gay Kirk
kerfuffle. Like when this it all
just started right is like
online I've always used like the
same like TK shoe type handle.
Yeah. And then when I met you
guys, I'm like, Okay, well, this
I guess this is this is still
online. And then it just like,
in the nature of friendship, you
know, like you kept interacting
with like, more and more of my
life and it's like, Hey, why are
you TK here in Kirk here and
like, Are you blind to us? So
you know, eventually we just had
to
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
right, when Kirk finally
accepted us. He allowed us not
to call him TK which we had been
calling him and said we're all
friends now. And so now you can
call me Kirk but it took a while
for him to warm up to us.
Kirk Shillingford: Just like how
the French have like Jew and you
know said same.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I do not
speak French. The number of
times. French in front of me. I
don't understand it.
Kirk Shillingford: All people
from Ohio speak French. Is that
true? Dan?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Do you
speak French?
Dan Ott: No...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Pretty
French?
Dan Ott: No, I took three years
of German in high school. I
think I can count to 10 in
German stuff. But that's about
it.
Kirk Shillingford: Do a for loop
in German.
Dan Ott: That class was a mess.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay,
speaking of No, that's terrible
segue not gonna do it. Normally,
when we have people on the
podcast, we have some idea of
what we're going to talk about
with them. And I had lots of
different ideas about what we
should talk about with Kirk. But
I said, you know, what are you
interested in talking about and
Kirk said, making mistakes, and
I just thought, like, That's
such a fantastic topic. Um, but
I just want to get a little bit
of insight into one you answered
pretty quickly, I feel like and
to why was this a topic that
appealed to
Kirk Shillingford: the topic
appeal to me, because honestly,
when I think of my journey, and
tech, and I guess just my
professional life in general,
eat for better or worse, I see
is like a series of like
mistakes, good moments, but but
ultimately mistakes. And, you
know, there's been all these
conversations, you know, with
our members, especially like,
what is a junior engineer? What
is a senior engineer? You know,
what am I supposed to be? I'm
just, like, I'm here. I've been
writing code professionally. For
five years, if you count, like
for my internships, maybe like,
seven years. I don't feel
particularly like, I don't feel
particularly senior, I don't
feel particularly Junior. And I
have been, I don't really know
how to, like, quantify the
things that I've done, except
that, like, I know, like, the
lessons I've learned from like,
all the places that I went. And
I feel like every time I have
gotten better at being a
developer, it was like,
immediately following a mistake
or something wrong. And at the
time, you know, like, I felt
terrible, like, Oh, I'm not good
at this, this is the worst. And
now, I'm just like, well, it's
probably it would have been
worse, if like, everything had
gone like great and perfect, you
know. And then just like working
in anxiety, and like mental
health struggles, and like, the
path to where I am now feels. I
don't know, if you're just
looking at me now. You're like,
Okay, he's got it. Like, he's,
he's got this figured out, he
knows what he's doing. Like,
he's in a career. He's got it
all together. Like that was not
the case at all, you know, which
is another reason why the whole
like, I, my degree is completely
different than what I'm doing
now. And even the specific role
that I'm in right now, the type
of software I'm working, it
wasn't something that I planned
at all. It's just like how
things happen to go. So I felt
like it would be relevant for
people to talk about, you know,
not, not the Twitter experience
of I lost 100 websites in 100
days, and I made $100 million.
Let me tell you, like, No, you
know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: are you
calling out my Twitter account?
Kirk Shillingford: Have you
launched 100 websites?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All the
time, that's what I do every
week for fun.
Kirk Shillingford: You know,
and, and I mean, even Virtual
Coffee, like, I feel like the
big appeal of Virtual Coffee is
that like I get to interact with
developers being normal. You
know, as opposed to LinkedIn and
Twitter, like every other place,
like you're, like, we like to,
you're not really allowed to be
normal, right? Like, and even
when we choose to be vulnerable,
like, it's a very specific
choice. And you can do it in
very specific ways. But, you
know, if I go there to VC chat,
right, now, I can go to random
and be like, I just ate a bag of
Cheetos and bitched out for
like, two hours. And then it
sounds like, Yeah, man, I love
Cheetos, you know. And that's
like, a normal thing, because we
are normal people. I get very
frustrated with the
conversations around developers
sometimes because I feel that
we're always trying to other
ourselves. And if
unintentionally, ostracizes
parts of the community. You
know, people are always very
quick to identify other
developer brands like this
developer mind is like this. I'm
like, I don't we're not
different than other people,
right? Like we, we have a job we
do. And we're good at it because
we do it. You know, if I didn't
do any coding, I wouldn't be
good at coding. Like I don't get
to like there's no special part
of my brain. It's like, oh, C
sharp, just because I did
cheaper. Yes. So, yeah, sorry,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I was just
gonna say I really like that
idea of the vulnerability that
we see online is still a choice
of when people are vulnerable,
right. So that's a point where
somebody, there may have been 10
other points that they haven't
shared, right? And, and when you
have a close community like
Virtual Coffee, or you know,
whether it's in a Tuesday,
Thursday coffee, or it's in
Slack, this is a close group of
people. And so vulnerability is
definitely more natural for our
group of people, which also
allows us to grow, I think, in
ways that if we didn't have that
closeness, that intimacy, we
wouldn't be able to.
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah. There's
something about like, the stakes
of like interaction, and how
much energy it takes to have
interactions with people. And
maybe it's different for other
people, but I found like, most
social media interactions be
very high stakes, in terms of
step it up better be a good
thing. And even if no one else
cares, like, I'm sort of coming
in as a, but I don't, that's
fine. But you can't sort of do
that all the time. And it's good
to have spaces where you can
just, you know, be okay. And
trust other people to just like,
let you be okay, or not. Okay,
you know, yeah, totally.
Dan Ott: One of the Colleen, on
last episode was was talking
about a similar idea, you know,
she was part of other
communities, and, and Twitter
and stuff. And she found that
same thing where you, it's
harder to share any sort of
struggles or anything like that,
and in certain situations, but I
feel, I feel like in Virtual
Coffee, because partly, at least
this is my, is my thing, but
like, because people know, me,
or I know other people, you
know, I have to worry less about
being misinterpreted, or, you
know, I don't know judged or,
or, you know, things like that.
And with Twitter, it's like it's
going out into the world to who
knows, is ever gonna see it,
and, you know, so then I sweat
over every single word, you
know, in a tweet. And therefore,
well, for me a tweet, like once
every three months, or sometimes
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think my
kind of playing off that to the
community has made me feel like
I can be more vulnerable in
other spaces. Because there's
this group of people that I have
that I know, support me. And so
that's allowed me to be freer,
and what I say on Twitter or
whatever, so, you know, like,
Oh, I cried at one division last
week, and the week before that,
like, I don't know, just stuff
about frustrations and growing
pains and that kind of thing.
When you know that there's a
group of people behind you, it's
just easier to do in life in
general, I think.
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah. I
remember, one of the big things
for me, I think, was, well, at
the time, I think we call it the
ADD/ADHD channel. And then it
became like a neurodiverse
channel. Mental health as if it
was one of those things, it's
just still in a space, it's very
difficult to talk about in
general, but also in like,
professional settings, and no
one wants to admit it, or be
honest about it. But like, I
can't think about my coding
journey without thinking about,
there was a time for about nine
months where I just, I really
could not do anything. I was
just kind of like completely
immobilized by anxiety and all
this other stuff. And I just had
no idea if I would ever work
again. And in that time, this
was a little bit before BC, but
one of the things that did help
me like was online communities,
like I couldn't really go
anywhere. So like, finding nice
spaces online, like kind spaces
online was like my way of like,
solace and recovery. And I
remember there be days of like,
okay, you can't do anything else
today, but you can, like, be
nice to somebody. And, if you
see has like a lot of that
energy, you know, where it's
like, okay, you know, like, my
day has been going really
crappy, like work has not been
working out or family trip or
whatever it is, like I can, I
can go on like Virtual Coffee
and like, be nice to someone,
you know, like, support them. Or
I just, I feel like the
community is just like, doing
that constantly. Like we're all
just helping each other because
like, it makes us feel good. It
feels good to make other people
feel good. Yeah. And that like
that's like forever energy,
right? Like, you can do that
forever. And you know, we can
talk about how like it's almost
it's almost a little You also
have to be a little careful.
Otherwise, you will keep doing
that and not do like anything
else. Because like, it's very
validating. But I do think
that's like a very good thing.
So a lot of times you'll hear
people talk about even the
online space. Now the pandemic,
a lot of people have had to move
to these spaces like us at the
same. I miss real life like this
is all fake. And I'm like, it is
different. And obviously, I do
wish, like things were, how they
used to be. And we could travel
again, and we could have those
like real contacts. But there's,
I think it's fair to say like,
there's the online space is not
it's not real space, it's just a
different space. Right? Like
it's lost, like, physical
connections, but like all the
other connections are still
there. And I've met some of my
most important, most trusted,
most valued most loved people
online. So yeah, it's all real,
which is why you shouldn't be
mean on Twitter.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I want to
jump back a second to the idea
of mistakes. Because I think
that, like there's a couple of
different things. I think,
sometimes one people mistake,
mistake mistakes for failure.
But also, I think that there's
an idea that imperfect,
imperfect things are mistakes,
right. And I don't really think
that's true. But I think it took
me a little bit to get there.
And so I just want to talk a
little bit about your approach
to doing something that's
imperfect or putting something
imperfect out into the world.
Kirk Shillingford: How dare you
put me on the spot like this? Do
you think this is a podcast? No,
no, I'm, I have a complicated
relationship with stuff like
mistakes, because I even though
for a long time, I didn't admit
it. I do have a type of
personality who wants to do
something right the first time,
which means I will spend either
way too much time planning, or
way too much time like micro
tweaking. And you know, if I
definitely like, have a my flaw,
I think it's definitely just
finish a thing. And then you can
come back later, is not my
natural like instinct. And it
was really funny. I'm gonna say
something very nerdy. Now, as if
the last 100 sentences haven't
been very nerdy. But there is
this role playing game called
Neverwinter Nights. It's like a
dungeon dragons game. And I love
this game. I've spent hours
playing this game. I've never
beat this game, not what's, what
I will do is I will spend like,
days thinking of the character,
I'm going to make, like, ah,
they're going to do this. And
then they're going to do this at
this level. And I will do all
that. And then like, I would not
actually do it. I didn't know
why for a long time. And through
just like introspection, and,
you know, talking of like,
therapists and stuff, if that's
okay, I definitely am terrified
of failure, especially like
catastrophic failure. And I
think like, Okay, I'm going to
do this. If you want to know
what's going to hate me, like,
it's all just kind of going to
go wrong. And then you just
don't want to do anything,
right. Because like, if I don't
do anything, then I can't mess
up anything. But that's like a
really, really difficult way to
live life. Like it's very safe,
but it's not very fulfilling,
ends up being very frustrating.
So I think when I when I think
of mistakes I've made, I don't
think of those moments where
I've done something wrong. I
like, I failed to do something,
even though I could be wrong.
Even though I could go wrong.
And kind of like that paralysis
is is a thing that that's my
personal thing, that thing that
sort of holds me back a lot. So
like I want to tell people like
all like when I say yeah, I've
been doing development for seven
years, a lot of that has been
not doing development or being
scared to do development being
scared to take certain
positions, because I was worried
that I just wouldn't be able to
handle it. Or I started
something and then like the
pressure of not doing like a
perfect job caused it to go
wrong in the first place. And
that's like a real thing I think
happens to a lot of people. So
yeah, just to say, it definitely
also happens to me.
Dan Ott: I love that it's like
and it's an interesting thing
that I don't know, there's
obvious When you're in the
middle of it, you know, if you
haven't, if you haven't framed
it that way to yourself, that
sort of, you know, hey, I'm sure
people, I mean, I know that I
have at least I'm just gonna
suffer from personal experience,
you know, have have run into
that, you know, avoiding jumping
into something or committing to
something because of because of
fear, you know, because of fear
of failure, or, for me, it's the
things that come along with
failure. So, so for me, it's not
so much being afraid to, you
know, afraid that I won't, like
won't change, trying to think of
a good example, I can't think of
one but like, not that I won't
be able to complete the task,
right, but that not completing
the task, or completing it in
some way. That is not, you know,
amazing and perfect, will cause
me, you know, embarrassment, or
let people down other things
like that, right, in the
complicated motions that can
come with that. And I just love
that you, Kirk that I mean, I've
learned from you like just
talking about this sort of thing
out loud, you know, I don't
know, it is, it's both, like,
sharing makes other people feel
more comfortable sharing, you
know, but also the way to frame
stuff stuff like this,
sometimes, people don't connect
the dots in their own life, you
know, until until they maybe
hear, hear what other people are
going through. And, you know,
something rings a bell, right?
Which has happened a lot to me
in Virtual Coffee, just, you
know, talking to people,
especially, you know, kirkin and
Bekah just kind of over and over
again, you know, so I don't
really have a point other than,
you know, thank you, Kirk for,
for like sharing all that stuff.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I always
like to say, Kirk is the heart
of Virtual Coffee, right? He
allows us the safe space to be
vulnerable, when you need
somebody to talk to even if you
think I don't want anybody to
hear what I'm feeling or these
words to come out of my mouth.
Like, I always know that, okay,
I can talk to Kirk about this.
And there's something about
that, you know, you just you
just have this. give off this,
this vibe word you allow people
to, to come to you in that way.
But also, because of the way
that you share that definitely
creates a space where I'm like,
Okay, well, he shared about
that. Now I can. And I think
that, you know, that's so
important to what we're talking
about, too. Like I know, for me,
I also have these fears that
have prevented me from doing
things. And, you know, one of
them was I was just not going to
apply for developer jobs. After
I graduated from Flatiron
School. I was like, I can't do
this. So I will just not do
anything. And my husband's a
developer too. And he was like,
nope, nobody ever feels ready.
So you just have to do it. Okay,
well, well, then I'll put out
this tweet or whatever. But you
know what I'm like finding now I
was terrified of that. And in
all the times that I've had to
apply for jobs, but now those
fears I can kind of like, are
tied to this feeling of maybe I
won't be dependable, right, I
get really stuck on this idea of
like, you have to be perfect to
be dependable. But just to be
able to hear people talk through
their own experiences and say
like, Oh, I didn't know what I
was doing at this point, to talk
to new devs now and say like,
okay, like, I felt this exact
fear, or I understand where
you're coming from. And here are
some things that you could think
of, but sometimes the most
important thing is just like
surrounding yourself with, you
know, good people, a community
of people like, like, you guys.
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah. I had
like, a bunch of thoughts in my
head, and he'll just like
condense on like, a very
enthusiastic, yes. Yeah, I think
it's, I think it's very, very
valuable to have spaces where
you can share without fearing
being judged. Right. And I mean,
like VCs, what, like, it doesn't
have that could be anywhere. And
when I think about, like, the
value of therapy or therapy is
this, you know, this person who,
you know, you say whatever to
them, and they're like, Okay,
cool. I'll see you next week.
Right? And you don't, you don't
have to kind of hold that. Or
even you know, before it was
like a village elder or your
priest or whoever. But it's
always that same thing, like you
will, you can talk and someone
will listen, but like, they're
not going to change the way they
behave towards you at the end,
which I think is just something
that's important for people in
general. When I had, like, my
moments, like very intense
trauma and anxiety and PTSD,
like the thing I remember the
most was like my, thankfully, I
had family who just said, okay,
you know, like they didn't, it
didn't make me feel bad for
feeling bad, you know. And I
didn't know if I was going to be
okay. They didn't know if I was
going to be okay. But they're
like, you know, like, we, we
love you regardless. So it's,
you know, if you can, I like the
idea of letting people know
that. Okay, whatever you say to
me right now, like, I'm not
like, it's not gonna change.
Like, I'm not going to change
things like because of that,
like, I've just, I just want to
listen. And that doesn't mean
like, we're in problem solving
mode, like for now, or just in
listening mode, because that was
what was done for me. And that
was really important for me, and
I don't think I would be here if
someone had done that for me. So
if I can do that, for other
people, that would be nice not
to say, want to be very clear
that I am, like, perfect at
these things I very much
nothing. And I, my, there's a
certain community who's also
known me for being like very
reserved, and maybe aloof. And
this pandemic has definitely not
been good for, like my type of
personality, who already wanted
to be inside a lot, really
inside. So I'm also thankful to
their friends who, like reach
out and be like, Hey, you know,
we should do something? Because
we should do something. Yeah,
it's just, I don't know, I feel,
I feel like I don't really have
any insights about software,
except functional programming.
Like we can talk about that all
the time, because I love that.
But I feel like everything. The
only difference between me as a
junior developer, as a senior
developer is that I have become
a lot more empathetic. And I
have realized, like, how fragile
sort of these things are these
like titles and dispositions,
and all these things we hype
ourselves up about, and what's
really important, our you know,
our relationships. And trying to
be good at those feels like a as
worthwhile and endeavor as
trying to be good at once,
what's the latest JavaScript
thing? We're into?
Something-dot-js...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, and I
want to say too, I think that
those moments where we allow
ourselves to talk through
things, or we're been vulnerable
with other people, that allows
us to grow in ways that we can't
otherwise, right, like, I am
very much. I don't know what the
word is right now, I process
things out loud, rather than
thinking them through my head,
right. And so I will go on
tangents that might not make
sense to many of the people who
are next to me, but it's just
because I'm thinking through
these things. And a lot of times
just having someone there that
can kind of figure out what's
going on in direct my thoughts
that are going all over the
place is enough to get me to
where I need to go to move
forward and to grow a little bit
more. And so for a lot of years,
I never did that I was just
very, very much internal. And
just over the last couple of
years, I've started to become
aware of how important it is to
make connections and how that
allows us to grow in different
ways. And I think that, you
know, no matter what you do, the
best version of yourself
includes connecting with other
people in real and meaningful
ways. And that will inform
everything else that you do in
life.
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah, I think
it reminds me of a conversation
we had Emerald at this
compensation. beckon you and I
were talking about how you like
the role of trauma in our lives.
Okay, this was a thing that
happened, that was like a bad
thing to happen. But sort of the
person that emerged from it is
probably the kind of person
maybe, then we might have
otherwise have been. And I think
that's, that's kind of something
I worry about, or try and pay
attention to sometimes. So, you
know, and I think the industry
is like moving in a better
direction. But sometimes I think
about like, when they asked you
Hey, well, there's this like,
eight month period where you
didn't work like what happened
then, you know, and I'm not sure
what answer you're supposed to
give, but I I'm pretty sure
you're not supposed to say well,
you know, like my depression got
really bad. And I just didn't do
anything trade, right? Like no
one of all the lip service
companies paid like, like no
actually really wants to hear
that. It's it's the Twitter
thing all over again. But that
is, I don't know, just that's
real people, right? Like, we do
not have this like happy go
lucky path of work to work to
work to cool things cool thing
to cool thing or you know, maybe
we shouldn't ask people like why
there's a big dip in there like
GitHub points things like maybe,
you know, maybe that doesn't
matter, right? Like maybe you
should be judging me on like,
what I've done not like, the
spaces between the things that
you think are relevant, you
know, I don't know. And, I mean,
the big thing for me was always,
I've always worked with small
companies, I work with a
research department at school.
And now I work for like a very,
very small software development
company. So you know, there's a
long time where I did not do any
programming. When I left work,
like I came to work to my job.
When I came home, I did not do
anything. I just didn't have any
motivation for it. Like, it just
didn't make me happy. And
Virtual Coffee happened at
Hacktoberfest happened and all
of a sudden, like, oh, okay, I'm
not just doing this by myself,
like, I'm doing this with other
people. And I get to show other
people things I've learned, and
they're showing me things that
they've learned, and everybody's
super appreciative. And
honestly, that was the first
time like, I'd done any side
projects and months.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Let's, um,
can we just pause for a second
and talk about hack tober Fest,
because I think like that was a
really pivotal moment for me,
especially and learning from
other people and growing. And
actually, in the trailer for the
podcast, there's a quote from
you about community and hack
tober fest. And so you did a ton
of work to make sure that the
community was supported through
documentation, and through your
presence and things like that.
And so you really played a major
role in that. Can you just like,
talk a little bit about your
process? And going through that,
because you played a lot of
different roles?
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah, I can
get on my soapbox for this,
because this is super important.
So like, I think the big thing
we learned from Hacktoberfest
was, we were all asking this
question of, well, why aren't
more newer developers getting
involved in open source? You
know, there seem to be all this
hype about open source. But when
you spoke to people they like,
actually, it still feels very
intimidating. I still don't know
what to do. Like, I don't think
I can do this. And I mean, I,
and there's a, there's a big
discussion there. But to me, the
short answer was, Oh, well, we
say that this is open, inviting
for new people, but it's
actually not. And it's like,
well, why it's like, well,
because like, not enough has
been done to make it welcoming,
right. And I'm not saying that
to chastise the people who
haven't done all the work, it's
just to say that like, it is
actually a lot of work, it is
like, you have to be intentional
about these things, if you
actually want people to work
with you, especially newer
people. And we realize, Oh, it's
actually very difficult if you
don't know what to do to like,
clone a repo or get a project
started or do a PR, and you are
super terrified that you're
gonna mess up someone else's
work, and you are completely
unsure that what you're doing is
a meaningful contribution. So
you have to come at it from so
many different angles. And then,
you know, I started writing all
that documentation, because
like, I kept finding, like, more
and more like, Okay, this
actually isn't very well
explained to my business and
will explain or there's docs for
this, but not that piece. But
there's like a full cycle of
what it takes to like make a
meaningful contribution. And
remember, we had like this big
discussion of, Okay, well, do we
find projects online and
redirect them to people or, and
we ultimately decided, like, it
has to be people from the
community, mainly because like,
it's the only way like, we can
be sure that the maintainers
have healthy interactions with
the people who want to help,
which is like the most critical
thing. And then that became a
Wait, what about the
maintainers? Like, they also
need to be supported to and that
be so you know, and I love that
that project was a lot of work,
but like, the big takeaway for
me was like, Okay, these things
are possible, but it is a lot of
work. And I think like the
danger is always that people
want to do a good job, but they
are unaware of the amount of
work it's going to take. And
then like they get burnt out and
then the people they're trying
to help get frustrated. And it
reminds me of one time I
attended this training, it was
some group and they like, Oh, we
want to get back, we want to
help out in the community, we
want to like bring tech.
communities and cultures don't
typically have access to it. And
they made this whole program and
they got a bunch of people. And
then on the day of it, I
remember, the presenter was
using a Mac, being all this
stuff set up and ready to go.
And then one lady was like, I
don't have a Mac, like, how do I
install this on Windows? And
he's like, Oh, I don't really
know, I didn't really think
about that. And I'm like, What
do you mean anything about that?
Like, I mean, I get it, but 90%
of the earth uses windows. And I
don't know about anybody else.
But like, when I abandon a
project, it's not like I'm
midway through the project. I'm
like, Oh, this isn't for me.
It's like, I couldn't install
this, you know, I couldn't get
this file to work. There's an
error. And I don't know what to
do. That's, that's why people
stop things, right? It's always
the config. So it's like, Okay,
well, if you're going to teach
anyone, anything, you need to
dedicate time to helping them
get the project set up. And you
have to anticipate at least like
the major base that people will
come up with, you have to meet
people where they are like, no
one's going to get a Mac use,
like, Oh, you can get this to
replicate like, No, no, sir. No
one's I don't know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
kind of tie some of these ideas
together. Like you said, it
takes a lot of time, right. And
sometimes you're just not aware
of the needs or the problems
that are gonna show up. And, you
know, that's part of the
learning process. And that's
part of the growing process and
thinking through things
deliberately is super important.
And is also very, very
challenging. We've got Dan, I
know that you set up the issue
for all of our contributors for
the Virtual Coffee pr for hack
tober Fest, and thinking through
all these things, is pretty
challenging, right?
Dan Ott: Yeah. Yeah. And it's, I
mean, Kirk what you said about,
you know, people started an open
source project, but didn't think
through all the writing of the
documentation you have to do,
and it is hard, it's, I mean,
it, I don't think you're gonna
find anybody that's, that will
argue with that. It's, it's a
hard thing with, with anything,
I mean, and it's a completely
different mindset than encoding.
And, and that's, I mean, just
just, like another reason why we
we wanted to, we decided to work
with just a few, you know,
maintainers, that we that we
knew, because we were going to
require them to put a bunch of
work in ahead of time to get
their, you know, repositories
ready. And yeah, so I mean, I
made that one of the
repositories was our Virtual
Coffee site, and I had an idea
to kick our event off with, you
know, just a very simple, like,
pull request thing to, you know,
without a lot of coding, but
that everybody could do, you
know, serve together an event,
and it seemed easy in my head,
you know, and there's just so
many things, you have to get
down on paper, to make sure that
everybody is sort of covered,
like he said, it's like the, the
windows thing, I mean, like, you
know, different operating
systems, it's, you just have to
do tests, almost like, I mean,
you know, automated tests for
like, browser tests, or
something, you know, like, in
front end, right. So I put out
some code and then, after work
on it for a while, I have to go
and check that it works in
Safari in works in Firefox and
Chrome, you know, it's it, but
when you're writing
documentation, that sort of
thing is harder to just like,
check, right? And so, you front
load a bunch of work, and then
hope that it's good enough, and
then hope that you're, you know,
contributors, let you know, when
it's not good enough, either
just by asking questions, or, or
submitting pull requests, you
know, with documentation fixes,
things like that. Which, I mean,
I mean, Kirk, I don't know how
many hours he spent in the
September, you know, preparing
for Hacktoberfest just writing
open source docs, both for us to
use as like templates, and, you
know, specific projects, and
also, you were maintainer for
your own project that was, you
know, heavily involved with
Hacktoberfest, but like, how
much how much time do you think
he spent in September writing
docs for? Like for
Hacktoberfest?
Kirk Shillingford: Way too much,
but that's the thing, right?
It's, it was definitely a lot of
work. But at the time, it didn't
feel like I didn't feel bad
doing the work, right? Because
it felt like okay, this is
meaningful. And this is going to
help people and was also helping
me because it's things I want to
learn about. And, I mean, one of
the things I do like about
Virtual Coffee is what you said,
like, the stuff we're doing for
the community. It's not
strangers, you know, so totally,
there's a little less pressure
to, like, get it absolutely
perfect the first time. And I
have a little more trust that
people will, like suggest things
to help. like to say, there's a
lot in my head, it's gone.
Right? Yep. It's like all this
stuff comes down to, whenever
you try and do something like
this, you are trying to empower
people, right? You're trying to
give people everything they need
to, to do the thing that they
want. But it's like, okay, you
have to think of the people that
you're serving. But you also
have to think of yourself, like,
it also has to be designed in a
way that you can keep empowering
them. Because otherwise, and not
pointing fingers, and pointing
fingers at all of us, you get
into this space where you're
doing this stuff, but it's also
like taking a toll on you like
it's just as a scribe it like
you should also be empowering
yourself. I remember another PC
member, the very, very wonderful
Nick Taylor. You know, we were
just like pairing up working on
something because Nick is
amazing. And he was like, hey,
do you want to, like, go live on
this? Like, I mean, yeah, sure.
And guess what, like he, he had
a setup already, that made it
very easy for him to like,
quickly get up and running.
Right, which took off the
pressure for me, because I
didn't have to do a bunch of
prep, that also took off the
pressure for him, because he
didn't have to, like spend a
bunch of cycles on setup. So it
became easy for him to help
people and like parent that way.
And I was like, okay, that,
that's neat. That's a good thing
to do. And, you know, Virtual
Coffee, like we've been trying
to get into that direction,
where it's like, it's easy when
someone wants to do something
that we can, like, help them in
a way that's also sustainable
for us. But again, like that
means you have to you do have to
Front Load a lot of trek to get
to that space. And it isn't a
bunch of things like we want to
do and the people like oh, yeah,
we, I mean, we want to do
everything. But whatever we do
in order to not be like other
experiences that have been
frustrating or disappointing. We
have we take the time to think
like, okay, either we can set
this up in a way that like,
people are empowered, and we're
empowered. Or we might have to
hold off on this until we can,
you know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah, and I
think that idea of things that
look easy, usually have a ton of
time put in that you don't know.
So if there's a developer and
you're watching them code, and
it looks so easy, right? It's
because they've done it before,
or, you know, it's trying to
explain to my six year old who
was watching a painting
tutorial, and he just couldn't
get it, like, the girl was
painting the turkey in the
video, right? Like, you know,
she didn't, this is not the
first time she's painted a
turkey, right, she's probably
practiced this a bunch of times
before, and then recorded this
video and maybe edited this
video, you know, but if
something goes smoothly, that's
because there's been a lot of
deliberate thought and effort
put in to make sure that that
happens. And so, you know,
everybody starts from a very
imperfect place. It's just the
practice and the time put in
that takes you to get to that
place where it looks easy, but
nothing, nothing is just easy,
right?
Kirk Shillingford: Bringing it
back to our theme of mistakes
when you are working with
someone, and, you know, you see
them like solve a problem that
you've been spending forever on.
It's not because they're a
genius. I mean, they might be
genius. But that's not why we
solve it like this, because
like, they solve that problem
before, right? Like, this has
already happened to them, or
something similar. And they're
working off of that mistake, or
that frustration that they had
back then to kind of avoid it
now. And like steer you away
from that path, right. Now, and
that's that's just like that to
me, like, oh, what's a senior
developer or someone who's I
think someone said, Maybe this
is from someone who's made a lot
of mistakes already. You know,
when you're new, you haven't
made that many mistakes yet. But
then this gets right back to
providing opportunities. You
need to provide opportunities
for people to make mistakes. I
don't think there's anyone who's
been in code for more than five
years at some point, like wasn't
given the chance to do something
that they were probably not
qualified to do or not exactly
ready to do like someone gave
you a chance and you kind of
have to pass that forward, you
know, otherwise you're being I
feel like a little disingenuous
about how this process works.
Dan Ott: Yeah. And you mentioned
and it actually, you were
talking about the senior
developer distinction. Like a
while, like, near the beginning
of your talk, but you mentioned
empathy, you know, as as, like,
one of the indicators, right,
but of a senior developer, and I
think that's, I think it's
really important to keep in
mind, the, one of the things
that I've learned over the last,
like, however long with Virtual
Coffee, specifically is, you
know, like, leaning on the
empathy to remember that
something is easy for me,
because I have done it a bunch
of times, and, you know, when
you practice anything,
eventually becomes second
nature. And then you kind of
forget, can forget what it was,
like, you know, to learn it in
the first place. I think that's
true with anything, really, but
it's especially true with
coding, because coding happens
so fast. And lots of times, you
know, people learn in all
different ways, you know, across
different ages and different,
you know, time spans, I learned
how to code over, I don't know,
five or 10 years, you know, here
and there, you know, it wasn't
like, I wasn't trying to do it
in six months, or whatever, you
know, because I was trying to
switch careers. I didn't even I
even think I said the word
career out loud. Until I was
like, 30, you know, like, but
just like circling back, I mean,
I, you're the, you're framing
around empathy as as a as a key
indicator of, you know, being as
a senior developer, I think is
very good. And been, very
important, and I appreciate you
like talking about it. With us.
Kirk Shillingford: Yeah. And I
think I think everyone here, at
least everyone that I know, in
the coding space is pretty much
in agreement, right? The 10 x
engineers thought the person
hate that phrase, but you know,
it's not the person who can
like, work 10 times faster than
other people. It's the person
who makes 10 other people around
them, like better at the job,
right? Like, what do you think
of that's, you know, and then
you realize that that role is a
supporting role, right, it's a
management role, it's a
mentoring role, you know, find
me that person, find me the
person where I can put them on a
team. And all of a sudden,
everybody else on the team is
like, feeling better, right,
that person is doing way more
for the organization than
someone who's, I don't know,
sitting at his desk or at their
desk, you know, just not
interacting with with others.
And I mean, but that's not even
something I talked too much
about anymore. Because at least
again, I don't think there's
anybody in the spaces that I'm
in, who still holds on to that
idea of being a good developer
means like, knowing lots of
things or being able to type
really, really fast or whatever.
And it's been really heartening
to see. Even the people in BC
who've been like job hunting,
looking for interviews, everyone
has a pretty much at a certain
point in everyone's career,
like, you hear the same phrases
being echoed, like I just want
to work with my people, you
know, I just want to do work
that's meaningful. I want to
have like a healthy balance of
like, my family life and my
professional responsibilities. I
want to give back and mentor
people who were in the space and
I want to, like receive support
from people who are more senior
in this space, like everyone
says the same thing, you know,
so I, that just, it feels like a
natural space to be and it feels
like the space that we're going,
and if I can contribute to that,
that is awesome. There was a
discussion, I think, yesterday,
the day before about passion on
Twitter. And that that was it
was really interesting seeing
everybody's responses, and some
people like hate, you know,
like, I'm here to I'm doing this
as a family, you know, or, I'm
doing this or something like I'm
doing this because I really like
it and like both, both of those
things are valid. No. I'm not so
concerned with your motivations
for being in the space as much
as your actions while you're
here, you know? And if you're
not being a jerk, and you know,
I feel like
if you are being a jerk, then
cool, like, we can't be friends.
Because you're gonna be a jerk
to my other friends.
Dan Ott: Okay, I like it. No,
yeah, no jerk friends.
Kirk Shillingford: No jerk
friends,
Dan Ott: I have to call some of
my old friends let them know I
can't be friends with them
anymore.
Kirk Shillingford: And I say I
I'm trying very hard to sort of
be clear in all this that I am
very much making lots mistakes.
And in a lot of ways, I am a
very big hypocrite about all
these things. There's very much
areas of code that like, I
really want to be good at, like
I, part of my motivations, like,
I want to be good at this thing.
I would like to be knowledgeable
about this thing and smarter
about this thing. I want to be
like, you know, I don't know.
And that's just like a personal
goal. As you all know, and
anyone who's spoken to me for
more than five seconds is aware,
I'm a big fan of like, certain
styles of programming. And I try
really hard to be good at those
things. Last night, students
work on the newsletter. And then
I was just like, reading, like,
functional TypeScript stuff.
Because that's fun for me. And I
like that. But you know, even
that, I've read like the same
articles, like eight or 10
times, just trying to grok some
of these things. And like, it
still hasn't worked yet. You
know. And that's super
frustrating. And it makes me
very angry. And I feel like an
idiot. But when I said earlier
that, you know, I don't think I
really have an aptitude for
programming, someone who's like,
I just don't mind doing it.
Like, I just, I don't mind
writing code, like, I can do it.
And I don't mind being
frustrated about it. And I'll
keep coming back to it. And if
you do that for long enough, I
guess, you know, you get good at
programming, you know, but I
really want to dispel the notion
that people think like, Okay, I
need to, I need to get this. You
know, I don't think that's how
software works at all, like, you
try and do it. And then you keep
doing it. And then you start to
get things. But if you feel
like, Oh, this is just not
intuitive for me, I don't think
it's intuitive for anyone. And
for the people it is intuitive
for I don't care if not like a
nice person, I'm still not gonna
want to work with that, you
know, give me somebody who finds
this stuff is really hard, but
like they're earnest, and they
want to learn and they're a good
teammate over a mobile like, you
know?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. I mean, I think that is a
great way to sum up everything
that you've been talking about,
right? It's about growing
through our mistakes, and about
being kind to the people around
us. And that supportive
environment is what allows
everybody to grow. Right. So
it's community growth. And I
want to thank you for being here
with us today. Kirk, this was
such a fantastic interview, we
heard so many good thoughts
about programming and learning
and growing, and I'm very, very
excited to share this. where can
our listeners find you?
Kirk Shillingford: You can find
me at Virtual Coffee, you should
should come hang out with us at
Virtual Coffee. I'm also on
Twitter at @KirkCodes, where
sometimes I say smart things.
And most of the time I just make
memes. Where else? I guess those
are, those are sort of the main
spaces, I think VC, VC and
Twitter. Oh, I mean, I guess my
GitHub, in case show if you for
anyone listening, if you ever
want to talk about functional
programming, or dive into
languages like Elm or you just
want to hear some strange man
from the Caribbean talk too much
about it. We can we can totally
get into that. Yeah, thank you.
Thank you for for having me. I
will say in a very, very
fundamental way, becoming best
friends. Yeah. Best friends with
Bekah and Dan has been one of
the best parts of the last year
for me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I'm buying
BFF necklaces
Kirk Shillingford: If you can
get the full necklace bracelet,
you can do the whole thing.
Yeah. So you know, and I think
that's that's ultimately it,
right? Like, it's so much easier
to work with people that you
appreciate and appreciate you
back. And if we could do more of
that, then I think we have a
good chance of doing some cool
stuff.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All right.
Well, I'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
Thank you for listening to this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at Virtual Coffee io, or
you can email us at podcast at
Virtual coffee.io. You can find
the show notes plus you can sign
up for our newsletter to find
out what Virtual Coffee has been
up to On our website at Virtual
coffee.io
Dan Ott: please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.