Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season one, episode
nine of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. This is
the last episode of our first
season. So we thought instead of
having a guest, we just talk a
bit about our own journeys to
tech and share some thoughts and
experiences spending the last
year with Virtual Coffee.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random
check-in question. Today's
question is, if you could choose
any fictional person to be your
imaginary friend, who would it
be? And why? We hope you enjoyed
this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could choose any
fictional person to be my
imaginary friend, I've got
WandaVision on my mind, because
today is the series or season
finale. And so I'm going to go
with Wanda.
Dan Ott: Wanda. Hi, I'm Dan. I
am a front-end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio. If I could
choose any fictional person to
be my imaginary friend, I think
I would choose Chewbacca. He
seems he seems like really good
friend, you know, always got
your back, good copilot
whatever; can, you know beat
people up? Like if they are mean
to you and stuff like that.
That's useful, or at least
threaten to beat people up.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I've got a
dog that looks like Chewbacca.
And so I'll just send her to you.
Dan Ott: Excellent. This is the
dog that you know, and jumped on
the counter and eats all your
food.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, she
had a bag of chocolate chips
this morning. But she, she might
be able to defend you. When one
of my kids caught the microwave
on fire she barked a lot. And
that was good. So that's
helpful. Let's see, that's
useful. I'll just send her up
later.
Okay, so this week's episode is
a little bit different than
other week episodes. This is the
last episode of season one,
which just means we're going to
take a couple of weeks off, do
some recording and get ready for
season two. And today, we don't
have a guest, we're just going
to kind of talk about how we got
started doing this. So in other
episodes, we get the origin
stories of our guests, usually.
And so today, we're gonna start
with our origin stories. And so
Dan, why don't you go first.
Dan Ott: Okay, so how I got into
tech, I sort of grew up having
computers, you know, around the
house, and started doing web
stuff in high school. So this
was, like 99 ish. 2000 I think
the first couple of things I did
were flash sites actually. So I
had like, I was in a punk band,
you know, in high school, and we
did a little like site. And some
web stuff. The fire flash was
fun, because I don't know
there's a lot of drag and drop
stuff that you could do cool
things with. And, and then
through college, I was I went to
college, as a computer science
major switch to English, because
I had a hard time with some of
especially the math and also
higher level computer science in
college got real boring, because
I wasn't really doing any
programming anymore. It was like
more theoretical stuff. And also
like assembly language, which is
not very fun for me, and but on
the side, I was kind of
continuing to do more web random
web stuff. And at some points, I
don't know, at some point in
there when I was in college, did
a couple for pay sites or you
know projects for people and
that was kind of fun. And I
ended up dropping out of
college. Not really to pursue a
career or anything like that,
but I was struggling in college
for a lot. Different reasons and
when I got home, so I moved in,
you know, back home with my
parents, and there was a sort of
family friend that had was
starting a local newspaper. And
so the Lakewood observer, and I
started just working for him and
doing that, and went pretty
well--did not pay very much. And
I didn't really know that it
didn't pay very much. But also I
was, you know, 20, whatever, and
just living with my friends.
And, you know, it was it was it
was fun, and started working for
Sprokets,  around 2007, I
think--Sprokets is another
independent kind of group that I
don't know they do projects for
clients. And so I was doing
front end for them and have been
doing front end for them since
then. And I don't know, and
then, now we're here. So I don't
remember exactly when it was,
but some couple years ago, I
guess I thought we, I could use
some extra help with some
Sprokets work. And so right
around that time, I saw Bekah's
tweet--I wasn't even following
you on Twitter, somebody
else--and I keep meaning to go
and track down who it was--but
somebody you know, shared, your
looking for a job, you know
tweet, you know just graduated
from--I always want to say grid
iron.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Flatiron.
Dan Ott: You know, and so I just
I think DMed your reply on
Twitter, and and so you were my
first like, contractor,
subcontractor or whatever. So we
start working together and then
and yeah. Yeah, and then right,
so and then we got to when the
pandemic started, and all of my
work dried up, which meant, of
course, all of Bekah's work
dried up. And so we had to sort
of stop working together for a
little bit. Which it turned out,
worked out pretty well, because
I think that's when Bekah
started. Virtual Coffee. Yeah,
and so I obviously, we were
still friends. And you know, you
were doing the Virtual Coffee
thing. And so I, I don't know, I
think I came to the third or
fourth one that you did
something like that. And so
that's how I found out about
Virtual Coffee, as well. And
yeah, so yeah, so that's my,
like, sort of long winded tech
and Virtual Coffee origin story
on on one story.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All mixed
together. Yeah, so my first
experience with coding,
actually, so I have an English
degree. And my first job--I
wanted to be a lawyer for my
entire life. And then I decided
in my last semester of undergrad
that I didn't want to be a
lawyer anymore. And so then I
was just kind of left like, "oh,
what am I supposed to do?" And
so, I ended up, I taught adult
education for almost a year. And
then I got a job as a community
organizer. And I planned to go
to grad school for English. But
while I was a community
organizer, one of my first
tasks, my boss was like, "Okay,
I need you to go home and learn
HTML and CSS this weekend." And
I was like, Okay. So, my, I
don't know if he was my
boyfriend, or my fiance at the
time, Jesse, who is now my
husband. And he had taken a
bunch of CS courses. And I knew
he had some books. I was like,
"Can you teach me HTML and CSS?"
And literally, we just like,
opened a textbook. And we're
looking through the textbook
over the weekend, and I came in,
on Monday, I was like, "Okay, I
learned HTML, CSS." But I just
basically had to know how to use
Dreamweaver. And so you don't
need to know that to make the
site and I was just doing mostly
content updates, but
occasionally, there would be
like some weird thing that would
happen, and the template would
mess up. And then you would have
to go in and look at the HTML
and CSS. So, um, I did not
really like it. And I did not
want that to be part of my job.
But it was, um, and then I went
to grad school for English. And
I taught for eight years. And
then I went through a trauma
with my fourth kid, and it just
kind of like flipped my world
upside down. And so I was going
through all these mental health
things, and I had PTSD and I
didn't realize that I was just
like cycling these events over
and over in my head. And my
husband was like, "Hey, why
don't you learn to code?" And I
was like, "why would I learn to
do that? Because I can't even
think straight." Um, but I
finally just wanted him to shut
up so I started FreeCodeCamp.
The fun part of that was the
cycling thoughts stopped when I
was coding. So I don't know if
it was learning a new skill, or
if it was just my brain was
getting into hyperfocus in a way
that like shifted away from all
of those thoughts., but it just
became a huge form of therapy.
And I found a really supportive
community. I think, like, I had
signed up for Twitter, and I was
trying to be funny on Twitter.
And I'm like, not funny. So that
wasn't going so well, and so I
was like, okay, well, I guess
I'm just gonna tweet about what
I'm learning about. And then
people were like, "Hey, good
job." And I was like, "Oh, cool.
I've got I've got
cheerleaders--that's fun--or
hype, people." Um, and I know,
just like having somebody being
encouraging, kind of like, okay,
I can keep going with this. And
then I found a group of moms who
were coding. And that was really
important. And one of them had
talked to me about her
experience with postpartum
depression, and how learning to
code really got her through
that. And that resonated with
what I was going through. And so
I ended up going to Flatiron
School. And I did that for a
year, I think it took me a year
to do that. Um, it's a part
time, remote, I can't remember
what it's called. It's like work
as you go kind of thing, right.
So like, there, there's, you set
your own pace, basically. And so
that works the best for me,
because I had kids at home, I
had a one year old, three year
old, six, and eight at the time.
And, and so after I graduated, I
felt 0% ready to apply for jobs.
And my husband was like, Hey,
you should just put it out
there. And I did. And then Dan
messaged me, and I thought, this
is this is not going to work
out. I am not ready for this.
Um, but then we had a
conversation and I felt really
comfortable. Like, okay, you
know, maybe I can do this. And
maybe I can work my way through
these challenges. And it was, I
mean, the first six months were
really rough. And just a lot of
like, second guessing myself,
and not knowing when to ask
questions. And then I feel like
we hit our stride, and then the
pandemic it. And then that was
really challenging. And that is
when I started Virtual Coffee,
because I started going to
interviews, and I never
interviewed before, because we
just basically had a
conversation. And the interviews
were horrendous. They were so
awful. And I just remember
thinking, like, you know, I need
to be able to talk to other
people. And so I just put it out
there on Twitter, and people
wanted to talk to, um, and so,
yeah, that's just kind of how
Virtual Coffee started. Because
I was having a hard time and I
needed friends.Yeah,
Dan Ott: yeah. Yeah, I mean, the
man, being able to talk to
people has been just so great.
It's been like the, I don't know
if it's like, I mean, this
probably isn't like news to a
lot of other people. But it was
sort of, to me, I, you know,
it's like, one of the things
that were, I didn't really
understand how much it was
affecting me not having it, you
know, being independent, my, my
whole career and even working,
like, working with Sprokets and
working with other groups at
almost all small, you know,
small organizations, and I'm
usually the only one doing the
work like, front end or
whatever, like, I'm only I'm
like working alone, even when
I'm working together. Right. And
having the, you know, having the
community I started, I like,
helped create the Cleveland
React meetup. Last, like,
summer or whatever that was 2019
I guess. And that was, you know,
really fun. It was the same
thing. I was just kind of, like,
just want to, like, I just want
to, like be able to talk to
people, you know. And, and, and,
yeah, and then Virtual Coffee
has been great, because it's, I
mean, Cleveland React is
awesome. But it's all you know,
just React stuff. Right? And so
Virtual Coffee is just a
collection of people in all
like, all different levels, all
different interests, you know,
we have, you know, people that
are front end people, we have
people that our back end people
you know, people are just like
learning for the first time, any
kind of code. You know, we have
people who have been doing for a
really long time, and you know,
I don't know, it's, it's great,
it's just so great to have a
collection of people like to
just talk, you know, talk to you
about things and share things,
you know?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, yeah,
and, you know, one of the, one
of the things that I like a lot
about Virtual Coffee is that how
willing everybody is to share.
So it's not just technical
things that they're talking
about, but we do have people
from all over. And so, like to
learn about DevOps, or to learn
about management, those are
things that I don't know that I
would really get to understand
anywhere else, but then also to
hear them talk about their
challenges, whether that's, you
know, in their personal life, or
at work those things, I am, I
think, helped me to really grow
a lot, because I'm looking at
this, this person, and a lot of
times what we see online,
especially, you know, as someone
who learned remotely, and has
always worked remotely, you
don't get a lot of to see a lot
of like, the frustrations or,
you know, all of the other
things that come with being
human because people put on
social media, like they're
curated personality or whatever.
And so to see, all of that is, I
know, has been really great to
understand that we're not just
what we see online, you know?
Dan Ott: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
I, you know, and that idea has,
even come up here on the podcast
with some of our other guests,
you know, that same thing. I
mean, I don't have much more to
add to it. But yeah, I mean,
like, that's it, right. I mean,
it's just like, the, we're not
just like, you know, putting our
best, whatever faces on, you
know. And it's, it's hard to do
sometimes, you know, it's, it's
hard to do, excuse me, some
people can do it really well,
even just on Twitter, you know,
to share this, like, like that.
I, I struggle with it, you know.
And so when I don't have
something like perfect and fancy
to show off, I usually just
like, just don't say anything on
Twitter. And it's hard. I don't
know, it's, I don't feel like I
always have to be like that, you
know, here, or Virtual Coffee,
etc. Especially, just the zoom
meetings, you know, I mean,
like, slack is great. It's like
so, you know, on Virtual Coffee,
we have this slack conversation,
that's pretty much always going
but the coffee's, you know,
twice a week are like, where we
really just get to, like, hang
out, you know, and talk. And
we're not like presenting,
nobody's presenting and nobody's
you know, doing anything like
that. And it's just people kind
of talking and following, like,
letting the conversations kind
of flow. And like, as if we were
actually just having coffee to
get there. And, it's nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I was
in Glenn's breakout room a
couple of weeks ago. And I loved
how he described it. He was
like, let's just pretend we're
sitting around a coffee table.
And we're all just like,
sharing, like, "We're friends
here." Right? And that's, you
know, initially, Virtual Coffee
was so much of that. It was just
like me coming into zoom and
saying like, Oh, I'm really sad
right now. And I just spent all
last night crying. That's like,
been my theme for the last year.
I cried today. Um,
Dan Ott: --yeah, but it's been a
rough year.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's been a
rough year. But also, like, it's
a group where we can, I can feel
comfortable, at least like
saying that stuff out loud.
Somebody messaged me last night
or this morning, and they were
like, thank you for talking
about crying, because I am
always afraid to cry in front of
people. And like, that
definitely was me too. And now
it's just think I had like three
meetings this week. And I just
cried in all three of them. Was
having a rough week, and like, I
don't want to spend emotional
energy trying to not be human
right now. So I'm, I'm very
appreciative of the supportive
environment that allows me to be
able to be human in those
moments.
Dan Ott: Yeah. I think that's
great. I think that's a great
way to frame it too. You know.
And it's really, I mean, we've,
we've, we've come to it sort of
organically, you know, over the
last year, but that like a lot
of people to just be people you
know, and not like developers or
job seekers or whatever else,
you know, x thing. And just like
a lot of us have similar, you
know, things we're dealing with
or whatever but the whole point
of Virtual Coffee is, is more
just like, you know, providing a
space right to be an actual
person, another 10x developer,
whatever.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: --or robot--
Dan Ott: or a robot in general.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, so
one of the things that I think
is really complicated about the
past year, right, with the
pandemic, and all of this stuff,
it's been such a hard time. And
there have been a lot of
struggles. But I always feel
like it's super weird when,
like, good things are happening
at the same time, right? Um, and
so like, out of this year,
Virtual Coffee started, and
we're about to hit on April 9,
that will be our one year
birthday. And March 23, I think
we'll hit our 100th Coffee chat.
And so we're hitting some big
things. And it's super exciting.
And it's always like, very weird
to frame that in, like, all of
the rest of the hard stuff
that's going on. And, but I
think it's been, I don't know, I
don't know what I would have
done without Virtual Coffee in
the last year and like, trying
to remember like, okay, there's
a lot of hard stuff that's still
going on. But like, it's, it's
okay to feel good about things
in the midst of the hard stuff.
Does that makes sense?
Dan Ott: Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah.
And I think that's really
important. I, I mean, you know,
I agree about Virtual Coffee.
And also, like, we, so, you
know, I have I have two kids, I
have a almost five year old,
right, and a two year old. And,
you know, that's been really
hard with the, with the
pandemic, the quarantine and all
that stuff. But also, I mean, we
have, like, spent a lot more
time I think together, you know,
than we would have, right,
because they were in daycare,
and then they weren't for a
couple of few months. And then
right, like, for instance, right
now, like, We're one of their
teachers, I think tested
positive. And so we had to
quarantine for a couple weeks.
And, you know, it's hard, like,
we have it stressful and hard
because of work and, you know,
trying to get everything done.
But also, I don't know, I'm
hanging out with the boys again,
you know, like, just during the
day, everyday instead of, you
know, after after school, and
then weekends, and, and there
are like pros to that too. You
know, so like, I tried like it
like trying to not get trying to
remember, like, all the good
things, or any good things, you
know, positive things that have
happened in during a hard time,
I think is is valuable and
important, you know, because it
can be it can be easy to get
really caught up, you know, in
the the bad, right of any, you
know, of any situation, really,
but I mean, this this, I mean,
it's a global pandemic, we're
all kind of going through it,
you know, some, I think it's, I
think that like, it's it's an
important thing to be able to
recognize positive things that
have come out of it, you know,
maybe Virtual Coffee wouldn't
have happened, had that not
happened? Or maybe it would
have--
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: --had you
not fired me Virtual Coffee
would not have happened.
Dan Ott: I wait, I did not fire
you. And this is you just need
to stop saying.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I only say
it just because it bothers you
every time.
It's like, my 11 year old will
just like stare at my six year
old in the car. And I freaked
out, right. So that's what I'm
doing? No, but um,
Dan Ott: so I'm the 6 year old
in this conversation. makes
sense.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Sorry, I
didn't mean it like that.
Dan Ott: No, no, that's fair.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Or my four
year old taunts my 11 year old
and he gets upset. So you can be
my 11 year old if you want.
Dan Ott: In our house, it's it's
very much always the two year
old who is bothering the five
year old, you know, who is like,
twice the size and you know,
really could just do anything,
you know, but he's just too, I
don't know, nice or whatever. Is
Samson just chasing around or
stealing his toys or whatever.
Anyway, sorry, I interrupted
you. You were you're heading off
in a different direction there.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: No, what I
was gonna say was, like one of
my favorite things, I think,
that's come out of Virtual
Coffee too has been the podcast.
I have wanted to start a podcast
for probably over a year. But I
was always afraid to do it. Or
like, I don't know how to do any
of that stuff. I'm not going to
be able to do it. And then I
think somebody asked in Slack, I
want to say it was Cameron--who
was in the mental health episode
a couple episodes back-- "So
when is Virtual Coffee starting
a podcast?" And I was like,
"we're doing it!" right? And
then, Dan, you're like, "Yeah,
let's do it." And so then, like
suddenly something that I had
been thinking about for a year
in my head, like all of, going
through all these things, then
we suddenly just did it. Right,
we have just jumped into it. Um,
but it's been, it's been a lot
of fun to be able to do this and
to like, look forward to talking
to members. And I mean, it was a
little bit rocky, I think, at
first when we were trying to
sort through everything that
needed to be done and how we
should--what the process should
be. But like, once we kind of
figured that out, it just, I
don't know, it just became like,
one of the the highlights of my
year.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I mean,
definitely, I agree, like the
being on a podcast is is, I
mean, I don't know, I don't know
if it's like some kind of thing
that I've always wanted to do,
or whatever. But I definitely,
it always sounded fun, you know.
And I like talking to my
friends. And, you know, I like
sharing things and, like audio
editing stuff. I mean, I did, I
did some of that just on a hobby
level. For a long time, too. You
know, in college, we made videos
or whatever. And so it was kind
of fun learning about some of
those tools. I found this MAC
app called Hindenburg and for
audio editing, like, I don't
think anybody's ever heard of,
except that it seems like it's
also really popular. So I, I'm
not sure. I'm not sure how I
found it or where it came from.
But I mean, or like, where I,
you know, how I ended up with
it. But it's a cool, it's a cool
app, and that it's like learning
about that it's like learning
about audio editing and learning
about podcast hosting and
learning about all this stuff is
just like, this whole block of,
like, experience that I know,
that I that I didn't have
before. And now I you know, not
that I I'm, I still consider
myself a hobbyist at any of it,
you know, obviously, but I don't
know, it's been fun. I mean,
from the technical side has been
fun. And then yeah, just being
able to, like, share what I
don't know, sure what our
members are want to talk about,
and be able to, like have these
smaller conversations, and you
know, share them out with the
world in this format has been
really fun to that idea of like,
we have an idea, and then we
just kind of decided to go with
it has been like one of I feel
like are hallmarks in Virtual
Coffee for you know, for better
and worse, usually better. But
like, it's been out and it's
been it's been fun. It's kind of
like how a lot of the, like, big
successful things that we've
done. I mean, I say big,
relatively big, big for us have
gone, you know. I, I wasn't in
the room, so to speak, when the
Hacktoberfest stuff like, like,
when that conversation started,
you know, but you guys like,
asked me to help out with
Hacktoberfest pretty soon. And
then we just kind of like, like,
yes, we're doing this, and we're
gonna make it awesome. You know?
And we've never looked back
really, you know, say with the
lightning talks, you know, that
was, you know, it was just like,
okay, we're doing lightning
talks the end of this month. And
we're like, "Alright, cool.
Let's do it." I don't know.
We'll figure it out. You know,
we'll do it live. It was
awesome. Like this lady talks in
November. We're amazing. I was
trying to make a list of I mean,
we could do this later, we had
one of our members asked just
for the podcast, like, Well,
some of our favorite things that
happened, you know, and those
lightning talks in in November
were really fun. You know, like,
it was great having the, the,
you know, our members, kind of
do all these like amazing little
talks. And I don't know, is fun.
And also, I learned how to do
livestreaming on YouTube. Which
is something I didn't know how
to do before. You know. It's
been fun. So, yeah, so I don't
know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: The whole
October. I mean, really, it
started, like late August. I
think with all these things. I
don't know, I want to say that
maybe we should do something for
Hacktoberfest, but not ever had
dreamt up what we ended up going
with, right. And so you had been
saying for a while, "okay, if
you if you need some help with
it," and at that point, we were
working together again, I think,
um, and so, I was like, "Okay,
well, you know, I'll see if if
Dan wants to help with this
too." And then we brought Kirk
on and Sara and Bryan, I think
had already talked about it. And
then suddenly, it just became
this really big thing with
mentors and supporting
maintainers. And having our
contributors and you know,
having a site--you totally redid
the site. So so we could have a
Hactoberfest first issue. Um, so
it was just I don't know, so
amazing, but also super
challenging because we were, you
know, kind of winging it. And in
the beginning, like, what are we
going to do, lots of
brainstorming. And then, I don't
know, you just got all of this
stuff up and going. And it was
challenging to, I feel like I
this is, like a point, in the
last year, that was super
pivotal for me to be able to
have conversations that were
harder for me to have. So I'm
generally like, Oh, this is a
hard conversation coming up. So
I'm just gonna, like, turn
around and just not talk to
people until it passes over, or
they just don't talk to me at
all anymore. Um, but it's much
harder to run from people when
it's on the internet. So having
these conversations that were
hard that I didn't want to be
having, and so it was just like,
forcing me out of my comfort
zone. And Hacktoberfest was
great. And afterwards, I was so
proud of everything that we did,
and all of our members. And
then, as we were, it took a lot
more time and effort than I had
thought. And then somebody
mentioned like, "Hey, didn't you
say we're gonna do lightning
talks in November?" It's like,
"Yes, I said that. And yes, we
will." No process nothing. I
kind of thought that I had some
people that were going to help
with that, that couldn't help.
And so then I was just, you
know, muscling through it. And
then Dan, I think you were like,
"hey, um, do you need some help
with this?" I'm not good at
asking for help. And so that,
you know, that's another thing.
My instinct, my gut reaction
would be to say, "No, I've got
this, I don't want to
inconvenience you." But I think
it came off of Hacktoberfest.
And that was a perfect time.
Because, you know, I was able
to, you know, work through some
of these communication issues,
like I knew that I could trust
you, and that it would be really
great to have your help. And so
then, rather than saying, like,
"No, I don't want to
inconvenience you," I was like,
"Yes, please." And so that was
like, two weeks. I think that
though, in the final two weeks,
there was a lot of stuff that
that we put together. But it was
an I was so exhausted after
that. And I just wanted to lay
down for a week. And then I
started seeing everybody who
spoke tweet about their
experience and how proud they
were. And then I was just like,
"this is amazing. When are we
going to do this again?" You
know, Kyle, Walsh calls it the
post conference high And I was
like, Yes, that is it 100% It's
so stressful. And you are like,
I never want to do this again.
And then it's done. You're like,
That was amazing.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that sounds about
right. Yeah, well, ask for help.
I mean, that's been that's been
sort of a big thing that we've
been working on that. I mean, I
feel like you've been getting
personally better at asking for
help, but we're, you know,
trying to find ways to, I don't
know, make make it so everybody
can do everything, right, and
come up with some processes to
make things less stressful. And
because up until recently, I
mean, Bekah has really even just
like doing everything, all of
the coordinating everything and
talking to everybody and you
know, and it's been amazing, you
know, but like we we want,
always wants to do more. Right?
And there's, like, limits to
what we can do. Right. And so
that's been one of the things
that like we've been struggling
with recently, I feel like is
that's where I wanted to start
struggling with how to how to,
like how to best do it right, at
how to set up processes for
people and, and, you know, how
to, like, empower our members to
to do things. Cuz, I mean, we
always like wanted, everybody do
whatever they want, you know, on
their own, obviously, but like
we've we've had some Virtual
Coffee stuff, we we want to be
able to give them tools, you
know, so they can like do things
you know, and like we can
support them and and provide
guidance and mentorship in
certain situations, things like
that. So that's been like, I
think, on top of our minds, you
know, recently well, that and
also our most recent lightning
talks, which also, you know, I
mean, this was part of that
practice, right? It was, we had
a really awesome team of, of
members helping coordinate and
mentor our lightning talk
session. This past, was it last
Friday? Yeah. Wow. Okay, so that
seemed like, three months ago,
but I guess it's. Um, but yeah,
I thought like it went really?
Well, I, you know, I don't know,
we're gonna talk to them, talk
to our team. And, you know, see
what, what went well, and what
didn't, you know, I think we
have something like that
scheduled next week, which I'm
looking forward to. But yeah,
like, how did you feel? I mean,
how did you think this was
different for you? You know,
compared to last time, when you
just did everything?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, so
this was, I mean, it was a great
experience, because I love
seeing everybody put in the time
and to support all of the people
who are speaking, right. And so
it's great to see the community
members, you know, really,
really having a chance to do a
lot of the things that that
we've been doing. And for me,
you know, I've never really been
in a position where I'm, like,
managing people, right. And this
felt a little bit like, so, you
know, I was the kid in school
that the teacher is like, you
have an assignment that's due in
six weeks, and I would go home
and do that assignment. And I
recognize that a lot of people
are not like that, right. And
so, um, there's like that
balance there. Right? Like,
let's give them the autonomy.
But at the same time, we are
trying to refine our process,
because before there was my
notes were like, not that great,
because I was just doing it. And
so now it was like, okay, so I
need to go back. And I need to
look at all these things, make
sure that they feel supported.
And there were definitely some
gaps that we missed in how
things should go. Or maybe there
was like a step that wasn't
clear, right. And that's part of
the process, it's going to get
better as we go along. And so,
for me, it was a lot of like,
trying to figure out, you know,
where I was needed, or how I
best could support people. And
then, you know, right before the
lightning talks, I had this, you
know, thing come up that I was
not expecting, and so I was
missing for the whole day before
lightning talks. I wasn't
available. And but I mean,
that's why you have a good team
and good structure. Right. Like,
you know, Dan, I know that I
messaged you, and you were
making sure that everybody felt
supported. And, and so I don't
know, I guess. So. This is my,
my long way of saying that, you
know, having good support is so
important. And making sure that
you you are allowing people the
opportunity to do things, but
also encouraging questions,
right? Because I think, you
know, especially as a newer
developer, that asking questions
can be really hard, because you
don't know if you should ask
questions, or, you know, if, if
you're asking the right
question, and in the same way
here, I think allowing people
the opportunity to ask
questions, that's what makes us
develop a better process,
because it's not about you know,
whether or not you know,
something, it's about us making
sure that it's clear for any
person that comes into the room,
that, that they can do this,
because it doesn't make sense
to, you know, depend on one or
two people to do all of the
things because if something
happens, and it doesn't go on,
like community is about
community, right. And so, I
think that, you know, I feel
very good about like being able
to refine this process. And so
we can do this again.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I've been, it's
been interesting. In there's,
there's a lot of similarities in
my mind to just software, open
source software, especially,
where, you know, one of the
things to figure out is, you
know, if you're going to have
like, when you're just
developing something for
yourself, it doesn't really
matter how, you know, like, you
can do it how you want and you
don't have to make every
decision, you know, clear and
you don't have to, you know,
write down specifically like how
you do things or how you want
things to be done, you know, but
as soon as like if you want
people to help you, right then
then then you need to start
writing some stuff down, right?
And so this is like any open
source project, if you want
contributors, then you know, you
need to decide, okay, like, what
do you want them contributing
to? And how, right and if, like,
you care what code style they
use, for instance, right, then
you need to either write it down
or automate it, right? I mean,
like, you know, and, or decide
that you don't care. You know,
like, it, code has a nice thing
where, like, especially if
you're using GitHub, right,
where you can do a pull request,
right, so you can, like, start
to, you know, start to figure
out where you need to improve
your docs or what you know,
like, you know, discuss things
and, you know, things like that.
You don't always get that with
not software. Right. And, and so
yeah, so it just takes more
communication, and more, talking
more writing, things like that.
Just a lot of work. But I think
the reward is going to be, you
know, worth any amount of, you
know, work we can put into it,
because it's just gonna make the
community you know, like, the
Virtual Coffee community is,
like, amazing, because of all of
the people like already doing
amazing things, you know? And
it's, I don't know, I feel like,
we're in this cool place right
now where it is, you know, we're
trying to, like, work a bunch of
things out, but everybody's,
like, excited, we have people
that are excited about helping
and I can, you know, I don't
know, you can, like see some,
some really cool things coming
down, coming down the line, you
know, and a little bit. So I'm
excited about the where, where
we're heading with Virtual
Coffee.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. I mean, if you would have
asked me a year ago, if we would
still be doing Virtual Coffee.
Number one, I would would have
said no, like, I think this is
gonna stop probably this summer,
right. But we're still doing
twice a week coffees, we have a
newsletter, we have a podcast,
we have a Twitter account, we've
done lightning talks, we've done
a million brown bags, like we
now have project boards for
things, you know, like, this is
so far outside of anything that
I could have dreamt up. And it's
just so great, you know.
Dan Ott: So I have a question
for you. If you like, we're, I
mean, I know, I sort of know the
answer to this. But like, if you
were like, okay, I want to
create a community that has
like, full of amazing people and
does, like is producing these,
like this content on their own
and everything like that, but
you're starting from scratch,
you know, a year ago? Like,
like, do you think it is even
possible to do what we're doing?
If you had this, like specific,
like a specific, you know, thing
in mind? Or, I'm not sure if
this isn't really a very good
question. Like, I'm not sure if
you can follow what I'm asking
or not. But when you started, it
wasn't like, I'm building a
community. Right? When you
started it, you just wanted some
people to talk to you, right?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Be sad
together.
Dan Ott: Let me sit together.
Alright, well, I'm glad you
didn't call it, you know, be sad
together club or something, but
might have been a different
community. But the the idea of I
don't know, I said, I was gonna
ask you a question that I just
keep kept talking. But I guess
what I was saying is like, the,
the, a lot of the stuff that's
happened has been happened, you
know, organically. And that,
like, organic creation versus
like, a very, like goal, or, you
know, driven like, goal
oriented, you know, creation is
it's kind of, you know, two
different ways of doing things.
And so I was, I guess I was just
like, when I thought, you know,
or if you've thought about that?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, well,
I think like, I've got two kinds
of answers. Like, first of all,
I'd never would have started
Virtual Coffee. I think in any
other circumstance, like, there
were so many like the first, I
don't know, probably six months.
I can't tell you how many times
I was like, I do not know why
people keep coming to Virtual
Coffee. Like, I don't think that
I'm a great person to be like,
talking to people or to be
organizing these things. Like I
there was just a lot of self
doubt. And like, what what am I
doing? There are certainly
people here that could be doing
this much better than I am and
maybe I should just be like,
"Hey, why don't you do this,
because I'm just not that great
at it." And so I think like, you
know, if somebody was like, hey,
I want to start a community, I
would have been like, No way I
don't have the skills for that
I'm definitely not good enough
to do that. And so I think like,
outside of happening
organically, it wouldn't have.
Um, but at the same time, I'm
also a planner, like, the last
year of just constantly growing
and pivoting and, um, has been a
challenge for me, but I mean, a
good one, right? Because like,
I'm growing with it, I'm, I'm
learning to let things go and
to, you know, apologize when I
need to, or not take a break,
because I need to learn that
one. But I, I like the idea of,
of having thoughtful processes
in place, that I can kind of
follow into this thing. And, you
know, one of the challenges too,
when I finally recognized at
Hacktoberfest, like okay, well,
we're a thing, and we're not
going anywhere. Um, maybe I
should start thinking about, you
know, what this should look
like. And so diving into, I did
like a deep dive into open
source stuff. And I really felt
like, okay, we are, we're, we're
kind of an open source
community, rather than, like an
open source project, open source
software, because we follow a
lot of the same. I don't know,
like guidelines or thought
processes, everybody is
contributing, we're giving our
time. And we're all growing in a
positive way because of it. And
then I was looking at other
communities, and I couldn't
really find any, like Virtual
Coffee, which was kind of like,
"Oh, no, I don't have a model
that I can look at." But also,
like, Hey, you know what, we're
doing something special here.
And there's a reason why people
are coming. And so trying to
embrace that is has been, I
don't know, like, really
important to me. But also, I
think that that's also one of
the reasons why I could have
never done it, because I would
want to have had more
guidelines. What am I supposed
to be doing right now. Um, but I
think like, we're on our way the
lightning talks was huge. I
mean, you put together like the
project board and broke down
issues and stuff. And that was
just like, okay, so to be
honest, anyone listening at
first, I was very resistant to
the project board.
Dan Ott: That's true
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I might
have gotten a little bit upset
about it and demanded, we stop
project boards.
Dan Ott: I just, I just I just
said he didn't have to look at.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: But it
turned out so good. We're able
to organize and support through
things. So like, if I, I think,
could go back and start with the
issues broken down and the
project boards there, then
that's like, right now where we
are, I would have taken that and
with that, um,
Dan Ott: yeah, I mean, that's
been a really interesting thing.
I mean, for one thing is an
experiment, you know, I don't,
we're gonna meet and see how
other people, you know, felt
about them. I have found, like,
when I'm, I don't know, on my
own, I don't do any of this
stuff, you know. But as soon as
I'm trying to work with other
people, I lose track of
everything instantly. Like, it's
just, I mean, that's how I mean,
that is just how my brain you
know, works or doesn't work. But
I, the project boards, any, any
sort of like, that board layout,
you know, is very helpful for me
to be able to visualize, like,
what's going on, you know, and
so I've been like, leaning on
them with, excuse me with
actually with your, you know,
like our work, like our, our
actual work work. And, and I
thought it could work pretty
well with some of this non code
related, but, but still task
related, you know, process like,
like the lightning talks, right.
So a lot of moving pieces, we
had, you know, a big team of
coordinators, and then also,
obviously, the speakers you
know, and a bunch of different
steps, you know, involved and
made a lot of help, and we had
people helping us figure things
out. So, I don't know so yeah,
so it was like a, I'm glad you
feel positive about them now.
You know, I like it really was a
lot of just me, you know, trying
to make it so I can understand
what was happening, you know, I
keep track of all everything
that was moving around. And I
will see how it goes. You know,
in the future I, you know, the I
like the board layout in general
for a lot of different things.
And people have used them for,
you know, I think we've talked
about using, like making some
roadmapy kind of things for
Virtual Coffee, like, you know,
some some wait some more ways
to, like, even just communicate
with the, with our members. With
like, aside from just specific
tasks and stuff like that, you
know. So they're just built into
GitHub, which we're, we're
already using some, say there
instead of Trello, or whatever.
external tool, you know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah. Yeah,
I will say, I think, you know,
the other thing, too, that's
been challenging, not having
thought through this community
is, we hit that point where,
probably in October, it wasn't
just like, I need to think about
what's happening right now in
Virtual Coffee, but it was
thinking about right now and
what's coming down the line for
Virtual Coffee. So you talked
about, like, you know, having
this this roadmap thing, and I
think it'd be awesome, if we can
get that up and out there.
Because there's, like, so much
thought that's going into, you
know, how do we support what we
have now, but how do we put
things in place to support where
we're probably going to go?
Dan Ott: Yeah. Yeah, I know, I
think it's gonna be good. Um,
before we wrap up, I thought
maybe we just like, can share a
couple of our favorite things
that that happened through the
year. I mean, we talked about
some of the big things. But
there's a lot of small moments
in there, you know, to over the
last over the last year, or
almost a year. I was, you know,
we were talking about the first
lightning talks. And, you know,
when I was thinking about the,
this, this question, one of my
favorite ones was actually
Karen's lightning talk from the,
you know, her first time out,
and it was just like, it, it was
sort of, I think, her first
public speaking. And it was, I
don't know, it was just a great
talk, it was great watching her,
I knew she'd been working really
hard on preparing and, you know,
this lightning talk stuff was
just like, so crazy, you know,
very fast pace. And, you know, I
was behind the scenes, kind of
doing the controller stuff, but
I was also trying to watch, you
know, most of them, and then I
don't know, Karen just started
talking about is like, kind of
stopped and just like, sat back
and watched. And she was talking
about imposter syndrome. And,
and, as related to tech, I
think, and shared a bunch of
her, like, a lot of her personal
career and story. And, like,
that is just, like, stuck with
me, you know, as one of the
things that I look back on a
lot, and you know, feel very
good, I feel very good about.
And it's like, it's the easy,
that is the thing that pops in
my head first when I think like,
when when someone's like, Okay,
well, you know, there's cool
things that happen in Virtual
Coffee. And then this is
probably a little recency bias.
But similarly, in our last
lightning talks, Glenn did a
talk about transitioning to
being a manager from being a
sort of regular developer, and
it was in a similar vein, a very
personal, you know, story. And,
and, and he, you know, there
weren't slides or anything,
Glenn just kind of shared with
us and talk through some, some
different, you know, things to
think about, and how they
affected him personally. And
then. And again, it was just
like, this moment of, sort of, I
don't know, calm and, you know,
like calm reflection and sharing
that I feel like those to stick
my brain because, like, we have
moments like this a lot in just
the coffee's to like all the
time every week or twice a week.
But you know, of people just
sort of taking a minute and just
talking, you know, and sharing
and not about whatever tech
thing is happening and not
necessarily about any sort of
specific advice or anything like
that, but more just, I don't
know, sharing experiences and
how they've, like reflected on
them and you know, have they've
sort of how their experiences
have shaped their, you know,
current situation and I always
just appreciate those moments.
When I'm when I get them, you
know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah, I
really love I do love quiet
moments are really really
impactful. I think for me, you
know, just hearing people
thanking each other or not even
one of my favorite moment
moments, I think was at the end
of the first monthly challenge
was in November. And I just
thought, okay, November is
NaNoWriMo, National Novel
Writing Month, okay, and so I
don't even know, it was a couple
days before then, like, we're
gonna run this monthly
challenge. And we're gonna ask
everybody to work together to
write 50,000 words, because the
challenge is, for one person to
write 50,000 words during the
month, like, maybe we can all do
this together. Um, and so,
people, we didn't hit 50,000
words, but like, being able to
hear what everybody was talking
about, and people saying that,
Oh, yeah, I haven't written,
like some people wrote their
first blog post, some people
hadn't written in a long time.
And the only reason they did was
for the challenge, and then also
just seeing everybody just
willingly to willing to support
each other and to share, and
then to be like, what's next
month's challenge? Like, okay,
this is, you know, a really
wonderful, small thing that we
did to create community and to
see everybody looking at each
other's blog posts and saying,
I'd love this thing that you
wrote there was really special.
And in the same way, I think,
you know, anytime somebody
comments on the podcast, or they
give their favorite quote from
the podcast, those are also a
lot of my favorite moments.
Because, you know, they're,
they're listening to what people
have to say, and they're like,
wow, this really stuck with me.
And I know, probably after every
episode we've done, there's been
one thing that every person,
every guest, we've had, has
said, that I have thought about
the rest of the week. And it's
been so great to, you know, have
that and to have that personal
connection. So, yeah, like all
of the I mean, there have been
so many great moments, but just
those those unexpected ones, I
think, are the ones that, that I
just kind of like, keep close to
my heart.
Dan Ott: Yeah. I I agree. I it's
just been kind of it's been. I
mean, it's been, it's gonna say
it's been a great year. It
hasn't. I mean, it hasn't it
hasn't, you know, but I don't
know. It's there's like you were
saying before, it's weird to
say, it's been a great year,
because it's really been at a
lot of awful things happen this
year. But this Virtual Coffee is
very clearly, you know, one of
the good things that has come
out of office.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure.
Dan Ott: All right. Well, we're
going to take a couple weeks
break. Well, a few weeks, I
guess. And I think we're going
to do four seasons. year, when
we were talking about this Bekah
asked if you could have four
seasons in a year. And I said,
Well, I think there are four
seasons. But
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I just
learned something new four
seasons in Ohio at least.
Dan Ott: Yeah, we have winter,
fake spring, second winter, fake
spring again, third winter, and
then spring for a couple of
weeks, and then it's 90 degrees.
That's really how it is in
Cleveland. But yeah, so we will
be back. Well, season two will
start first week of April and
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: right in
time for one year anniversary.
Whatever. One year, one year.
Dan Ott: It's an anniversary? I
don't know whatever. No, I
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: was. Yeah,
I'm having a hard time with that
Dan Ott: one year celebration.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: we've been
around for a year.
Dan Ott: In the meantime, if you
would like us to answer any
questions, or I don't know, send
us any thoughts or suggestions.
Feel free to email us at
podcast@Virtualcoffee.io I
believe we're on Twitter, and
other things. Are we?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, we
are on LinkedIn, Twitter, you
can hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeio. And that's
really a great place to ask
shorter questions. Or if you
want to say hi, you can come to
coffee on Tuesday or Thursday.
Dan Ott: Thanks again for
listening to the Virtual Coffee
podcast. This episode was
produced by Bekah Hawrot Weigel
and Dan Ott. Please remember to
subscribe and leave reviews
wherever you get your podcasts
and we will see you in April. Bye