Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome back to the Virtual
Coffee podcast. I'm Bekah, and
this is a podcast that features
members of the Virtual Coffee
community. Virtual Coffee is an
intimate group of developers at
all stages of their coding
journey. And they're here on
this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. Here with me today is
my co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Hey, Bekah, I am pretty
excited to be here for season
two; last season was really
great. We had how many episodes
we have eight 9...10, nine, nine
amazing episodes. And I know we
had some really great guests; I
thought we had a good rhythm.
And I'm pretty I'm pretty pumped
to be back for season two. We
have a very good lineup again,
for this next season.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And not
only is it Season Two of the
podcast, but also we're also
moving into the second year of
Virtual Coffee, which is pretty
sweet as well. Pretty cool. What
started as one tweet as suddenly
turned into a community of
developers and we have had two
sessions of lightning talks,
over 100 Virtual Coffees,
Hacktoberfest, brown bags,
bookclubs, this podcast, and a
lot more. So it's been pretty
great.
Dan Ott: newsletter
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: and a
newsletter.
Dan Ott: If you would like to
join the Virtual Coffee if
you're not a member already, the
way to join is to come to one of
our coffee events with so we
have coffees right now. We have
coffees, Tuesday mornings at
9am. Eastern and Thursday
afternoons at noon, Eastern. So
coming to one of our coffee
zooms is the way to join the
group. You can get links to
those if you go to our website,
Virtualcoffee.io. And I think go
to the events section something
like that, and come and come and
hang out.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: In this
season. We're talking about some
new topics and we'll be talking
about starting your journey,
making hard decisions, asking
for help and finding your voice,
so we're really excited to be
sharing these episodes with you.
Dan Ott: Kicking off season two
our first episode we have Gant
Laborde. Gant Laborde is an
owner of Infinite Red. He's a
mentor and adjunct professor, a
published author and
award-winning speaker. For 20
years he has been involved in
software development and
continues strong today. He is
recognized as a Google Developer
expert in web and machine
learning. But informally, he is
an open sorcerer, and aspires to
one day become a mad scientist.
I feel like he's I feel like
Gant's already there. Yeah, this
is from Gant's bio that he gave
us, but I feel like he doesn't
need to aspire anymore. I guess
for sure he's our local mad
scientist. He blogs, videos, and
maintains popular repositories
for the community. He also just
released his new book, Learning
Tensorflow.js: Powerful machine
learning in JavaScript. It's an
O'Reilly book. It's available
now. You can follow more of
Dan's adventures at
GantLaborde.com. And this
episode we're going to talk to
you about overcoming challenges,
being authentic, and finding
your voice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee. So we'll introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from what we do and a
random checking question. So
today's random checking question
is: the zombie apocalypse is
coming. Who are three people you
want on your team? We hope you
enjoyed this episode.
Hey, I'm BeKah, I am from a
small town in Ohio. I am a front
end developer. And if I could
bring three people with me in
the zombie apocalypse, I would
bring Marion Ravenwood from
Indiana Jones; I would bring the
dog from The Sandlot even though
that's not a person--oh maybe I
should bring Benny "the Jet"
Rodriguez who would be good. And
my six year old has decided to
be called Fireblade now and that
just sounds like it could be
cool for the zombie apocalypse.
I'll bring him.
Dan Ott: Hi, I'm Dan, a front
end developer from Lakewood,
Ohio. And if I had to choose
three people, I feel like I, I
really feel like we need to get
some powers going. You know, I
was trying to I was trying to
pick up I was a Dumbledor, but
like he's too much of a risk.
Can't run like he's too slow.
You know? Maybe maybe like later
on Harry probably, Hermione,
honestly, you know, we need her
magic you know; whoever's faster
of the two of them and then
probably; I don't know Hulk
maybe, predictable might might
ruin our defenses. And yeah, I
need I need a dog to I don't
know, I'd have to get him in my
whole power ranking of dogs too
so it's a whole big thing but
you know some some kind of
friendly companion and well
that's great, Yeah, that's it.
Gant: Hey, I'm Gant Laborde and
in the great zombie apocalypse,
I would I, I guess like I'm
supposed to say here my co hosts
like the people here on this
podcast, but I'm sorry, Y'all
dead. It would be my daughter
and my partner. So Alicia and
Mila, my dogs but they don't
count as people. And then I get
one more person who gets to go
with me. So I guess I'd take
Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson.
Because if I can't figure it
out, I know he can.
Dan Ott: I like it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. I
suddenly feel bad about not
taking my family.
Gant: You've got Fireblade so...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I do I've
got Fireblade, someone who's
gonna get us to where we need to
be. So welcome to the podcast,
Gant. We're really, really happy
to have you here. And I want to
start off with asking a
question: what is one non coding
thing our listeners might not
know about you?
Gant: So I always hate these
questions because they make me
realize just how boring I really
am. I'll say this. I feel like
public speaking is a cool thing.
But I do public speaking about
coding. I'd say like building
stuff, but most of the stuff I
build I code like IoT stuff. So
cool. I'll go with the fact that
I used to be terrible at
gardening. Before the pandemic,
I killed artificial plants.
That's how bad I was. And now
I've had the sandwich yesterday.
The lettuce was from the plant
right here next to my monitor
and the spuds were from the
sprouts. We're from my window
sale. And I'm working on some
jalapenos in the backyard to go
ahead and make my own pepper
jelly to mix in with that
sandwich. So truth be told, you
can teach an old dog new tricks.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. That
is amazing. I want some pepper
jelly now.
Gant: On a sandwich. It's good.
Actually, I don't know if you've
tried that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Oh, for
sure.
Gant: sprouts and lettuce
sandwich. That's good.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Sounds
delicious. I I'm ready for one
now. So you let me know and that
pepper jelly is done. Alright,
let's talk a little bit about
your origin story and how you
came to be Gant Laborde...
Gant: That's a little bit boring
as well. So like, everybody's
got these really cool stories
about how, you know oh, you
know, I was an accountant or a
teacher for 17 years and then
one day I decided forget this
I'm gonna do some kind of like
workshop or something. I'm a
changed my life for my career.
My family hated computers. My
family is like very anti
computer anti technology. To not
not on purpose. They're just for
some reason my dad kind of kept
it out of the house. And I had a
Nintendo and I wasn't allowed to
hook it up to any TV that was
worth anything because it would
cause ghosts as something he
heard. Whatever. Ghosts not not
like real ghosts. Back when you
had CRTs you could actually
cause like images to get burned
into the phosphorus. So it would
cause issues. So I loved that
thing. And then finally he had
to get a work computer that
shows up. And then I make that
computer say hello Gant. It was
windows 3.1 or do some qbasic
aren't making say hello Gant.
And I was like, Okay, this is
what I'm doing with my life. So
I self taught myself how to
program in high school. I went
to college for computer
programming, I graduated. I've
just been in this field for so
long, it wasn't like, there was
like this weird, cool hero's arc
to get there. It really was that
once my computer was able to
play games and do these cool
things, I said, I'm gonna do
that. And I'm gonna be the
person in my family who does
that. I guess they could
sprinkle it in here, I did have
a lot of like computer
programmers anxiety, lack of
support. And a few ways. Like,
you know, I didn't have anybody
to ask, I had the oldest
computer in high school, I
didn't have any money. So I
guess I've self made myself into
this profession. That's probably
as interesting as I get.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Well, I
mean, I think that's great.
Because you can make anything
interesting, you are a
storyteller. And you'll find a
way to make it interesting. And
I think that was great. Like,
kind of going off of that. So
you are basically a master of
all trades, right? Like you do
all of these things. You speak,
you write, you code, you mentor,
you're like my Yoda figure. So
when I have a problem, you just
ask the right questions, and
then I hopefully come to the
right answers. So what is your
favorite thing to do?
Gant: Um, I found that it really
depends on my state of mind, I
need to be creative, though, I
need to let creativity flow
through me. And sometimes that's
writing; writing is very
cathartic. If you, you know,
went through high school and
used to get B's in English, and
you kind of enjoyed it, I feel
like you could be bringing in a
whole value to the whole world
of computers and documentation
and storytelling and the helping
and giving narrative, it really
misses a lot of that, you know,
it's so calculated that, that
sort of how I want to say that
algorithmic sort of you should
have known this is cold. And it
could use a lot of kindness and
stories and interest and
examples and fun things to kind
of bring in there, like zombie
apocalypses. I would love to
learn via zombie apocalypses as
a course. Actually, there used
to be this Rails course, rails
for zombies, right? And it did
fantastic. Where's the new
version of that? Yeah. So my
thing is bring the creativity
through you, you know, let like,
write the blog posts write the
story is create a game that
helps educate, create podcasts
like this. And so I find that I
tend to center myself around
other creatives who, despite,
you might be fantastic At one
thing or another, or maybe your
video editing skills are just
like off the charts. Maybe you
can make a tic toc that
everybody's like, how did you do
that? Whatever it is, bring it
together and use it to tell a
story.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
love that. I did--I had totally
forgotten about it, but--I did
crypto zombies a couple of years
ago. And that was really fun. So
it's programming with etherium.
And you were going through and
defeating these zombies, I think.
Dan Ott: Yeah, there was a CSS
Flexbox course, that's all like
zombie. Zombie-like, solve a
bunch of zombie related puzzles
to like learn CSS,
Gant: I guess you got to like,
get down in the alleyway using
Flexbox without touching the
zombies or something. That'd be
funny. Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's
awesome. Now we need a
collection of all of the the
zombie coding lessons that are
out there.
Gant: Yes.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Um, so so
speaking of zombies, and
challenges, what are some of the
challenges that you've gone
through in this journey? I think
you know, you come off as
someone that can do a lot of
things really, really well. But
I know that we all go through
something. And so I especially
love to hear from people who do
things so effortlessly, you
know, what they had to do to get
to that point.
Gant: There's a couple there's a
Choose Your Own Adventure:
there's trying to graduate was
really hard for me because I was
a I was a D student in math. I
wasn't very good at math. I
didn't see how it actually
pertained with anything. And
that was really hard for a
while. NowI actually watch math
YouTube videos for fun. So
that's a different version of
me. The other thing I'll say is
that I used to be afraid of
crowds or speaking at all, at
all. I had a college, you know,
101 psychology, no no it was
philosophy. And I did everything
wrong, like I'm getting ready to
go ahead and do this right? I
have no money. I'm in college
first year, I decided, you know
what I'm gonna do that I'm
really nervous about this, I'm
gonna treat myself to a really
nice latte. I'll feel very happy
because I've got this latte. I'm
just going to put myself in the
corner up until it's time for me
to go ahead and give my talk.
And so I drink my latte, sat in
the corner, just kind of like
crowded over myself, sitting
over my notes, reading, reading,
reading, and you know, like the
first sentence, almost like, I
couldn't help myself, I was just
consistently rereading the whole
thing. Get up there. Just super
ready to go ahead and give this
presentation. First sentence
comes out of my mouth. Boom.
There you go. Take that
everybody. What's the second
sentence? Gant what's the second
sentence? Gant? Did you memorize
the second sentence? Alright,
now it's quiet. Forget the
second sentence, you're
completely quiet and everybody's
looking at you. Come up with
something that's better than the
second sentence. Right now, with
everybody watching, do something
that's gonna be fantastic and
blow everybody away. It is.
Okay, you're still quiet. And
everybody's still looking at
you. You just need to say the
second sentence. That's really
good. Now, no pressure better be
the best second sentence you've
ever said in your life.
Someone's coming over to you.
They're moving you to the side
of the room. They're continuing
this talk without you. You still
haven't said anything. That's
what happened to me in college.
And that's where I was. And
everything I did to prepare for
that was wrong. Everything I did
was wrong. And from that day, to
where I am now, that that's a
that's another adventure. So
yeah, I could talk about either
of those things. Your choice?
Dan Ott: Well, just listening to
you describe that. I'm like
sweating now just listening.
Like,
Gant: --you know what, you know,
you're you're not hyper tuned
into one person, the audience,
you are reading the minds of
about 30 people watching you.
You're like, I think I saw
somebody roll their eyes, you
know, in the third row. Like, I
was super tuned in to all the
wrong things. So so named some
of the things I did wrong there.
One I took I had coffee, right
before I was gonna give a talk
was I was nervous about what I
was crowded over myself. I had a
body language. I know that
there's a lot of argument about
power posing being false or
whatever. No, I think I think
that even if it's not
specifically tied to
testosterone, or if they can't
have, they're having trouble
proving that part of it, I don't
care how you're positioning
yourself right before a talk
helps create, you know how
you're going to be doing it. I I
was trying to memorize, I was
rereading the same thing. I
tried to come up with something
right on the spot. Instead of
understanding how to go ahead
and present a story. I was
presenting exactly what I was
trying to say. It was I was
trying to be perfect. And so all
those things were totally wrong.
And it created a super fear
existing human being putting me
in a crowd any more than like a
small circle of people, and I
would start getting extremely
uncomfortable. Now, I've I've
MCed conferences, online and in
person with over 1000s of
people, so it's a big change.
But that was a bunch of steps
between here and there. I do
have a blog post about that,
too. I can share that at some
point.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. Well,
shall we need to drop that in
the show? Yeah.
Dan Ott: I mean, that yeah,
that's very like this, that
whole... That door is the one I
choose. Sorry. Yeah, picking the
door. But like, what were some
like, I mean, obviously, it's a
lot of time has passed since
then. You know, and there's no
you know, just like go like that
to from from stage fright to
where you are now. But can you
like highlight some? I don't
know. Some "aha" moments are
like what, I don't know if it
was just, you know, reading
books and dressing or how did
you get closer to being more
comfortable? You know,
Gant: It's a combo move. For
sure. One of the things I
realized was I did everything
wrong, right. I was anxious, not
excited. So like, which actually
changes your biochemical makeup.
So first thing I did was kind of
like studied, what the hell did
my body just do? Why did I go
into fight or flight? and why
would my body go into fight or
flight talking to people? Why
whatever evolutionary thing is
that that's gonna be so good for
me. And the truth is like, it's,
it's great for as a societal
animal not to have everybody
ready to go ahead and take the
stage and talk, you know, we
inherently actually respect the
stage and the power of it and
the passing of the microphone,
there's a reason why MCs will
sort of like, almost like, pass
the baton and shake someone's
hand, as, as an authority pass
to the next person who's coming
up and talking, there's a
certain programming that we all
follow, or looking at these
things. And, you know, when I
was kind of like, analyzing
this, I could see how wrong I
was, I could see all this stuff.
But like, when I was anxious, my
body was releasing all this
cortisol in my blood system, and
it was just more and more
cortisol is causing me to get
more and more fight or flight.
Neither of those will let you
give a talk. I can't go in the
front row and punch the first
person I see. And I can't run
out of the room. So I froze.
Yeah, I didn't have I couldn't
do either the fight or the
flight. And so what I was
missing was oxytocin, you know,
which is actually what you have,
as the difference between a
person who's about to go on a
ride, and be excited about going
on a ride, you're standing in
line, you're kind of jumping up
and down, you're like, yeah, and
so you don't have anxiety.
Because cortisol is dripping
through your bloodstream,
telling you pay attention, as
pay attention, that be afraid
that's be afraid of that. And
without oxytocin combined with
that, your blood vessels all
shrink up. And it just creates
this hyper tunnel vision of
what's going on. And that
oxytocin helps relax you and
also make sure you're paying
attention to the right things.
And so I wasn't leaning into
that I wasn't leaning into all
these things. And when I found
out sort of what the biochemical
and what my body was doing, I
found out like, Hey, now with
practice, you can figure out how
to get your oxytocin released,
prepare for a talk, get these
things happening. And, and then
I went to my local Toastmasters.
And I was nervous as hell. And
what they did is, let me talk as
much as I was comfortable
talking. It was just like me
saying my name and sitting back
down. That's all I had to do.
But I could always like do a
little bit more to a little bit
more to a little bit more. And
then so that let me sort of like
carve through the stone a little
bit. And I want to say, just,
you know, half a year of
Toastmasters is probably the
most valuable thing I can
recommend to anybody.
Dan Ott: Can you can you share
what like what Toastmasters is
just general?
Gant: Yeah, absolutely.
Toastmasters was formed at the
YMCA back in like 19-- whatever.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
it's 98 years old?
Gant: Yeah, it's this
ridiculously old organization is
a fantastic organization where
it was just the only way that
you can, you can learn a lot
about public speaking. But then
you got to do it. It's like, you
can learn how, you know, a gun
works. But people still have to
go to the gun range, you can
learn a lot about swimming, but
you still have to go swim. You
have to go do the thing. And so
how do you do public speaking,
you know, like, you're gonna sit
in the in front of a mirror and
practice it and that you need,
you need a bunch of people who
agree that they'll listen to
you, and you'll listen to them
and you'll give each other
feedback in a safe space. And
that's what Toastmasters really
is, it has three pillars, one of
sort of this public speaking,
another one of this evaluation,
and then this third part that
ties them together, which is
like this Leadership Initiative.
So if you want to get better at
giving people feedback, speaking
or leading, that's the place and
so it's cheap as hell man these
people haven't raised their
prices since forever It's
international so people who are
listening to this like there's a
there's a Toastmasters quite a
few in Amsterdam, you know, all
kinds these other places. So and
they have like, the speaking
competitions and fun stuff to go
watch and cool people to go see
and, and motivational stuff. So
if you get yourself mixed up in
there for a little bit, and you
kind of learn what your body was
doing. The inevitable conclusion
is that you will sort of solve
your, your your own sort of
quandary that you can't solve,
you know, just by being the
first time you speaking in front
of a class for a great, you
know, like, what a terrible
first experience. And way better
than that is a group of friendly
people who have worked with 100
people just like you, who had
the same concern. Have you had
and give you the amount of
feedback that you're ready to
receive? Because I've learned
some pretty advanced tricks. But
I didn't learn those my first
year at Toastmasters? Hell no, I
was just learning how to go
ahead and get up there without
having a down a whole bottle of
wine at a time or something.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: They do
have oxytocin nose spray, so
maybe that's the,
Gant: well see, there you go.
Well, even even easier than that
is like if you. So I'll say
this, like when you're about to
lift weights, you can. You can
do all kinds of crazy stuff. But
you can actually like, get
yourself in the right mindset,
to lift weights. If you're about
to go for a run, you can get
yourself in the right mindset to
go for a run. And if you're
about to give a talk, you can
get yourself in the right
mindset to give a talk. It's
just the same thing as all those
other things. So I would always
go for the internal skill versus
running out of nose spray at the
right time, or whatever else
happens. But yeah, it is it is
good that we're kind of like
chemically biohacking ourselves.
But I think that starts with
what we eat, think and do.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
that's such great advice. And
that goes across so many
different boards, you know,
whether you're coding or, you
know, we talked about
interviewing a lot of Virtual
Coffee, and you go into an
interview, I always like to,
like, watch a comedy show or
Yes, funny clips beforehand,
because I do that, you know, get
that fight or flight. And it's
so intense that unless I can
bring that down. It's really
hard for me to get back to a
place where I can answer
something confidently or present
in a positive way.
Gant: Mm hmm. Yeah. Yeah. The
fight or flight is, is it is
awkward for us as an evolved
societal species. You know, it's
fantastic. If somebody breaks
into your house, but almost day
to day, it's such a great skill
for you to kind of manage that,
that discomfort and be able to
work on it a bit. So I'd say
like, it's kind of a life skill.
It's opened up a lot of I'll say
Toastmasters has opened up a lot
of doors for me, and I can never
stop singing their praises for
for honestly, what they've done.
I can have a hard conversation
with someone. You know, there
was something I couldn't do
either. I could do it anytime I
need to know.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I could
do--can I call you? Instead of
me doing it? I'll just let you
do the hard conversation.
Gant: You're fired! You're done!
I just just record me, you're
fired?
Dan Ott: Can you use the zombie?
The like one of the zombie tones
for that too? Like?
Gant: Yeah, I have to pull up
all the weird stuff.
Dan Ott: Voice modifier for
you're fired?
Gant: Probably have to...fired?
I guess. Let me let me go ahead
and find one for you. And I'll
come back to that. It changed
their icons on me for the voice
month stuff. And now I don't
know what anything does.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I don't feel like
I just
That's it. That's it. We found
it. That's interesting. It's
really interesting. how all this
stuff kind of relates, though,
and the, yeah, the fight or
flight and the way that your
body is, like, the reasons
behind why your body's doing
things, you know, or your mind
is reacting to things. I feel
like that aspect of it is really
important to learn and not just
for obviously, for public
speaking, I've been doing a lot
of that with, like with any
anxiety stuff, too. And yes, and
it's all sort of part of the
same puzzle, you know, and,
yeah, I think that's very
interesting that it's like that
was one of your like, starting,
you know, like one for all this
is cool.
Gant: Hey, it's about so we have
a saying, I'm gonna I'm gonna
Toastmaster y'all real quick
with a saying we don't, we don't
get rid of the butterflies in
your stomach. You make them fly
in formation. And it's about
writing your energy levels. Like
for instance, I am naturally a
little bit anxious with that is
what I realized, which makes me
excited when I go places. So I
am about to give a talk before
I'm on there. I feel like I'm
about to get on a cool ride. And
then when I get off of it, I
feel like I was on a cool ride.
If you're normally a board
person, you can be a relaxed
person. You know, if you're
stubborn, then you could be
committed. It's not about
changing who you are. It's about
changing the outcome and what
that ride is. And you could
apply this to all these
different things like he, I'm
not going to change my
biochemical makeup much more
than a little bit. But that's
enough. You know, you can
significantly alter the outcome
with some well placed chess
pieces along your way. And make
yourself you know, let's say
like you say you get on stage,
and you're just way too hyper.
Well, I mean, if if you present
that as energetic, I mean,
that's fantastic. I mean, that's
what you want, when someone's
running your spin class, you
know, like, people are paying a
ton for the most energetic spin
class, you know, like videos
that are out there. And people
find that niche, and they kind
of ride it. That's, that's how
you turn it into success.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I find for
me, it's much easier to do in
front of a live audience. So you
know, being virtual, and giving
talks that way, it's been much
harder because I can burn that
nervous energy in front of a
crowd of people. But when I'm
looking at myself on the screen,
giving a talk, there's nowhere
to put it.
Gant: Yeah, and there's a
there's another piece of this,
I'll say that when I was. So
here's something I noticed, I
was able, fortunately enough
before the pandemic to give
enough talks, to believe that
audience is on my side and wants
me to succeed. They are super
awesome. One time we had a
technical glitch, and I jumped
on stage to go ahead and say the
technical glitch, because the
audience would, I knew they
would support me, I knew they
were they wanted someone to come
out there and make a joke about
the technical glitch. Right?
That's great. But now anybody
getting into speaking in a
virtual world has no
reinforcement on what their
audience really wants, and what
they're really feeling. And they
don't see heads nodding in the
front row, or whatever it is,
and they're not looking for the
positivity is hard to find. So I
couldn't imagine what it's like
to start breaking into that
during the pandemic, and start
actually having this where you
don't get any kind of
reinforcement as a speaker. And
the second thing that's really
awkward about that is, I think
audiences really need to step
up, send, if someone does a
tweet that you like, don't just
heart it, say, I love this
tweet. Thank you so much. If
someone does a podcast you like,
you need to go find them
afterwards, you can say
something. It's so much more
important as virtual world.
Because it's just like, I know
somebody who did a blog post,
and they're like, nobody cared
about this blog post, as like,
well, what's the stats on it?
And there's 1000s of people who
had read the blog post, I was
like, Here's 1000s of people's
whose life you've influenced and
like, well, how come no one left
a comment. I was like, Well,
welcome to the virtual world of
lurking where you're gonna get
one comment per 10,000 people
who care. That's it. And that's
a little bit weird. We're not
programmed for that, either. So
this is the next battle.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, that
is so hard to try and work
through that. And you're,
especially when you're writing a
blog post or a tweet, like you
said, or, you know, you you're
releasing your second book here
soon. And so you put all of this
time and effort and heart into
creating these things. And then
when there's no feedback, it can
be challenging and kind of doubt
or imposter syndrome or
whatever, because you have sunk
a lot of yourself into it.
Gant: Yeah, it's put yourself
out into the void and it feels
like nothing nothing heard you
nothing said that. You know,
that's, I feel very Okay, I know
that some of us in this podcast
has gotten some kind of value
out of it. And that makes me
extremely happy. I know that by
the way, you know, y'all get a
lot more likes on your tweets
and I I got to work on my
tweeting structure to have it
more conversational because I
just tend to tell people stuff
it's to like Redux you know,
it's just like uni directional
process here. I need to work on
that a bit. But I think being
here is perfect
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: my most
liked tweets are about my kids
and poop. So good. Start there.
Gant: Okay, you got it. I will...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: see how
that goes
Dan Ott: Every parent has just
millions of poop stories i feel
like
Gant: I i have i've been
tempting fate as well. I just
hung an oil painting in my
living room. And if you see a
photo of my living room, it is
for my daughter. She has a slide
and this and that and and these
cushions that I apparently had
to buy because they're super
they're basically like mad. This
is like memory foam mattresses a
fold out. But they named it for
kids. So now it's more expensive
and I had to get those. And I've
got all this stuff all over the
place. They just see this oil
painting. I'm like, I'm gonna
defend it. I mean, it's not
gonna last I know it's gonna get
destroyed. I'm trying.
Dan Ott: Yeah, we had, you know,
an old TV in our family room
with same deal slide all the all
the all that, that we move the
couches all over the place and
stuff. And I was always joking
about like, if you're gonna
throw things at the wall, just
aim it at this TV so that we can
get a new one you know, but then
we got a new one. And now I'm
like, Okay, do not. Do not. So
far so far. Everything's fine.
Gant: That's good.
Oh, man. All right, kids and
poop, done. I'm right there
right here. It's on my desk
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: in your
Gant, Gant way of writing things
you have to find. Find the right
way to do it, I guess.
Gant: Perfect.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So what
like kind of going back to what
we were talking about before you
have a really distinct voice and
all of the stuff that you do.
And it's nice, because it's
really consistent. Like, if I
opened up an article, I don't
need to read that. It's by Gant
Laborde because I read it. I'm
like, this is definitely an
again, article, right? And so
you're like covering it and all
these spaces? So like, how have
you managed to stay like
consistent across all of these
things?
Gant: Here's something funny, I
wrote a blog post really late at
night. And I asked a few friends
to review it. And they're both
their feedback was this isn't
Gant enough? You've you failed
as like, I don't want to rewrite
it. So like, I went back in
there, I was like, Oh, I see
what they're saying. Then I kind
of re added stuff to it as like,
Here you go, can you review
this? And they're like, yeah,
there you are. Which is really
funny. I'd say that. For me.
It's my it's, it's a little bit
of authenticity of myself here.
And I don't, I don't think that
I'm a great story. Sometimes I
every I think that might be
everybody's case, right? We, I
know my story. I've been
watching it for 40 years. So
unfortunately, I am a little bit
like, I'll be able to do my
voice anytime. And I'll be able
to do my version of something
anytime. I don't know if it
always is going to resonate with
people or if it's going to be
that. But for the most part, I
need to I need to get over that.
And I need to do it more. So I'd
say that if you were turning
yourself into a brand, or you
know, if you're working on your
own brand, be as authentic as
you can. And I think that's
what's so great about the fact
that your kids and poop stories
are doing so well on Twitter.
Because if you were trying to do
something else, I think
everybody would notice, you
know, like that goes away. And
you got to find what you're
really, really, really excited
about and, and what, bring that
to the forefront. And then you
will always speak in your voice.
So when I am talking to people,
I'm very excited about the
people I'm talking to. And I
really want to get my story
across. And I want to make it
like fun and entertaining. And
this is the same thing. If we
saw each other at a conference,
and we had to talk about what
your top three movies right,
then I'm going to talk about
that the same exact way because
that's who I am. And if we go
out to dinner and have drinks,
and everybody's like, Come,
actually anybody come visit New
Orleans, once the world opens
up. Let's do that, like, let's
go all have drinks and sit out
there and listen to some jazz,
and talk about whatever it is,
but I'm going to sound exactly
the same. And that gives me the
easiest way to keep my voice
consistent. Now I can raise that
bar by by improving who I am. So
this is like that same thing I
was talking about before, where
you've you've not destroying
your energy, but you're
channeling it and you're kind of
improving it and you're working
on it, you're letting it flow in
a different different way. So if
I, you know, go start taking
music lessons, or if I start
learning how to speak with this
crazy new dialect or I start
doing Shakespeare in my spare
time. Those things are going to
pepper into who I am, and what's
going to start happening there.
And then the bar raises in
everything that I do. So I found
that like Virtual Coffee is a
lot about virtual improvement as
well like improving yourself.
You have book clubs you have
finding your voice here. You
have mentorship and things like
that. Those are all perfect. As
long as they're actually coming
in and hitting home and being
who they are, I know people who
tried to open up like Twitter
accounts to be a personality.
They did great for three months,
and then just couldn't keep it
going. This is the formula for
consistency. Be 100%. You.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
really great advice. I like
that. And I think for me, so
normally when I'm writing, it's
just more, it's personal. It's
storytelling. And that's where I
feel comfortable. And so I've
tried to write more technical
things, and it's much harder,
because it's like this
negotiation of like, why I need
to appear to be an authority or
something like I'm not an
authority on this. Like finding,
figuring out how to find that
balance of like, okay, just
like, be myself, but also be
myself and talk about code, you
kn ow?
Gant: Yeah. Well, and and the
thority. Here's a weird thing,
the authority doesn't have to
say they're an authority, or
doesn't have to talk like an
authority to be an authority for
a certain time, especially in
our field. So we're used to
authority coming from, like a
uniform particular mentality and
things like that. But, but
that's just the first, you know,
reaction that we have. And then
after that, and authority
doesn't have to say they're in
authority. That's a sing. That's
a sign of it. And so my last
blog post for the Google
Developer experts that was
published, has a Harry Potter
themed cartoons and terrible
drawings in it, and a secret
easter egg, that if you draw a
skull on the website, it'll,
it'll like, show these snakes
that come out and call you a
death either. It's like a fun
little thing. And what happens
is, none of that is
professional. But I think that
what's great about it is that,
sure, we set up a little bit of
the professionalism and why this
is on that blog post and what
the categories are, and what the
technology that's going to be
used are. And then the trick is
not to sit there and constantly
say, I am still an authority,
let your let your story be told,
and let people be able to leave
that because they're already
following you. Now you have the
stage, you don't have to keep
mentioning, you're on stage and
you're talking into a
microphone, you have the
attention. Now keep it, that's
the trick. If you were to bring
out the most boring person on
stage, I could give them an
introduction and hand them a
microphone and everybody would
start listening. And that would
be my job as an emcee or as the
person who brought them on. But
Five minutes later, if they're
not listening, that's not my
fault. That's the story that
they're telling. That's what's
going on. So you can start with
authority, but don't stay in it.
It's not, it's not really as
cool as it sounds. And I would
say, that's...there's, there's
enough people ready to hand you
a microphone that you don't have
to worry about improving your
authority, you just have to be
willing to go ahead and accept
poor microphones in your life.
Dan Ott: I Like that, yeah, one
thing that I have worked on with
this sort of thing, too, is, is
if you're writing about a topic,
you know, you don't have to,
it's okay that you don't know
everything you know, and also,
like your readers, or audience,
or whatever, will maybe trust
you more, if you are upfront
about like, I'm not really sure
about this part, but here's what
how I solved it or, you know,
that kind of thing. I found
personally, like, it's a
struggle to get through
sometimes because you want it
like you. I don't know, like, my
lizard brain wants people to,
you know, think that I know
everything or whatever, you
know. So like working on that,
like little step of I really
don't know everything, here's
how I solve this problem,
whatever, you know, and like,
like, I feel like, when I'm
reading as an audience member,
listening or reading that, that
sort of thing actually makes it
helps me trust somebody, you
know, more, more than if they
don't mention it or act like,
you know, in some way that they,
you know, pretend to they know
everything because nobody does,
Gant: no one actually wants
perfection man, it really
you know, so
doesn't, you know, the PhD
presentations, like you're
talking about where nobody can
be wrong. You can't go up on the
curb. You can't you know, you
have to have driven most
effectively. I mean, how many
how many PhD presentations? Can
you go to a conference and
watch? Like, it's just, it's
terrible. If you ask and then we
could do this experiment right
now. Think right now about the
best talk that you've ever seen
in person, the one that was
like, Wow, that was really
really good. Just choose one of
the Really good ones. I want you
to name three properties of that
talk. Okay, so like three
adjectives that describe that
talk. And we'll start to you,
Bekah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Um it,
okay. It was engaging and no,
that's not an adjective.
Gant: Not perfect, perfect.
Yeah, engaging.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Something
the entire audience could relate
to at different stages. So I
guess relatability maybe? Yeah.
Um, and then was fun.
Gant: Yeah. Perfect. And we'll
get three more.
Dan Ott: Yeah. So as I was also
struggling with a word choice,
but it was like, non pol...,
like, not all the way polished.
I don't know, what's the right
word for that? Yeah.
Gant: And that's that, you
Dan Ott: know, like, the story
was personal. I mean, it was a
tech talk ostensibly, but the
story behind it was, like,
personal so like, you know,
relatable, like kind of like
Bekah saying and had a third
thing, but I forget exactly what
it was. I don't my mind. My mind
is, is empty now.
Gant: That's okay. Neither of
y'all said perfect. No one says
perfect. And that's, that's what
we can get. What was it
relatable? Is someone coming and
feeling like they're making eye
contact with you, and leading
you through something fun, and
relatable. That's it.
Congratulations, like, that's
it. Nothing you do should be
perfect. No one cares about the
perfect speech that they saw.
That person failed. The
relatable speech is the one that
was everybody's favorite. teta.
Now, the bar is a lot easier. I
think we can reach telling a
story and having people be happy
that they heard it.
Dan Ott: Yeah. I love that way
of thinking about the whole
thing.
Gant: Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: When I gave
my first talk at a conference,
it was when I was a graduate
student in English. And it's a
very different feel. Because it
is you have to be perfect. And
there will be that person in the
audience who will raise their
hand and try and stump you or to
make you feel like you don't
really know what you're talking
about. Like, trying to unlearn
that anxiety, that first
experience, guys.
Gant: I had that. So I did a
keynote for Amazon. It was one
of my favorite talks I ever
gave. It was a it was amazing.
It was great. And we had q&a
afterward. And there were so
many cool q&a. And then there
was that one person, you know,
who stands up and says, starts
telling their life story. Like,
like, Okay, you've got the
microphone, and now it's your
turn. Okay, go ahead. They do
all this stuff, then they asked
the most esoteric question. And
it was like this really crazy
thing and this and that. And
they just wanted to sound super
impressive. And I knew everybody
knew I basically I could say
something. And we could have
this conversation be like done,
because like no one else who was
there was following what they
were saying. And I was half
following it. And if I just kind
of conceded to them, they would
have been like, haha, you know,
I know so much. And then they
would have maybe sat down or
something. The way I handled it
is because I saw it happen as
like, this person is not
supposed to be here. That's not
the you know, this. You're at
the wrong kind of talk. So I
told them, I said, Google it.
Google it. They were they were
visually shocked that I said
that. And I actually enjoyed
that way more.
Dan Ott: It's the "Let me Google
that for you" approach.
Gant: Yeah. Yeah, I guess they
didn't expect that to come. You
know, there's, there's always
those people and truth is, you
don't need to waste time on that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah.
totally true. I just need my
brain to remember. You know, I
like I really have enjoyed this
interview. I think that you just
do such a good job of like
mentoring in every situation.
And, you know, Have you always
been that way? Like is that a
skill you develop?
Gant: I honestly say I learned a
lot of how so I won Best
evaluator and some Toastmasters
competitions. I learned I
learned how to evaluate and give
constructive feedback there.
Like I said, there's three
pillars to it, and I really do
Oh, My speaking ability, my
ability to give feedback and my
a lot of my leadership skills, I
really do owe to the fact that
I've been area governor at
Toastmasters for a year, I've
been a club mentor, I've spoken
in competitions, as well as a
club level, like hundreds of
times now. And I've been an
evaluator hundreds of times.
It's just these are the things
that that I've been allowed to
practice. And anybody who goes
and practices these things, is
going to find that they've built
a muscle that they can use in
all kinds of life situations.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's so
great. And I think that you've
hit on this idea a couple of
times of its, its practice,
right? You know, it might seem
effortless that you see somebody
doing something, but it's
because they have practice these
things over and over. And it
takes growth and it takes time
and effort. But
Gant: yeah, always be growing.
He always be growing. What What,
what book are you reading,
that's, that's challenging you
what, you know, blog posts, are
you writing that's challenging
you? What's the next thing if
you're not, I mean, I know this
is like the oldest and everybody
hates hearing it. But if you're
not growing, you're dying. And I
really do believe that it's
important for you to be, you
know, we've got so much time
with a very, very sharp
intellect. And we tend to waste
that, you know, for our first 28
years of our life, some people
really kind of get there. But
for the rest of the time,
you're, you're sort of like
crystallizing new thoughts and
ideas and bringing those in. And
I love that because, you know,
you could do that till, you
know, the day you die, you can
always be getting these new
thoughts and kind of adding new
skills and getting new updates
and improving who you are. And
it's a little bit like as if I
add a new word today, or new
word a week, you know, I've got
52, amazing, cool new ways to
express myself a year. If I add
new concepts, I'm finding new
ways to express myself. And I'm
getting new nouns and new
neurons that I can hold ideas
and that normally I was unable
to hold before. So I'm a
relentless self improver, I buy
books, and then sometimes they
can be just brought down to one
paragraph, you know, I know
this, you read the whole book,
and you're like, I was one
paragraph, just just to say
this, and then ignore the book.
But I'll still, you know, that
one paragraph of perfectly
usable, well identified,
information is locked in your
brain forever, because you read
that whole book, and you'll be
able to reference it and use it
for the rest of your life. So I
think that these are, it is
practice, and one of the most
beautiful things we can do is
constantly improve.
Dan Ott: I...my...so one
question was like, how do you
personally manage, like, the
learning along with obviously
doing work, and he seemed to be
doing, you know, like mixing in
your side projects, and
everything else that you have
going on? Plus, you know, family
and all that stuff? Do you have
a specific method or anything?
Gant: For me, I combo things as
much as possible. And some
people absolutely love it. And
some people, there are certain
situations where it's like, No,
you don't combo this, right? You
don't, you wouldn't go to a
recital, and then like, check
your emails, right, bad combo.
But if you've got to learn a new
technology, and you've got like
a marketing task, and you have a
cool idea that you want to work
on, well, if you build that new
idea into that new technology,
yeah, it might take you three
times as long. But you're,
you're kind of like building
your resume, or you're kind of
adding a marketing concept. And
so you kind of combo these
things, and then you want to get
as much out of those as
possible. As a developer, I tend
to not so for instance, I've
mentioned like so I just wrote a
book, write my intuition is to
shut the hell up and have said
that once I set up wrote a book,
I put it in, I pinned the tweet.
Didn't I do like all the
marketing, right? That's, that's
your intuition. That's my
intuition is how we can just The
truth is, I have to force like,
other things I have to
constantly like, you know, fit
those things. So here, take a
look at this. I'm on this
amazing podcast. I'm interested
in you know, I'm talking about
All these cool concepts, and
then boom, guess what I'm
opening my spreadsheet of
marketing drips. And I'm saying
mentioned the book, boom combo
move. So there's kind of stuff
there. I think I think finding
proper combinations of things is
going to give you what is like
attractive to go after, as well.
Like this serves like all these
different kinds of things.
That's what I always loved about
computers, like you could leave
them running. And they're always
crunching numbers and collecting
emails and solving problems in
the background back, I want to
say, a billion and a half years
ago, I might be off by a little
bit. There was a screensaver
that used to like, try to help
identify radio signals and space
member SETI. And so one of the
things is like your computer
when it went dormant, used to
like try to help identify
signals to spread. I love that,
you know, like, when I'm not
using it, it's working on this
cool thing. This is of course,
before crypto, because who has
an extra? Now, we'd come up with
that idea, then just like,
Alright, everybody's gonna mind
crypto for us now. I mean, now
they're shoving it in the
JavaScript. So it's doing in the
background of webpages, right.
But it's, I think it's about
finding, finding situations,
partnerships, interactions,
where you can have a lot of the
things that you want all kind of
come together, and making sure
that you're pushing yourself to
get all the juice out of every
single piece of fruit, you you
get better at squeezing it out,
you get better at using every
piece of it, you become a chef,
you know of, Okay, I'm going to
cut this part over here, but
these skins are gonna go over
there and be flavoring for that
I'm gonna leave this in the pan
for this. And like this weird
sort of combination in this 3d
math starts to come out. That's
when you know, you're getting
more value out of your time. And
I think that's what we're really
worried about, because I spend a
lot of time doing something that
has low value. And then if I
could do something that does a
whole bunch of things. For me,
that's a high value thing. And
those aren't easy to figure out.
And I think they're very per
person. But that's my favorite
thing. If I can find something
that hits a bunch of different
plus signs. I'm like, Yes, I
deserve this dopamine.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. I like
that I like this sort of
intentional, you know, approach
to that, that sort of thing.
Because I always have a billion
different things going on, you
know, and trying to like, review
and figure out how to pull them
all together, you know, and do
some different, you know,
overlaps in different circles or
whatever. I think that's I think
that's a great approach.
Gant: Yeah. Venn diagramming, I
guess, is like, it's the Venn
diagram of life here. Like what
things can I do to have the most
impact and in my, and here's a
trick. learn to say no to the
things that don't. So you have
all these things, that Venn
diagram, you have five to 10
things on this list that are
huge impact. The 10 things
underneath that are evil,
attractive things that you want
to do that are low impact things
that don't move the needle that
don't do anything, you have to
cut those those are those your
do not do list at the top as you
do list. And you say no to the
things that go that serve the
bottom, you say yes to the
things that serve at the top.
Dan Ott: I like that. Got to
figure out how to say no to a
different question. That's a
whole nother podcast episode...
Gant: "Saying no, the episode."
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We do. We
need that episode. I think I get
you and I met one time and you
said yeah, one of the things you
said to me was when you say yes
to something, you're saying no
to 100 other things or something
like that. And I was like...yeah
Dan Ott: yeah. I think we're
Yeah, pretty much there, right?
Gant: yeah, Right.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. Yes.
I was. thinking through all
these things now.
Gant: That's good. That's good.
There's a there was this artist
who went on stage and he played
and then after he played, no one
applauded. And so he felt really
bad. And then the person said,
they're they're still
emotionally feeling what
happened there. So it's okay. So
I was like, whenever I say
something, there's like silence
afterward. That's what I tell
myself. But hey, people are
thinking about what you just
said. That's okay. Yeah. Versus,
you know, you have this inner
cynic that I've fortunately been
able to kill, or like, subdue,
which is the one that was like,
Hey, no one said anything. What
did you do? Why is there
silence? It is certain people
who have to feel silence, they
that cynics winning for them, if
you can have a pleasant pause in
the conversation, those are
people who you are actually
talking to. And that's a
friendly conversation.
Dan Ott: I, I'm glad you said
that. This this, I mean, this,
this happens to me in our
podcast recordings often, right?
where somebody will say
something like, meaningful, or
we'll just like, start, you
know, my brain will start going
on that. But then also need to,
like host the pack, you know,
it's the exact same exact thing
happens where there's just
silence because I'm just like,
we're both just like, Whoa, you
know, just like thinking, yeah,
then we have to remember like,
Alright, we're like podcast
hosts.
Gant: Wait, is this thing on?
Where am I?
I know that that definitely
happens, you know. And I think,
there, there are lots of signs
that have picked up that, you
know, like, when this
conversation, we're not happy,
we're not afraid to go down a
path. And that just makes it
such a friendly conversation.
You know, if you had like a
rigid agenda, and like, it was
like, we go to this point, this
point, this point, this point,
like, oh, man, when somebody is
listening, this podcast, it's
gonna feel forced or that y'all
don't do that. I really
appreciate it. It's like, I you
know, if I had started talking
about Dwayne Johnson for 15
minutes after the zombie
apocalypse conversation, I think
y'all would have let me and I
appreciate that a lot.
Dan Ott: Yeah, no, we almost
went down that road. I was close
and then I think Bekah started
moving on. So it's probably
good, but
Gant: That's good. We.. "The
Rock, the Podcast"
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I love
tangents. tangents are my
favorite.
Gant: Yeah, yes, indeed.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, well,
I think this has been a really
great episode, you, we covered a
lot of stuff that was really
important and really meaningful.
And now everybody gets to have a
glimpse of what it's like to
have you as their personal Yoda.
So thank you so much for being
here with us, we will drop all
of your links in the show notes.
But is there anything else that
you're working on that you would
like to plug right now
Gant: I'll just say that I
really am lucky enough to work
at a company Infinite Red, where
we, we really have a huge
footprint. And I'm really
excited because we work in the
React Native space. So we build
mobile apps and stuff like that.
And I work with a lot of other
Yodas there. A lot of really
friendly people who, who could
easily go off to work for
Microsoft, Google, Facebook,
like they could go to a fortune
500 tomorrow. And I think that
I'm in a place in my life where
I get to choose my company and
who I'm around. And I'm around
other people who do the same
thing. And they kind of choose
us. So we're a real fun company
for explaining stuff, working
with stuff and building
technology. And I'll say that,
like, I appreciate them for
supporting me on going on
podcasts, as well as like how
cool it is to kind of come in
and work for us as well. We have
a careers application for people
that we don't usually push too
much now. But we're at the point
where we have to grow. So it's
at careers dot infinite dot red.
So if you want to work with us
feel free to apply. They're
currently only hiring US and
Canada. We're being extra picky.
And then also, if you want to
work with us, and a consulting
standpoint, just Hello at
infinite dot read and we'll send
somebody your way immediately.
Start talking about your app,
and you'll get to meet our CTO
and our CEO. And like, you know,
we don't even have sales people.
Just a group of group of people
having fun and building great
stuff.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah,
that's awesome.
Dan Ott: Yeah, Infinite Red is
very cool. Sorry, I didn't mean
to interrupt. I just, I've been
an admirer of Infinite Red for a
long time. So
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah, I've
met two out of Three of the
owners, so
Gant: Oh yeah,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Still
waiting for that third.
Gant: Yeah, you gotta meet Todd,
he's he is he is a bundle of
fun. He focuses internally
constantly, we call him our
internal glue. He is, first to
comment on something, the person
anybody goes to if they like,
they feel like they need to talk
to somebody. Because he's, you
know, like, I guess you could
talk to me, if you're talking
about career stuff and things
like that. Todd knows what
everybody did this weekend. He
knows what everybody did this
weekend. And he's, he's gonna
show you what he did, you know,
and to have that as a CEO, is
like, great for trying to be
like a humanizing sort of
company. We care a lot about
what, what's going on, and
people, well, not what's going
on in your life, but like, how
you're doing, you know, and how
we are part of like, what's
going on there. And I know that
people are super anti, saying,
like, we're a family kind of
thing. We're not, we're not a
family, but we sure treat you as
a human being and as like a
friend and we, we help you with
things. So like Todd, if you
meet him, he's, he's gonna
attach and just like find out
like what you're doing this
weekend and stuff like that.
He's super cool. So we try to
reserve his energies to internal
but he, you could definitely
reach out and talk to him. He's
super cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, well,
thank you so much for being
here. And for always supporting
Virtual Coffee because you do so
much whether it's mentoring or
coming to coffee and talking or
giving a million brown bags on
things that we need to hear. We
very much appreciate it. I'm
glad to have you on the podcast
too.
Gant: Thank you for having me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Becca Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at Virtual
Coffee, IO. Or you can email us
at podcast at Virtual coffee.io.
You can find the show notes.
Plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtual coffee.io.
Dan Ott: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.