Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season two, Episode
Two of the Virtual Coffee
podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their coding journey. And
they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. In this
episode of the podcast, we
talked with Lucia Cerchie, a
software engineer mom and
Arizona transplant. We talked
about the importance of having a
growth mindset asking questions
and pair programming. And we
also talked about the power of
community and feeling
comfortable asking questions and
asking for help. It was a great
conversation as always with
Lucia, and I know you're going
to enjoy it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from
what we do, and a random check
in question. Today's question
is, if you could write a book,
what genre would you write it
in? We hope you enjoy this
episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I am from a
small town in Ohio. I'm a front
end developer. And if I were to
write a book, I've written one
nonfiction, so I would not do it
again. in that genre. I would do
thriller, I would write a
thriller, I think, oh, super
thriller.
Dan Ott: A superhero thriller.
Nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yes.
Dan Ott: Cross genre. Hi, I'm
Dan, front end developer
from Lakewood, Ohio. And if I
could write a book, I have not
written any books. So I don't
have any past experience.
nonfiction. So you know, I think
I would go fantasy, but I feel
like with fantasy and thriller,
you really have to make sure
you've connected all the dots,
you know, and everything. So
which could be fun, but also is
a lot of work. But I feel like I
could push through it. It'd be
cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Fun to map
it out.
Dan Ott: Yeah. Alright, fantasy.
That's my answer.
Lucia Cerchie: Hey, I'm Lucia. I
am a software engineer from
sunny, Sunny Arizona. And if I
had to write a book, it would
definitely be fiction, and
probably in the sci fi realm,
because I've been reading a lot
of it recently. So yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Very cool.
Any good recommendations.
Lucia Cerchie: Um, I have been
reading a lot of the like, best
sci fi of this or that year
collections, like short stories,
and I really liked 2017. That
was a good year, and sci fi
short stories, apparently.
Dan Ott: Nice.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Cool. So
welcome to the podcast. It's
so good to have you here. It's
always nice to see you in
Virtual Coffee. And I know
that's changed a little bit
since you've taken a new job. So
it's good to to see you today.
And I always like to get started
with your origin story. So how
did you come to tech and where
you are right now?
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, I was a
teacher for four years and
transitioned into digital
marketing for some software as a
service startups. And I saw what
the software engineers were
doing there. And I liked it. So
I started coding last year.
Cool. And did you do a boot camp
or self taught? How did you kind
of make that transition? Yeah, I
did a self paced boot camp,
which really worked well for me
because I'm also a mom. And I
also enjoyed doing things
outside the boot camp, like
blogging my journey, and
networking with Virtual Coffee
and those types of things. It
was, it was it felt like a
really good choice for me, and
it's worked out well. So
Dan Ott: that's awesome.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, nice
as a self paced for me, too. And
it was pretty much the only
option for me as a mom, because
there there was no way that I
can just set aside that time for
an intense boot camp. That was
all day or whatever.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, I feel I
learned better too doing, you
know, eight hours versus 12
hours a day I think is healthier
pace.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Right. It's
so intense. And I think that
trying to balance mental health
and motherhood and career
changing. That's all that's a
lot of stuff to do. And if you
don't have any time and you're
super exhausted from doing that
all day, it just leaks into your
life in a lot of ways that are
usually not good.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, I got to
get that rest time in.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, so
you're an early career
developer, and you are a fairly
new mom. And so you've kind of
made a lot of transitions in the
last couple of years. So can you
kind of talk through what those
transitions were like for you
and how you navigated the
challenges?
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, yeah, they
were all pretty much happening
over one year, which is also you
know, the year that we've had
this pandemic going on. So there
was a lot of changes. Not all of
them welcome, because all the
things that happened because of
Coronavirus, but a lot of them
were very welcome, like the
birth of my daughter and the
discovery of my passion for
coding. And it's felt a little
bit like, like me, and my
daughter and my computer are a
little bit it's almost like an
ice floe. And like, anytime I
look up, it's like, oh, the
environments completely changed,
right? But we've got, I've got
these core things that are
anchoring me like my family. And
you know that my daily practice
of coding really helped me get
through the past years, it was
very helpful to have some things
that stayed the same, like
getting up every morning at the
same time. And, you know, still
having my family and my house
with me every single day like
that. Sometimes, you know, when
you're in the same house, the
same people, everybody knows now
that that can, can become a
strain, but it's also something
that you can really rely on, it
becomes a strength as well.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Right. I
love that. And so, I think, too,
there are a lot of parallels
between being a mom and being a
new mom, and the growth that you
experience and also like, career
changing, too, right? There's
these moments that can be really
great and powerful. And then
there are some that are so
challenging that like, Am I
going to make it through this
problem? I don't know if you had
anything like that? Or if if
there's any advice you want to
share to moms out there
listening as they're going
through this too?
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, yeah, moms
and and bootcamp students,
something that I tell every
bootcamp student is because I
came across my first really long
bug. And I thought was helpful
for me, too, is to remember what
I used to teach my students
about the growth mindset, which
is like, just because you don't
know something, now we're just
dealing with something that
doesn't mean you can't do it,
right. And when the first time I
hit like a three day bug, I was
like, Oh, my gosh, was I cut out
to do this? You really start to
start questioning yourself when
you're in your first big
challenges. But, I remember the
thing that I used to teach my
own students about the growth
mindset, I was like, Oh, I
understand why this was so hard
for them now, because it's hard
for me, but I have to like, I
think what I did was like, write
down what I was feeling about
it, and then write down, you
know, what the truth about the
situation was, which was that I
was learning about how to debug
things, and that it was going to
be fine. And you know, in a few
weeks, I'd have my website out
there. And that, that helped me
kind of externalize that growth
mindset. A lot better, was super
helpful, but it's also totally
normal to, you know, get the
first time the first huge
challenge and coding and feel
that feeling of like, Oh, no,
and am I cut out for this? You
know, it's something that I
think everybody may feel,
unless, you know, they're
completely bathed in that growth
mindset from early childhood,
which not everybody is. But
everybody may feel at one point
or another when they're on this
journey.
Dan Ott: I love that. Like
the...and i feel like that's
true, not just with career
change, you know, any big
transition or, you know, any,
any new thing you're trying to
get into, it's, there's
always...I don't know about
always, but it's a very common
thing, right to run into some
huge thing and and the "Am I cut
out for this" question is, I
don't know it's very real and
hard to sometimes get get
through you know, and and it'll
it'll interfere with actually
solving the problem or whatever
it is, you know, to fix that
Lucia Cerchie: That happens with
parenthood too, right? Like, I
look at my kid and like, Oh,
that's, that's my child. Whoa,
like, and and imposter syndrome
can reroute there too. And that
can make you it's, it can make
you compare yourself to other
parents, you know, in good or
bad ways, things like that. I've
it's less of like, when is my
daughter going to discover that
I'm not a mom, I'm three owls in
a trench coat and more like, Am
I a good parent, you know, I
mean, but at the same time, you
know, just like with coding,
it's like, I've got to where I
am now. I'll keep improving.
Your kid is alive. You know,
you're alive, you guys have this
relationship. And that's a
wonderful thing. And there's
there's nothing that can change
the power of that relationship.
So
Dan Ott: that's awesome.
Definitely, I've had plenty of
"am I cut out for this" moments
with the kids over the last
almost five years to have Ben's
about to be five on Sunday. So
well, I can relate anyway.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I've got an
11 year old and I still
sometimes feel like that. I did
this four times, I still am not
sure whether or not I am any
good at what I'm doing. But I
think it is, you know, you push
through those moments. And then
you think about those other
moments. And I always try and
tell people who are new to
coding to look at how much
they've grown. So I haven't made
any progress. But if you look at
where you were last month, or a
year ago, or even yesterday, you
probably have grown, sometimes
it's big leaps. And sometimes
it's tiny steps, but it's still
forward progress. Right. And I
think that it can be hard to
recognize those subtle moments,
but it it's super important.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, no, it's,
it's, it's so true. And it can
also be helpful to look at your
own children, I think, kind of
in the context of what they're
learning, because childhood is
an incredible time of growth,
and they make just such big
leaps and bounds, you know,
like, looking back on it. Last
year, I remember, like holding
my two and a half month old
daughter and one arm, she
couldn't hold her head up while
I was like, you know, writing my
first lines of JavaScript with
the other arm, and it's like,
oh, we both comes off, like
she's almost walking. And here I
am, you know, having dealt with
the databases and deployed
things. But I don't even know
how to pull something up in a
local host ,when I started.
Dan Ott: one thing you mentioned
earlier was, like a part of your
process as writing, you know,
like writing things down, like
writing, working, you know,
you're talking about working
through the huge bug or
whatever. And I've always, I've
been, I don't know, I like
noticed and admire, you're like,
just you're sort of...I don't
know what the right word is,
but...I don't know, you're
writing a lot. And, and I
thought that was really cool. I
was wondering if, if you, like,
if you started out with the plan
of, you know, learning and
writing as you learn, or if you
came to it naturally, or if it
was like part of an assignment
for your, you know, for your
boot camper, you know, like, how
did you get yourself to do that
as like, while you're, while
you're learning to code and
everything like that.
Lucia Cerchie: So at first, it
was definitely very intimidating
thinking of blogging, what I was
doing, because it felt like,
just another thing to learn to
do. But I think it was
eventually going to happen
anyway, because I write to
process almost everything in my
life. So learning, writing is
like a natural way for me to
learn something. So I eventually
started doing that just to be
able to process things. Or if I
wanted to learn something,
sometimes I had assigned myself
a blog post, you know, but I
just found that really, really
helpful way of going about it.
And yeah, it's just nice to have
something out there to, to you
also not just to learn
something, but to look at where
you like to have a marker of
where you were right, because
I've learned things I've I've
written blog posts that were
either just like, oh, that was
just the wrong way to think
about it, you know, or, this was
kind of like an older way of
going about approaching solving
this problem. And someone in the
comments brought up a new way to
do it. But that, like it records
that moment in time for me,
which I think is really helpful
just to see, okay, you know,
this is where I've come, this is
where I started. Yeah, just kind
of going with that whole growth
theme.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And I feel
like you push yourself so much,
or I don't know if this is a
natural thing, or if you work on
getting out of your comfort
zone. But you know, you're
blogging, we did our first round
of lightning talks in November,
and you're they're doing a talk
and you're you're competently
asking questions, which I think
is a really hard thing. And so,
you know, is this been pushing
yourself out of your comfort
zone? Or, you know, how do you
channel that confidence because
I think that is something that
that can be really hard to do.
Lucia Cerchie: I would say a
little bit of it is probably
being an extrovert in a
pandemic. So there's there's a
lot of me that wants to get out
there and communicate and all
the ways that I can't find out
which is not in person. So that
includes giving talks and
joining groups and asking
questions. But another part is,
um, something I've been trying
to do over the past year. And
this is this applies to I think,
parenting too, but it's like
your comfort zone is not a place
of growth, like it's okay to be
there for a little bit, you
know, if you need to just have
some time to rest, but it's
wherever improvement comes from
kind of like, being completely
out it like not completely
uncomfortable, like there's
psychological safety that always
needs to be there, right, but
but just being like, Oh, this is
new, this is something that I
haven't done before, you know.
And, yeah, it's a little
uncomfortable because of that.
But if I don't keep doing that,
there's no learning happening.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Let's talk
about, I want to kind of move
forward with the conversation
about all this stuff that you're
doing and this idea of
confidence. And, you know, I
want to touch maybe a little bit
more specifically on asking
questions and the experience
that you have with pairing
because I think that that's one
of the things that I missed out
on a lot at boot camp. And along
the way, some people had said,
like, well, you should try
pairing more. But it wasn't
naturally set up. And I didn't
understand the value until I
started working. Because you
learn and you grow so much. But
also it can be a really scary
experience. And I know that,
that a lot of people are
hesitant to do that. So, you
know, why? Why did you start
asking people to pair and how
was that experience?
Lucia Cerchie: Well, it was
really, I mean, it was because I
was comfortable in Virtual
Coffee, and provided a safe
environment for me to be like,
Oh, I running into this bug in
this framework I've never worked
with before I know you have,
would you like to pair with me?
Can you navigate me. And that's,
that's been the essence of a lot
of the pair programming. I
really like Martin Fowler's
article on it. But it also
doesn't have to fit into any of
those definitions, you know,
it's just two people same piece
of code. Another thing I've run
into out there that I think
least some of the intimidation
around pair programming is that
there's like a perception that
you have to like, I don't know,
reach a certain level or a
certain amount of tools to start
doing and it's like, no, like,
there's no reason you can't just
pay her on your first few lines
of HTML. You know, there's,
there's absolutely no reason. So
that's another thing that I just
think because it's out there,
that is just a perception that
needs to change.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's, that's
interesting. Just even the I
came to pairings sort of
organically, mostly through
Virtual Coffee to and hadn't
read any articles. I hadn't read
any of any of that stuff. And so
it never really even occurred to
me to like that people will be
hesitant or whatever about the
actual process, you know,
because I, I guess, I mean,
mostly because I just didn't
know, there was a formal process
to know. But I... you and I have
had some, like really good
pairing sessions, too, I found
as a teaching tool, it's like
one of my favorite modes to
write because, because it people
can just kind of like work
together and work through a
thing, you know, instead of...as
opposed to somebody asking, oh,
like, trying to copy whatever
the bug is in, you know, from
your console, and like hope
that, you know, like, somebody
can find the, the answer, you
know, like, like, just kind of,
like, hanging out and going
working through something
together. Always just seems
like, it's just one of my
favorite ways to both learn and
and like and helping, you know,
and teach.
Lucia Cerchie: And it's just,
it's it, like you said, there's
an efficiency aspect to it to
where you're not just going back
and forth. Like with
screenshots, trying to recreate
the environment. It's definitely
I think saves time. But also,
like, builds relationships
between programmers, you know,
and maybe you could say more
about this Dan or Bekah, but
I've heard a lot of a theme I've
heard in Virtual Coffee a lot is
that both navigator and driver
get to learn. It's not just one
or the other. That's, that
that's not how it goes. And I
was wondering as, as people who
have navigated a lot, I wonder
what that's been like for you
guys.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
want to say, you know, I've been
on both sides a lot in the last
year, and I have learned so
much. And I do think that you
hit on something, this idea of
psychological safety or feeling
comfortable asking within the
community, because I think that
that just kind of decreases the
feeling of like, I'm taking a
risk here. And like, what is the
risk really, if you pair with
someone and you don't know what
you're doing, you just don't
know. Right? And then you have
an opportunity to learn and you
have an opportunity to grow but
I know even when I've paired
with people on their projects
when they were asking for help,
I had to look stuff up and ask
questions and just that ability
to have the conversation, the
back and forth, we for sure,
we're both growing through that
conversation, whether it's how
we communicate with each other,
or I hadn't thought about it
that way, let's kind of explore
that and walk through, it can be
a really great way to get a
better understanding of
different ways that people
interact with code, how they
think about things, and that
inform your process going
forward. And so I think it's
been, you know, one of my
favorite things of the last year
being able to pair with so many
different people.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I totally agree.
I, the, I mean, it's, you're
always gonna learn things
looking at, like learning about
how people make, you know, solve
problems and their own way. And
every, every new code base has a
whole bunch of stuff to learn
about, even if it's tech that,
you know, you know, extensively,
you know, there's always stuff
to learn. And the, as I say, the
driver, navigator, like, thing
was never really a formal thing
in my mind, you know, and I know
that it's, it can be helpful for
people to like, sort of navigate
the social structure, but at
least at the beginning, before,
before you've like, worked
together enough to build up a
rapport, you know, but, you
know, it's just such a useful
tool, and you're right, like,
both, like, everybody should be
alert, like, everybody should be
learning all, like, can be
learning all the time. We I've
heard stories of people having,
you know, bad experiences with
pairing, and most of the time,
it's because of usually the
person who is hoping to learn
something, you know, and ask him
for help. And then the other
person, I don't know, just like,
I don't really know what the
right phrase is, but just drives
without any input, you know,
like, you know, like, if we're
gonna use the driver, navigator,
then like, the driver is
driving, but not like actually
asking for navigation, right?
Or, you know, something like
that, right? The just kind of
like powering through something
without actually communicating
and working together. And, and I
feel like that just misses the
point, you know, I'm sure
there's a million YouTube videos
of whatever that problem is, you
know, that somebody could go
watch, like, as a passive
observer, you know, but the, the
pairing, I mean, it's like, it's
in the name, right? It's like,
actually a pair, it's not just
teaching or something, or not
just learning, you know, it's,
working together
Lucia Cerchie: yeah, yeah, I
think, like, there's a lot of
strict definitions out there,
right. But I think it can at
least be helpful for the people
in the session to talk to each
other about it, like, just lay
some expectations like this is
how long we're going to do it.
This is what this relationship
is, we're a team on whatever
this is, and we're learning from
each other. You know, it's just
a few things like that before,
before we get started. That way,
you can avoid, hopefully, some
of those experiences.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: When I did
coding club, pre pandemic, one
of the rules was, you could
never take the keyboard or the
mouse from someone else, right.
And I think that's kind of what
happens in these situations. So
they're not necessarily
physically taking it, especially
if you are remote. But if you
just kind of, don't communicate,
you don't talk through things,
then you're you, you are taking
that away, you're taking away
that person's voice, you're
taking away their ability to
play an active role. And both
people, the driver and the
navigator should be taking an
active role in what's happening.
Lucia Cerchie: I like that a
lot. And just thinking about it
more. That seems like a really
great analogy to describe what
happens and could be extended to
I think other situations. In
tech too just it's just a lot to
think about.
Dan Ott: I was just imagining,
physically, like pulling a
keyboard from somebody, you
know, like, I don't know, sorry.
There's a scene...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Even like
Oh, just just give me the
computer and then you know, they
just like move it and start
doing the typing. It's Anyway,
there's a scene.
Dan Ott: Oh, yeah, no, no, it
was a NCIS or some one of those
shows. And the, the two tech
people like one person was like
typing and trying to solve the
thing. And the other person
said, move over. And instead of
like that person moving over in
the second person typing on the
keyboard, they both just started
typing on the keyboard, just
different sides of the keyboard
at the same time, which well,
it's it's funny, I don't think
very effective pairing method,
but....
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, but I think
it's in a way. The fact that
most parent has moved to zoom
has made us better communicators
because it can get a little bit
frustrating when you're like, no
the the button at the top right
at, Cuz I don't know where I
left from, right? And like, oh,
the other right? Sometimes the
days you have to think about the
words that you're using to
describe what you mean. And
yeah, there's that there's kind
of a list of little helpful
things you could do, like, go by
line number, not by like, what
the word is, and the function.
Things like that.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I think that's, I
think that's good advice. And
like, thinking about that,
there's like a lot of general
things like that, that help. And
if you pair with the same
person, you know, enough, like,
I feel like it's two or three,
but you start to learn, you
know, how to navigate, you know,
the way that their brain works,
or whatever, you know, which is
different for everybody. That's
kind of cool, too. Yeah, I mean,
it's just like, with everything,
it's just like, the more you do
it, the more effective effective
it'll be, you know, for yourself
and for your team, stuff like
that. Um, so you recently
started a new job, right?
Lucia Cerchie: I did Yeah, it's
at StepZen we're "one API for
all your data", that's the
tagline. And I'm really enjoying
it. It's, it's been great. I am.
It says, a startup and we're all
remote. We have a meeting every
day. Stand up meeting every day.
At least one. And then yeah, so
I've been it's, it's fun. It's
been fun meeting everybody. But
it's also I think, this is
probably experience, a lot of
people are out there about
spending interesting starting a
job without having met anyone at
it. You know, be hope to meet
each other someday, but it's,
it's still not going to be
within the next few months. And
that's also been something
that's been our point Virtual
Coffee too. I would just love to
fly and see some of you Okay,
now, but it's, it's, it's it's
been tough with, but it's also
like, opened up some, some doors
like I would, which I think I'm
trying to think here. Yeah,
like, I don't know that I
would've joined Virtual Coffee
if the pandemic hadn't happened.
And my, the startup that I'm at
expanded to remote because of
it. And that's how, that's why I
was eligible, you know, cuz they
were, I think, California,
specifically beforehand, so,
yeah, yeah.
Dan Ott: Is there I was really
just gonna ask if there's any
pairing going on, you know, at
the new at the new job, or if
that's part of the company at
all?
Lucia Cerchie: I haven't seen it
as part of like, that defined
protocol. But I've paired a lot
with people doing that. Yeah,
yeah, it's been good. It's been
been fun. It's definitely a
culture where I feel very
comfortable asking questions.
And it's, it's encouraged. So I
have been appreciating that a
lot. feels a little bit like
pairing in Virtual Coffee. So
that's, that's awesome.
Dan Ott: What What is, what is
like one way that they made you
comfortable being able to ask
questions?
Lucia Cerchie: it was really,
like I've said, so far, it's
been modeling. So I've just seen
everybody from the CEO to like
the hybrid just before me, not
that we're like on a flat
structure right now. But they've
all been comfortable, just like
popping the slack and being
like, Hey, I run into this
error, like, anybody know what's
up here. And that has really,
really helped me feel more
comfortable, just come out there
and asking my own questions. And
there have been some, some of my
teammates have been very strong
in showing that, like, you know,
they've been in the field for
many more years than I have. And
they're, they're still have
like, a growth mindset. And I
just appreciate that so much.
You know, I think those are, I'm
new to the idea of like, what
you call psychological safety
backup, but I've, I've a feeling
that that's part of it, you
know? So, yeah, I'd like to hear
more of like about what you
think is part of that
definition.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, we're
gonna have an episode coming up
this season, that's going to
talk a lot about psychological
safety. And I'm really excited
for that. Because I think, you
know, it's, I think I've heard
that term before, but hadn't
really thought about it that
much until hearing so many
different stories through
Virtual Coffee, and especially
the places that do not create
psychological safety, right,
where there's micromanaging
going on and there's constant.
There's a lack of appreciation,
there is a lack of
acknowledgement that you're
making progress. And instead,
it's just this, you need to keep
doing these things over and
over. And it doesn't matter how
much you do, because it will
never be enough. And there are
people who will always be right.
And there are people who will
always be wrong, right? Like,
they're just these behaviors
that that are totally
unreasonable. And I think I'm
totally miss that you have a
human being in front of you,
right. And so instead of like,
recognizing this is a person,
and I want to support this
person, it's like, this is a
being that does work. And I only
care about their productivity,
and how much I can control that
more than anything else. Right.
So there's a dehumanization,
that happens in environments
where there's a lack of
psychological safety. And so
when you are in a positive
environment, I think sometimes,
that's when you really recognize
that, oh, wait a minute, maybe
that place didn't allow me to
grow. Because when you're so
caught up in just trying to feel
safe, it's very hard to grow.
You're just in protection mode.
Lucia Cerchie: Right? Yeah. Cuz
because you won't. Yeah, you're
gonna be inside your comfort
zone out of defense at that
point, right. Yeah, which is
something I've been very lucky
so far, I believe, just with
Virtual Coffee, and at my new
job, just to have been in
environments of safety like
that, but I, like, you know, I'm
trying to think of times where I
was like, I was at a, a
restaurant job as a teenager, or
there was definitely no
psychological safety present
whatsoever. So I'm sure
everybody has had an experience,
and I think talking about it
will help people define those
experiences and help them avoid
them in the future. So I think
that's going to be a good
episode. I'm looking forward to
it.
Dan Ott: Yeah, the the topic of
being feeling comfortable asking
questions, I feel like comes up
a lot in our in virtual coffees,
you know, discussions with, you
know, with newer devs.
I lost my point, I don't really
know... I was just gonna say
like, it's a pretty common,
like, struggle that I think
there's somebody who does
struggle with is being able to
feel comfortable asking
questions, or like, you know,
showing that it's okay to ask
questions. And I was just gonna
say, it's really cool. That
your, your, your new company at
StepZen, like they, the
modeling, you know, the modeling
that behavior is, I'm pretty
sure how you phrased it. And I
think that's perfect. Like,
that's the way that like, it
seems to me, the best way to, to
do that, right, is to have more
experienced devs model it
because, as we all know, or
should know, at least, at least,
more experienced devs also still
have lots of questions all the
time, you know, like, it's just
a very natural normal thing. For
a developer. It's just part of
being a developer, right, is not
knowing a thing. And then like,
I don't know, you like work on
it. And then he asks you, you
know, you get stuck and ask
questions. Like, it's just like,
this circle of life
Lucia Cerchie: It's also a part
of being human, right?
Dan Ott: Yes. Yes.
Lucia Cerchie: And I think it
comes up, I mean, it should come
up probably every professional
field, right, because being
human means to learn. But I
think it comes up a lot in our
field, because it changes so
quickly. And that just means
you're learning a lot all the
time. And there are, I think,
some perceptions out there in
tech that like, you might just
be born being extremely
authentic and extremely natural
coder. It's like that's, I mean,
you know, as really, anybody can
learn how to do it, but you have
to invest the time. And that's,
I think that's important to get
out there, there too. Yeah, or
so.
Dan Ott: Yeah. And I think the
other another piece of that is
that so many people learn on
their own in various ways. Like
both of you, you know, did and I
mean, and I did too, like, it's
you know, you come up you come
at it at your own angle, you
know, and I don't know there's,
there's wait until you work at a
company there's there's or until
you find a community like
Virtual Coffee there's like you
know, your peers or it's hard to
like it's hard to know you know,
how to find the like normalized
behavior for you know, what,
what is normal for a new
developer or, and if if most of
what you do is read to it, like
follow Twitter, follow like
people with have like millions
of followers on Twitter or, you
know, blog posts where, who
knows who it is, it can be easy
to get the perception that like,
it's important to just know
everything or, you know, the
only successful people like know
everything and don't ever ask
questions, which is just like,
very much not the case, you
know? So
Lucia Cerchie: yeah, yeah. And
that's, that's kind of it makes
me think of parenting too, you
know, it's like, yes. But the
thing about parenting, I think
this is it kind of taught me how
to do this, when I started
learning to code, too, is like,
I don't have time to not ask for
help when I need it anymore. I
mean, it's just like, I have it,
I have a daughter, and I'm
responsible for her. And if I
need help, being responsible for
her, I am going to ask for that
help right away, you know. And
when it came to coding, like in
college, I used to, like, sit
and struggle over things for
hours and hours and hours before
asking someone to help me with
it, you know. And that, you
know, there is there is
definitely you want to have the
experience of your like three
days to a week to who knows how
long working on that one bug,
because everybody's gonna have
that, and it will come up again.
And again, I'm not saying it's
not part of it. But but but
like, when I was doing boot
camp, when I needed to ask for
help, I was gonna go do that. As
soon as I realized it would
become more valuable for me to
learn that from someone else
than for me to keep struggling.
Because there is a balance,
there's like, there's value in
the struggle and learning how to
do things yourself. But there's
also a point where it's like,
okay, the cost benefit analysis
makes it such that I need to go
ask for help right now, you
know, and that's, that's been
something that's been super
helpful.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's a great
point to keep in mind. Right,
especially once you're working
for somebody is, you know,
you're spending their money,
right when you're working. And I
forget who was one of our
guests, I don't know if it was,
I guess, or somebody on a
Virtual Coffee, like just one of
our talks, but somebody had a
company that worked for had sort
of a sliding scale?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Drew, I
think
Dan Ott: Was it Drew? Yeah. So
we like so they had like a sort
of general rule of if you're, if
you're like, stuck, like
spinning wheel stuck for x,
like, an hour or something, you
know, that, like, that's when
you should reach out and ask a
question or, you know, something
like that. But then on certain
projects, you know, they would
change the scale, you know, they
all sort of knew what that
meant. And then the the managers
or whoever would, you know,
running a project would say,
Okay, this project is like,
there's a lot of more moving
pieces, or I don't know, it's
higher priority, or something
like that. And so, you know, for
this project, we're going to
bump that up to half an hour and
seven hours, you know, like
that. And I think that was kind
of a cool, it was a cool way to
approach it, that  modulating,
like how, how long you take to,
you know, dig into a problem
before you reach out and, you
know, things like that can
change per team per person, and
will change over your, of
course, the course of your
career, too. And...I would say
personally, it doesn't get
easier, like trying to figure
that like when that line is, you
know, yeah, it's like, it's not
always easy to figure out.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah. And then if
you're on the more junior side,
and you're asking, sometimes
what's in your head is like, Oh,
no, am I gonna waste their time,
but I was recently I realized,
you have to flip the tables,
like, you know, you're, you're
on the clock here. You're gonna
save some time by by asking for
help. And again, yeah.
Dan Ott: Yeah. Yeah. And I mean,
you're, like you said, this,
the, the struggle is like
important too. You know, like,
it's like, obviously, you don't
want to just like, it's the
second you get stuck, you know,
ask random question, but I don't
know. It's just something to
learn in practice. But it's just
like, the idea of being able to,
like, feel uncomfortable at
being able to ask questions is,
is very important. And it's
something to take art and
practice, as well.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah. Something I
tell myself, which I always tell
my students is like, what can
they do to take away your
birthday? What are they gonna
do?
Dan Ott: That'd be so sad,
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah. Nobody has
the power to do that. So I'm
just gonna go and ask a
question.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
think, you know, Lucia at you
and I both come from teaching
backgrounds. And for me, it was,
it almost made it harder to ask
questions, because I had spent
10 years like in front of the
classroom answering questions,
right. And there was an
expectation that I would know
all of the answers to all of the
questions and there's a total
different mindset in tech. So it
took me a while to try and
transition from those like learn
habits of you don't ask the
questions because you're the one
that should be answering them.
But I think you've done a much
better job than I have. But how
has your background I guess, in
teaching kind of informed how
you've approached all of this.
Lucia Cerchie: Um, so I was a
literacy coach. And that meant I
was dealing with a lot of
students from very different
backgrounds. And a lot of them
had learning differences.
Because of, I was meeting
students who, usually, we're
falling below the mark for
reading, right. Um, and so I
think it gave me a, it made me
more like, understanding of
myself when I was running into a
problem. I was like, okay, like,
you know, you're a new mom, and
it's a pandemic, and have a lot
going on. So maybe like, instead
of, you know, imposing needless
suffering on yourself, go for a
walk and take a break, and then
come back to this later, with a
fresh, fresh brain. And that I
think it's important for
everybody to be like, this kind
of goes back to pairing but for
me to be on the teaching and
learning side. Cuz both both
coding and teaching are in my
family, like, I have a lot of
uncles who do those two
professions. And my dad went
from here taught for 20 years,
then he went back to get his
PhD. And after he came back from
getting his PhD, he told me
like, I am so gentle with my
students now because I
understand the strains that go
on outside of just student life.
Like they're, they're not just a
student right now to me, like
they have everything there pull
people, and going back to school
for him while being a dad helped
him understand that. And I
think, again, just having that
perspective with yourself when
you're learning something new is
is really important. Just like,
again, keep going. I can't get
stuck though. Like just take a
break and then come back to it
because there's there's no
reason there's no rule that says
you can't just like take 10
minutes to breathe. Yeah, and I
get I get so bad that I
breathing like while coding. Oh
my gosh, sometimes I realize
like, I'm dizzy from going
purple because I like have been
holding my breath while
debugging it's.
Dan Ott: Yeah. All right. Well,
I'm glad that I'm not the only
person in the world that...
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I just
really like did that the other
day and then I googled it and
like, it's a it's a thing.
So it's like,
computer...something
Dan Ott: Alright, I'm gonna have
to Google it, because I
definitely do that I like will
be breathing like incredibly
shallowly, just through my nose,
and like I don't, man that's
Lucia Cerchie: I don't know
what's triggering that, I feel
like there's a bear chasing me
or
Dan Ott: maybe that's like,
fight or flight or something.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Email
apnea, that's what it's called
Lucia Cerchie: email apnea.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah.
Dan Ott: Oh, my God.
Lucia Cerchie: Wow.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. The
14. Yes. So a former Apple
executive coined that term, or
it's credited to her Linda
Stone. But it's it is it's the,
it describes the long periods
where you go without breathing
or hold your breath without
realizing it while at your desk
or while at work. I like to do
it all during the day. And I
just noticed it the other day, I
was like, oh, I've been holding
my breath for a while now. When
I get into deep thought mode, I
don't know my brain needs to be
reminded that it should be
breathing.
Lucia Cerchie: Because I got so
much going on. I'm not gonna
modulate breathing.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Not
Important.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, that's why
I like yoga. That's a whole
other thing...
Dan Ott: No, yeah, that I mean,
that kind of stuff. The taking a
walk the breathing. I mean, it's
so important and hard, hard to
do without practice. I mean, I
assume it gets better with, with
practice, I couldn't exactly
tell you because I'm still
really bad at it. But it's so
important. It's so useful, like
such a useful tool, even to
solving problems, right? I mean,
just like you were saying that
just like, take the walk, you
know, go away from your
computer, and it will be better.
Like, it's like, every time I do
it, it I'm like, why don't I
just do this every time? You
know,
Lucia Cerchie: yeah, haven just
like do a tour, like load the
dishwasher. And then like in the
middle of a job like, Oh, I need
to check my environment
variables ... staring at your
screen, it sometimes becomes
unproductive.
Dan Ott: Yes, absolutely.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I listen to
a...oh sorry,
Dan Ott: No ahead
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I listened
to a podcast recently where a
neurologist was talking about
that. And that was the first
time when I was like, Oh, yeah,
maybe I should listen to
people's advice. But once you
hit a certain age, it's hard to
create, like neuroplasticity or
whatever in your brain. And so
you have to approach it
differently. So as a kid, like
you could keep going through
that and trying and trying and
Trying, and you would learn it
because of, you know, your
ability to create those pathways
as a kid. But like, once you get
older, it's harder to do. And
the better tactic he was saying
was, you go until the point of
frustration, and then like,
maybe a little bit more, and
then you take a break, and then
you go back to it and keep going
in that pattern. And as adults,
that's how our brain creates
those pathways that we need to
learn. And I thought, Okay,
well, that kind of makes sense.
And taking that walk like this
is, this is a strategy for
learning and growing. And so
there's like, the science behind
that, too.
Dan Ott: I, my wife, was, I
don't remember exactly where she
learned this, but was this
phrase about like, treating
yourself like, this is actually
like, abusive, you know, I mean,
like, not not taking the breaks
like not, you know, like
treating this. I mean, it
affected me because it was like,
okay, the way I treat myself
sometimes where I'm like, really
deep into something, and it
helps to say just like, imagine
if, instead of yourself, you're
like, forcing some other person
to sit at this desk until this
thing is solved, and like,
Lucia Cerchie: And you're not
allowed to breathe,
Dan Ott: Not allowed to breath,
not allowed to go to the
bathroom or whatever, like, you
know, like, you must sit there
and just imagine you're doing
that to somebody else instead of
yourself, you know, and that's
been, like, incredibly
instructive to me. Like, and
helpful. Like, I don't know, it
was just like, a weird way.
Like, you could kind of like,
imagine, like, you're making
these choices, but like, for
somebody else, and your choices
are going to be probably much
different than, than what you're
forcing yourself to do.
Sometimes, you know, it's like,
you know, I see my kid, like,
whatever I'm like, okay, he
needs a break. Like, let's just,
you know, you know, I mean,
like, this is very obvious,
sometimes with a three year old
or four year old. Like, we just
need to remove him from the
situation for a little bit, you
know, and I, if it was myself,
you know, I wouldn't, you know,
he just kind of keep like,
banging my head against my
keyboard or whatever. And if I
saw somebody doing that, I'd be
like, Hey, go...go take a walk,
you know?
Lucia Cerchie: My daughter makes
a noise, like, ehhhhhh time to
remove her from the situation.
But yeah, it's hard. And she
does, she'll do that for like
two minutes straight. But yeah,
it's, it's hard to monitor these
things for yourself, just
because you can't, it's
sometimes it's as simple as you
just can't see yourself, because
your eyes are in your own head.
So. But it's hard to find ways
to be able to monitor yourself.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We kind of
talked about this in Gant's
podcast, Episode Two, where he
was saying, just this idea of
knowing your body and the things
that you do, and then kind of
exploring, like, Oh, my body did
this thing. Why did it do that
thing? Or what's going on here?
And it's really interesting to
kind of do that monitoring as we
go through these different
problems, right? Because I think
like, you know, I was holding my
breath, or, you know, whatever.
There are certain, like, our
body gives us the indications,
but we just keep, we're ignoring
the notifications of our body,
right? Like, but approaching
that and saying, like, Okay,
look, here's some evidence that
there this thing is about to
happen, or I'm getting a little
bit better about like, that was
my anxiety of things like, Oh, I
just felt this way. Now, I know
what comes next here. And this
is the opportunity for me to try
and move in a different
direction. And I think that
those things like recognizing
those are super important. And,
and that's how we help ourselves
to grow to rate by listening to
what our body or whatever is
telling us.
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, 100% Yeah,
it's amazing how smart your body
is.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, so
you have been going through this
journey, right, of a lot of
different things that you've
talked about here. And so what
are some of the most important
tools that you think have helped
you to make it through and get
to where you are now?
Lucia Cerchie: Oh, man, that's a
that's a big question. I'm
because there's so many things
that said, I've had a supportive
family, you know, and supportive
friends. I've I've had a year in
digital marketing, which is
really helpful. I think for job
searching. I could probably do a
whole nother podcast. But um,
I've Yeah, I think the the
family and friends thing is
really big too, though, because,
you know, like, my husband and
I, we were both working from
home now. And we've been on our
computers eight hours a day with
a baby If you know, during the
pandemic, and that's not easy.
So we like constantly been
having conversations about like,
Okay, how are you doing? Do you
need any support here? And like
how are you feeling is like
this, you have the baby from
this hour to that hour and a
half or from that or to that or
is working for today, you know.
So during that has been been
really key and so has having
Virtual Coffee, because I
started when you can, like go
somewhere and meet people. So
most of my friends I've made in
tech or online, you know, and
the support I get there's as
online that a lot of that has
come from, from Virtual Coffee
also from like the willingness
to just ping random people who
seem like they know things and
be fun to talk to you on
Twitter, that can actually
that's less safe than like
within the community of Virtual
Coffee, obviously. But it's also
had some really good results.
For me, I have enjoyed talking
to some people. And they're
like, there's one guy I made
like a recursive tweet. His name
is Oisn Moran. And he was like,
just willing to talk to me for a
half hour about how he worked at
the API to like, it was a
retweet of the same tweet. That
was the like, it's hard to even
describe it. But he did. It was
pretty cool to talk about it.
Yeah, so just just being able
to, I think rely on community is
really important for anybody
just starting this journey out.
Because you can't, I mean,
sometimes it feels like you're
coding on an island, because
you're in your house on your
computer coding, but you're not,
you know, and nobody can code on
an island and learn how to do
it, especially by themselves. So
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: there's no
Wi Fi on the island....
I think that what you just said
about, like, randomly pinging
people is been one of the things
that I decided to do this year.
I don't know why, like we you
know, what are you going to
lose? And so then I've been able
to talk to people who have so
much more experienced than I do,
and almost everybody has been
really generous with their time.
And in walking me through those
things. And I think that, you
know, sometimes that feels
risky, but it's not.
Lucia Cerchie: I mean, there's
like a safety thing with like
zoom bombing, you know, but if
you pick someone who was like
public enough on Twitter to be
accountable, then I think that's
there's that certain level of,
of safety there. But yeah,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah, for
sure. I am one of the other
things that you said that I
really liked is you have this
background in digital marketing.
And that's been helpful. And I
was talking to a hiring manager
at a pretty large company
recently. And one of the things
that he was saying was, you need
to people need to approach the
job search, like it's marketing,
because you are marketing
yourself. And you found a job. I
feel I feel like it was pretty
quickly. And so can you just
talk a little bit about how that
how those two kind of work
together?
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, um, so I
finished boot camp right before
I started this job. And I
hadn't, I was thinking of a job
search or something that I was
going to be doing eight hours a
day, which is ended up not being
the case, which was nice. So I
was what I was doing during boot
camp, it was and it was a long
boot camp, too, right. It's
like, nine months, though, is
every day I was pinging people
like random people to talk to,
just to start building my
community. A was tweeting, I did
the 100 days of code thing on
Twitter that gets you in the
habit of sharing what you're
doing pretty consistently, and
that was helpful. I was
blogging, I was going to Virtual
Coffee. And if I saw a job that
really made sense for me to
apply to in the sense of that,
like, I either knew the person
or they had approached me first,
then I would apply and so that
was what my job search was like.
And I had several interviews,
too. And that that was that's
what it was, like, I feel like
it was like, you know him to
like, Okay, this is I should
make a portfolio site because I
can't just have these skills, I
need to communicate them, you
know, and I need to do that in a
very online way. And that
there's just a bunch of things
that I habits that I naturally
had from a year in digital
marketing, like consistency is
more important than volume when
it comes to like being on
Twitter, for example, or things
like I know, just like, this is
a nice color scheme and it's a
little bit different from every
other color scheme I've seen out
there so I don't use it for my
portfolio website. You know, now
I want to go back and redesign
it so I realized it was not
accessible. But you know, like
there there are things like
that, that do that. Do help us
And, you know, I'd love to, you
know, maybe do a brown bag on
that for Virtual Coffee people
because it's in a way, it's,
it's almost not fair that that's
the way it is now, because
sometimes, like, there's a lot
of these jobs where you're like,
you aren't doing marketing, as
you're coding. That's, that's a
lot of what my job is like right
now. But some of them, you'll
just be coding click, you know,
and it's, it's, it's hard,
because you, it feels like you
have to learn two jobs in order
to get one, you know, but there
are a few tips, I think that can
really, really help with that.
And investing little bits of
time along the way through your
boot camp can be really helpful
and make it a lot easier
afterwards, I think,
Dan Ott: Do you...like, what
piece of ... aside from actually
learning the coding part. Not to
like "aside" that, cuz that's
hard. Everything. Like, what do
you think was the most impactful
thing that you did over that,
you know, over that? To help
like to help this process? Like,
was it the blogging? Or was it
you know, like, if you had to
just pick like the top the top
of the list? That's hard. Yeah.
Like what, like, what do you
think the most impactful thing
was, that helped you, you know,
like, find a pretty awesome job.
Lucia Cerchie: I mean, I could
ask the people who hired
me...but, but like, as far as
like, getting the all the
interviews that I did get, um, I
think I did not take like this
scattershot approach of like
just applying to literally every
job on LinkedIn. And indeed,
I've heard that has worked for
some people, you know, so I'm
not saying, like, the way that I
did is the only way but I did
make sure that I had a
connection every time I apply
it, and I, you know, would
mention it in my cover letter.
And so that that was definitely
helpful. But I think blogging
about what I did was probably
the best, the best thing. And it
was, it can be a little bit
difficult to learn how to do it,
but I had done it in my previous
job. So it was a little bit
easier to pick it up. But then
again, try to think what I'm
trying to say here, if you've
never done it before, you
shouldn't be afraid of it, you
know, like, just pick it up. It
doesn't have to be a fancy
topic. It doesn't have to be
even a new topic, if you're if
you're just starting out just
because blogging is new to you.
And what you're trying to learn
to do is learn how to blog.
Right? So yeah, it's the most
important thing there, I think,
is to just get started because
it shows in a way that someone
who's looking at your portfolio
can digest that you've think
about, you know, these things
that you're thinking. And if
they've gotten to that point,
then it can maybe even like
segue into a conversation later,
which, which has happened a lot
interviews, it's kind of a
natural way to discuss something
that you're interested in, which
is, which is always I think, I
think that's a good strategy in
interviews is try to direct the
conversation, something you're
interested in, because you want
to, you want to show your
passion. And unless you're
actually interested in it,
you're not going to be able to
show your passion for that it's
not going to naturally come up
in your tone of voice and your
face. Right. So
Dan Ott: I think that's great. I
think it's great. I'm glad you
like it. Maybe I led you there.
But I'm glad you said love
blogging, I think that it's
incredibly important for
especially for developers who
are hoping to find a job, it's
like one of those things that
will, in my opinion set you far
apart more much more than like a
random portfolio side project.
Do you think that isn't? You
know, you know, like, those
projects are good for learning
and important to do you know,
but if you're not like reading
about it, like alongside then
it, you know, it doesn't mean
much to somebody who's like
looking at your portfolio site,
like
Lucia Cerchie: Yeah, because
occasionally, unfortunately,
some boot camps really hold your
hand through those or all have
the same type of portfolio
project, you know, so,
Dan Ott: right, absolutely. And
there's no way to really know
what, if any of that is the
case, if as somebody who's just
looking at them, right, but if I
can read about your struggles,
you know, going through it or
what you learned or like,
whatever, however you just like
approaching it, it makes it
makes a huge difference. Plus,
it shows some communication
skills, which like, even if
you're just developing and not
doing any marketing,
communication skills remain
very, very, very, very, very
important. and writing skills,
you know, I mean, writing is
just part of communication, but
it's, it's, it's, if you can
manage to convince your brain
that it's part of like learning
how to be a good developer. You
know, which I think it is, but
yeah, I feel like, you know, for
anybody listening who's on the
fence about it, I feel like it
will, it will go a long way.
Lucia Cerchie: And it's okay to
not know everything in a blog
post, like part of Yeah, I think
almost a main thing and
communication is understanding
what you don't understand.
That's, that's always where you
want to start a conversation to
if you're not sure, with the
other person, but being able to
define that as is a huge, huge
thing.
Dan Ott: Yes. 100% agree. Yep.
Again, we're talking to again,
about the exact same thing about
about that, like, starting
blogging in you know, not
knowing everything and like,
that it can actually be a
virtue, you know, like, you
know, and help your, you know,
people reading trust you more if
you are sort of honest about
what you don't know, you know,
Lucia Cerchie: that kind of goes
into ask him for help to just
it's okay to be vulnerable
without being apologetic, you
know?
Dan Ott: Yes, it is.
Lucia Cerchie: It is not your
fault that you don't know.
Right. But you can admit that
you don't. And that's that's,
that's fine.
Dan Ott: Absolutely.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
think that's such great advice,
and you hit on so many important
things in this episode. I really
love that idea of it's about
consistency, more than volume, I
think that you said and the idea
of like, being open and being
out there and communicating. So
thank you so much for talking
through your journey and for
being here with us on the
podcast.
Lucia Cerchie: Thank you. Thank
you for giving me a platform to
have this conversation on
really. And I've always enjoyed
talking to you guys.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at Virtual
Coffee, IO. Or you can email us
at podcast at Virtual coffee.io.
You can find the show notes plus
you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtual coffee.io
Lucia Cerchie: Please subscribe
to our podcast and be sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week.