Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season two, Episode
Three of the Virtual Coffee
podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Joining
us today is Glen McCallum, a
software engineer from Victoria,
Canada. Glen does back end
development in C sharp and SQL
while managing a team of eight
engineers for the second largest
independent book distributor in
the United States. I really
enjoyed our conversation with
Glen. We talked about his career
journey, some hard decisions
he's had to make along the way,
and the unexpected ways that
Tech has entered his life.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from
what we do, and a random check
in question. Today's question
is, you have your own late night
talk show. Who do you invite as
your first guest? We hope you
enjoyed this episode. Hey, I'm
Bekah, I'm from a small
town in Ohio. I am a front end
developer. And if I had my own
late night talk show, I think my
first guest would be Mindy
Kaling because she does lots of
different stuff. She's super
smart and funny. And I think she
would be fantastic to talk to.
Dan Ott: Yeah, she's really
cool. That this is really hard,
because there's just so many,
you know, like, potentials. By
Oh, sorry. Hi, I'm Dan. From
Lakewood, Ohio. I do fronted
development. And if I had a late
night talk show, my first guess
I'm just gonna go with recency
bias. We most watching a lot of
Brooklyn nine nine and Terry
Crews is just like one of my
favorite people. And he's, he
seems very, very cool and
interesting. Like in the real
world, too. So that's, that's
who I would have as my guest.
Glen McCallum: Hi, I'm Glen
McCallum. I live in Victoria,
Canada. I'm still learning
software development. But I have
my own team, I manage a team of
software developers.
If I had my own talk show, my
knee jerk answer to this one was
Mr. Rogers. I have such a
special place in my heart for
him. But at the same time, I
didn't want to have like the
awkwardness of a stranger. I
really got to meet someone. I
wanted someone other than a
stranger though.
So the name I'm going to put out
there as a name you've never
heard of is Robert C. Gay. And
it's someone I met by chance he
does private equity investment,
and dropped it all to do service
and charity work in Western
Africa, and had this chance
meeting with him and heard him
speak. It was absolutely
riveting. So I'd want to talk to
him for another full hour if I
could.
Dan Ott: That's, that's awesome.
Yeah, I like I started going
down the road of like, actually
interesting people, but that
might not make a good TV
commercial, you know. And then
like, I don't, I got very
confused, so I just like kept it
to celebrities. But this is
another thing I could do a whole
hour long episode just about
some of these questions.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That would
be fun. Glen, thanks so much for
being here. We are very, very
happy to have you today on the
podcast. So thanks for agreeing.
We always like to get started
with the origin story, where you
came from and how you got to
where you are. So just the the
short version of how did you get
into tech?
Glen McCallum: Well, originally,
and this goes way back, I, I
wanted to be a large animal
veterinarian. And I went through
pre veterinary in school and I
didn't get into veterinary
school and there's only one
veterinary school in Western
Canada. And they get like 200
applicants and accept 20
positions. And so I was ranked
low 30s as I remember. So it
wasn't mean it wasn't too
discouraging from that
standpoint. But you know, when
you're, when you're at that age,
you just feel like you need to
keep moving on with life. And so
I had taken a computer science
elective course I taken two of
them Just because I thought you
can't go wrong with some
computer science. And I took, I
didn't take like the computer
science for non computer science
people, I wanted to take real
computer science. So I took the
year one programming courses.
And I got a pluses in both of
them.
And this school sent me a letter
asking me if I wanted to join
the computer science program.
And so it all kind of happened
at the same time that I got this
one rejection letter from, from
Veterinary College, and got this
invitation letter to study
computer science. And I was
like, Alright, let's do this.
And so that was a transition
moment. And that's kind of what
got me started on this pathway.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That is
awesome. And well, you've been
coming to Virtual Coffee for a
while to do you remember how you
found out about Virtual Coffee?
Glen McCallum: Yeah, absolutely.
I guess I have to credit it back
to Jesse. Because I heard Jesse,
on a podcast months before
pandemic. And this interesting
thing came out is called moms
who code which just sounded
fascinating to me. Because I
mean that that notion where I
mean, your family still comes
before code, but you still have
that.
That career integrated, just, I
mean, secretly, I want to be a
mom who codes really. And so I
started following some moms who
code stuff on Twitter. And from
that came this Virtual Coffee.
And when it first came up, I
thought it was for moms who
code. And initially, I thought,
that would be really cool to
meet some people. But I didn't
come because I thought it was
for the moms. And later on, I
started seeing, you know,
retweets or lights just popping
up in my stream from, from guys
who are going to Virtual Coffee.
And that's when I decided to
join for the first time in
August.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I had no
idea. That's the first time I've
ever heard that story. So Jessie
is my husband, who's also a
developer, and moms who code I
was really involved in that
early on. Well, I was learning
and getting into tech, that's
just very, very fascinating. Um,
there are lots of moms that do
come and it's nice. A lot of
them bring their kids. And so we
get to see kids and cats and all
the fun people that that come to
Virtual Coffee. So very glad
that you're here. And you can
hang out with the moms.
Glen McCallum: Yeah, it was
really, it was really
interesting. I've been looking
for better friends, is that a
way to say it? I love this
phrase, it's been attributed to
different people, you are the
average of your five closest
friends. And so, you know, I'd
been looking for some better
five closest friends to hang out
with, and just not quite sure
how to find them. And so after
my, I mean, I came to Virtual
Coffee, it was good. And I
remember sitting here
afterwards, that initial
session, and I just felt sort of
empty inside. And it wasn't me
it wasn't that
I realized what I was missing.
until after I kind of
experienced it in that
professional connection, that
professional camaraderie with
excellent people. And I've been
coming regularly ever since.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That is
really awesome. And I think that
resonates with so many people.
And I think you know, having
community has been super
important in the last year, but
also this community has been one
of my favorite places ever for
people because I have a hard
time making friends or talking
to people because I can be
really shy and just having a
group of people that I have felt
comfortable around has been such
a great part of not just the
last year but my adult life.
Glen McCallum: I think there's
something very atypical about
this technical group. And I'm
sure it's come out and everybody
says it, it's just there's
there's no ego and nobody's
judging or nobody's trying to
prove themselves and so often I
don't care what community like
Stack Exchange, it just seems
like the insecurity comes out.
And that's manifested in
snarkiness. And, and put downs
and things like that, but this
is just really safe and
supportive. Welcoming.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's nice to
hear. Yeah, I, I'm not sure what
your work situation was before
pandemic, but I've been like,
pretty much remote for my whole
career, you know, you know, and
I come and go from, I don't
know, searching for communities,
you know, I was part of like, a
meetup group early on that, like
a physical Meetup group. And
then we moved in, I don't know,
it sort of fell apart. And then,
you know, there's, it's just so
hard to find people to, like, be
with, like, when you don't know
how to, like, you know, go into
an office with people for
people, you know, stuff like
that. And, I don't know, it's,
it's, that's, that's kind of
felt to you, like, it's just
been so nice to like, this
group, you know, this group
doesn't have the like that some
of those problems, you know, and
so it's just, it's my kind of
group to, you know, where I can
just be comfortable and like, be
myself, you know, and not have
to worry about the upvotes, or
the popularity contests or
whatever, you run into lots of
other places.
Glen McCallum: I think the the
face to face interaction,
augmenting the online
discussion, group interaction
just changes the whole dynamic
to get to get to know these
people.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah,
there's something really, that
invites vulnerability and
intimacy, when you do have that
experience, like you're, you're
seeing them, you're hearing
their voices, once or twice a
week, and I loved how you said
it in one of the breakout rooms
on a Thursday session where you
were talking about, like, if
this is like sitting around a
coffee table, as friends, just
talking, and that's just what it
feels like when when you're in
the room with the people.
Okay, so you your career,
obviously, it's been quite a
journey. So not only were you
going to be a vet, but you made
a lot of like big career
transitions. And I want to know,
there had to be some challenges
along the way that I want to
hear you kind of talk about and
in, I'd love to know how you
felt as you were going through
the challenge. And then now
looking back at that challenge,
in retrospect, like how that's
changed, because, like, so much
of the time, when you're in the
middle of that thing, it feels
unbearable. And then once you
get out of it, there's you can
kind of look at it a little bit
more objectively. So do you have
any big moments to talk about?
Glen McCallum: We could talk
about lots of moments. I mean, I
kind of spent my first seven
years in enterprise healthcare
IT. And there are some big, big
transitions in that. My second
seven years were spent in more
tech software development
straight up. And there was a big
transition to shift between
those but let's go back kind of,
while I'm still in enterprise,
healthcare IT and I'm an Oracle,
because that was a things went
pretty smooth. Up until then, I
mean, you you graduate computer
science, I was in the co op
program. So I already had work
experience. I had a job offer
before I finished school. And
things just kind of start
trucking along when you're on
that kind of traditional track,
which is nice. However, and and
I went to a big integrated
healthcare network and did some
big type of government work,
which is really boring, but
we'll continue on. And I got
recruited to Oracle to work on
their enterprise healthcare
analytics platform, and got into
that world of traveling. We had
a dev team in India, in addition
to California, so there was
like, people working on these
products 24 hours a day, I would
essentially get up, have
meetings to transition work back
to me, I do my work all day.
Well, my counterpart, slept. And
then at the end of the day, I
would hand my work off to him
and he would do it. Lots of
travel to meet with customers.
But you know, over time, it
really took a toll on the
family. And I can remember, you
know, coming home to the
airport, my wife picking me up
and like, just like breaking
down and crying on the way home
really hard on the family. I can
remember my second child I would
hug the computer and be like,
goodnight, Daddy because I would
talk to them on Skype. And as
well as I wasn't liking the
person I was becoming in terms
of kind of that environment of
traveling eating nice
restaurants, you start to lease,
I started to get a certain
expectation of how things should
be. And when they weren't that
way, I just wasn't very nice.
So the I was at Oracle for a
couple years, it was actually
the day my third child was born,
that I decided I was leaving.
And there's a not sure where
they call it law or program in
Canada, where you can go on
employment benefits at the birth
of a child, regardless of
paternity, maternity. And so I
registered for that program. And
he gave me a year of minimal
income. And, and left Oracle.
And that was a major shift for
me, because I really didn't know
where I was going at that point.
Towards the end of that year,
off, and I did, I did various
things on the year off that we
could talk about if you want, I
finished building our house, and
landscaped our yard,
Dan Ott: I was just gonna ask if
you took the whole year, that's
awesome.
Glen McCallum: It gets really
boring if you're just sitting
around, although, yeah, there
were some complications from
that birth. So I was really glad
that I was there and available.
Towards the end of that year, I
tried to get into some
consulting work. But I found
that my contacts and experience
took me into a enterprise type
consulting world, which number
one, was leading back to travel.
Number two, it's really hard to
financially weather, the cycles
of enterprise consulting
payment. And maybe you've tried
that maybe you haven't, it takes
from the time you have an
agreement, it takes a month to
get legal review on the
contract. After the contract
gives legal
review, it takes a month to get
a billing number set up. And,
and so that's like, two months
from actually getting a deal
hammered out before you can
start billing. And then there's,
you know, submitting the invoice
and just kind of waiting
indefinitely for payment to
come. So it was in having been
at kind of the tail end of a
year of, of time off. It wasn't
very comfortable to financially
weather that. So I I ran back to
the hospital where I worked
before, and got a position
there, which is very senior, but
it was an interesting time there
time to change there as well.
And I was back there for another
year. And they were in the
process of negotiating a big
vendor agreement, 100 $50
million contract for consulting
and software services to roll
out across the whole Health
Network. And when that got
signed, I just didn't feel there
was a place for me there.
Because those those types of
services that I could offer
would be just come through that
consulting agreement. And I was
just feeling bored.
And so I had a friend at a sort
of an established startup in
Victoria. And I had seen
postings for that company come
up regularly. When I was
cruising around, and I just
asked him if he was happy there.
And he said, Yeah, they treat me
pretty well and so I I he put me
in contact with his boss who I
also loosely knew we had lunch
and it was a done deal. And
that's what got me kind of back
onto the software development
track from the enterprise
healthcare IT track
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
wild. And I think I mean, you
talk about this also commonly,
but those all seem like really
huge decisions to make. Were you
ever freaked out about those
decisions? You had a kid? And
your third kid, I think you
said, and then you're like,
Well, I'm not gonna do this
anymore, right? I don't think I
can handle the birth of a child
and leaving a job at the same
time.
Glen McCallum: Yeah now that you
point it out...
I always had something that I,
that was there for me. I didn't
drop in leave into nothing. So I
had a, I had a runway and I had
to set a context when I left
Oracle. And I didn't leave the
hospital the second time until I
had another job in place. Yeah,
so it wasn't like I was just
taking the leap of faith.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I know, I
totally get that it just
transitions like that can be so
difficult. And so for me, it
would be it would require a long
stretch of second guessing
myself as to whether or not that
was a good decision.
Glen McCallum: And it wasn't.
without emotion, I'll say that,
especially ... transitioned back
into software development. As I
joined a team that was that is
was also...what's the
word...cross international cross
border. So we had a split
between Canada and Russia, on
this team. And it was, it was a
bit of a rough onboarding, in
terms of, they're putting me
through my paces, and it had
been a long time since I've been
building software. And so I, you
know, I totally get kind of that
new developer experience of
getting put on a team. And I
don't know if hazed is the right
word, but maybe a bit where
you're, you're getting picked
on. And, and you're expected to
know things that you really
shouldn't be expected to know.
And getting hassled a bit when,
when you stumble. And I
remember, I remember breaking
the build, and just being really
upset, like more upset than I
should have been looking back,
it wasn't a big deal, but pay me
at the time. I think I like
cried in my garage office at the
time.
Dan Ott: I mean, that, that kind
of kind of thinking feels so
stressful. Like in the moment,
you know, it's, I think it's
pretty natural reaction. I mean,
it's pretty natural reaction to
something like that, especially
when you're new, right? And
also, especially when it's your
first time, if you're an old hat
at breaking the production
build, like I am, eventually you
realize, like, wait, like he
said, with experience, you
realize maybe, you know, doesn't
have to be as big of a deal. But
yeah, like that? I don't know.
That seems...It's so hard to
like think like that when you're
in the moment and sweating and
like, you know, the things
broken? And
Glen McCallum: well, and maybe
it really wasn't even about that
maybe it was just about the fact
that I've been through a wide
career swing and stuff going on
at home and all the implications
of that and just all kind of
coming out in that one moment.
Dan Ott: Yeah,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah I like
to do that, too.
Dan Ott: I was just gonna say,
that's a really good point. I
like the, I was actually to was
talking about with my therapist
about this about how, like, on
some days, like, like, if the
exact event happened on, you
know, one day and then happened,
like, four days later, my, my,
like, my reaction to it the way
I like, react to it in the way
that like, everything else,
like, comes from that will be
completely different can be
completely different. If I'm,
you know, in that if I'm, like,
overwhelmed, if there's, you
know, depending on like what the
other external things are
internal things are happening,
you know, at the moment. I
don't, you know, I don't know,
we're talking about how to,
like, ways to like, remember
that when you're in the moment,
you know, which is like, That's
hard. I mean, I don't even have
it the advice you know, we're
just kind of talking about
talking about it, but But yeah,
that like, anytime you're in a
big transition, you know, of, of
any kind, you know, everything
is going to it's just like a
stress on your system, right?
Glen McCallum: Yeah. But I mean,
just like to point out that if
it happened to me could happen
to anybody. I mean, wasn't like
I was new to this game. And, and
going through that and having
that experience, just imagine
what it's like if you really are
new to this game, and you kind
of don't know, the behind the
scenes of how things work.
Dan Ott: Right, absolutely. Like
you probably knew that data. No,
I mean, I don't know,
specifically what was happening
with the with breaking the bill,
but like you probably knew, you
know, intellectually that you
didn't like destroy the company
or something right. You know,
but like, yeah, if you're, if
you're newer to the whole thing,
obviously, the promisee would
seem seem bigger, you know?
Glen McCallum: Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I know.
I've heard of companies when
they're onboarding new
developers, and I don't know if
this goes across the board,
whether it's somebody new to the
team, or just people who are
early in their career, but
they'll introduce them to other
members of the team. And tell
ask the other members of the
team to talk about what they've
broken in the last week or
something like that, or the
their biggest story about that.
And I always thought that was a
fun way to kind of maybe defuse
that future situation, or to
say, like, hey, like, this is
normal, we do it and then we
work through it. Right? And
look, we are a team and we get
along.
Glen McCallum: It's a really
good idea. You can you have to
have the right team to feel
comfortable sharing that, you
know, there's a certain amount
of egolessness to get people to
open up that way. I think we
could do that. Now. I'm not sure
if we could have done that at
the time.
Dan Ott: Yeah
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: for sure.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's I mean,
that's, that is a cool idea. And
it, it's important, I feel like
that the people are sharing
their own, you know, moments of
that. It's not like somebody
saying, Oh, this guy messed up
here. And this guy just appears,
you know, like pointing it out
for somebody else. Right? That
doesn't seem as good, right?
That's one of the things I've
actually liked about in Virtual
Coffee is having you know, some
of the more senior developers,
like, share stories like that a
lot. I know, Bryan has. He's the
first one I think of, with with
this practice, you know, of just
like, I don't know, like, he
also, I mean, he's the, you
know, it's like running the
company. And like, he also has
broken the builds. And his
company, you know, it's just
like, everybody, everybody will
be okay, you know, so that,
like, relating relating that
kind of the same kind of thing.
I feel like it's, I don't know,
seems like a good practice. You
know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I also want
to touch on a story that you
have mentioned, if you're up for
it, I'm your first full time job
out of school, the one where you
almost died.
Glen McCallum: Before we go
there, do you want to finish the
topic on change, because up
until now, we've kind of talked
about change that I've inflicted
on myself, but there was this
there's been this event in the
last four years where change was
kind of inflicted on me. And
that was when the company that
the company went to after
leaving the hospital, carved off
kind of half of their products,
and sold them to a book
distributor. And with that sale
of those products, they took
three Canadian developers, and I
was one of them. And that whole
thing was a really interesting
day.
And it was September 1 2016, as
I recall, and for weeks, there
had been kind of a oddly placed
random status meeting on our
calendar for that day. And I
didn't think much of it. And,
and, I mean, the company I was
at had a new CEO, and he had a
new mandate. At the time. I
didn't really know what that
mandate was, but he'd been up to
visit and to meet us. We live in
Los Angeles, and it come up to
Victoria. And and he'd been
hired by the venture capital
firm that owned a share of the
company. And at the time, I
didn't know but I believe he'd
been hired to liquidate the
assets of the company. And so
this day was the first sale that
that new CEO had made. And so we
walk in, walk in, we joined this
call, and there was a few people
on there that I wasn't expecting
in terms of higher ups. And then
it was like we'd like you to
meet the new owners of this
product line. And it was like,
jumped into two hours of
PowerPoint and then talking and
telling us about their new
company. And then it was like,
Dan Ott: and that's the first
you heard of it at all, like the
first, the first
Glen McCallum: first mention,
I've heard of it, maybe people
knew, maybe I was just isolated.
And then they're like, they were
in San Francisco, at the main
company office, and then they're
like, we're all going to lunch.
You guys go have some lunch.
And, and at the time, I don't
remember if they were specific
about who they were keeping. And
like, we, of course, got off
that call, and all of a sudden
got back on another call, like
the secret call. Where we kind
of like, are venting and
debriefing about this whole
thing. And later that day, I got
a letter of offer for a job from
them. But it didn't, just the
way. I mean, they're good people
trying their best.
But the the letters of offer
weren't quite squared away in
terms of what our current
positions were and what our
benefits were in things, which
is fine. They made good on it.
They matched everything. So, so
stand up job for them. Over the
next couple of days, they did
that. But I like not going was
not an option for me. I went to
my boss, the same one who hired
me two years earlier. And I was
like, What are my options here?
And he is like, if you don't go,
we're laying you off. And but
you know how these things are
right, because at the same time,
they had job postings. So it's
not like, it's not like they
didn't need people, they were
hiring at the same time, but
also learn things in hindsight.
The team that they took was part
of the sale, they didn't want
just the product, they actually
wanted to acqui-hire a software
development team.
And so and so that boss in good
faith, in good faith on that
deal could not have kept me
because it was it was part of
their their deal they'd made
between companies onboarding us,
I would say. I mean,
technically, it was hard.
Because we had shared repos,
shared libraries, shared
infrastructure, shared
continuous integration with the
whole other product line. So it
took us months to kind of tease
all these products apart. And,
and get end of our side of the
fence located to a new data
center. And even then, I mean,
the initial hardware that was
SPECT wasn't quite adequate. And
so it wasn't quite running right
until we got some new hardware
in place. I learned this as a
software developer, having to
take over some infrastructure
planning roles. Because we have
a whole infrastructure team at
the old company at the new
company we didn't and they're
like, Glen, you're in charge of
this. Okay, we'll do it. But
yeah, I think it was harder on
their IT team because they they
wanted to software developers,
but they kind of kind of a
smaller it group. And then they
brought us in and we're sort of
bit more rough and tumble in how
we work together. And we may
have overrun them a little bit
with just our way of doing
things which is good because
it's all following software
engineering best practices. But
I mean back to back to my
onboarding experience. It's a
bit it's a little a little
rougher with each other and some
other teams can be. It's not
like Virtual Coffee.
Dan Ott: That's Yeah, that's,
that's pretty crazy. I try to
integrate, like a new team into
an existing team, you know?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: And like
surprise.
Dan Ott: Yeah, the idea of Yeah.
Being a, I don't know, an asset
in acquisition, basically,
without your, you know,
knowledge. That's,
Glen McCallum: it's an
interesting experience. Yeah,
straight out hearing people all
in good faith. And by no means
was it anything...anything shady
going on there? Nobody was
trying to, to hurt anyone else,
but just just difficult change
thrown upon you.
Dan Ott: When, at that time,
like when that transition
happened, were you still more of
like an individual contributor?
Like in that role?
Glen McCallum: Yes, I was
Dan Ott: so. So is after that.
So because because I know now
you're, you're managing a team.
So that that kind of happened,
like organically over that over
the preceding? I forget where we
are in the timeline, but like,
in the in the in the years after
that?
Glen McCallum: Yeah. I mean,
'bout year after there was a
software development manager
came over as well with that. And
about a year after we got the
infrastructure migration
complete, they announced they
were leaving. And I was offered
the position at that time, I
think, mostly because of my
roles. I'd had him back in
healthcare it.
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah. Cuz, I
mean, that's, that's a choice,
too. I mean, did you have to
think about it? Like, take,
like, you know, when they
offered? It did, were you? I
mean, I assume that, like I did,
like, I mean, like right ...
traditionally the, that sort of
offer will, you know, have be
like a raise and everything, a
new title, whatever. But like,
it's, it's a, it's a different
ballgame. Right.
Glen McCallum: I should give a
talk about this...
Dan Ott: Well, I mean, you know,
for listeners that don't know,
like, Glen did a lightning talk
on this transition for our
lightning talk round in
February. I knew was I mean, it
was very, very good talking.
Well, the talk is on YouTube, so
we'll link to it. But I, one of
the reasons I was very excited
by having you here was was to
like, sort of, have you dig in a
little bit more? Because it's
such like a I don't know, we
were just talking about
transitions this whole time. So
I don't want to say like, Oh,
it's a huge transition, compared
to compared to a lot of the
stuff you've gone through, or
anybody's gone through, but
like, it's still as a career
choice, you know,
Glen McCallum: things different
transition, sort of transition,
because, I mean, I went from
kind of a team member to team
owner. Yeah. Some respects.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Sorry, I
just want to pause for a second
and see if you can you define
the difference between IC to
engineering manager
Glen McCallum: define the
difference between that I mean,
it's a it's a in terms of the
work I do day to day, or in
terms of how it felt? Well, you
can go with both, I just want to
make sure that listeners
understand what the transition
what what that means in terms of
your role and expectations. And,
and I guess how you feel plays
into that for sure. A lot of
that can depend on where you are
where I am, that took me into a
whole new leadership layer that
I didn't have any access to
before. And I should qualify
that, that I worked for a big
classifies small company, but in
my mind doesn't really seem very
small. There's 200 staff.
There's one large team of
software developers and a few IT
personnel. But in terms of
leadership hierarchy, above me,
I mean, now I report directly to
the CEO and on the software
development manager, so I'm
pulled into many strategic
planning, company crisis
meeting, things that things that
I just had no knowledge of
before. And I mean, that's kind
of the
the tightness of my team going
through that acquisition and,
and having been together through
that. I mean, we didn't keep
secrets, that was our policy, no
secrets, no matter who would
hurt among us, I mean, we're
trying to hurt anyone else. The
policy was you had to tell it.
And, and so me going from
independent contributor to the
manager is really me kind of
leaving some of the closeness
and the tightness that I felt
with those comrades. And kind of
going out and doing more on my
own, which is led to a lot of
growth, but also some growing
pains there. My work, I do a lot
more project planning now,
supervising what other people
are doing. Occasionally, I get
to help people and touch code.
And that's really fun. I'm
probably guilty of touching code
too much and avoiding some of my
other duties. But that's just
me. You want me to hit on some
of the things I talked about in
my presentation?
Dan Ott: Yeah, I mean, I like
that, that I've been, I can't
remember what podcast was, I was
listening to another podcast
about, about this, and about the
how Traditionally, the way to
move up in a company or you
know, get a raise, or whatever
it is, you know, there's just
like a ceiling for being a, like
an individual developer. And the
next step is always management,
you know, but the in the podcast
I was listing to is about
pushing back on on the idea. I
know. Not everybody like, has
is, you know, possibly good at
being a manager, or wants to be
a manager, you know, and things
like that. And, and so anybody
that has, like, consciously made
this transition at you know, I
always want to, like, the things
I wasn't want to know is like,
like, did you think about that
at the time? And now that you're
in it? You know, it's, from what
I can tell, it seems like you're
pretty comfortable in the
position, but like, are you like
glad? Do you ever think about
moving back to being, you know,
like, it? And I see like, in
another, you know, if you could
keep all the whatever your
current benefits and everything,
but be coding all day, instead
of managing? Would you take that
job? Or, you know, would you
think about it, you know, that
kind of...I know that that was
just like 7000 questions that
you can pick which one you want
to hit, sir.
Glen McCallum: I'm gonna start
at the beginning. Yeah, there
definitely was a ceiling. I
think at any mall company,
there's going to be a ceiling
and how far you can progress as
an independent contributor.
Oracle's different Oracle had
career tax for software
development, you could have, I
mean, you could go all the way
up through the levels, almost to
the top as an independent
contributor. I mean, there were
ceilings that you're not going
to go to the executive later
moving from independently
contributor, you had to go
through the management track to
get kind of up past that. But
you can go a long way as an
independent contributor or call
and get very good income. So but
at this small company, I mean,
there really wasn't any place
for me to go. In fact, I'd say,
about six months before that, I
was looking for another job,
just because I didn't think
anybody was ever leaving. That
was ahead of me, and I wasn't
going to have any place to go.
And I was looking for some place
with more of a progression
possible. But I had a really
unexpected
health care issue, that year,
health issue and a diagnosis.
And so over those months, it was
just not even on my radar. I was
just trying to make some life
adjustments. And so when that
came up was completely
unexpected. And, you know, I did
think a lot about it quickly. In
that, you know, I wasn't in a
place to make a ... transition
that year, just because of that,
that stuff I was going through
in the other part of my life.
And so I kind of looked at it
like, I kind of took over the
team when that other person
left. And what were my options?
I say no. And I'm still running
the team while they hire
someone. And then I'm going to
be training the person probably
and doing part of their workload
for, I'd say, a period of
months, and maybe, maybe I don't
even ever stop doing part of
their workload. We'll see. I see
what they're like, maybe there.
Maybe they don't work out. You
know, this just and I just think
At my current rate, or if I take
it, at least I get a new job
title and a pay raise and do
what I would have had to do
anyway. Yeah, totally. So that
was the decision that kind of
led me through there. Sorry, I
lost the the second part of your
question.
Dan Ott: If you don't remember,
I certainly don't remember
Glen McCallum: if I can do it
over again or?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: not, if you
could do it over again. But if
you had the opportunity to go
back coding all of the time,
with the same benefits that you
have in your role?
Dan Ott: Yeah. So not like,
would you go back and make a
different choice? But like,
right now, you know, how much do
you miss? coding is, I guess,
like the right. I mean, like,
you don't have to answer like
that.
Glen McCallum: Do I think about
it? Only every day.... I mean, I
equate that to taking a step
back in the progression of your
life to a certain extent. Would
it be awesome to go back and
live with my parents? My mom
makes me french toast every
morning. Yeah, that'd be really
cool. But would you really want
to do do that? No, I don't think
that I could
go back and kind of that back to
that same goal where I was
before, I think there might be
something different for me in
the future where I get to do
more coding, but we'll just see
kind of where that leads.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Okay, so I
think there, there are two ways
that this can go. So I still
want to hear your story. Um,
about your first job.
Glen McCallum: The story where I
almost drowned?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah.
Glen McCallum: See, I didn't
even put that in my speaker
notes there.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Well...
Glen McCallum: But you
remembered because I told you at
some point,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: yeah, you
put it in slack. And I still
have a record of that.
Glen McCallum: So my very first
job at a university was setting
up health IT systems in remote
Aboriginal communities along the
western coast of Canada. And so
many of these communities or
villages are flying only or boat
and I guess traditionally boat
in. And so to go do this work,
and we'd be getting satellite
Satellite Internet hookups,
being some advanced wireless
signals off different islands
from the mainland kind of thing.
We'd get to charter flow planes.
And so getting to this day, if I
get on a float plane, I fall
asleep. Because I had to leave
my house, I'd drive for two,
three hours, it'd be like
3 30am, I get to the flow plane
dock at 4 30am. We get on a flow
plane, we fly for two hours and
get to our destination. But as
soon as I hit the flow plane
every morning, I was just out.
But the company put us through
this. It's called egress
training. And what it is, is, I
mean, statistically, any plane
class crashes, like, I don't
know what the percentage is.
super high percentage to happen
on landing or takeoff. And the
the creator of this course,
survived a plane crash himself
on the Fraser River in
Vancouver.
And after that, the RCMP started
calling him in to help
investigate other plane crashes,
especially on water. And what
they found was that everybody
was surviving these crashes and
getting trapped in the plane and
drowning. And float planes
float. So these people were
drowning, like, only a few feet
below the surface of the water,
because they couldn't get out of
the plane,
Dan Ott: because it's upside
down, right?
Glen McCallum: Yeah, the plane
inverts the pontoons hold the
plane up. And so he created this
course to teach people how to
exit inverted submerged planes.
And so, I was put through this
course. And the way he did it is
he had to forfeit deep hotel
swimming pool and he had built
this fuselage with seats in it
and doors and windows and this
is strap you in The seat and
essentially, like, dump you into
the pool upside down. And, I
mean, this is it happens in
stages. So, I mean, first you
practice getting yourself out
and getting your belt off and
memorizing where the door handle
is and where your hand positions
are kicking out a window. And
then, I mean, it leads up to you
dumping this fuselage thing in
the pool upside down, and you
have to get yourself out. And
there's actually a smaller one,
too, as well that it's for more
advanced, this little cage thing
with doors and windows. And what
they do in that one is they,
they tumble you until you're
just completely disoriented. And
and then you have to get your
way out. And I was in the
tumbler one and got out, but I
just had no idea which way was
the surface of the water kind of
thing. And yeah, I got like one
foot on the ground, luckily, and
just like got my head up and
vomited. I got I took in water,
and I can see how people drown.
I learned a lot in that moment.
Dan Ott: Yeah,
Glen McCallum: So that was
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: like two
things. One, I would never have
expected for my first job in
tech to have to experience that
and two, Glen. I think this
whole podcast episode, you've
talked about a million things
that like have terrified me.
I've had a stress reaction here.
And you're just like, so calm
talking about it. I very much
want to know how you do that,
too.
Glen McCallum: I don't know,
maybe that's why I got the job I
have would just figure it out,
start moving forward. Take
things as they come.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. And I
just I want to touch too on.
Okay, so you talked about you
faced a challenge a couple of
years ago, and that was kind of
part of this decision making
thing, right. And so I'm not
positive about what that
challenge was. But I think that
maybe that has to do with your
diabetes diagnosis. Is that
true?
Glen McCallum: That's true. I
mean, that's a, that's a whole
other story in itself, we have
time for it.
The brief version is I lost 38
pounds in about three months.
And that was while I was like
eating everything in sight. I
would literally like go to the
grocery store at 10 o'clock at
night because I was hungry. And
I mean to anybody familiar with
Type One Diabetes, this is
really kind of stereotypical
behavior. Other symptoms, kind
of went back a few years it had
been progressing, runs in my
family. My grandfather had it,
my grandfather died of it. And
so you know, I drink a gallon a
half of water per day. It would
be like, you know, one liter
bottle of Nalgene, I'd be like,
I just need a little drink water
before bed and drink the whole
thing and like 10 seconds.
So made a doctor's appointment.
And the doctor knew. And it's
quite unusual to get type one
diabetes as an adult. Normally,
there's, there's kind of two
ages that are common to have an
onset of type one diabetes, a
one is around five or six years
old. The second one is late
teens, you know, 18 to 20 years
old, can have an onset, and I
was a bit older than that.
And so they sent me to an
endocrinologist to get all these
tests. And I mean, the
interesting part about this
whole story they gave me needles
is it's all no fun. And I had to
learn how to use it. But is that
I got introduced to
this idea of an open source
artificial pancreas. And this is
a really amazing community.
Because the open source
solutions have far surpassed
what's available commercially.
This is the term is called we're
not waiting if you're looking
for it on the internet. And it's
actually I believe, driven by
parents of diabetic kids who
build software. And have made an
incredible set of open source
tools for advanced diabetic
care. And so there's kind of two
main components to, to this one
is called the continuous glucose
monitor.
And it it's like a sticker that
gets stuck on you with a
Bluetooth transmitter on it. And
there's a little filament of
wire that goes under your skin.
And it continuously monitors
your blood sugar levels
throughout the day, you get that
you get that from a company
called dex calm, that's where I
get mine, there's a few. And
then you have an insulin pump.
And it continuously microdoses
insulin throughout the day to
maintain your proper blood sugar
level. And the crazy part about
this situation is that these are
made by two different companies,
and they've never actually got
together and figured out you
know, hey, I can sense the blood
sugar level, and you can dose
the insulin. When I eat, if I'm
just using a
straight up insulin pump, I have
to you know, count my carbs, and
program how much insulin to give
myself or if I'm going to
exercise I have to like reduce
my insulin level ahead of time,
or else all I need to eat sugar.
Because exercise burns sugar. So
what this open source community
did is they built a bridge
between the two, with with
university researchers as well.
And so my phone, the software
running on my Android phone acts
as a kind of an artificial
intelligence bridge, there's a
certain algorithm analysis in
there, that senses my blood
sugar levels and automatically
adjust my insulin dosage levels.
And, like I said, the crazy
thing is that this, this
couldn't have been figured out
by industry, they couldn't have
talked to each other and done
this. To me, people were
literally taking the wireless
remote for the insulin pump and
reverse engineering The, the
commands to it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I mean, so
this is this all fascinating.
And one of the things that I was
thinking about so my first
instinct, if I weren't intact
would be to be really afraid of
that. But I was wondering if
you're because you are in tech,
because you kind of understand
what's going on? Did that
impact, like the solutions that
you were looking for? Or you're
trusting this? Or I don't know,
just how did you decide to make
this?
Glen McCallum: I mean, it's all
not the FDA approved, let's,
let's come up with that. Right
away, I think that I couldn't
have pursued this. If I didn't
have a background in tech. I
mean, I had to build Android
clients from scratch and deploy
them myself, myself, and that
sort of thing. Number one,
number two, I was lucky I even
found it isn't like this is
advertised. It's not like the
doctors are telling you about
it. I mean, my family doctor, I
don't even think I've explained
it to her. I just she's just
like, Yeah, you got a pump,
good. My endocrinologist knows
about it. Because he specializes
in this. And he thought, you
know, this is, this is pretty
cool. Let me know how it goes.
You got a background, you know
what you're doing? He said he
has one other patient, you know,
of his entire patient load. He
has one other patient who does
loopings what it's called, you
close the loop. And he's like,
Yeah, tell me about it when you
come back next time.
And so in terms of me being
afraid to try it, not really.
Oh, yeah, it wasn't first. It
was at first but everything's
subtle in degrees, right? It's
not like live or die, pass or
fail. There's a lot of areas of
gray in between everything. And
I mean, I had I had problems. At
first I'll see that. The nurse
that set me up with my pump
initially, who probably still
doesn't know that I have this
running. Initially dosed me
about 30% too high. Maybe more
than that, maybe 50% too high
even on my insulin. And it's
really subtle. From me who
doesn't know anything to tell
that necessarily because there's
no that was, that's my kind of
constant level throughout the
day, she dosed really high. And
it's mixed in, I'm giving myself
other doses when I eat. So it's
really hard for me to tell that
that that base level was, was
too high.
And so I had problems with my,
my algorithm setup. Based on
that for six months, maybe. And
I say problems, what, what's the
solution to the problem, it just
means I got to eat. And so
luckily, I have, I have a
constant monitor, and it has an
alarm that tells me what I need
to eat. But I got, there's a
book that the endocrinologist
recommended I read. Initially,
that was like, months before.
And so I started reading this
book one day, and it started
giving me these protocols to
actually determined my correct
levels. And I did them involves
a lot of fasting and pricking
your finger every two hours
throughout the night. And that's
how I got my correct base level
figured out. And once I got
that, things started to go
smoother with the artificial
pancreas feedback loop.
Dan Ott: That's, that's crazy,
it's tough to win when the kind
of thing takes time to figure
out and it's also like, your
health, you know, like your
body. And it's so hard, I don't,
Glen McCallum: I never really
found someone to talk to about
this. I'm still going at it by
myself. And it's one reason why
I bring it up. Sometimes it's
like, if there's someone else
struggling with this, I want
them to talk to me, the I mean,
the docs, let's just say open
source docs. Nuff said there.
But they tell you, and there's
like a gajillion settings on
this thing. And they tell you
kind of what give you an
explanation of each setting. But
they don't really tell you how
to know what to set it to, like
how it applies to you. And so
it's been a lot of trial and
error there. On my own party. I
mean, it goes on every week,
every day, trying different
things, trying different set
different settings. And I don't
have everything dialed in yet,
but it's like way closer than it
was. So, I mean, I still
consider myself lucky to have
stumbled on this number one.
Number two, lucky to have the
technical knowledge to even get
it running by myself. And number
three, like the effectiveness of
the treatment using the open
source system is lightyears
ahead of what is available
through traditional medicine
like there is absolutely no
comparison not even in the same
bill ballpark.
Dan Ott: So hard to imagine.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Right? And
that's what's so frustrating. I
don't know, the healthcare
industry is one of the things
that frustrates me the most for
like exactly this reason, right?
Like there are things that they
try that we treat people over
and over in the very same ways
that are not accurate or not the
best ways. And then newer and
better ways aren't pursued, or
they just take so much time, or
just people don't even doctors
don't even know to offer them.
Right. And so then there's just
I don't know, my inner rage
comes out when I talk about
this. Because it's just it's not
fair. Like we're letting people
down by not pursuing these
different ways or the the most
exciting way or whatever. Like
maybe you're not going to make
headlines for doing this thing.
And so then nobody pursues it.
Glen McCallum: But gosh, put
insurance companies in that mix?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's the
worst. Like, I'm in the middle
of that right now. And it's just
such a shame. And that's why,
you know, I'm really glad that
you talked about this because,
you know, hopefully one person
hears it and they tell another
person and just, I think even
sometimes knowing that there are
options out there that you
haven't stumbled upon is enough
to provide hope for somebody
who, who's just going through a
really rough time with it, you
know?
Glen McCallum: Yeah. And I mean,
it's, it's quite humorous
looking back. There's even if
you have a child who's diabetic,
there's great monitoring tools
that that had been built in. So
me, I monitor myself, obviously,
I'm able to do that. But I mean,
this cannot be this is all
internet enabled through
cellular data, if you have this
on your child, you can be
monitoring constantly, if
they're not managing themselves,
you can manage them remotely. If
it's a small child, we set up
this up. Initially, for me, it
seemed like a good idea, because
I do a lot of work outside by
myself. And, and this is, I
mean, in that initial month,
when I was first trying this,
and I had monitoring setup to my
wife's phone.
And the exact same monitoring
you'd use if you had one of your
children on this. And I was
working at the back of the
property doing my thing, and not
really paying attention to
anything. And she like comes
running through the field with I
don't remember like sugar and
water and these things, and, and
I'm just like, Hey, what's going
on? She's like, convinced then
like, laying there dying?
Because my connection was
disconnected. It was it was it
was not reading accurately.
Dan Ott: Well, nice to know she
is ready to ready.
Glen McCallum: So that was the
last day the monitoring was
installed in her phone. After
that. She's like, You're on your
own. So now I'm on my own. But
it's been good. It's very
difficult to get into that type
of situation. Now that I have it
tuned better.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Wow, Glen,
this has just been such a great
hour plus talking through all of
these things. I just very much
like hearing you talk about all
of this. All these things that
you've gone through and all of
these things that you've done,
and just hearing your story,
because you're a really great
storyteller teller. So it's easy
to you know, just sit back and
listen. So I very much
appreciate you sharing all of
this stuff for everybody else to
hear as well.
Glen McCallum: Thank you.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I agree. I feel
like you have a unique
perspective on life. I'm sure
some of that is from, you know,
created from your experiences.
And some of that is, you know, I
don't know, innate or whatever.
But I always I always like, kind
of listen to you. Talk about
your experiences. And you know,
the way the way you've kind of
viewed things as you go through
them. I Appreciate it.
Glen McCallum: Thanks, Dan.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All right.
Well, that's our episode for
today. We will put some of those
links in the show notes. And
again, thanks so much for being
here with us, Glen. We'll see
you soon.
Glen McCallum: Thank you.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at Virtual
Coffee, IO. Or you can email us
at podcast at Virtual coffee.io.
You can find the show notes.
Plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtual
coffee.io.
Dan Ott: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.