Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season two, Episode
Four of the Virtual Coffee
podcast. I'm Bekah, and this is
a podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Today,
we're joined by Debra-Kaye
Elliott. Debra-Kaye is a front
end developer going through a
bootcamp on she's adding a
community learning to her
learning process. And she's a
career changer from the
administrative field, and has
always wanted to be in tech. And
we talked about what it's like
to be on the self taught
developer journey, which I can
tell you is a long one. We
talked about imposter syndrome.
And also some of the key things
that Debra-Kaye has learned
along the way.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from
what we do, and a random check
in question. Today's random
checking question is, if you
were famous, what would you be
famous for? We hope you enjoy
this episode. Hey, I'm Bekah,
I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could be famous
for anything, I think--I like
approach this in two ways, like
one - like what might be
possible
or like two - anything? So I
really like the superhero, the
flash, and so I would like to be
famous for being the flash. And,
Dan Ott: like the flash
specifically, or just very, very
fast?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I don't
know. I think I think I would
like to be Barry Allen. If but,
if I had to do something that is
more practical than that, I
would want to be the strongest
mom in the world. I think I was
telling someone earlier today. I
like weight lifting, heavy
things. So I will be the
strongest mom, because that
that's realistic too.
Dan Ott: Hi, I'm Dan. I'm a
front end developer from
Lakewood, Ohio. I am not going
practical at all. I my first
instinct was you know, spaceship
flying. So like, like, you know,
the the Millennium Falcon or
whatever, you know, doing the
Kessel Run. I basically like
that'd be my famous you know,
out Dan. Oh, man. He's thinking
he's the fastest you know,
spaceship flyer there is so
that's that's that's what that's
my choice,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: spaceship
flyer?
Dan Ott: --spaceship pilot I
realized flyers are silly way to
say. But, you know, so be it.
That's what it is: Dan, the
spaceship flyer.
Debra-Kaye: Hi, I am Debra-Kaye,
front end developer from
Jamaica. If I was to be famous
for anything. Um, my first
answer would be like, fiction
novels, because I am a sucker
for fiction. And I tend to put a
book down when I start to read
it. And I have a really long
book list of books to read. And
then my second answer would be
I'm so happy to pick a superhero
because my favorite superheroes
are Captain Marvel and Deadpool.
So like if I could combine their
two powers into one like that
would be because like I'm a
little bit obsessed with
Deadpool. I don't know why I
love Ryan Reynolds. So yeah, so
I have two answers for those
surprisingly so I'm so happy
that it's not, like practical
because I always go for
superhero and books first.
Dan Ott: That's sweet. That's
pretty awesome. What are you
what are you reading right now?
Debra-Kaye: Um, so I'm reading
its title-- let me, one sec
sorry cuz. Yeah, cuz I am almost
halfway, Well, I'm past halfway
through the book. And it's by
Estella Vasquez Perez in her
last name is. And it's a series.
So I'm on the second
book. And it's called Dark
Serenade. Yeah, so it's
Montenegro Book Two dark
serenade by Estella Vasquez
Perez.
Dan Ott: Well you're on Book
Two, then you must have like the
first.
Debra-Kaye: Yes, there's three
books so yeah, actually bought
this one because the first one
was free, I know they knew what
to do series first And then see
f you like, it sounds like you
eed to finish series. So two or
three now.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. Nice.
I've gotten into a bad habit of
getting the first book of a
series on the library or
whatever. And then just like the
second one isn't available, and
I need it and just buy it, or if
I can find the set, because I'm
just like, Alright, well, I
know, I'm just gonna do this
with the third one or whatever.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
always make the mistake of
waiting for it to come in from
the library. And then by the
time it comes in, I'm like, what
happened in book one?
Debra-Kaye: Like, what I've been
trying to do now is if I see
that the book is a series, after
like, decide, okay, I'm either
gonna read through the entire
series before I take up any
other book, or leave that until
like the very end, because if I
started series, I don't want to
be like, okay, read book one,
then start something and then
forgot what happened in that
book, one would have to meet
over so Yeah, totally.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It's a good
strategy. Alright, Debra-Kaye,
we are super happy to have you
here with us today. And we
always like to get started with
what brought a person to this
place in their life. So if you
want to give us the Debra-Kaye
origin story, we would love to
hear it.
Debra-Kaye: Oh, I could talk
about this all day. Oh, I'm so
actually studied information
technology. I did my degree in
information technology, like
seven years ago, eight years
ago. Um, because I always like
to take always like the web--I
taught myselt to use a computer
when I was like 16. But just
didn't really have any sense of
direction and didn't know what
development was, I think so just
didn't really know how to get
into the field. So I studied IT,
did a degree and just never got
a job in it. Because that is
wasn't able to when there was no
guidance, no anything. And where
I'm from in Jamaica, it's mostly
always system admins, network
admins, and I dislike hardware.
I did not like hardware. But
I'll play it with software all
day. So I just didn't know what
to do, how to get in it. And it
always seemed like programming
was this rocket science thing
that only certain people could
do. So I was like, Okay, I don't
know what to do with. So I
discovered I like design too. So
I did like a couple of courses
in graphic design. And then I
was like, Okay, I'll go to that.
But then after a year, I was
like, No, I really don't like it
as much. I like it, but not as
much as I did. And then in 2019,
I was like, wait, it's time to
be active on Twitter again
because I had an account, but
just didn't do anything with it.
And I kept seeing people talk
about this thing. I was like,
wait, this is a thing. And then
I got the courage to dm somebody
and ask them like, how do you go
about this? What is it, and they
were like, what do you what do
you like? And they're announced,
like saying like, okay, you
could do UX UI. And I was like,
Okay, then I went down that
rabbit hole of research for
months and months and months.
And that's an aside to realize,
like, oh, but development is a
thing. People actually do this.
And it can be done. I don't have
to go back to university for it.
Okay, how do I do this? So I
went down the rabbit hole and
bookmarked all the courses and
enrolled in lots of things that
I to this day haven't gotten
back to. But when I actually
started to realize that there
was actually a way a path to
actually do it. I was like,
Okay, yeah, this is a, this is a
side of things to figure out how
to do it. But this is the this
is what I've been searching for.
And when I was always I don't
have to know, every single
thing. And there are certain
things that you should know. But
then there are other paths in
tech that you really don't need
to get into. Like, okay, I can
do this. So I'm probably going
to need some some help, but it
can be done. So that's a long
winded we have over the course
of several years. Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
that's so great. And I think
that so many of us, like, I
know, I've been down that rabbit
hole a number of times, right?
And there is so much out there
to try and figure out like what
everybody will say like, Well,
what do you like doing? And
sometimes you don't even know
what you like doing because you
don't know what's available and
Debra-Kaye: And sometimes it's
more than one thing too.
Dan Ott: Yeah, for sure.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. And
figuring out how those work
together. I think it's really
great that you dm somebody and
ask for help because I think
that can be a struggle just to
get to that place and to know
that you know you were willing
to put yourself out there is
such a great first step.
Debra-Kaye: Yeah, and funny
thing too when I did that  I DM
is this guy that I have been
following for a while on
Twitter, but he is a, I think
he's a Ruby on Rails developer,
if I'm not mistaken. And he has
been doing it for like, over 10
years because he like taught
himself. And he, I sent him this
long message. And I was like,
you know, and he'll never see
this, and he'll never respond.
And he actually responded, I was
like, Oh, my god. And he's like,
yeah, you can do this, just
like, Look, look into this
avenue, since you like design.
And I was like, Oh, my god,
somebody responded, and from him
telling me that you can do it.
And he was also self taught, I
was like, Oh, my god, it's
actually a thing. Like, there's
actually some kind of path here,
some kind of Avenue, there's a
way to actually get into this
field, because I always wanted
to be in tech, but I just never
got an opportunity to. And
actually, for someone to
actually who's been doing it for
a while, and encouraging people
to get into tech and tell you
that, hey, it can be done.
There's actually a way they seem
to figure out what works for
you. But it can be done. So that
was really cool.
Dan Ott: I love that. I was
wondering like how he said, find
out which ways work for you. So
what have you found to be the
most like personally useful, you
know, tools to learn other
courses or tutorials? Or, you
know, what kind of what kind of
strategies, or have you been
using?
Debra-Kaye: I have been in--No,
I won't, I won't say another
tutoria hell- I'm not saying
tutorial hell. But I, when I
started, I was enrolling in
every free course that I could
find. Because you know, there's
a treehouse, and there's Udemy.
And there's everything. So I
have like a bookmark folder full
of courses that I could sign up
for. And then I signed up for a
bunch of Udemy courses, never
took them, but like I signed up
for them. And then I bought like
one or two Udemy courses, that
recommended ones. And I still
haven't gotten to those that I
bought yet. And then I started a
Free Code Camp. And then I was
doing I'm currently doing front
end masters. And then I was like
10 attorneys do two three at the
same time. And it took me like,
four months to realize that
Okay, one of them is not
sticking with information. And
it just wasn't understanding.
And it's like, okay, trying to
juggle too many courses at the
same time. They're all the
basically the fundamentals of
HTML, CSS, I haven't gotten to
JavaScript yet. But I was trying
to like balance. What I was
learning from one boot camp, to
what I was doing with the other
I was like, wait, but they
didn't show me this one in this
boot camp. So this doesn't make
sense. And I had to just decide
like, okay, pick one. Job, the
others, try to finish this one,
and then maybe pick up another
one afterwards. So I was, so I
mainly use some front end
masters, and of course, YouTube.
And I haven't even gotten to the
Udemy ones yet. But I have like,
one boot camp with me because I
did buy the cold Steel's boot
camp last year, but I still
haven't gotten to it yet. So
main sources, front end masters.
Free Code Camp here for some
little things like piece of code
that I know that I honestly
better than and Udemy and
YouTube.  Yeah. Those are the
main ones.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think it
can be super hard as you're
trying to figure that out, too.
Right? Like you're seeing there
can be conflicting material or
one teaches one approach. And
there's, it just makes it really
hard to kind of learn. But also,
if you can find something that's
good, I was doing a boot camp
before I went to flat iron that
I just dreaded opening up every
morning. Because the material
was just so hard for me. It was
a lot of videos, and I struggle
with videos. And they just kept
trying to make jokes in the
videos. And I was so frustrated
with it. Like just just tell me
what I need to do. And then just
deciding I'm not doing this,
it's not worth it. If it's gonna
make me frustrated and hate what
I'm doing, then I need to find
something better. And that works
for me. And so I think that
sometimes exactly what you did
is a good path, like look at
these things, and then kind of
figure out what you need to
focus on.
Debra-Kaye: Yeah, and the funny
thing is like I was doing and
granted, granted. Free Code Camp
is a great resource, like that's
the first thing I tell everybody
to go to. And like for the first
like couple sections. I was like
okay, yeah, I understand this,
but I got like, half Through
CSS, and I was like, I don't
know what I'm doing. And it will
say things like, you know,
remember so and so I was like, I
would have to literally go back
to that read the thing again, do
the little exercise again,
because I just wasn't getting
it. And then I kept switching
between that and something else.
And that's important in frontend
masters. I was like, I need to
pick one. And when I started
frontend Masters again, for
like, the third time, I was
like, Oh, wait, this makes
sense. No. And it took me like
partway through to realize that
I wasn't learning inline CSS for
one boot camp, and external CSS
for the other one. And that's
why it wasn't clicking. Because
I despise inline CSS, like, I
just don't read the code. I was
like, I don't know what this is
saying. But it is the external
stylesheet what I can see
everything like, lined up. I was
like, oh, and that's when he
starts to click. And I was like,
okay, yep, jump in this one for
now, because I don't understand
anything here. And let me go do
this one, because I understand
this one better. And I also
like, boot camps or tutorials
where you get like little
exercises to do on your own. And
you actually have to write the
code or to yourself, that you
have to type it from beginning
from your h1, and you have to
like everything on your own,
because it helps us do better
than when a tutorial gives you a
part of the code. And you have
to like change a little one lane
or a little change a color. So
for me, it worked better, where
I had to, like, type everything
out myself, because it helped it
stick out.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I'm the same way
I am. I don't know, I don't ever
remember anything from like
reading or watching videos or
anything like that until I until
I can actually, you know, write
it or apply it or whatever.
Whether it's exercise, you know,
at the end of a course, or, you
know, actually trying to do a
project that uses whatever I
learned that kind of thing. For
me, that is always it's always a
way to make it actually stick in
my brain and if I'm going to be
honest, to actually understand
it, you know, I'll sit there not
through a video or a talk or
something, and I won't ever if
somebody asked me a question at
the end, I'd be like, I'm not
really sure. Until I, it's I sit
there and use it, you know? And
I'm like, okay, yes, yeah.
Debra-Kaye: Yeah, and one of the
things that I found that work
for me too, is like, shorter
videos, because there are some
tutorials that are like, an hour
long, four hours long, like 20
hours, this and you know, and I,
like I can't, my attention span
is like really short. So like,
with the front end masters
videos, they're all like really
short, like a minute, four
minutes, five minutes. But for
me watching a video is actually
like, the instructor will say
one thing and be like, to do
this, you do this, and I hit
pause, and I'll just start to
try to do it. So for me watching
a video is like me spending two
hours trying to get through one
video, because I will just hit
pause and try to do it, and
rewind and try it again. So a
one hour video for me could
probably take like, I don't
know, five hours because I don't
like to make plays through I
will just, stop trying to do it.
Didn't get that. Okay, and then
play it again. Try to do it.
Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
that's a really great point.
Like you just said, a one hour
video can take me five hours,
right? Because sometimes when
you're learning something, you
think like, Okay, well, I'm
gonna sit here for an hour, I
have an hour. But that's not
practical application of what
you're learning. And so as
you're going through those
things, actually doing them,
it's going to take more time,
but you're going to learn more
in the long run. And so thinking
about it like that, in terms of
I remember when I was in boot
camp, I had maybe complain that
it wasn't clear how long each
lesson was going to take or
exercise. And then somebody
responded, and they said, Well,
you know, part of it is learning
how long it is going to take you
because it will be different for
everyone else. And that was a
lesson that didn't really click
with me until later. But, you
know, depending on where you're
at, and how you approach it, and
how much you've taken and
understood from the previous
lessons, it's going to affect
how long that thing is going to
take you. And don't judge
yourself based on how long it
takes you judge how much
progress you've made and think
about like how much you've
learned through doing that. It's
not it's not a race, right?
Debra-Kaye: And something that
you also realize, too, there are
some things that even though
you've done it to through the
video, so you may you know, stop
and code it. There's some things
that you just can't remember to
do. Or something that you kind
of can't figure out why it's not
working but they didn't Realize
that you didn't do something or
you missed something in the
code. And then there are other
things that you'd have to think
about you just type it because
it's just there in your brain
and some things just don't
stick.
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah. And that's,
I mean, that's like part of
learning how to code, right? You
know, and trying to do that,
while you're watching a video,
watching it in the middle of an
hour long video seems
challenging, the best as egghead
has their courses. So it's like
a course on a topic, but it's a
series of, you know, of short
videos, like you're saying, you
know, and so they have like
broken up, you know, built in
pauses. So it's like, one,
you're gonna learn and like a
large thing, and it's how, you
know, an hour long, an hour's
worth of content, but you just
see that it's broken up. This is
like, a minute and a half
chapter or whatever it is,
whatever they call it, but I
like the way that they they
organize that because they kind
of realize that nobody is going
to really learn anything
sitting, consuming for an hour,
you know? or not, I shouldn't
say nobody. But you know, it's,
it's probably challenging for a
lot of people to do that. Do it
that way.
Debra-Kaye: And then some things
you will still have to Google.
Oh, yeah. Because some things
you just can't remember.
Dan Ott: on that, that's also
always true. I don't know, I've
been you know, I've been a
developer for for a while now.
And I google that mean, I google
things every, every day as that
I don't know, multiple times a
day, if you know, if I'm going,
I can't, I can't recover.
There's one. There's like an
array method that just a
JavaScript thing. That is just
like been the same for 100
years. And I, I literally just
can't remember the order of you
know how things go in. I look it
up every single time. I don't
know, I don't know what it is
mental block, but that Google is
top top developer tool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's,
I've been writing my blog with
markdown for a couple of years
now. And I can never remember
the right format for the link.
Like I googled it every single
time every years, right, and it
just wouldn't stick. And then I
had tweeted about it. And people
like offered me all of these
different ways to remember it.
And finally one of them clicked
and now now I don't have to
Google it, the brackets, the
brackets come first and the
parentheses come second, like a
function. I think that's what
they were kind of saying,
anyway, doesn't matter. It makes
sense to me. And now I don't
need to give up. But I did for
like two years straight. And I
think that's kind of part of the
other thing, too, right? Like,
sometimes you'll be presented
the information and somebody,
there will be 12 people that
give you a different
explanation. And that one
explanation will fit. And I
think there's a tendency for new
developers or people who are
learning to think about, well, I
can't get this in this other
person got it. And so I must not
be good enough for this, right.
And that's not true. It's just
not presented in a way that
makes sense to your brain or
something that's easily usable.
But that's why it's great to
have so many different people
writing blogs or creating
content, because there's more
options for you to kind of
search out and, and figure out
what works for you.
Debra-Kaye: That took me a while
to understand that and took me a
while to accept to because I was
like I sorted it, this should be
easy for me. And I kind of
thought going into this that it
would be so easy because I did a
degree in it. And when I did my
degree I did Java and c++. And
granted, I didn't understand a
thing in Java. Like, I just
couldn't get it. I mean that I
had to get so much help with
that course. And I did. c++, did
discrete maths and started
thinking called I can't remember
the name of the other course.
And I was like, Okay, I managed
to get through those granted a
lot of help because they were
just, it wasn't clicking. And my
issue was she loved programming.
Like she's like a hardcore
programmer. And she's like, you
should do this. And you should
go to your masters now. But I
just it just wasn't clicking.
And when I found out about web
development, I was like, Okay,
this should be easy for me to be
able to catch on because I
started it and I Tinker in it
all the time, but it just wasn't
clicking. And that kind of
starts to feel like, maybe it's
me. And especially when you see
so many other developers out
there who've been doing this for
five years, 10 years, 20 years,
and they make everything so
easy. You start to feel like
okay, maybe you're not just cut
up, maybe you're not cut out for
it. Maybe you're just this is
not for you. And it really took
me a while to realize that,
okay, I'm not the only person
who struggles with someone These
things like, it's actually not
as easy as people make it look,
for some people, it may click
quicker than some, but it's, if
it was kind of easy, everybody
would do it took me a while to
get to that place.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I think that's
really important. And I mean,
I'm glad to have gotten to that
realization, because it comes up
a lot. And I've been thinking
about this, I've been thinking
about this recently about how
everybody is, I keep saying
everybody, but lots of people
learn in ways similar to you,
right? Sort of on their own
different courses, you know,
maybe boot camps or whatever,
but much different than sort of
in school, right. And so, if you
were going in school, you'd be
in a class with other people.
And you're not following 7000
people who are already experts
at what you're learning. And so,
you know, and I've been thinking
about how to, like, approach
that, right? Because, on one
hand, I like following people
who are, you know, domain
experts in whatever it is I want
to learn about, but at the same
time, that that sort of
pressure, external pressure, and
it's not even the it's not even
those, anybody's fault, right.
But once you know, something,
you probably like to talk about
it. Right? But coming from when
you don't know it, you know,
it's just like you're saying, it
can seem it can seem like they
make it seem easy, you know, and
how to how to approach that like
learning process, when you're
when you're starting out. How to
avoid falling, falling into that
trap, you know, of like,
following all those people,
because you're like, Okay, let's
have developers to follow, you
know, like, follow these
different, different Twitter
accounts, and, or whatever it is
blog posts. And meanwhile,
there's like 1000s and 1000s
people in the exact same boat,
you know, struggling and, you
know, trying to push through
everything and trying to figure
out what to learn next, and
they're not on all the top
developers to follow lists, you
know, you know what I mean?
It's, I know, it's an
interesting problem. And I don't
have any solutions or anything,
but you know, it's an
interesting problem to think
about. And you're not like, I
just lots of people we talk to
here at Virtual Coffee, on the
podcast or in, you know, Virtual
Coffee proper, I guess, around
the table and then have the same
sort of realizations, you know,
that, like, it's a struggle,
it's hard. It's hard to learn.
And it's hard to learn anything
new. And I don't know, I have
been. Yep, I don't know. That's
the end of my thing. I don't
have any further, I don't really
have a question or a statement,
you know, but it's a very
interesting topic to me.
Debra-Kaye: It's something that
I also realized too, like, and
honestly, Virtual Coffee is the
committee that has made me feel
more comfortable asking
questions. But it is something
that I noticed too. You know,
even on Twitter, right? Even if
you decide to ask for some
wherever you ask questions,
especially as a newbie, like, I
am so good at overwhelming
myself with like, all the things
to learn all these things. But
sometimes when you ask like a
really a question that you think
in your head is really simple.
And I mean, it's not overly
complicated, but it's just, it
hasn't clicked for you yet. And
you may ask somebody who is an
experienced developer, and they
give you this really advanced
answer. And, you know, you do
this and you do this. And this,
like, I don't even know what
that is. And because they have
been doing this for a while,
they kind of don't really know
how to explain something in like
layman's terms to a beginner
where it like it will connect
the dots for you. And because I
even I'm learning it, and I'm,
like, a little bit more
comfortable with it now. But as
asking someone a person about
it, and they gave me like, this
answer was like, Oh, my god, I
don't even know what to do with
that. So is there any way to
like, avoid that right now?
Because I don't know how to do
that. And I'm gonna mess up
something if I try it. So it's
like also realizing for yourself
how you learn, and also to not
try to grab everything because
you need to learn everything. So
I like and I mean, even when you
Google stuff, too, like I said,
yesterday evening, reading a
blog post trying to fix
something in CSS, and I read the
article just like, I don't know,
five minutes long, and I still
didn't understand what to do. So
it's it's really, it's a tricky
kind of thing. Because some
people we don't know how to
break down the answer on your
level because they've been doing
it for so long, it's so natural
for them. And for you, it's not
really natural. So it's, it's,
it's a tricky, it's a, it's like
dicey. It's tricky.
Dan Ott: It is. And it can be,
it can even be not so much that
they don't know how but they
haven't. Like, maybe they don't
know you, personally very well
yet, or they don't know where
you are on your journey or any
person, you know. So if you're
answering a question, it's hard
to, like, intuitively calibrate,
you know, your, your answer, you
know what I mean, for a given
person, other than just talking
to them, which is what I do,
like when I'm when I'm like,
starting a pairing session with
somebody who I haven't worked
with before. Like, if they're,
if they're trying to solve a
specific problem, you know, the
first questions I sort of gauge
I like, I just try to gauge
like, where, you know, what,
like, where, what things they do
know, and what things they
don't, so that we can, like,
talk in the language that like,
both of us understand, you know,
because in a couple years, you
know, you're going to be, you're
just gonna have all that good
stuff under your belt, and
you're gonna forget about how
hard it was, you know? And then
and your answers, if somebody
asks the same question, we'll be
okay, we'll just do this. And
this, you know, and then it's
very easy, like, because that's
the process that's in your
brain, right? So like, Okay, how
do I do this? Oh, well, what I
would what Dan would do is, you
know, x y&z except if I don't
have, you know, if the person
doesn't know, at what x it means
that answer is useless. Right?
So calibrating like, trying to
figure out how to how to
calibrate those answers is
complicated, it doesn't fit
everybody, you know? Because if
they're answering that good
question. I don't know. Like,
like, there are ways, you know,
you could just write a book on
pretty much any question about
get, like, you know, what I
mean? Like, the answer to any
question on get, if you get all
the way down to it is like very
complicated, you know, and, and
same with react, and same with
JavaScript is all just a bunch
of House of Cards of different,
you know, different pieces of
data, you know, and it's just, I
feel, I feel, it's, it's, I
feel, I was gonna say feel bad,
it's not quite right. But like,
I can understand the struggle of
trying to learn all this stuff,
you know, at once, all at once,
you know, early, because when I
learned there was none of when I
was learning HTML and CSS there,
like, it didn't, it didn't even
exist. Yes, exactly. You know,
like, I didn't have to learn
git, or version control or
whatever, because we were just
like cobbling files up to like a
server, you know, it was bad.
Like, I'm glad that it exists
now. But it's complicated on its
own, you know, and it's this
whole, this whole thing, I
always try to tell people to
just learn one thing at once,
you know,
Debra-Kaye: it's kind of hard to
like, it's tricky, because like,
on one hand, like in your head,
you know, you need to focus on
one thing. So you can, like be
good at something. But at the
same time, with tech, you kind
of have to know how to do one or
two things at least. So you can
never really be learning one
thing alone, at whatever, at one
point in time, you kind of have
to know how to do at least two
things to go because they are
they connect somehow. So it's
kind of hard to just focus on
one thing. So it's, and that's
why people will get trapped into
whole learning to three
different languages at the same
time. Like, I'm not even trying
to learn frameworks yet. Because
like, I want to get really good
at JavaScript, cuz like, the
advice that I keep getting is,
if you get good at JavaScript,
or you can handle yourself with
it, then everything else will
come a little bit easier. So I'm
not really worried about
frameworks. I kind of already
know which framework I want to
learn first, which is view but
looks like down the road. And I
probably will learn react, of
course, because I noticed the
demand and everything. But
people will get caught up in the
all in the Buddhist framework is
hot right now, that is hot right
now. And people will be trying
to learn two, three at the same
time. And then there are really
an ad from what I have learned.
And I'm constantly being told,
like, get your basics, right.
And like once you get your
foundation set, then everything
else will come. And I'm trying
to get the foundation set. So
but it's really easy to get
caught up in the whole, you
know, hot new thing, and also
learning more than one thing at
a time because tech changes so
quickly, too. So it's kind of a
tricky balance.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: It is
really tricky. And I think what
works for one person doesn't
work for every person to write,
like we've been saying. And I
think, you know, sometimes
jumping into a framework might
be the way to go and like not
mastering all those things. I
know I think it was when I Went
from Ruby to rails. Ruby, like I
was kind of getting it. And but
then I hit rails. And I was
like, oh, okay, now suddenly,
this makes sense. And I'm not
sure what made it click, but
jumping into the framework
helped me to understand things a
lot better than I had before.
And so it was, you know, kind of
this backwards way of doing
things, but hearing other people
say like, Oh, yeah, I've done
that, too. There weren't as many
people saying that there were a
lot of people saying that's not
the right way to go. But it
there's not a right way and a
wrong way. There's the way that
works for you. And, you know,
it's great to be able to
recognize what those things are.
Yeah. No, deprecate. I know,
like learning on your own, I
went to a boot camp. And I feel
like that was challenging. I was
online, and I didn't have a
sense of community. But I'm sure
learning on your own is maybe
extra challenging, because you
are trying to like, find good
resources, and maybe find
communities. So I, you know, can
you talk a little bit about what
has been most challenging for
you?
Debra-Kaye: Yeah, so I have been
like trying to learn on my own
well this year would make it two
years. But they found that
before I found Virtual Coffee, I
was, I started to like, do a
little rabbit hole research. But
I was just like, trying to look
at too many things at once. And
I never had any one of I could
ask questions. And I was just
struggling because I would, I
was going through one free boot
camp. And I was even trying to
do the 100 days of code thing.
And if I missed the day, I would
just be like, okay, I messed up,
I'm gonna start over because I
wasn't really consistent. And I
wasn't really focused. And I had
no way to talk to about what I
was struggling with. So it was
just difficult. So I would start
and stop and start and stop. And
if I did good for a week, and I
missed two days, because I just
was too burnt out to do it. I
was like, Okay, let's start
over. No, because I kind of
messed it up and had no way to
keep me accountable as couldn't
ask the questions, I will be
like, going through the bootcamp
didn't understand what I was
doing, and had nobody to ask and
felt like, okay, it's not for
me, because it's not clicking,
why is it not clicking? Now get
frustrated, and the frustration
would just cause me to be like,
okay, it's not working. And then
when I would see like, someone
tweet, like, Hey, I'm struggling
with this. And I'm like, okay,
it's not me alone. So maybe I
should try again. And then I
will try again, then get
frustrated at some point and
stop again. So that was really
like actually actively looking
for a community that I felt
comfortable in. And when I
finally found Virtual Coffee,
and I was like, Oh, my god. But
it really took me a while
because studying on your own
like, on one hand, self paced,
boot camps are great. But if you
have no one who is in it with
you, and you have no one to ask
questions, or be like, Hey, I'm
not getting this is it me. And
for someone to tell you that
it's not you, it's actually
normal to struggle through this
process. And it's like a long
journey. Like, I have no problem
with learning forever because I
constant learner. So I have no
problem learning forever. Like,
that's my thing. But when you
have when you know that there
are people who are also
struggling, and can help you to
get through those rough patches,
and encourage you, it is not
you, you're going to get it.
It's okay. It's not getting it
today, but you will get it Don't
worry about it. And to kind of
talk you out of procrastinating
and talk to you all itself,
talking yourself, although
stuff. That's a great thing took
me a while to find that space.
But that was me that I was just
like, up and down, up and down.
Start today start next week,
frustrated, okay? I have no one
to talk to about it. And more so
me it's not really you, it's
normal and you won't get it in a
month. You won't get it in a
day. So it was that was really
instrumental for me because I
when you study on your own, it's
just not. And we don't really
even even without the pandemic
like I don't really have anyone
who like is like really Intertek
or wants to learn this thing. So
to find a community where You
people have the same interest as
you. And they actually went
through it. So they kind of know
what you're struggling with and
understand like, hey, this was
shiny for me too. Or maybe you
could think about it this way,
like some suggestions, anything,
but just something to help you
realize that it's, it's normal
for you to struggle through this
because the learning curve is
steep, and you're not going to
get it overnight.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
like That's it. That's it,
right? It's normal for you to
struggle through this because
there's so much I don't know if
I would call it imposter
syndrome or whatever. doubts
that comes when you're like, I'm
struggling, that must mean I'm
not good at this, or I'm not
meant to do this. And that's not
true at all. Right? we all
struggle through it, or most of
us.
Debra-Kaye: That's exactly it,
like the imposter syndrome is is
real. Like, I know, people talk
about this, I know that there's
so many articles I have read
them, I have watched the videos,
but when you're trying to learn
something, and when you're like,
why is it not easy for me? Or as
easy for me? Or why is it that
this person like gets it and I'm
not getting it, the imposter
syndrome will be like, it will
tell you stuff that it will
really make you procrastinate.
And I spent a lot of time
procrastinating too, because I
just like I'm not getting it. So
it's me, I'm not getting it. And
then we're taught myself how to
stop because this like, it's not
for me, it's not cooking. So
maybe I'm not cut out for this.
So imposter syndrome is so real.
And like, I know, maybe even
last year, developers may think
Oh, these your developers talk
about imposter syndrome, they
didn't know that I still have
it. Or maybe as a senior, you
may not have it as much because
you have some experience. But as
a junior with where and how tech
is now 2021, a lot of things
have changed. And you know,
tools and all these things will
always be coming Oh, but when
you're just starting to learn
something, and you have to try
to get up to par with where the
text base is today. And you have
such a long way to go. Seniors
don't really think because they
have already passed that stage.
And I really understand that
imposter syndrome for a junior
s probably even more than wh t
they feel now, because they
ve been doing it for 5-10 years
So you know, you can have an
dea of what you're doing. You k
ow, you don't know everything,
but you kind of know what yo 're
doing to a point. But a ju
ior who has no clue what the 're
doing, has like 1000 times
the imposter syndrome, becaus we
don't know what we're do
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
that senior devs are just better
at hiding their imposter
syndrome. And like over the last
year, I have been surprised at
so many of our members who I
would have expected to be super
confident in things say that
they're nervous about doing it,
or they don't know if they're
good enough to be doing this
thing. And that was so eye
opening for me because I thought
like, wow, you know, they're
here. They're doing great.
They've had this amazing career.
But it was it was just like
this, this hidden thing, where I
think people on this journey
where a lot of us are openly
talking about it, which is
great. And I think that that
should happen more. But it's
been, you know, like we're all
here in tech grows and moves so
quickly that it makes sense that
we frequently don't feel like we
know what we're doing. Because
we can't it just keeps moving.
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah. I mean, I I
don't know, it's one of those
things where it for me, I it
makes sense that a person would
struggle with learning, like
learning to be a developer,
like, for the first time,
because I can't remember if I
can actually remember it being
very hard. You know, it's hard.
And I think, as somebody who
like in a senior developer role
I, it's the imposter syndrome
rears its head all the time, but
sort of different, right?
Because, like, not different.
It's in different spots, right?
Because I do like, I'm not like,
it's more like, Okay, well, what
if, I don't know, I don't know
how to phrase this. Like, what
if everybody finds out, you
know, like, that's the thing,
you know, like, it's, I'm not
finding trying to find a job for
the first time and I'm not
trying to, like learn this whole
new thing, you know, but so
it's, I don't know, if it's
like, just not as sharply like
you were saying, like, maybe
when you're learning for the
first time it's, it happens more
often or something and that
might be true, you know? Right.
Right. Right. But yeah, You
know, and I feel like once
you're there, and also back to
what you said, we never like,
it's it's the this sort of
feeling, I feel like once you
are more experienced, like, once
you've been doing I think for a
long time is a little bit more
under the surface, even under
your own like, like
subconscious, you know,
sometimes I'm like, I don't have
imposter syndrome, I just
embedded This is like what I say
to myself, like, oh, wait a
minute, that's, you know, like,
those are like feelings that I
have. Often even, you know,
like, trying to push through
these things, it still happens.
I think it happens to a lot of
people. And you know, some
people don't talk about it, some
people don't realize that it is
happening or you know. And then
and then some people do talk
about it, but--
Debra-Kaye: And then too, sorry,
and then also, as a junior, I
guess, because while you have
some senior developers who are
more open about talking about
the imposter syndrome, and then
there are others who, you know,
you don't really see that, you
know, they cannot make it look
like Oh, I'm so good at this not
been doing this for 20 years.
But as a junior, because we
don't really see seniors talk
about that they haven't pursued
and we think, you know, they're
so good at this, like, they know
it, because they've been doing
this for so long. So we're like,
when are we ever going to feel
comfortable knowing enough? and
be able to show that we know
enough? Because and like no
enough is like a relative of
course, because you know, this
space is like so crazy, where
you know, there are always new
things to learn. And I love
that. But also, it's almost
like, from a newbie you you kind
of feel like, when will I apart
from trying to actually learn
the things? I'm going to do it?
It's almost like, when will I
ever feel like I know enough?
And how can I show someone, you
know, a company, a contractor,
whatever, that I know enough to
do this. And because we don't
really see the senior developers
openly showing that, hey, you
kind of won't know everything,
and it's okay. And you may see
me here 20 years later, but I
was at the same point you were
and when I started, things were
much different. Things have
changed a lot now. So it's okay,
you will get there. And you
don't have to try to get to my
20 year veteran, but just get
comfortable with enough things
that you can do whatever you're
required to do, or you know how
to go about learning how to do
it? Yeah,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think we
were just in the book club
meeting. And somebody there has
been a developer for 15 years.
But as a freelance developer,
and one of the things they were
talking about was, they don't
have feedback from anyone,
because they take on freelance
clients. And so they don't ever
really know how they're doing
right. And I think that's also
plays into this role of
learning, especially on your
own, or in a place where you're
not getting feedback from people
because you are kind of your own
reference point. And you're you
are looking like Dan was saying,
you follow all these people on
Twitter, right, who have been
doing this for years. And so
then it becomes you and these
people that you're looking at,
and you have no one to kind of
look at what you're doing and
say like, Look, you're doing a
great job. And this is amazing.
And hey, I didn't know that
thing. And I've been doing it
this long rate. And so that lack
of community response or
feedback can be really
challenging to gauge where you
are.
Debra-Kaye: Yeah, yeah. And they
did to me a while to like,
connect those dots too. Because
when you're learning on your
own, you really don't have
anyone to bypass ideas have to
be like, Hey, I don't know what
this means. Can you walk me
through this? And also, as a new
person, one of the things that I
learned the hard way is asking
for help. Because you don't want
to look like I mean, you don't
know what you're doing. But you
kind of don't want anyone to
know that you don't know what
you're doing. So it took me a
while to ask questions. And
sometimes it's also a case of
finding the right people to ask
those questions, because not
everyone will be willing to
assist you. But find the right
people who are willing to help
and would actually encourage you
to ask questions. That was a big
thing for me because I don't
like to ask for help. It kind of
sounds weird, but you don't want
to seem like you have no clue
what you're doing. But you also
what I've learned is that It is
better to ask questions than to
sit there and struggle and you
know, doing the wrong thing, and
you have no idea that you're
doing the wrong thing, or you're
going about it the wrong way. So
asking for help is really
important. And when you find a
great community that you can ask
for help, or the person that
that you know, who is willing to
assist you. And they will
actually walk you through
something, you realize, Oh, so I
kind of got a but I just went
wrong, right here. Or I could
think about it this way. So
asking practice are really is a
really big thing. But new people
are suppose as newbies, we don't
like to ask for help, because we
just don't want to look like we
have no clue what we're doing.
We don't but we don't want
anyone to know that. So, yeah,
that's my focus really, really a
big thing, too.
Dan Ott: Yeah. I mean, I don't
really have anything to add,
other than I love that if I
think it's great advice. I think
asking questions is important.
And I think it's a burden for
everybody at every level, you
know, but just like you're
saying, you know, you're saying
you didn't want to, I don't
know, appear like you didn't
know anything, or whatever. But
the fact that you're working on
anything, have a question to ask
even as evidence enough, that,
that you that you do know,
things, you know what I mean?
And I don't know, it's, it's
possible to struggle through
everything all by yourself, you
know, it is possible, but it's
much easier with, with people,
and it's not even just like
learning how to be a dev or
whatever, you know, any problem
you're struggling with, you
know, is, is at some point going
to be better if you can get
somebody else to, like, look at
it, or, you know, talk through
your, your mental process, or
whatever it is, you know, asking
questions is just, it's just
such a useful tool, you know, an
important important thing to
keep in mind.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
think, to go along with that,
you call it a useful tool. And I
think that's a good way to frame
it, right, because it is
something that we need to
develop. And it's something that
we need to use often. And I
think if you could learn that
while you're learning, it's so
important, because it took me a
lot longer to learn about asking
questions, and when to ask
questions. for a lot of reasons
you said, Debra-Kaye, you know,
I was like working, but I didn't
want anybody to think I didn't
know what I was doing. And so
then I just like, I don't know,
I was trying to, you know, carve
a mountain and no that I was
just gonna go and do this
analogy. And it's just not not
gonna work.=
So the point is, ask questions
early.
Dan Ott: No, no, I want to know
what it was.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Like, I can
see the image in my head too, of
like, where it was going and how
it would play out.It looks cool,
but doesn't translate.
Dan Ott: There's a podcast, I
listened to that. They've built
up this very complicated
metaphor for like brain
processes. And like it's, it's
it's a it's a, it's complicated,
and they built it up in like,
the first couple episodes, and
then they just use it the rest
of the time. And so they're
like, referring to these weird
things. Like, I think if you
jump in the middle of like, if
you just listen to the most
recent podcast episode, you have
no idea what they're talking
about. But I
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: -- that's
what I was trying to avoid.
Exactly. Okay, so we're like,
trying to see what we have.
We're just about at time. So I
just want to know before, I
don't want to wrap up if there's
something else that you want to
talk about. So if there's
anything else that you want to
cover, we can go ahead.
Debra-Kaye: No, I mean, I just
want to say that I encourage
people to play me encouraging
someone to ask questions and to
not be afraid to put yourself
out there that took me a long
time to get comfortable doing
that. still working on it. But
you have to get to a point where
you're willing to take a little
tiny step and ask a question and
ask for help and share something
that you think you don't know,
but can actually help someone
else. And it took me a long time
to get there. Because I even
like just started blogging, not
just started but last year, late
last year, and I was like, you
know how to write about tech and
I don't know anything about
tech, but I've just been like
trying to write about My
experience in learning my
learning journey, and the way
that I saw it resonate with
other people. I was like, No,
some are the only one who feels
this way. Cool. And that kind of
helps show me that I'm not alone
in in the struggle, and like, I
knew I was ventually getting,
but when I saw other people
responding like, this is me to a
team and was like, Okay, cool.
So it's not only me, that's
really cool. Like, that was like
the highlight of my day when I
read that feedback. Like, okay,
cool. That means I'm on the
right track. It's not only me,
this is kind of cool.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I love that. I, I
don't know, that's always a
piece of advice I give to
everybody to is is writing at
any point, any point in your in
your journey, you know what I
mean? But like the those, it's
so valuable to share those
experiences, you know, I get
appreciate it down the road to
when, when you're, you know, was
an old developer who's been
around the road and, you know,
reading back, I mean, I mean, I
had I have blog posts from, you
know, early in my career, I
guess, but they're not. I was in
college when I was learning for
the first time, I was still on
my own. I wasn't learning in
college. But But like, I didn't
mean, I wasn't writing any of
this down. And I do wish I had
even just for myself records,
you know, of this sort of thing.
I think it's I think it's very
cool. And a very good idea. for
a lot of reasons.
Debra-Kaye: Yeah. Someone wrote
a blog post about that. I think
it was I can't remember if it
was swyx, on Twitter, Shawn,
somebody who I think it was him,
but just the idea of like
documenting your journey,
because not really for anyone's
benefit, per se, but for your
own benefit. Because I've seen a
lot of developers see that the
maybe solve a problem. And they
wrote about it. And then when
they forgot how to do it, they
would search and find by their
own blogs and be like, Oh,
actually, what about this, to
remind themselves how to do that
thing or help solve that
problem. So I and I like to
write and but I'm always
something like what I write
about. So like, my job is always
what am I What am I going to
write about? Because I don't
know it yet. But writing is
something that I definitely want
to continue when, like, have it
be a part of my thing, because I
always did like to write I did
my blog before but not tech
blogs. Because I always had the
thinking that I have to actually
be an expert in it before I can
write about it. So and that's
why I always procrastinated on
trying to blog because I'm like,
I don't know enough to write
about it yet. So what am I going
to write? Yeah. So it's, it's
it's a it's a journey.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's for
sure. Okay, you have given us so
much great information. And
thank you so much for being with
us here today. We are very
excited to be able to share
this. Thank you.
Debra-Kaye: Thank you for having
me. This was great. This was
fun.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: All right.
Well, we will talk to you soon.
Bye.
Debra-Kaye: Bye.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
@VirtualCoffeeIO. Or you can
email us at podcast at Virtual
coffee.io. You can find the show
notes. Plus you can sign up for
our newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtualcoffee.io.
Dan Ott: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.