Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season two, Episode
Five of the Virtual Coffee
podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Today we
talk with Tom Cudd, a systems
architect and 20 year veteran in
technology. We talked about his
experiences with DevOps and how
it changed over the years about
psychological safety. What that
means to Tom and how important
it is to build into your team
and workflows, and about the
dangers of hero culture in the
workplace.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee, we introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from
what we do, and a random
checking question. Today's
question is, if you could start
a collection of one kind of
item, what would it be? We hope
you enjoyed this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could start a
collection of one type of item,
one kind of item. I don't know
what it would be. But when I was
a kid, I used to collect tree
fungus. And that's one type of
item. So there you go.
Dan Ott: Wow, I think a million
guesses and I wouldn't have
guessed though.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Also,
cicada shells. I had a
collection of shells. Yeah. But
tree fungus is very serious.
Dan Ott: This year is one of the
17 year, cicadas years.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
it's missing us. So it's gonna
hit like Pittsburgh, it's
looking to go around, so...
Dan Ott: Fair enough. Hi, I'm
Dan. I'm a front end developer
from Lakewood, Ohio.
So if I could start a collection
of one item, what would it be?
And I feel like this implies
that I can't I can't like, say
anything that I've already
collected, you know, that I have
a collection currently have. And
I like I said, so I'm going with
something brand new, but I feel
like I could get into like
shoes, you know, like I could
see, you know, again into the
sneakers, you know what I mean?
Like that, that I try to stay
really far away from it so that
I don't like, you know,
accidentally get sucked into it.
I can get carried away with
like, collecting pretty much
anything, you know, very easily.
So I tried really, really hard
not.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Not trying
really hard not to collect
fungus.
Dan Ott: Yes. Including that.
Tom Cudd: So I'm Tom Cudd. I'm a
systems architect in the Kansas
City, Missouri area. Yeah, I'm a
reformed hoarder, I think so
like I have a lot of collections
that I've had to like get rid of
over the years. So I'll say
something that I have not
collected before. I would
collect exotic supercars
because, you know, oh, that'd be
pretty awesome. Except, you
know, you'd have to actually pay
for them. But I do like cars. I
I'm not like a car person. I
just really think that fast cars
are awesome.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that'd be cool.
That'd be cool thing to have a
collection of for sure.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. Well,
welcome, Tom. we're really,
really excited to be talking to
you today. So thanks for being
here. And the way we normally
get started is we ask all of our
guests, kind of how they got
into tech or where they are now.
So if you can give us your
origin story we would like to
hear
Tom Cudd: Yeah, absolutely. I
think I took more of the
traditional approach if you
would call it that. To get into
tech I graduated from University
of Nebraska Lincoln with a
computer engineering degree.
That meant I focused a lot on
like hardware and electrical
engineering in some of my
classes. But by the time I
rolled around the end, I was
like, I don't want to like
design chips or anything like
that. So I started looking
around for for it was pretty bad
job market when I when I
graduated. So I just tried to
find whatever I could that was
remotely related to tech and
ended up doing like desktop
support and For a small mom and
pop shop, which, which most
people would actually call a
startup now. So like we did like
dial up internet for people in
rural, we did wireless internet,
like off of wireless towers to
get more high speed and I fix
people's computers I installed,
you know, modems and desktops
and sent people on their way. So
I did that for a few years and
eventually moved into sort of
the more enterprise space. So
now, after years of kind of
building up moving on from
desktops to data centers, now
I'm, I guess, I work a lot in
the cloud space. So I'm kind of
a cloud engineer, cloud
architect, right? I do work in
Azure and AWS to build out
infrastructure, with
infrastructures, code, and
whatever new technologies come
about.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. So
one of the things we wanted to
talk about today was DevOps. And
before I ask any questions, can
you give us a definition of
DevOps?
Tom Cudd: Yes, there are many
definitions of DevOps. It's sort
of like asking people what agile
is, you'll get a lot of
different answers, depending on
what people's experiences are. I
look at DevOps from a cultural
and professional perspective. So
like, it's more about a culture
and mentality, one where there's
an emphasis on, on collaborating
and working together with
different parts of the
organization. It's it's sort of
misnamed, because DevOps implies
that there's just two pieces
that would be working together,
we're really it's like, Bus,
Dev, Sec, QA, Ops, you know,
like, it's like, trying to bring
everybody to the table. So yeah,
I look at it from the
perspective of it's a, it's a
cultural movement, that
encourages collaboration across
what were previously known as
silos within organizations or
experiences.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think
that's a really great
definition. And when I was
looking for a job, when I lost
my job, at the beginning of the
pandemic, someone reached out to
me to apply for a DevOps job.
And they asked me what my
definition was. And it was,
like, I had a very little
understanding. And so my
homework for the next interview
was to read the Phoenix Project
in the Unicorn Project, and then
come back with a definition of
what DevOps was. But I wish I
could have just asked you then,
but I don't think I knew you
then.
Tom Cudd: I would have gladly
given the answer. Yeah. I mean,
a lot of people think it's, it's
like, I might apply for this
like DevOps job, it's people who
were--I call them reformed
systems administrators often
really have just titled change
to kind of DevOps engineers. And
so, a, there's a certain set of
experiences around operational
tools and techniques, like
deployments, you know, Jenkins
builds and, and doing releases,
that's sort of traditional what
used to be, when the developers
are done coding, they throw a
tarball over the over the wall
and expect an operations person
had to deploy it out onto the
server. So that's sort of what
many people consider the
mechanics, the actual tactics of
a lot of DevOps, folks, but
it's, it's more than that. Now,
it takes a little bit of
experiences from all sorts of
technology areas.
Dan Ott: It's interesting, the
rise of DevOps, and you were
touching on this, it's been
interesting to watch. Because I,
my experience, for a large
portion of my career was the
same, right, like, I kind of
finished my coding thing, and
then I'm like, okay, make it so.
Right. Like, you know, somebody
put this up on the internet, you
know, and, and there's so many
tools now available, you know,
that, like the cloud services
and everything, you know, that
some barriers have been lowered,
right. But that means, but also,
like, lots of times, somebody
who traditionally would never
have to even think about that
sort of thing has to think about
a lot of it. Now, as more with
smaller, you know, with smaller
outfits, probably, but I guess,
I guess I was wondering if,
like, if you talk more like how
you've seen that, that's sort of
like the DevOps, you know,
things change and last, you
know, however, a lot like last
couple years, even, you know, as
far as the definition or even
the roles, you know, what kind
of what kind of different
interactions are using things
like that.
Tom Cudd: Yeah, I have seen
changes over the last 10 years
when I didn't know I was doing
kind of DevOps work 10 years
ago, really, I really read the
Phoenix project, I think, six or
seven years ago, which really
introduced me to the methods of,
of how we deliver code to the
world.
Dan Ott: Could--I'm sorry to
interrupt--but could you...I
don't know what the Phoenix
project is.
Tom Cudd: Oh, yeah, the Phoenix
project. Yeah, the Phoenix
project is a great book that
really widely presented DevOps
in a, in a story format, to to
the world. I don't remember, all
of the authors, there's couple
authors that work with Jean Kim,
who is the main author, and he
he's an excellent speaker, and
an excellent contributor to the
DevOps landscape. And he, the
book was a lot of people's first
introduction to what DevOps is
in, in how it can be used to
correct problematic behaviors
within an organization. And, and
so when I read that, I like it,
like blew my mind, I read
through it in a day, I didn't
sleep until I finished that
book. And I came back to work
the next day, and I was like, we
have to do this for everything.
And yeah, my boss was like,
okay, chill for a second. And
then let's like break this down
and analyze what what it is that
we can we can do. There are a
few things that we learned right
off the bat, we were already
doing right, like emphasizing
our ability to empathize with
the people we're working with
and understand the problems and
meet people at least at least in
the middle. And sometimes more
than halfway, we would, we would
try to reach across the aisle to
get the problem solved. But what
what's really changed, I think,
over the last five years is that
we've seen other areas of
technology developer is QA,
infosec, they all have kind of
embraced more of an emphasis on
on that empathy with other parts
of the organization. Mainly,
because I think people are
realizing there's only so many
abstractions about technology
that you can hold in your head
at the same time. So what I mean
by that, like, I have an
understanding of hardware, and
then how the cloud you know,
system sit on top of that
hardware, and then how we
present that clouds systems to
the the developers and to the
end users. If you have to
understand like, at some point,
you have to go, Oh, I need to
understand what exactly is
happening in the networking
layer here. If you have no
familiarity with that, you're
going to have to ask somebody.
And so what is the the
abstractions that people are
understanding kind of overlap?
It's like a Venn diagram of
DevOps is really like the
intersection of, I'm working
with a developer who understands
how a Spring Boot application
works on top of an application
server. And I understand how an
application server worked on top
of an OS. And so we're meeting
in that. That middle, it used to
be, there was a job title, a lot
of people had called middleware
application developer. And they
had, that was sort of like,
instead of finding a way to
collaborate, they just found
someone who understood both
parts of those abstractions. And
that making another team for
something where you really
shouldn't have just found a way
to collaborate and work together
isn't the way to solve the
problem.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah,
that's, you keep saying the word
collaboration. And I think
that's great. And I also think
it's, it can be super hard,
right? Especially when you have
two teams that are two or more
used to communicating in certain
ways with each other. And I
imagine that sometimes there can
be friction or challenges to,
you know, make it a space where
everybody can talk together.
Tom Cudd: Yeah, in, in, like the
enterprise 10 years ago, in sort
of larger enterprise
organizations. The needs of
developers and the business
working with developers was
different than that of the
operational groups. developers
were tasked with releasing
features and getting code pushed
out. And operations groups were
put into the place where they
had to ensure the stability of
an application, make sure that
things stayed running, the
safety and security and
stability was of utmost
importance. You know, uptime was
a big deal. For operational
groups and developers were like,
you know, I don't care about
uptime, I have a new feature
that has to get out to the end
users. And so that collaboration
wasn't happening, because we
were all coming from a different
place a different perspective
of, we had to figure out how to
align the needs of each
organization, to to solve
problems.
Dan Ott: Did that sort of, you
know...like, everything you
said, may made sense, and so
trying to, like, where were you
in that process of trying to,
like figure that that out, like,
figure out how to make new
communication channels or new,
you know, decision making
processes, stuff like that?
Tom Cudd: Well, it, it's kind of
fun to talk to people. For me, I
love talking to people. And I
had been working or I'm at now,
I've been there for 10 years
now. And when I started to take
some of these DevOps approaches,
I had been there for about four
years. So I had inroads. I had
trusting relationships built
with certain people in the
organization, because you know,
you get, you're getting a cup of
coffee, and you talk about, oh,
hey, this person also plays the
electric bass like me. So like,
let's talk about that. One, one
person on my team said a couple
years ago, they're like, trust
takes time. It takes time, you
can't I couldn't have just come
to a new person and come into a
new job and go, Okay, we're
gonna DevOps everything around
here. And I'm gonna do things
this way. And you're just gonna
have to deal with it. Because I
think I know what's best. No, it
doesn't, it doesn't work, I got
to know the people that I was
working with certain trusted,
valued partners in the
development organization that
realized, hey, nobody wants to
be up at 3am trying to press a
button to make this code end up
on production. So let's work
together to it. It started with
we created custom scripts that
people would just be able to
trigger with a, you know, a new
code build would be triggered by
a commit. So something like that
kind of opened up a whole new
world of realization that no one
has to throw code over a wall,
we can actually work together to
automate systems can do what
systems are good at, which is
save people time to do more deep
level thinking about problems.
Because that's what we that's
the ultimate goal, you pay
people to solve unique and
interesting problems not to
press buttons all day that an
automated system can handle.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, so it
sounds like a lot of the job
too, is creating an environment
where there's psychological
safety, right, where you have
this trust, where you are
thinking about the people who
are working? And is that
something that you're
consciously thinking about as
you're creating these
relationships? Or I don't know,
how does the role of
psychological safety fit in
there?
Tom Cudd: For a person who's a
team lead or manager or
supervisor like myself, and also
doing the technology work, it's
the most important thing to me
is to create a, you know,
trusted, safe environment. The
big thing I found, started doing
research after reading Phoenix
project, a couple other books,
Lean Enterprise and Accelerate
are two other books that I found
very powerful in, in my journey
to to optimize our DevOps,
DevOps experiences, and our team
capabilities. Google did a, a
huge research project on what
made teams successful. And they
found that optimizing for like
individual contributions to be
better, didn't ultimately bring
about success. So you can you
can train people individually as
much as you can, but that, that
only unlock so much potential.
When they, when they figured out
what made certain teams more
successful by doing you know,
observational analysis and
surveys across their whole
organization, they found that
the idea of psychological safety
was the most important factor to
successful teams. So that means
giving everybody an opportunity
to speak knowing that you can
take risks without the, you
know, embarrassment of things
failing, like, I have a person
on my team that they deployed a
config that accidentally broke
prod one time and it was there.
They're a junior person. And
there's the first time they did
something that broke prod and
another person on the team went
out and bought champagne and
brought it back to the office
and was like, congratulations,
it's your first time breaking
fraud, it won't be the last. So
let's celebrate it and learn
from it. So knowing that, that
you can do risky things without
penalty, in order to try and
learn it's, it's, it's how we
learn from the mistakes, that's
important. And so making a safe
environment for your team to be
able to try new things and have
that growth and learning mindset
is, I think the only way that
we're going to make our teams
better and our organization
better. So that's, it is really
important to me to create that
kind of safe area to do that
work in it.
Dan Ott: Can you talk a little
bit more about some specific
techniques you use to foster
psychological, psychological
safety within your team? you'd
mentioned that, you know, making
failures explicitly. Okay,
right, and risk. But what are
some other like techniques that
you use to help your team feel
safe all together.
Tom Cudd: So I, as a person who
has been technology person most
of their life, and who's been
mainly focused on development
and experiences like that, I had
to kind of learn a little bit
more about what it is to be a
manager and to manage people. So
I know this month that Virtual
Coffee, were reading Radical
Candor, which is a really
excellent book for learning how
to have conversations with
people that are helpful to them.
I used to be, if you've read
that book, you'll you'll
understand the term ruinous
empathy, like I felt bad for
people, all the time, people
that I worked with that I you
know, that were having troubles
with things. But instead of
politely and directly giving
them the feedback and criticism
that they need, I would just be
saying, "Oh, it's okay. Well,
we'll try to, we'll, we'll try
to fix it together." And then
I'd go back and fix their,
whatever was broken, that didn't
help them improve. It didn't
give them the opportunity to to
learn. It was it was, it was a
problem for everyone to kind of
cover that pain. And that that
goes back to like DevOps is an
important part of DevOps is that
shared pain, like you don't hide
the pain, that one process or
area or effort brings you, you
expose it and bring it out,
bring it up and say, Hey, this
is something that's causing
people problems, let's work
together to fix it. We have to
have to be professionally direct
in those times. Because if we're
if we're not, we're not
improving the space that we're
in. I mean, I work at an ad
agency. So it's, it's it can be
hectic at times, and it even 10
years ago, it used to be like,
hey, we'd get a project started
on Monday might have to have
something launched by Saturday
night, and it would just be work
all hours until it's done.
Bringing up those types of
things is difficult. But we
built up the trust with people
to recognize, hey, maybe a 40
Hour Workweek is better for us
in the long term. Well, how do
we get to that point? Well, for
one thing, we can automate more
so that we don't have to keep
wasting two hours rolling code,
we can press a button and go to
sleep, or press a button and
give the output to someone else.
So working, working together in
that space, is how we got there.
And the only way to do that is
to just say, Hey, this is a
problem. We need to fix it
together. And say it over and
over again, in as polite and
professional manner as you can
and hopefully, someone will
eventually pay attention. And if
if they don't, you know, maybe
it's not the best culture or the
best place. There are things you
can do to help improve it, but
for some, some places, there's
only so much you can do. I'll
I'll tell you that.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I'm sure that's
true. I was going to ask like
how, how, I mean, this sort of
thing has to come down from you
know, like, has to have support,
you know, further up the
management tree, for instance,
you know, I was just like
wondering how far up you feel
like this, this sort of
approach, you know, is directed
in your organization.
Tom Cudd: Now, at this moment,
yeah, everything around the idea
of DevOps is embraced And Heck,
it's used as a selling point for
clients that we're, we work in
this manner. And it's to the
benefit of everybody, including
the teams we're working with.
And, and eventually, the end
user and customer that we're
dealing with. We took it as a
bottom up kind of approach, I
didn't ask for management buy in
to start doing these things, we
found areas where we could eke
into improvements. I've always
leaned towards the ask for
forgiveness rather than
permission. When I when I'm
doing work, mainly because I, I
figure, the worst that can
happen is someone just fires me
and I go find a new job. But I
have that kind of like risk. I'm
normally risk averse in my
personal life. But like, in my
professional life, I'm like YOLO
pride, you know, let's, let's
go, let's go get this done.
Dan Ott: So an example of
something like that would be,
you have a project and you could
like power through it quickly.
But if you spend a little more
time, you know, working through
some automations, or some some
of the things like that, the
product will be different, like,
it might take a little bit
longer to get out the door, like
the first time or something, but
then the full product will be
much more valuable. Right. Is
that? Am I mistaken? That kind
of correctly?
Tom Cudd: Yeah, that's exactly
what I mean. Investing some time
up front to save you long run.
Time is the way we mentally
operates. Right now. I'm
thinking of my future self is my
future self going to be happy
that I created this build
pipeline, so that I can give
developer a button to press when
they need it? Yeah, my future
self is going to be really happy
that my past self did that, that
work ahead of time, it does take
you know, I talked about
building those relationships up,
I had to start making sure that
people who were going in on
like, client pitches and people
who were working directly with
clients and creating scopes to
work off of understood the lead
time we needed in order to make
the project successful. That
also took that kind of like,
hey, let's have a cup of coffee.
And I can explain, this is how
we work. And this is what we're
trying to do. And if you you
know, redline this line item in
the scope, you're actually going
to cost yourself more money in
this time period in the future,
because you didn't invest this
time up front. So you can either
invest front heavy on our sort
of building the automated
processes, or you're going to
pay more over the entire life of
the project to have someone
available all hours of the day
to get this work done. So it
does require a little bit of
storytelling to make sure people
understand, hey, this, this is
why we're doing this. You can't
build the landing gear while the
plane is flying. You should have
done that, you know, before you
even took off, right?
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. So it
sounds like you are also
investing time in the people,
right? Because you have to have
those relationships, and try and
get people to trust you. And
that's gonna save you time in
the long run, right? Because I
find that, you know, avoiding
hard conversations are trying to
work around them, they have a
way of coming back and creating
something that's much more
challenging to deal with rather
than, like, okay, let's get this
out now, or let's talk about
this, or let's grab a cup of
coffee and get to know each
other a little bit. Because then
you have a relationship where
you can be more honest with that
person.
Tom Cudd: Absolutely. It's, it's
the part of the job that I like
the most is to, to foster that
kind of friendship, work,
friendship with people to
understand what they're doing,
and how it applies to the
problems I'm trying to solve.
And then and in telling them how
look, Okay, I see I see here,
when you're when you're selling
the client this, here's what you
want to tell them so that they
don't like cross off this line
in the scope thing. I'm not
paying for that. Like No, it's
built in to the kind of agile
work that we're doing in order
to save you like how we used to
sell agile and working in
Sprint's to clients is
completely different now than it
was even a couple of years ago.
How many clients wanted to say,
oh, you're going to pay for a
team of this size for this long
and we're not going to commit to
saying we'll get this done.
We're just going to say how many
points during this sprint, we're
going to get done, and then this
sprint, and then this sprint,
but we can't exactly tell you
what releases are going to be
out the door, like, what
features are going to be done,
you, you're buying out a team
for this loan, that didn't work,
even three or four years ago, no
one, no one would buy out a team
to work on projects like that. I
mean, a handful of larger
organizations may have
understood the value. But DevOps
is sort of like that, it's like,
oh, you're going to pay for this
up front, so that you save
yourself, the time and the money
in the long run, being able to
tell that story through, you
know, creating slides and
visualization for teams, you
know, selling our services,
that's, that's an area where
I've had to learn, you know,
some new skills. But again, I
fostered the right kind of
friendship inside the office to
say, hey, this person actually
works in the creative department
and has a bunch of slides that
we can use, and then I can just
layer some stuff on top of so
that Kismet of like randomly
running into people in the
office is still something that I
hope I eventually get back to,
so that I can still foster those
relationships a little bit more
challenging. In a kind of remote
world, but I it's, it's still
important, there's ways to do
it. And we're still trying to
reach reach the reach the parts
of the organizations, we're
still trying to learn more about
how to interact with and how to
engage with, even in the even in
the remote sense.
Dan Ott: That's cool, it's cool
that you have, I don't know that
the freedom to be able to do
that, right, that you're not
like stuck and stuck in silos or
being told to you know, stay in
your, your zone or whatever, you
know, in your organization.
Tom Cudd: I've been told to stay
in my zone a couple of times and
stay in my lane a couple of
times.
Dan Ott: Well sure, but, but you
didn't get fired, right. So...
Tom Cudd: no, I did not.
Dan Ott: I think that's really
cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So how do
you deal with challenges or
pushback on the things that
you're trying to do? I guess,
like, Is there an approach to?
Well, I guess I don't I don't
want to lead the question. So if
you...
Tom Cudd: Oh, how do I deal with
the challenges of it? Well,
there are, there definitely is
pushback. And there's some I
want to say Old Guard mentality,
I think that's probably the
closest way to describe it.
People who are coming from their
industry experience was 1520
years ago. And that's kind of
what they stuck with. Changing
that kind of mindset. As proven
to be very difficult. I, we
sometimes bring in senior
engineers, for a specific client
project technology stack needs,
and changing how they think has
been more challenging than then
maybe hiring more junior entry
level boot camp type grads, so
we have a tech apprenticeship
program now that we're, we we've
brought in some apprentices that
are coming from, you know,
career switching and their the
fact that they're learning
something like technology, after
another career has proven to be
invaluable to, to bring in and
they're more flexible and
understanding Oh, well, this
person, just, you know, they
don't want to do it this way,
that's fine. We'll just we'll do
it their way, and then show them
and explain to them and train
them. It's it's a more patient
approach. It's what I end up
doing. A lot of times when I get
pushback of I want to spend the
time upfront to automate this, I
want to build this
infrastructure using terraform,
or something like that. I, I
actually show and explain. If I
build it with terraform versus
build it by hand, it's going to
take this amount of time for
this amount of time. But if I
need to scale up this
environment, to like 10, times
the number of systems very
quickly, because you said there
was a possibility, this may have
to scale very quickly. I just
changed, increment this number,
and boom, we have 10 systems.
Whereas here, I would have to do
that one time, effort 10 more
times. So like being able to
like just instead of getting
frustrated and saying, No, you
have to do it my way. Why are
you arguing with me? I tried to
understand, like, it's really
hard to just sit and go, Okay,
what is it that you're actually
complaining about? are you
complaining because it's going
to take me two weeks longer?
Well, okay, let's bring in
another resource. I can borrow
one of your developers, I can a
developer can learn you know,
some YAML configuration based
language like terraform and and
help me out here. So We try to
find, you know, unique solutions
that way. It's it's active
listening, you know that the
whole, like, back to thinking
about communication studies
being an active listener and
actually trying to Okay, let me
let me rephrase what you're
telling me. And sometimes that's
the simplest way to get back to
the solutions where people are.
People are really pushing back
against you.
Dan Ott: Yeah, I like that.
Colleen's podcast, social, man.
I'm blanking on the name.
Colleen has a podcast--Yeah,
yeah--Software Social sorry,
she, she has a podcast, and they
just did user interview with it.
Like they did a two parter where
they interviewed Drew actually
from Virtual Coffee, but for
Colleen's app, and then as the
host, Michelle, is that her
name? Yeah. So she did the
interview. And then the second
part was, Colleen, like,
reacting to it or whatever. And
Michelle was talking a lot about
that active listening, and that
technique of rephrasing
something that somebody said, or
like, to get them to, you know,
sort of talk more about it. And
she said, she actually will do
this, or maybe she used to
because she didn't use her
interviews for like, you know,
for work and would rephrase
something, but Excuse me, but,
um, intentionally mess it up a
little bit, you know, and to get
them to get a person, and this
wasn't even tech, this is like,
any, any user, you know, but
like to get them to talk up,
like, explain why, you know,
like, talk more about their,
their, whatever was, you know,
their farm or whatever it was,
you know, that she's
interviewing, I thought that was
a cool, cool idea.
Tom Cudd: That is a really good
technique. I'm gonna have to
remember that. Yeah, yeah. You
mean to say sort of like a
really annoying clipping like,
Did you mean to? Did you mean to
say this? No, that's not what I
said at all. Let me explain it
better. Oh, that would be great.
I would love it, if you would
explain it better.
Dan Ott: Yeah, yeah, exactly.
That's pretty much exactly it.
You know, she, I mean, she, she
was talking about how she would
lean on because she was younger,
I think and would lean on, you
know, people's, she's
interviewing men and would lean
on the assumptions, you know,
sort of, of talking to a young
woman, you know, we're like,
and, like, let the but like, but
her job was at the time was
getting the person to talk, you
know what I mean? And so she
would sort of make mistakes on
purpose. Just to get them to do
exactly what he said, No, no,
that's not it at all. Let me
explain it. I thought that was
really great.
Tom Cudd: I seen that technique
in action. My wife is actually a
broadcast journalism major, and
was in the field for a few
years. And I'm like, every once
in a while, like, Are you
trying? Are you trying to get me
to say more about what I mean?
Like, like that, that's a pretty
interesting technique right
there. So yeah, it's, it's a
good tool in the belt to have in
the building relationships with
people that you work with. So I
love it, I need to use it more.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. I like
I like coming to it with that,
that sort of attitude, right?
Like that. You know, I mean, I
think of active when I hear
active listening, I think of
interviews and stuff like that,
but you know, even doing it with
your with teammates, and trying
to try to just like dig into,
like, what problem we're trying
to solve, you know, like, or why
we're trying to, like, somebody
comes and asks you for some
pipeline or, or whatever, but
digging in and finding like,
what the root of the thing that
they actually want is, you know,
is, is like an interesting
skill, it's something I'm always
trying to practice by Vince,
the, the guy I work with, is
like a master at that, of, of
like, somebody will come and one
of our one of our clients have a
long term client. They are they
do deck construction, and came
in and said, they want a
website, you know, and they had
gotten quotes around other
places or whatever, and then
talked to the owner for like, a
solid day. And out of that came
a contract to redesign their
logo and not nothing about
websites, redesign their logo
and and create truck decals, you
know, because, like, they're,
like, they had some small
website, like some, you know,
whatever website, you know, but
like, their main thing, it
wasn't that they needed a
website is that they needed more
customers, you know, like, and
like, they're, like prospective
customers for them are people
like next door to the brand new
deck that they just installed
for, like the neighbors and you
know, things like that. So it's
like getting a website that can
serve all the world not very
helpful for a local construction
company, necessarily. You know
what I mean? At least that is
step one, you know,
Tom Cudd: yeah, I see that
happen a lot. Like, I get a lot
of JIRA tickets handed over to
me or the people on my team that
are Hey, can you put this config
out on this server for us. And I
see those types of things right
away. And I go, No, no, no, no,
tell me what to do, tell me what
it is you're trying to
accomplish, and I'll be happy.
If it ends up being that all I
have to do is put that config
out there, that's great. I can
also provide you the system for
you and your team to do that
yourself, rather than handing a
ticket over to me. But if if all
you need is the config, great if
what you're needing is a method
to deploy that config regularly.
Let's talk about that. If that's
not what you're meeting, needing
at all, if, if you're just
having a troubleshooting
session, because you're running
into a problem, we'll just
invite me to that, and I'll help
you figure it out. I'll get
online with you and help you
solve the problem. So getting
other people to recognize that
sort of that same sort of issue
that pops up in a ticketing
system or request where, or
someone who may not be familiar
with, like the abstractions I
talked about earlier, if
they're, they're not familiar
with that, they may say, Hey,
can you do this one thing for
me? But really, it's what is it
that you're actually trying to
accomplish? What What is it you
want to solve here? And let's
work together to do that.
Dan Ott: Totally. There was an
anecdote in our latest developer
tea podcast actually, for and I
didn't really look up, this is
true or not, but Henry Ford was
saying, you know, if, you know,
it's the, if he just did what
users asked, they would have
just made like a faster horse,
you know, instead of like
building a car, you know, like,
Tom Cudd: that's a good
paraphrase of that. Yes.
Dan Ott: Whatever it was sorry.
Yeah. I don't know what the
quote is
Tom Cudd: It is Henry Ford,
though. I I've worked a lot with
that particular client for
years. So I've heard a lot of
the Henry Ford quotes.
Dan Ott: Well, there you go. But
yeah, right. So I mean, like
that, the what they want is to
get to another place faster, you
know, or easier, or whatever. I
guess in that situation, you
know, digging into, like, what
people are really like, wanting
is, is a skill, but also is
like, going to be much easier if
people feel safe, you know,
communicating and like, both
ways, right? Like, the person
asking feels safe. And the
person, you know, on the other
end feels safe digging in, you
know, I mean, I do it all the
time. And I like it work. And I
know that I bother some people
sometimes. I mean, I'm not like
being annoying, but like, I know
that some people are like, why
can't Can you just Could you
just do the thing? I'm like,
Listen, you know, it'll be it. I
promise. It'll be better this
way. Like, let's just talk a
little bit, you know? I don't
know, it's, I like talking about
it. It's a cool, it's a it's a
cool way to approach you know,
Tom Cudd: I sometimes get like
people send me the GIF of like,
why are you the way you are? I
get it. I'm like, I'm stubborn.
And I'm like, I really should do
it. This we should really should
do it. There's no we should
really like, like trying to get
more. I can't just yell louder
at at people to try to get them
to accomplish what I want it. It
requires a little bit more
effort on my part to try to
understand and then maybe, maybe
I didn't do a good enough job
educating or training or
explaining like, what, what
happened that broke down in what
I thought we all agreed upon was
the right way to do things and
then suddenly isn't so totally,
totally understand that a
digging in the heels. situation.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
think that's so important. And
so overlooked, especially
because things move so fast. And
there's this sense of urgency
like everything has to be done,
right. So let's find the
quickest path there. But it
sounds really methodical and
deliberate. And this this
process that gets developed, but
I'm definitely something that
that pays off in the end.
Tom Cudd: It does it, trust me,
it does pay off in the end. I
mean, I could have said, you
know, four or five years ago,
well, this Job's never gonna
change, I go find something
else. And the problems that I
had with myself and how I worked
would have followed me there.
This was I really, let's see,
what's the Tolstoy quote? It's
like everyone thinks of changing
the world, but no one thinks of
changing themselves. That's
that's sort of what hit me that,
okay, maybe I can make some
changes in how I operate around
people and how I work with
people. And that will help more
than just the work. They'll make
the work environment better,
because there are some places
where the culture may be
irredeemable.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah.
That's it was gonna be my next
question like, where do you draw
the line? Right?
Tom Cudd: Where do I draw the
line is probably different where
other people draw the line. I,
like I said, I dig my heels in,
I see, oh, we can, we can change
everything about this place. I'm
more patient than others, I
jokingly tell some of my co
workers, I will outlast all my
enemies. So like, if there's
someone I don't like working
with, I'm like, well, maybe
maybe I should change how I work
with this person not expecting
the other people to change. And
it goes back to, you know, you
mentioned earlier, like, how
much buy in do you get from
management and upper management
on DevOps? Well, sometimes you
may not get any buy in. But that
doesn't mean that you shouldn't
adhere to some of those like
positive practices. In your own
experience, there are things
every individual contributor can
do to improve their working
situation. And sometimes you
can't change the culture, just
like expecting the culture
check, like, hey, this culture
should change. Well, what brings
about cultural changes is
specific behavioural change, you
have to actually change what
you're doing. in your day to day
how you work, how you interact
with people, we used to have a
huge problem with, I call it
hero culture, where people just
work themselves until they
collapse. And burnout and
fatigue were really big
problems. I started setting a
good example, I worked 40 hours
a week, I'm not doing that right
now. But I know I have a
specific, like deadline. And
once I'm, once I'm past that, I
know I'm gonna have some like,
some time to relax some time to
take it easy. Back to my like,
sort of 40 Hour Workweek, I was
really strict about making sure
that I put in just the amount of
time that I needed, I used my
vacation time accordingly. If I
didn't feel mentally well, even,
we would use sick days for like
mental well being days like and
that was totally fine. And by
being a good example, other
people on the team started doing
that same thing. Now, some
people were sort of addicted to
that superhero culture and
didn't like some of the changes
that were happening, and they
left and that's their
prerogative. But more people
stayed, then left when I started
saying, hey, maybe we should
work only 40 hours a week, for
the most part. That seems like a
reasonable thing to do.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Now, what
if somebody higher up in your
company said no, that's not
acceptable, you need to put in
at least 50 hours a week?
Tom Cudd: That's a good
question. And like I said, I, I
am more willing to take risks
with my professional career
there my personal life, my
mentality is I'm going to work
what I think is going to be best
for everybody in the long run.
And that means I'm going to put
in a 40 hour a week for the most
part. And if that led to people
realizing, hey, maybe this is a
good idea, or maybe we should
get rid of this guy, the the
cultural things are going to
take care of themselves one way
or another. And if and if it led
to my having to go find someone
else, I would have done that.
But it led to a lot of people
realizing, hey, when this team
works, sane, solid hours, they
do high quality output of work.
And so it was encouraged. And it
was celebrated, that we were
doing the right thing, kind of
like we accidentally broke prod,
hey, that's a that's a behavior,
because we took took an
acceptable level of risk and
recovered from it quickly.
Because we had built all the
right things, let's celebrate
that not, you know, harass
somebody about the fact that
they broke prod.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So do you
think that you would say if you
were in a working condition
where you felt like
psychological safety was
something that wasn't valued? At
what point do you walk away from
that? Right?
Tom Cudd: Um, that that's a
really good question to me. I
may have mentioned it already.
It's number one, for me the
psychological safety, being able
to feel safe in a work
environment. I don't tolerate
low psychological safety very
well, like the one of the jobs I
left a long time ago. This was
like I think I wasn't even
graduated college. I was like
building computers on a line for
a company that doesn't even
exist anymore. They asked me to,
I had already worked 70 hours a
week they asked me to come in
the next day, which was also my
birthday, which my girlfriend
was coming in from out of town,
who's now my wife, but she was
coming in from out of town. And
they were like, No, you have to
come in tomorrow. I'm like, No,
I'm leaving right now. I never
and I'm just like, you can mail
me my last paycheck, I'm done. I
don't tolerate that. But like I
said, I'm also have a high
threshold for what I consider
safe and unsafe. But you know,
something like that. I just, I'm
not going to just don't
understand. I won't put up with
kind of the BS that sometimes
happens when people think that
their, their method of working
people to death is the only way.
I'm trying to dance around the
issue that I know, we've heard
people in Virtual Coffee have
very specific problems with bad
bosses and bad behaviors. And
it's like, I would have left a
long time ago, you have more
power and will then I do it. And
that's amazing. But yeah, I
bosses yelling aren't exactly my
favorite thing. But I I've been
able to put up with that because
I can kind of get around it and
get to the point of it. And you
know, it's, it's, it's something
that happens every once in a
while, like I said, I worked in
a mom and pop shop, I saw a
husband and wife team yell at
each other every once in a while
and maybe sometimes yell at the
staff. And I was like, when that
started getting directed towards
me, I was like, I'm out of here.
So like, you know, I don't you
know, if it's abusive behavior
and bordering on, like, hey,
this might be something that
people could get sued for. I'm
usually out the door.
Dan Ott: That's actually an
interesting part about radical
candor. Was was some of the,
some of the examples she talked
about where people would get
like, he did indiscretions.
Like, like, like, yell, you
know, but it was, you know, it
was not unsafe, you know, if
that makes sense. And like, that
was kind of a revelation for me.
Because, you know, I don't know,
I'm not like, I don't, if I'm
yelling, I'm probably like,
upset, like, not, you know,
like, probably not feeling very
good. You know, I mean, but
there there are definitely times
where I have with people I work
with, and, you know, respect,
like, we have, like, gotten
heated at about because we're
like, it's not like we are
yelling at each other, you know,
we're like yelling to each other
about a thing that we're arguing
about, you know, like, an
approach or something. And it's
an interesting like, that the
the raised voices sort of
situation is like, it's always
an interesting topic for me,
because I don't do I don't do
pretty well with confrontation.
Like, I also would, like, just
be peacing out as soon as
somebody was yelling at me, like
a boss was yelling at me, you
know, I mean, my personal
experience was with a colleague,
you know, it wasn't like, it
wasn't like, a higher up
dealing, you know, so. I don't
know.
Tom Cudd: I mean, arguing is
something I'm fine with, but
like the actual, like, directed,
like, we're, it's just, it
doesn't even make sense. If
people are just yelling to yell,
that's no good. I have like a
one situation where like, I got
really mad, or call. And I like,
like, slant, like, I picked up
my keyboard and I just slammed
it down, and like, broke the
little like feet thingies off of
it. And I'm like, Okay, well,
that violence in the workplace
is never accepted. Like, I came
back an hour later, like, Okay,
I'm sorry, everybody for doing
that. Like, like, I actually
still have that keyboard. Like,
that was eight years ago. And I
taped it back up, and I still
use that keyboard as a reminder,
don't slam stuff in the office.
Like, that's just not okay.
Like, there's some lines that
you know, I my boss likes to
joke, everyone so well, he tells
people you know, we broke Tom
once. Because he was it was like
three in the morning on the day,
something was supposed to launch
and it just completely
collapsed. And nobody else was
online. And you can just see his
frantic messages in slack
getting more and more until he
was like, I'm done. And, you
know, I felt safe enough to go,
I just give up. I'm gonna go to
sleep for eight hours. And
whatever happens over that next
eight hours, I leave it to the
rest of you to deal with so
like, it's, it's sort of you
have to know, I may not have
known my break point then. But
like, I know now what my limits
are. And I I'm do a good job of
staying within that. And
understanding that about
yourself is important. But when
you start to understand
yourself, you can say, Okay, I'm
seeing where this person on my
team has a limit that they don't
even recognize and I'm like, you
need to go home. Well, I know
you are home, you need to turn
off your computer, or I'm going
to send it a message to change
your password without telling
you so like, so you can't log in
until it's Till I say it's okay.
It's, it's, as a manager team
lead, you sort of become a
little bit of a psychological
safety net for the people that
are around you. And it's a, it's
a different skill. But I like
doing it, I like helping the
people that I work with and hope
that I'm doing a good job.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I think too
knowing the people and having
that relationship also can
determine how you're
communicating with them, right,
and understanding what their
limits are. Because sometimes, I
always like to think about this,
even in terms of what a good
trainer is, right? Because a
good trainer knows how to
motivate each person there,
because they have some type of
relationship. So sometimes you
might need them to say like,
okay, you need to stop, it's
time to do something else. Or
sometimes you give gentle
encouragement. And then there is
times when, when you know, some
people need a specific type of
encouragement, and maybe that's
going to be loud. Or maybe it's
going to be a different approach
that you take with someone else.
But recognizing how to motivate
that person. And that it's not a
blanket approach for everyone is
what's going to create, like a
solid culture of respect, and a
place where somebody can grow
and take risks, like you're
talking about.
Tom Cudd: Yeah, I have learned a
lot from the manager, manager,
tools, website and podcast,
about some of those
communication methods, I do one
on ones with the people on my
team, that's a good way to build
up rapport and build up that
kind of that all that
relationship building that I
talked about happens in there,
especially now virtually, like
the one on ones are the way I
can engage with people on a
regular basis. I've learned a
lot of skills from that in terms
of I, like I said, I have true,
I have had trouble giving direct
criticism and feedback to people
that I'm working with in the
past. So like that, some of
those tools gave me techniques
like, find a very small thing
that you want someone to do that
you need them to do directly.
And you may know they're not
going to do it, even though you
may ask them directly so that
you keep following up and like
you sort of show how you're
going to escalate through the
like, okay, I asked you to
submit this report last week to
this thing. What prevented you
from doing that? And then the
next time you can you just add
more emphasis and say, Look,
this is a part of your job. And
this is a job expectation that I
expect from you. So learning
some of those techniques is, you
know, like I said, I'm a
individual contributor,
technologist in training, but
like, retooling my sort of
managerial capabilities and team
lead capabilities over the last
like two, three years, has been
a new and interesting set of
challenges. It's also
interesting to see how many of
the same lessons in tech apply
to dealing with people and
systems of people. So it's not
it's it's more one to one than I
think most people realize doing
that the tech to lead kind of
sideways shift.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Well, I
feel like I could talk to you
about this stuff for at least
another hour.
Tom Cudd: I probably could too,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I mean,
this hour is gone by so fast. I
just looked up like wow, we've
been doing this for a while. But
this has been really, really
great. So thank you so much for
being here with us today. If
there's like a top Do you have a
top resource that you recommend
for people to get started?
Tom Cudd: So if it's for DevOps,
I would definitely start with
the Phoenix project, or the
unicorn project as a follow up
that has like additional
learnings from over the years,
one of those two is a good way
to really focus on that kind of
DevOps. What DevOps is
culturally? And what can can it
do for the actual technology
that you're working with and the
teams that you're working with.
So Phoenix project is sort of
the big unlock there. If, if
you're looking for how to be
dealing with people and
fostering that psychological
safety, radical candor is still
my favorite resource for that. I
have got a copy from the library
because I think I load my copy
up to someone back when we
actually were in offices, so
have to dig that up eventually.
But yeah, radical candor is just
an excellent resource for that.
Fostering those good
relationships and trusting
relationships in a safe way.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Great.
Well, thank you so much for
sharing that and everything else
with us today. This has been a
really great learning experience
for me. Thanks for being here.
Tom Cudd: Glad I can join.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Tom.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
Episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at Virtual
Coffee io. Or you can email us
at podcast at Virtual coffee.io.
You can find the show notes plus
you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtual coffee.io.
Dan Ott: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.