Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to season two, episode
six of the Virtual Coffee
podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. And we're here
to share it with you. Here with
me today is my co host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Thanks, Bekah. Today
we're talking with Courtney
Landau. Courtney is a software
engineer currently working at an
early stage startup in the
education technology space. We
talked with Courtney about how
the trend of constant self
marketing and Tech has impacted
her career. Our experience as a
developer and what it's been
like to take on a variety of
roles as a Virtual Coffee
contributor.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We start
every episode like we start
every Virtual Coffee, we
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from what we
do and a random check in
question. Today's random
question is, if you had to
delete all but three apps from
your smartphone, which ones
would you keep? We hope you
enjoyed this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah, I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could keep three
apps on my smartphone, I think
it would be slack. Spotify.
And then Google Drive.
Dan Ott: Google Drive.
Nice. Yeah. So so one
entertainment, one and two sort
of work working once.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That seems
to know what that says about me.
Dan Ott: Three's...three's
tough. Hi, I'm Dan. I am a front
end developer from Lakewood,
Ohio.
And if I so if I had to keep
three apps, I thought I would do
Spotify as well. I would do
overcast, it's just podcast app.
And that I listen to pretty much
all time. And I don't know. I
feel like some kind of game
except that I can't really get
into any games right now. I'm in
between games right now. So I
don't really have a good I guess
I'll say slack. But like I was
kind of honestly looking forward
to not having slack on my phone
in this imaginary, you know,
thing. But slack is probably
pretty lost without having slack
on my phone. So that'll be my
choice. Choice three, slack.
Courtney Landau: Hi, I'm
Courtney. I'm a software
developer from Bethlehem,
Pennsylvania. And three
apps that I would keep were are
gonna sound like everybody
else's now overcast, number one,
Spotify. And I would definitely
not keep slack Just saying. And
I guess Instagram.
Yeah, because I do like the
photos.
Dan Ott: I have, like, you know,
I could do pretty easily without
Twitter. I'm not on Instagram
anymore. I was like, thinking
about
was it? Oh, things like my to do
app? You know, except that I
know. I never use it.
Courtney Landau: would happily
give up any of the work apps?
Yeah.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I was like
between slack and Twitter. I
couldn't decide. But
Dan Ott: well, Twitter, you can
more easily get on. Just on
safari. Right. Like I was
thinking.
Courtney Landau: That's true
Dan Ott: slack's a little... I
don't know, slack works on the
phone through the web.
You know, I know you can on your
computer on the web. But
regardless, I mentioned it would
not be the fun.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah. All
right. Oh, thanks, Courtney, for
being here today. We're very,
very excited to be talking to
you. And usually the way we get
started is asking our guests how
they got into tech. So can you
give us a little bit about your
background and how you ended up
where you are today?
Courtney Landau: Yeah, um, so I
am Yeah, a career changer. So I
came from clinical field. I was
CAT scan tech. Well, actually, I
still work per diem as CAT scan
tech once in a while in the
hospital.
So yeah, I did that while
out. I went to X ray school after
and then I did CAT scan for a
long time had kids and when they
were young, I worked the weekend
program. Kind of
While they were young the entire
time, so I worked 212 hour
shifts on the weekend. And
so that was great for when they
were young. But when they were
going back to school, I ended up
thinking I wanted to change
careers. And I really liked tech.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: What it
what interested you about tech?
Courtney Landau: Yeah, so I was
really into
kind of computers. So I kind of
went, thought it would, I would
get a master's in
Information Sciences kind of go
into like, stay in medical, but
kind of do like more like an IT
thing. But then I took
working out problems. And that
kind of led me to focus my
master's on coding moreso than
it so while I was doing the
Masters, I was kind of building
a bunch of working on Free Code
Camp at the same time kind of
doing web dev stuff, along with
my coursework. And that kind of
led me into web dev once I
graduated.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice, what
is your master's in?
Courtney Landau: Information
Sciences. So I kind of it was my
bachelor's in biology. So
what I went when I found that
this program was local, and I
could go in like half time, so
when I was first starting, like
doing these, I did kind of some
MOOCs online, like with coding,
and it kind of see what I would
like, and I, I figured I could,
because you could kind of
structure your classes around.
Like, either like development or
it more I and I did take some it
classes along with it, but most
of them were like, all
coding classes. So
Dan Ott: Oh, that's so cool. So
yeah, so when you started your
master's program, you weren't
really thinking about coding at
all. interesting.
Courtney Landau: Yeah,
Dan Ott: that's really cool.
Courtney Landau: I didn't want
to do like a boot camp type
thing, because
Unknown: really solidifying it.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Nice. And
so then what was the transition,
like, from your job at the
hospital to your first job in
tech?
Courtney Landau: Yeah. So um, I
ended up well, I was still
working the weekends, like, I
worked weekends for probably 10
years. And so when I was about
to graduate, I was kind of
applying when I was in school,
but nothing worked out. And then
I when I was about to graduate,
I managed to land an internship,
so I, a paid internship full
time, so Really like
software developments more,
using more my brain basically,
it's got CAT scan, there's not
really any room for, like,
moving up, there's no, it's
either like management or go to
school and become like, I don't
know, pa or a doctor. But yeah.
So yeah, I like being in
software development now.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Did that
internship lead to a full time
job?
Courtney Landau: Right now, um,
the internship did not lead to a
full time job. I was hoping that
it would. But they were not
hiring at the end of it. So no
one got hired. big company,
Dell, which was would have been
about an hour and 15 minute
drive. And so I had that offer.
And then the very, very small
startup where I would be the
only developer and working from
home. So I ultimately chose this
one, obviously. So yeah, I've
been there since September of 19.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Wow, I feel
like that's a little bit
overwhelming. When you were
talking about the commute to the
other job. I thought like why
why definitely pick the remote
one. But then also being new to
the industry. And being the only
developer seems a little bit
overwhelming. How was that for
you?
Courtney Landau: Right, yeah.
And it's here and almost a half.
So
Dan Ott: that's really cool.
That's cool that they, you know,
newer career developer,
You don't have a somebody else
that, you know, that was there
before.
Courtney Landau: Right. So, um,
I had the CTO who
I don't know how much he
actually built. I think he
contracted out I think, a lot of
it. So coming, I came into that.
And so
can you repeat that question?
Sorry?
Dan Ott: Oh, yeah, well, no,
that makes sense. Because
usually, if anybody has listened
to this podcast for a while,
they will know that I will talk
for like a minute or two and
ask, like, several questions. In
the middle of the sentences, no
worries. The first question I
was wondering about was what you
answered was like, you know, if
you were the only developer who
built it, and then the second
part was, was, yeah, like, talk
more, can you? I was just
wondering if you could talk more
about
what it was like getting used to
like that, that codebase. I
know, they they said,
or you said that they sent you
to some view training and stuff,
which is really cool. But
just in general, like not having
a another developer to sort of
lean on for questions. I was
just, I was just curious, let
you know what that looks like
for you.
Courtney Landau: Right? Yeah.
Um, yeah, a lot of the majority
of like, the code that was
written at that point was the
Chrome extension, which does a
lot of like website tracking,
and doesn't use a lot of the
chrome API's.
So that was pretty complex, and
kind of overwhelming at first.
But really, the Vue app was
the easy part. So and I did have
him too. He was available, you
know, he still is available to
for but it's at this point, he's
more like big questions, big
picture questions.
And a lot of the stuff he's
like, I don't know, JavaScript,
so. Okay, you're on your own. But
yeah, no, it was actually like,
the first thing I'm remembering
now that the first thing that I
had to fix was like a bug. So I
had to get root in the Chrome
extension to really dig in to
like off things. And
so that was a lot. But yeah, it
worked itself out. For
questions. Yeah, I either go to
him or go to, like, I use
discord a lot like the when I
had Firebase questions, there's
pretty helpful discord on that.
And
Dan Ott: That's awesome. Yeah,
so the CTO was, like, maybe
didn't write most of the code,
but at least was familiar enough
with it, you know, because he
worked with custom contracts
with whatever to point the way
and answer some big questions.
That is, so you're still though,
like, you're still the the only
developer there. At this point?
After?
Courtney Landau: Yep.
Dan Ott: How long was it? A year
and
Courtney Landau: September of
19. So yeah.
Dan Ott: But I mean, that's
really cool. It's like I was, so
being a solo developer, you
know, you have, there's,
there's, as you know, there's,
you know, some different
responsibilities. So, what is it
like for you, When, when, when
they have a new feature, you
know, that they? I guess I'm not
gonna I don't want to lead the
question too much. What is what
is like, you know, when you when
they have a new feature that
they'd like, you know, to
implement?
Courtney Landau: Right, so, um,
basically, I handle it all I
have to come up with like, the,
my plan and kind of, like, mock
stuff up for them. And for new
features, I'm pretty much
handling Yeah, still, at this
point, handling all the whole
process from start to finish.
And they're really good with
that, that's, they're not like
impatient with me, I'm sure.
Especially in the beginning,
things took longer than they
could have with a more
experienced developer. But, um,
yeah, so.
Dan Ott: I mean, that's, that's
great. Like, when I was sort of
getting I was it's a lot of
responsibility for for any
developer, right, like,
regardless of their experience
level, or, you know, the path in
their career. And it seems like
it seems like it's a really good
fit, you know, I don't know it
seems like pretty cool situation
to be in.
Courtney Landau: Yes, I'm sorry.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: No, I was
just gonna say I think that it's
amazing what you're doing.
You're talking through all of
this stuff, but you know, coming
on and working on all this stuff
by yourself. I just think is is
a pretty big, I don't know if I
want to accomplishment, or it's
just something that I certainly
admire hearing you talk about,
because I don't I don't think
that I would have been confident
enough to take on something like
that.
Courtney Landau: Yeah, thank
you. But I don't always feel
that way, like the actual coding
and stuff. But that's my
favorite part. I don't really
like all the time planning
everything out and having to go
through. I mean, I'm getting
better at it, I think. But I
wish I had a project manager to
tell me what to do. Sometimes I
just want to like pull a ticket
off a JIRA board and call it a
day. But yeah, I like it. I
mean, and also, I get to do
other things like, not just
coding, I get to talk directly
with teachers. So it's an
education, tech nology. thing.
So I, like I get to have
meetings with teachers and talk
through features and like, build
what they want to like with, you
know, the founders, if they
agree and see how they, you
know, have meetings with them,
and see how they react when I
build something that they want
it. And that's awesome.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That's
really cool.
Dan Ott: That's very cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I want to
talk a little bit about this is
like changing gears a little
bit, but you had this tweet that
I was really, I really enjoyed,
but it's as quiet and soft
spoken doesn't mean
inexperienced. And I thought
that was so good, and powerful
and important. Because tech is
kind of a really loud place
right now. Right? And we're
always talking about, like,
marketing yourself and putting
yourself out there. And so,
people kind of have to like, be
a marketer, or be a devrel for
themselves to get new jobs. And
so I, I wanted to hear you kind
of talk through, you know, maybe
one what this tweet means to
you, or, you know, how being
somebody that is quiet or soft
spoken, has impacted your tech
journey?
Courtney Landau: Yeah, um, so
I've always been pretty quiet
person, especially when I first
meet people definitely tend to
more keep things in. But then
once I like, once I'm
comfortable, I am probably
completely the opposite. I don't
know. I do, like really like to
talk. I really. I like, so in
tech, and just in general, I
feel like even in my previous
career, I feel like sometimes
people take your quietness for
not knowing what you're talking
about, or, but yeah, I, and I
feel like that continues to
happen, where I'm not like, out
there all the time. And like, I
like on Twitter, like, I'm
barely tweet at all because I
like, well, Major, I really
can't think of anything else. We
don't have the time, but pretty
much. But I don't know how
people come up with stuff. But
I'm saying, especially tech
related, like, I feel like
everything I type, everything I
write will be boring. And But
anyway, yeah. So I feel like,
also, I think, like just being
quiet and not like speaking up
for yourself all the time, just
like constantly saying what
you're doing and things it makes
people maybe like, assume that
you may not have experienced or
know what you're talking about.
I'm not sure. But
Dan Ott: yeah, it's I mean, it's
interesting. I mean, I really
like the way you phrase that. I
mean, I've I feel like I've
can't be the same way,
especially with with Twitter and
things like that. I never even
never even occurs to me until
much later to tweet things. Like
when they're happening, you
know? And I don't know. Yeah,
and I, and the same with trying
to, like, think of ideas to
tweet about or read about or
anything, you know, it's just a
weird process to me. When I'm
coding. It's the farthest thing
from my brain, you know,
Courtney Landau: right. Yeah.
And I also feel like, there's
kind of, it's kind of, we're on
Twitter, and we're reading, you
know, Twitter, but there are a
ton of people that are
developers that don't have
Twitter at all. They just, you
know, work and do their thing.
And or same with like, open
source they don't like there's a
lot of people who just do their
job and then go home. If it's
not open source, then it's not
out there. But that doesn't mean
like they don't know what
they're doing. You know? I don't
know.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, for
sure. And I think, you know,
since there's just such a focus
on people who are out there
talking a lot, and I was just
thinking back, like, you've been
coming to Virtual Coffee for a
while, and I think like your
first involvement in coming to
more than, like, our coffee
chats was with HacktoberFest,
and you sign up as a mentor, and
a contributor. And I think, you
know, it was funny, because it
kind of made me think about
this. Um, I don't know how to
say this. I was surprised, I'll
say that you signed up as a
mentor. And I had to kind of
like, check myself because you
are quiet. And thinking about
like, okay, there are different
people who are acting in
different roles. And so it's
important to, you know, like, I
don't think that I made an
assumption about you being
quiet. But I also think that I
didn't think to, like, reach out
to you and say, like, hey, do
you want to play a bigger role
in this? And so like, it was
great to see you do that. And
all of the support that you gave
was amazing. So I know, it was
like a nice check for me in
terms of thinking about all the
members of the community and how
we all work differently.
Courtney Landau: Yeah. Thanks.
Um, yeah, I really, like I feel
I've been doing web dev kind of
since probably, at this point. I
was doing Free Code Camp
probably started that in 2016.
And then yeah. And so I've been
doing kind of JavaScript, HTML
and CSS for a while. And I felt
like I could. Now that I've been
more, even though at that point,
maybe been working a year, I
guess. Like, I could definitely
help out someone new or someone
completely in boot camp, like,
and I really like working with
people who are really new,
because I like sharing my
knowledge. And even though I
still feel like I know nothing,
I do know a little bit more than
when I started. So yeah, so I
worked with someone who's in
boot camp, and that was a great
experience. And also back when I
was learning, like, I was, like,
I my, I did a couple
contributions to Free Code Camp
actually. And so the but I never
finished a whole HacktoberFest
because I just never found was
able to. So I liked being able
to help someone through that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah,
that's awesome. And, and I know,
I mean, you were paired with
Andrea, right? You had one. And
she definitely benefited from
that she I just remember her
saying, like, what a great
experience it was to work with
you. And it's just so great to
see like those connections
happening and the community
supporting one another. So that
was, I don't know. Something
that I really enjoyed seeing
happen.
Courtney Landau: Yeah, I mean,
community is great. And I try to
help out as much as I can. Yeah,
when I came into Free Code, I'm
talking about Free Code Camp now
I'm talking about Virtual
Coffee. It was really great for
me because I was working on
still am working by myself. And
I really don't know anybody in
tech. Besides like, the three
guys that were on my team at my
internship, and so when you were
tweeting about Virtual Coffee
and even before the pandemic, I
was working from home, so I was
really excited and then the
slack group and it's just been
so great. Like I made so many
friends in tech now.
Dan Ott: That's, it's, it's
pretty cool. I was gonna ask
like, you know, given not sure
how to phrase this, but like
given your, like quietness and
what is the what is the right
word for that? But like, given
the fact that you know, you
know, you're not out there like
tweeting all the time, you're
not doing a lot of that other
stuff. I still see you getting
involved in you know, things
like Bekah was saying that
HacktoberFest and you You know,
I've given talks at our
lightning talks. For instance,
do you find yourself like
looking for ways to To create
content or like, you know, do
things like that. Other than,
you know, I don't know, the
traditional, like, tweets and
whatever, that you know, a lot
of other developers do.
Courtney Landau: Yeah, um, I
think, like, we're the lightning
talks are concerned and things
like that. I do want to put
myself out there. And it's more
like me making myself do things
that are outside of my comfort
zone like so
Dan Ott: Totally
Courtney Landau: yeah, because I
get, you know, even like this
podcast, get so nervous, for it,
but, yeah, it's good for, you
know, I could easily just stay
in my office and not contribute,
but I want to get out there and
I do benefit a lot from it. So
yeah.
Dan Ott: Do you have I mean, I
suffer from suffer, I don't know
if that stuff is the right word.
But I struggle with the same
thing. And especially before, if
I'm got, you know, fun Virtual
Coffee guy bolts, the I went
through long phase years of my
career where I was just like, I
don't know, I just did that I
just stayed in my little cave,
you know, uncoated and whatever,
I follow people on Twitter,
probably, but I was not like,
very active, and I was honestly
kind of comfortable with it, you
know, sometimes, and then I do
find that the more that I do,
force myself out of my comfort
zone, you know, there's, there's
these moments right before,
like, like talking, you know,
giving a talk, for instance.
And this was, honestly, for me,
it was much worse, in person,
you know, and I was, I was
trying to give talks for my
Meetup group, and would have
these moments, like, shortly
before, where I was very
nervous, and I was just like,
why, why, why, why did I do
this? Why did I make this
choice? Like, can I just, I want
to just go back to my cave where
nobody can see me, but
afterwards, generally felt
pretty good, you know, glad that
I did it. And so that's one
thing I keep looking for is ways
to, I don't know, force myself
to do things like that. You
know, I don't know if that makes
sense. But like signing up for
things before I can think about
it, for instance, you know, you
know, things like that. Have you
is, have you had any other out
of your comfort zone adventures,
recently, aside from the ones
we've covered? Oh,
Courtney Landau: yeah. But like
you said, like, I just keep, you
know, forcing myself the more I
do it, the more the better it
gets. But that's why I have to
force myself but the only other
situations where like, recently,
we're just taking interviews
while take phone calls once a
month, just because I know that
how that I don't know that I
come across great interviews,
just because I'm so nervous and
things like that. So just, I
made a decision to like take,
because now that I've been in
the industry for a little bit,
now the recruiters are reaching
out like crazy on LinkedIn. So
I'll take a call, like once a
week, and that's what I'm trying
to do. Because when I go too
long, without talking to people,
I get worse at it. So and I know
that about myself, so. And that
kind of helps. But
Dan Ott: that's really great. So
I mean, yeah, so like, that's, I
mean, these aren't practice
interviews you're taking, you
know, these are real. I mean,
they might be the first round or
whatever. But these are real
interviews, you know, that
you're just taking for your own,
you know, your own I don't know,
benefit or whatever. Right.
That's awesome.
Courtney Landau: Um, yeah. I
mean, yeah, they're also like,
if it's not just like, any
random, like, if I'm interested
in hearing more about it, I will
reach out but yeah, totally.
It's more perfect. I like where
I'm at right now. But also, we
are very new, and we don't have,
you know, a lot of money coming
in. So it's kind of assurance to
to keep up my skills.
Dan Ott: Totally. Well, and
I've, you know, I've heard from
other people that like this,
that interviewing is is like,
honestly, just a separate skill
that is worth practicing. And I
just think I think it's very
cool that you do it sort of
intentionally like that, even
when there's not a need. Seems
like the right time to practice
is when what is that an
emergency? Right? Right. Yeah.
That's really, really cool.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: You, you've
given two lightning talks. So
we've had two lightning talk
events, and you've given talks
in both of them, which were
fantastic like you do. Such a
good job like communicating
things through and going
through, you know, the things
that you're working on. And I
find like, I give talks, but I
am terrified, pretty much the
entire time. And then wonder why
I have agreed to do this. But
like, Are you comfortable? You
look comfortable when you're
doing it? Or is this Oh, are you
pushing yourself out of your
comfort zone in those things?
Courtney Landau: Oh, I'm totally
pushing. But the lightning talks
are nice, because I can I mean,
you know, I did a traditional
kind of college route. So I
have, like, if you hired
occasionally, you're giving
presentations constantly, at
least with my masters. I was. So
I've done it before. And I found
really just having, like, tons
of preparation and practice. I
practice like so many times
beforehand, because if I don't,
then I get, you know, also, I
have to know exactly what I'm
going to say. So I don't like
lose, you know, my thoughts. So
I don't know. Yeah. I am
surprised to hear you say that
back up. Because I mean, you did
say that. I've done well before,
you know, in my lightning talks,
but I can't go back and listen
to them. Because I just feel my
nervousness all over again. I
know that I should to improve,
but
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: it's so
hard. Oh, for sure. I mean, I
don't like listening to myself
talk or like, let alone going
back. And like watching a video
of myself talking. I am given a
talk next week. And the last
time I gave a version of this
talk, I like cried on camera for
10 minutes. And I was telling my
friend Oh, yeah, I'm doing this
talk. And she's like, Is that
the same one that you cried? And
you're gonna do it again? Well,
yeah, I didn't I didn't really
think about it that way. But now
I will. But I think it is like
that practice. And then also
realizing that sometimes you can
practice and things are still
aren't going to happen the way
that maybe you hoped. And then
it's just kind of figuring out
like, how do you push through
that when you've got a roomful
of people staring at you or
whatever.
Courtney Landau: Right. Yeah.
And also, the topics I'm taking
are very, like, some things I'm
very familiar with, like I know
pretty well that I'd be afraid
to, like, do a topic on
something that I've been using
for just like a practice project
or something. I don't know.
Unknown: I don't know. I just,
Courtney Landau: if I really
know what I'm talking about. I
feel like I could what you're
talking about Bekah? Yeah,
that'd be really hard for me.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Well, I
think that's good advice. No,
something that note, well,
especially if it's out of your
comfort zone, or if you're doing
something for the first time,
like, find a topic that you're
comfortable talking about,
because then that can offset
some of that discomfort in
trying something new.
Dan Ott: Yeah, that's, that kind
of goes along with my, I'm
working on these, like, I didn't
need to come up with the name of
them. But like, these pieces of
advice, you know, for different
situations, right. And like
that, trying to not do something
new, like too many new things
all at the same time. You know,
it's like, that's, that's a
danger zone. Right? So, if
you're, like, just getting into
speaking, right, it's just like,
when he was saying, like, pick,
choose something you're
comfortable speaking about,
right? And then once you get
like, I feel like the talks, you
see sometimes where somebody
learns, like, is presenting
something that they just learned
about or whatever, that stems
are seasoned, you know,
speakers, right. Right. So where
they're like, okay, the the
thing that they don't know, is
just that tech or whatever, and
not, you know, not being
comfortable with what speaking.
I do the same thing. You know,
I've done the same thing, that
the times that I've done. The
lightning talks and stuff is it,
it's nice Also, if you get off
track, or something you at
least, like, if you're if you
know, you know the topic, you
can kind of usually find your
way back. Right.
Courtney Landau: Yeah. And
another thing is, yeah, I like
when you're talking about so I
kind of think I could only talk
about like technical things. I
don't know if I would be able to
talk about more things that
weren't like with the technical
talk, it's kind of more you're,
you know, you're kind of going
through steps. So I find that
easier.
Dan Ott: Yeah, well, I mean, and
there's lots lots and lots of
value in the, like technical
talks, you know? And have you
found like, in your experience
with, you know, the talks or
whatever, that you've written,
that they've actually helped
you. I don't learn anything new,
or reframe anything for
yourself, you know, even though
you, like, we're, you know,
talking about a topic that you,
you know, sensibly, like, knew
pretty well.
Courtney Landau: Um, yeah, I
think that there's value in
that, because you have to cover
the topic. When you're giving
the talk, like, you want to
cover all aspects of it? And if
it's something I haven't, you
know, there's certain parts of
it that I haven't really used in
depth that really helps solidify
things. Yeah,
Dan Ott: yeah, I've had that
experience where this was, I
guess, this was for that the
last round of lightning talks, I
talked about CSS Grid, and I
picked it because I like knew it
pretty well, you know, and,
like, grammie grid is like, kind
of, I say, knew pretty well. And
that means like, I only had to
look up half of the things that
I was trying to do. But like, I
honestly, like, had a whole
thing wrong in my head that I
was going to talk about, you
know, and I had, like, read it
out incorrectly, and went to
just reference the docs just so
I could like, nail down one
piece of syntax and realize that
I had this whole thing that I
learned it, you know, what I
mean? Like, like, in preparing
for the talk, I was like,
actually, like, improve my own,
you know, knowledge at the same
time as it was kind of cool. I
was just like, you know, and
writing is I think that kind of
the same way, except maybe with
some less pressure, but like,
the the act of like, teaching,
you know, in some way can is
like a very valuable, like
learning tool for yourself,
right? That's the way I look at
it at least.
Courtney Landau: Yeah,
definitely. There's definitely a
lot of value for. And I admire
people that are making blog
posts about things a lot. And I
just don't know how people find
that time. I wish I could do
more of that. But yeah, it's
very time consuming, but you do.
It does really solidify your
knowledge. For sure.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I know, you
know, it's a strategy even in
teaching, like if you're in a
classroom to put a student who
might be a little bit ahead of
another student together and
have them pair. No, I'm not even
on coding things, but just, you
know, whatever topic you're
learning about, because there's
something about that peer to
peer interaction, and the, how
you're able to solidify your own
understanding of a concept. But
how teaching it and working
together helps students retain
information better and to grow.
And I think, you know, a lot of
it has to do with like that
sense of accomplishment and
teamwork. And I don't know, I
think that's one of the great
things about Virtual Coffee,
because people are always kind
of pairing up to work on things
together. And, you know, with
the mentoring you've done to
Courtney, maybe you've had that
experience as well. But you
know, the idea of, you know,
pairing with people who you
talked earlier about being able
to offer something, even if
you're a little bit ahead of
someone else. And I just think
that's so important. I don't
think that people realize that
enough that you if you're a step
ahead of somebody, you can still
teach and mentor.
Courtney Landau: Right? Yeah,
and definitely
mentoring and, like doing the
Oktoberg mentoring is definitely
helps solidify my knowledge as
well. And I really enjoy it.
Like, I like
talking to people about tech. So
I hope to continue doing that.
throughout the rest of my career.
Dan Ott: I feel like one of the
nice things about nice, but like
one of the most one of the
important things about mentoring
is like showing that it's okay
to like, not know, everything,
you know, and you can be like
successful at whatever project
or task you know, without like
having the complete knowledge of
all things, you know, which is
one of the hardest, like, I feel
like one of the hardest things
about learning to be a developer
and learning new, new skills is
is just like you it's very
natural to feel like you need to
know everything, you know Yeah,
but like very obvious, like,
Courtney Landau: yeah, that is
impossible.
Dan Ott: Right? It's impossible.
No, you're fine. I was just
gonna say it's it's like, it can
seem like everybody that's
experienced does know
everything, you know. And that's
like a lesson we try to I don't
know display is even people who
have been working in the
industry for a very long time.
Don't know everything, no don't
know nearly everything, you know
what I mean? They they've just
like gotten better at finding
things out, you know faster,
like lots of times. So it's just
like learning things together is
a great like mentor mentee you
know, activity for lack of a
better word.
Unknown: Yeah, definitely. And
Courtney Landau: they,
especially Andrea for
HacktoberFest, she
definitely saw a lot of that I
wasn't familiar with because we
worked on the Virtual Coffee
site itself. And I wasn't
familiar with, like, the static
site generator. I hadn't really
used that before. And we use
eleventy. And so I was learning
along with her. But yeah, it was
really, it was great. And she
actually, I steal her story, but
she taught me I knew she'd
definitely taught me things cuz
she, she was committing a fight
like a half of not the entire
file. Like I've just always just
committed that entire file, but
she's on how you can stage just
selection and selected parts.
She I think she was very happy
that she got to show me
something. Yeah, just she has a
good experience. And yeah, we
went mentoring with me will see
me googling and and it's very
valuable to show how you go
through your process to like,
and it definitely gets better
over time of how to figure
things out, just working
through. Because I mean, web dev
is constantly changing anyway.
Dan Ott: Yes, exactly. Yeah,
that's, that's really awesome.
I, I feel like, Oh, no, I can't
speak for Andrew. But like,
being in that position, I almost
would would rather that
experience of like, my, like a
mentor, like not, not being the
total expert, and just having
all the answers, right, you
know, because that like learning
how to figure things out is,
right, it's just like, the most
important thing I feel like to
get under your belt, especially
early.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, I
want to, I want to say too, so
you did do the lightning talks,
you have mentored, you know,
take for some of our coffees.
And this last time for the
lightning talks, you also were a
coordinator, which meant that
you worked with a bunch of
different speakers, and you work
with us to kind of create this
process or to understand the
process that to create these
events. And that is a lot of
stuff to be doing. And you did
it all really well. You had so
many people that you were
working with to coordinate that
while you were writing your own
talk. Um, do you think like
maybe some of the stuff that
you're doing with Project
Management at your job came into
play here? Or you just decided
you are going to do it off?
Courtney Landau: Um, no, for
sure. Yeah. Definitely have to
do I like working on I like
doing stuff that like helping
out where I can, you know, and
doing that back end like stuff
is like, right up my alley.
Like, by like, doing the
coordinating type things. I was
always kind of one of those
people who aren't here's to be
like, oh,
like Vice President, the one who
doesn't have to do everything.
Know of clubs and things. But
yeah, so yeah, like doing that
kind of thing. Coordinating was
not hard. It was just reaching
out to people every once a while
wasn't Yeah, it wasn't a big
deal. And my own talk was
something that, you know, I was
pretty familiar with, so I
didn't really have to spend a
ton of time. Now you notice I
didn't haven't done like a brown
bag. Right? That that involves a
lot of work, I think like to
speak for an hour, but
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: so that's
what you're gonna do next. Is
that what you're saying?
Courtney Landau: I don't know
about that.
Dan Ott: What's your brown bag
topic? Gonna be?
Courtney Landau: Yeah, that's I
that's the question though. I
have no idea.
Dan Ott: I mean,
Courtney Landau: I probably will.
Dan Ott: There's lots of options
though. With the brown bag to
eat. You know, they don't always
have to be just like,
presentation for an hour, you
know, can be like, even with
Firebase, you know, mix in some
workshop II stuff or whatever.
There's like, there's lots of
options.
Courtney Landau: Yeah. All
right. Yeah, that's me. I would
really like I think that's more
up my alley than an hour long
talk is more of a workshop
personally.
Dan Ott: Interesting, I think in
general, anyway, maybe not more
interesting. But I always I very
much enjoy workshops, because
it's fun to like work along, you
know, alongside. Yeah,
Courtney Landau: yeah. I mean, a
bit of a tangent, but the code,
was it. Like DEV.to's, dot com
or the code newbies conference,
that workshop? those workshops.
were really good. I really
enjoyed those. Nice. That was
definitely the best part of the
conference for me. Yep, so VC.
Next step, we should do
workshops.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: We've had
one workshop. At the beginning
of the year, this year, we're
hot did one. And that was really
great. I would love to see more
workshops. I think that's
intimidating. I don't know, I I
feel like I could never give a
workshop. I would be intimidated
by that. But we should
definitely get your workshop
started Courtney.
Courtney Landau: Okay.
Yeah, no, I don't know why. But
I like that. I like teaching
things like that. I think that.
For me, my comfort level was
more geared towards that kind of
thing, then talking on stage, or
would it not really on stage,
but you know, for an hour?
Dan Ott: Yeah, I feel the same
way I feel I very much enjoy,
like, especially even want a one
on one, you know, like
conversations, but anything
where it's, the closer it is to
having conversation, as opposed
to you know, like you said, like
standing on a huge stage or
whatever, you know, I don't
know, the easier it is for me to
get into it and feel less
nervous about it anyway.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: So we've
talked a lot about the things
that you've done to kind of push
yourself out of your comfort
zone and your journey. And I
don't know if you have a recent
win that you want to share. But
if you do, we would love to hear
it.
Courtney Landau: Let me think
for a second. Probably like, a
month ago now or not sure. But I
had for work I had designed and
built. We I mentioned the Chrome
extension we had for students,
but I designed and built one for
teachers as well, to solve a
need that they saw that works
with Google Classroom. But um,
yeah, so that came out like,
couple weeks ago, and I got some
really good feedback on that.
And everybody seems to really
like it. So that's a win for me.
Dan Ott: That's awesome. That's
a huge win.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Yeah, it is.
Dan Ott: I've never messed with
Chrome extensions. Are they
like, is it JavaScript? Yep.
Yes, it's just like a, like a
whole nother world. Like, just
if you know, JavaScript, are you
still gonna just be totally lost
until you learn it? Or is it
like, you know,
Courtney Landau: it depends on
what you want to do. I guess
it's really, like, there's a pop
up part that's just, you know,
styling, HTML, CSS, and
JavaScript there. But then
there's like things that you can
do within, like, use Google
Chrome, API's to like, inject
things into the page, like,
websites or grab things from
them. And then there's the
background that's does a bunch
of stuff. But that's Yeah, and
that's just JavaScript too. So,
yeah, totally depends on there's
it, there's a million different
things you could do with the
Chrome extension. But
Dan Ott: that's, that's a whole
area I've never I've never
messed with, but it always
seemed like, could be some, you
know, possible to make some cool
stuff, you know,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Could be a
workshop.
Dan Ott: Yeah. Could be.
Courtney Landau: I could do a
workshop on that.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: That would
be awesome.
Dan Ott: I'd go.
Courtney Landau: I don't know
how, yeah. How many people want
to build Chrome extensions, but
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: I mean, I
think it's cool. Everybody in
the community is always
interested in something, you
know, there's enough people here
that they just want to hear
whether they want to do it or
just want to have some
understanding of it. I think
that you know, there are always
people there that are going to
support the talk or the workshop.
Courtney Landau: That's Yeah,
that's really true. Because
there's always a lot of people
that I go to as many brown bags
as I can, even if I'm not as
interested in the topic, It
always proves valuable some way,
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: for sure.
All right, Courtney, this has
been really great. And it was
nice to talk through all of
these things with you and kind
of hear your stories behind
things. So thank you so much for
being here. today. We will post
all of your contact information,
your Twitter handle and that
kind of stuff in our show notes.
So thanks for being here.
Courtney Landau: Great. Thanks
so much.
Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at Virtual
Coffee, IO. Or you can email us
at podcast at Virtual coffee.io.
You can find the show notes plus
you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee has been up to on
our website at Virtual coffee.io
Dan Ott: please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a review. Thanks for listening
and we'll see you next week.