Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season two, episode seven of
the Virtual Coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their stories
and what they've learned.
And we're here to
share it with you.
Here with me today
is my cohost, Dan.
Dan: And this episode, we
talk with Nerando Johnson,
a full-stack developer,
and in my mind, a living,
breathing ray of sunshine.
Nerando shared some of his
experiences running freeCodeCamp
meetups in Atlanta, learning
through hackathons, and
his approach to learning
in general, as a developer.
Bekah and I also decided
on his next endeavor:
Socialization as a Service
for introverts at tech events.
It was a true delight as always
to spend some time with Nerando.
And I know you're
going to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every
episode of the podcast.
Like we start every
Virtual Coffee.
We introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're
from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's question is- you're
going to sail around the world.
What's the name of your boat?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Hey, I'm Bekah.
I'm a front end developer
from a small town in Ohio.
And if I was going to sell
around the world, my boat's
name would be, I think I would
probably go with the name
of my first pet, which was
a hamster named Starscraper
to the Highest Moon.
And, um, that would
be my boat's name too.
Dan: Second appearance of
Starscraper, I feel like
on the podcast, do we have
any pictures of Starscraper
to the Highest Moon?
Bekah: No I don't think
I have any Starscraper.
Dan: all right, well, we'll
have to dig it up in my head
Nerando: I was, I was
saying, okay, go for it.
Dan: Um, hi, my name is Dan
I'm a front end developer
from , Lakewood, Ohio.
And, um, if I'm going to sail
around the world in a boat.
I, somebody asked a boat
related name, you know,
boat naming thing on slack,
I think a while back.
And I came up with float none,
which was a CSS joke that I
was just giggling to myself
about for the rest of the day.
And so I'm sticking with
that float float colon
none is my boat name.
Bekah: Right.
Nerando: Um, hi,
my name is Nerando.
I am a, uh, call myself
a level 1.5 full stack
developer out of Atlanta.
If I was going to sail around
the world with that boat,
what would the name be?
Yeah, I'd call it Almost There.
So every time, every
time you asked me,
where am I Almost There?
Dan: That sounds familiar.
I like that.
Bekah: That is awesome.
Well, thank you so much for
being here with us today.
We're really excited
to talk to you.
And we always like to start
with the origin story.
So how did you get to this point?
Um, what is the
backstory of Nerando
Nerando: so there is a 15
minute version and the five
minute version on a three,
I'm going to give it a three.
Um, because I talk so much
in my early teens, my mom
sent me off to teacher's
college in the Caribbean.
So I started teaching when I was.
19 cause I'm one of
those kids who are way
too smart for anything.
So I became a professional
teacher at 19, along the way.
I discovered that my students
learn to way more when I put
them in front of a computer
than I actually stand in
front of a classroom teacher.
So I'm like, all right, cool.
I started making like drag
and drop games for them.
And I hit like 28.
I was like, yeah, I
can't do this anymore. Um, so I.
A couple of other stuff happened
and I'm like, you know what?
Let's make a shift because
I lived in Jamaica, but
my family lived here.
And my mom says if you
want  to make a move, like,
all right, cool, give away
everything and sell everything.
Move. Being here, the book world.
Was a big thing.
CS 50 was a thing.
And I am like, I was
always a techie guy.
I also have a background
as a computer.
I'm a trained computer
repair technician.
So I've always liked.
Had like small programs to
like fix and build stuff.
But the code was always like,
there I up, like I've been
running Linux since like
2010, like Ubuntu was my
thing and I've made stuff.
I fixed stuff.
I'm like, it was always cool,
but the code was always there
and I'm like, you know what?
Let's go learn this.
HTML and CSS was fun.
And then JavaScript promptly
decided to drop me on my
face and reminded me that I
have no idea what now my dog,
Bekah: Sounds familiar.
Nerando: um, while doing
all of this, I mean,
freeCodeCamp came out.
Like the first version came out
and I'm like, Ooh, this is cool.
I went through my first
meetup, fell in love with it.
Um, that group canceled most
of my second meetup group,
which was in, um, the Sandy
Springs area of Atlanta.
This is like 2017.
I met some cool people and
I never dropped a habit.
I'd always wanted to drop
it because it's frustrating,
but I've never dropped
the habit after that.
Um, did some community work with
one of our other men became good
friends with a lot of people.
Did some community work
with like one of my
friends called Mark Noonan.
I don't know if he's a guy
who should be on this next.
He can tell the other,
usually he can tell the
other side of the story.
Um, we've done.
I've done a hackathon.
I got a scholarship
to go to Flat Iron.
That was interesting,
like the whole nine yards.
And I eventually got to the
place of like, did the bootcamp
experience failed along the way?
Got back at it, finished
the boot camp went
through the job search.
My last place was Warner, but
COVID decided to borrow back,
take back my job from me.
So I'm currently on there.
So yeah, bear bearing
in mind along the way.
I almost learned to code in
high school, college ones.
Cause all my friends
learned to code.
I didn't um, when I was
teaching, there was a
program that came up.
I never took it, but every
time coding came up, I stepped
away because I was more
interested in other things.
So the last time it
came up, I'm like, yeah,
we're going to take this
Bekah: nice.
Were you online for Flat
Iron or did you go to campus?
Nerando: In person. Dear God, in
person, it was good.
Bekah: Yeah.
I always was curious about
that because I did their online
self-paced program and it
always seemed interesting to
be able to like go on campus
and see other people and to
have those conversations.
But I mean, it wasn't available
around me and also I didn't
have that availability either.
Nerando: Mhm, in person is
a whole different experience
because it tends to be at
any one time you have two
cohorts on campus back then
when you were doing the
first module, you had three.
But it was always, I,
it was collaborative.
It was a lot of
people going crazy.
You saw that you are the
only person losing your
mind, trying to learn so
much stuff at one time. Yeah.
Stuff like that, but it was good.
Bekah: I feel like that's
a really important part of
the process because when
you're isolated in learning,
there's nobody else to
kind of compare that to.
And so having that.
I don't know if it's community
support or at least that
recognition that like, oh,
other people are, are really
struggling right now, too.
There's this weird
feeling of, okay.
I feel, I feel good that
everybody's struggling, right?
Like,
Nerando: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, learning collaboratively
while learning for yourself
is helpful because the
emotional support is there.
And you get to ask questions
because some parts of it
you get, but some parts
you don't get and you get
to ask like instructors
or TAs or your classmates.
So yeah.
Bekah: so you mentioned
Mark Noonan and we were in
a Virtual Coffee one day
and we were talking about
like how to stay motivated.
And he said, you need a Nerando
because he makes sure that I
stay on top of these things.
And I thought.
Nerando: okay. All right.
So the joke around that
is that, um, Mark's been
my friend since God.
It's 2021 now.
So I think 2017, 2018, we
got to be really good friends
through our hackathon.
And because I have a
teacher's grown, it kind of
helps me literally go stay
on task and get it done.
So Mark's like, oh,
pretty butterfly.
I'm like, you are not.
The dog from Up, you do
not have a squirrel moment.
Focus. He's like, "what?
No, I want to!" I don't care.
And he's like, "but you don't
know how to write a code".
I'm like, no, but if I
put you here long enough,
we'll get it done.
He goes, "I hate you".
But yeah, it's it's to this
day, I'm still learning
how to be better focused at
stuff, but it's a continuous
progress and project for me.
Because it's like the one thing
that nobody really tells us as
human beings is that you have
finite time to do anything you
want, not infinite, finite,
like you have this amount of
years before your body stops
working or your mind goes,
and you've got to get all this
done before that, but we keep
thinking we have all the time.
No you don't. So yeah.
Bekah: Okay.
So you've been involved in a
lot of different things and
you talked about being involved
in freeCodeCamp already,
hackathons, and in boot camps.
And so I'm curious, like what
were some of the lessons that
you learned there, but also what
were your favorite experiences?
Nerando: um, so you say
hackathon, bootcamp. Um, alright.
Bekah: freeCodeCamp.
Nerando: freeCodeCamp.
So let's  start
with freeCodeCamp.
Cause that's where
it all began for me.
freeCodeCamp taught me that
A: learning in a community
is really good for you.
The operation sides of running
a meetup is way different from
just talking, because like
I learned and I'd be there.
And I learned stuff when
I started running it, I
learned from like 15 minutes,
cause I'm walking around
and talking to them, people
breaking the ice so-and-so
stuff, so and so forth.
And at the same time, I'm really
good at making connections.
Cause then I like I've learned
over the years that frequently
we have a lot of teachers,
former teachers, we have a
lot of former musicians, which
is weird to me and we tend
to have like 40% left-handed
people as developers, which
Bekah: I always wanted
to be left-handed.
Nerando: The trick is that I'm
left-handed so I notice it.
Like we have a lot of
left-handed people.
So those aren't experienced.
I learned in there, like
some people will come learn.
The code would be wanting
to be a developer.
Others will learn it.
Want to be a developer and
then go hey, not for me.
And you should be that's okay.
You will have hobbies.
Like I learned how to deal
with moms with children.
Like that's a whole nother thing.
I've never had to think of.
Um, I learned how to deal with
people who can come for an hour
cause they are running Lyft
or they're working on a Sunday
and that's all they can do.
I learned how to
support peopleonline,
like stuff like that.
I learned how to do, I'm
still learning, but those
are the things that I
learned, uh, hackathons,
the myths of thinking you
can't create something
from an idea over 24 hours.
Is not true how good it is
is that total different ball
game, but you can do it in 24
hours filled with the right
set of people and coffee
and no sleep and red bull.
Um, MARTA's hackathon
was one of the best
experience I've ever had.
I still have pictures of all
the food they put on the table.
And one of the chairman or
one of the senior guys singing
and singing karaoke at one
o'clock in the morning.
Cause we were all up.
Um, but like hackathons tend
to, I encourage everybody, even
if you you're not confident,
Hey, I don't know anything.
Nobody cares.
Like honestly, nobody in the
room will care because you will
have something to contribute.
Bekah: Let's jump back to
freeCodeCamp for a minute.
Cause I think that's
really interesting.
So you attended two
different freeCodeCamp
meetups, but you also ran
freeCodeCamp meetups, right?
Nerando: I'm still running it.
We're more we're slowed down
because of COVID, but yeah.
Bekah: Right.
that freeCodeCamp Atlanta?
Nerando: Yes, it's
freeCodeCamp Atlanta.
We have like a Facebook group
that we use that we do, like
once, like once a month we
have like a check-in I'm
trying to go a little bit
bigger, but I kind of have a
lot of other things going on.
So I'm trying to just
slow down for a minute.
Hopefully by the end of this
year, next year we can start
doing in-person meetups
again, that would be awesome.
Bekah you should submit for
our in-person conferences.
Bekah: That's referring to a
tweet yesterday that I sent
saying I'm very tempted to
start submitting for in-person
conferences, again, I miss it.
Not even speaking, just being
there and having the experience.
Dan: Can you tell me a little
more about what you do at the
freeCodeCamp, Atlanta meetups.
Nerando: all right.
So our freeCodeCamp Atlanta
meetups are generally structured
as in we find a comfortable
place that we can all sit and
have food and all of that stuff.
And we just for, our use-case we
sit and whatever project you're
working on, you can come and
ask questions and discuss it.
We tend not to be structured.
We've always tried going
structured, but it never
works out so it's...
more like a group of
chill, people just sitting
and working and stuff.
But what happens
from this though?
Because we have no structure.
We tend to refer people
to like other meetups.
We tend to have people who are
further ahead in their career.
So you have mentorship going on.
You tend to have networking
opportunities where somebody
could say, Hey, can you
apply it to this job?
Because mine has an opening,
bearing in mind that the opening
has not been made public, but.
You see somebody who
has a potential to go.
And even if you don't
pass the interview,
you have the experience
Dan: great. Yeah.
So cause, cause freeCodeCamp,
like, so everybody's maybe
a different, you know,
different levels of whatever.
And so your meetup is more
of just like a, almost
like a support group,
Nerando: well, yeah, that's,
that's
Dan: Yeah. That's awesome.
That's really cool.
I am also looking forward
to in person meet ups, uh,
becoming a thing again, you
know, we had the Cleveland
React meet up and it was, it
was a lot of fun and we had,
you know, it was just pizza
and that same kind of thing,
and went online and, you know,
we were still doing meetups,
but they're, I don't know.
It's just, it's so
much more nice to
Nerando: I
Dan: be in the same
room with people. Huh?
Nerando: I think we all
took pizza for granted.
Dan: I still have in my notes,
my like, you know, script for
running the meetup about, you
know, directions and pizza,
you know, where the, where the
pizza is and stuff like that.
Oh, man.
Bekah: I think one of the
nice things though, that's
come from all this, like I
could never attend a meet up
because I've got four kids
and I live in a small town.
Um, But in the post COVID
world, I imagine there's going
to be a really nice balance
of those things and maybe
even some hybrid events that
are going to be happening.
And I think that'll be nice
to provide community for
so many more people than
then would have had it. Otherwise
Nerando: I have been
thinking about that too,
even as a organizer, because
then you see like, it.
It like, it helps way more.
Like I've had friends who
say, Hey, I can't meet in the
meet up, but if you can grab
your laptop, turn on your
hotspot go in your car and
set what else for an hour.
I probably could walk you
through an issue you're having.
And like you're at
home, you could make it.
But instead of driving 30
minutes to us bearing in
mind, we've had members who
used to drive an hour just
to get to us just because
they liked the environment. But
if you can just spend
the time and come.
I mean, it helps.
Dan: Yeah.
I, um, I'm very, I'm very
interested to see what
happens to w all this.
There was definitely some, um,
some groups experimenting with
like, sort of hybrid designs,
stuff like that before you COVID
I, um, I cannot remember what.
ReactaDelphia. That's what it is.
The Philly, the Philly React
group was doing a lot of work
with this, um, before COVID,
you know, uh, where, where
they were streaming, they
were having in-person meetups,
but they were also streaming.
And I think projecting, I'm
not sure if they were doing
this too, but, um, like
having maybe zoom or something
like that, where, uh, people
could sort of be sort of
there virtually, you know?
Um, and there's a lot of,
you know, there's a lot of
Opportunity for cool stuff
coming up, but it really is.
I mean, like the same with
Virtual Coffee, right?
I mean, Virtual Coffee is,
you know, I don't know if
this was some other thing
where it wasn't a pandemic,
you know, but same situation.
It might've ended up being
a local thing, you know?
Um, the Steubenville, you know,
I don't know, developers meet up
or something and, uh, you know,
the, the exposure and the, the.
The flexibility of the
virtual meetups is huge. Right.
But, well, I think we're lot
of people are missing actual
in-person feel of some things.
Um, um, um, I'm looking
forward to the future.
You know, I feel like
there's a spot for all, all
of this, all this kind of
mixed together, you know?
Nerando: Bekah, you had a point.
Bekah: You read my face.
Our initial tagline for
Virtual Coffee was "The
Always-Remote Hallway Track".
Right. Cause there's that hallway
track at conferences that
is just really nice because
you get to meet people and
have that support and talk to
people, get that interaction.
And then at some point,
I mean, we are Virtual
Coffee, but I think I.
I mean, I hear it over and over.
Like when are we
all going to meet? Right.
And there is something
very special about these
friendships and the
community that's been formed.
And that's why I like really
like this idea of a hybrid model
because also in-person, I don't
get to meet people that are on
the other side of the world or.
In Canada, even, you know?
Um, so it's nice to be able to
meet those people and then like
finding that space where you
can have a physical presence,
I think would, is going to
be a really amazing thing
when we get to that point.
Nerando: I think like one
of the things I learned like
over the years, so here's a
cheat code to anybody who is
going to think about this.
When conferences come back
in one of the easiest way for
like junior devs or level one
developers to get into big
conferences is to volunteer.
I've done that at Connect.Tech
when it was that thing.
And I don't mind the physical
work cause sometimes that
literally like physical
work and cooking literally
is like therapy for me.
So when I got my ticket,
I'd get the ticket to go
to the all-day conference.
I've met so much people
over two, three years
just by doing that.
Um, another thing is
like when they have the
after-parties for conferences.
Those one thirty conversations.
They are like, it tends
to be the persons who
present, who socialize.
So you are in a newbie learning
from somebody who's been
doing this for like 10 years.
Like I met  Chris DeMars.
He, I think he's
been here before.
I don't know if he's ever been
on Virtual Coffee, but Chris
DeMars is we, he presented,
I went to his talk while at
Connect.Tech and then, when
they had the after party,
me, I'm one of my batch
mates, um, to any kind he
works for, I think FullStory
now, but we were there late.
And then I met somebody
like along the way I met,
I got to develop a better
relationship with this
guy called Homer Gaines.
Homer does accessibility.
He is crazy. He also makes music.
So. I didn't meet.
I didn't know these
people until then.
And then I thought another
connection to go to another
conference by meeting somebody
else just they're like,
Hey, would you like to come?
And I'm like, no ticket, no time.
They're like, okay,
we'll get your ticket.
You got to find your way there.
A friend of mine and a
friend of mine connected
me to go to the conference.
I'm like, my car won't make it.
They're like, okay.
Uh, how much do you
need to rent a car?
I'm like, oh, and what you're
like, you need to exposure.
So it's like conferences
that helps that's a
cheat sheet right there.
I'm giving away that one.
Dan: I think that's right.
I mean, volunteering is great.
I mean, like that's
great advice, I think in
general, and it's the same.
If you're helping out, you
know, it, people are always
gonna appreciate it and you
know, they'll go a long way,
but I actually was actually had,
thinking about what you said
about like after parties and
the late night, you know, or
like the diff the conversations
outside of the events, you
know, and, you know, honestly
for me, that's the, those
are the things that, um, at
conferences that stick in my
brain the best, I was just
thinking back, you know, and,
and just sitting on like a patio
of a restaurant with, with like
Dan Cederholm and Andy Clarke
like having conversations with
these people that I like look
up to, you know, and I don't.
I'm sorry. I don't remember what
their talks were about.
You know what I mean?
But like, I very much remember
like sitting there and just
soaking it up and you know,
like talking on, I don't know.
It's cool.
I don't really have a point
other than like, I was just,
it made me nostalgic, um, for
Bekah: I think I have lots
of thoughts now, but I
will say too, there's also
diversity scholarships.
So if you're from an
underrepresented group in
tech, that's a way to get
into some conferences.
Some of them even
pay for your travel.
Um, sometimes they'll offer
discounted tickets too.
So I think that number one,
recognizing if it's not
doable, For you reach out
to the conference organizers
because there might be
some way to get you there.
And I think Dan, like what
you're talking about, and
Nerando what you're talking
about, it's the idea of
these personal connections
that are being made there.
And I love that aspect of
the conference and that's one
of the things that I think I
wish would go on beyond that.
Right? Because you have this
conference, you make these
connections and then there's.
At least most of them that
I've been to, there's not
been that like, Hey, let's
continue to keep up in some way.
And I think that that would be
a really fun thing to continue
to do all throughout the year,
because then you grow together.
Nerando: All right.
There is some, like, what
I've learned with for
myself is how to keep up
that con conversation.
So I have been known to not
be afraid to stop be like,
one of my friends says, do you
want, if your greatest skill
is that you're never afraid to
walk into a room where nobody
knows you and talk to people.
I'm like, I know what
I need from the room.
So like Virtual Coffee came to
me by means offs like posts.
How should I say it
posts COVID Warner.
Like when I was at Warner,
because I've worked, I'd
like I needed a group.
I couldn't find anywhere.
I'm not like somebody
like a Virtual Coffee.
I'm like Virtual Coffee?
Like okay.
Hopped in first meetup.
I'm like, Ooh, like this room.
And then we had Mike
Rogers walk into room
and hype in the room up.
I'm like, who is this dude?
And how shall I be his friend?
And then Meg, like for me, Mike
Rogers, Meg, um, Debra-Kaye
is like, I, the energy that
comes to the room and then
Bekah's kids were running
through the background?
And I'm like, mom, I'm home.
Like, that was awesome for me.
But to further on the
conversation is like we
don't tech is on Twitter and
a lot of us are afraid of
using Twitter for what it is.
Talk to people, engage.
I am a fan of Gary V and
the whole conversation of
like, understanding who
you are, what you're about. Yeah.
Do that.
Some conferences will have
like swag, like Bekah, I'm
throwing this out there.
We need stickers.
And also we need to get,
we need to get Mike.
I want one and we also need
to get Mike his official
Hype-Man t-shirt I'm just
saying, but we con like,
like for us as developers,
engage, talk to each other.
Like some people will
be the best thing that
ever happened to you.
And some people suck
and that's okay.
Filter, keep it going.
Because at the end of the
day, developers are highly
in demand and the better
off we are like a developer
can make quarter-million
dollars, easy trick is that
you can only do one job.
There'll be 50 more that you
know of that needs to be filled.
And you have, if you make
better associates, it's better
for you in the longterm.
So I'm just saying. Yeah.
I learned about an AWS
developer that makes quarter
million dollars and my
head is still hurting.
Bekah: I love, I think, well,
for me to, uh, conferences, I
am super shy and an introvert.
And so I get really
nervous going into there.
But I think if you know, someone
ahead of time, um, making
sure that you meet up or have
that friend person, um, there.
So Nerando, you'll be my
friend person because I'll
just follow you around.
Nerando: I have no problem.
I got no problem with that.
Believe me. I will, I will take
you on as my wing man.
And literally goes, oh
yeah, this is Bekah.
You should talk there.
I literally have done
this to somebody before.
I'm like, this is Bekah.
You should talk to her.
She's awesome.
She runs Virtual Coffee.
Here's a website. Goodbye.
It was like, why are
you leaving me here? Talk mingle.
You'll be fine.
Dan: Yeah, I have that too.
That that's probably really
why I have more fond memories
of sitting like at the table.
You know, it's like a
little easier to kind
of know what to do. I don't know.
Then when you're in a
large group of people, but
I'll follow, I'll follow
you guys around too.
Bekah: just having your little
line of Virtual Coffee people.
Dan: Right. It's just gonna be
dropping us off.
Nerando: Stay right here.
Talk to all these wonder
people I'll be back.
I was like, why
are you doing this?
Because I can stress you
out for the fun of it.
The people that know me on
Twitter, if they ever hear
this podcast are going to
start crying, especially Homer
is going to start laughing.
I know this already.
Dan: I have it.
This is  socialization
as a service.
This is, it started charging.
So you just like, you know,
somebody, somebody pays a fee
and then you you'd be walking
around in the conference.
I love it. All right.
Nerando: Socialization
as a service. I like that one.
All right.
We missed, we missed one topic.
I think hackathons.
I think the thing that stops
a lot of, I'll never say
junior developers because
it doesn't really feel good.
Level one developers from,
and people who have no code
experience from even trying is
because they think that there's
this bar there and you have to
be as good enough as this to do.
As I have previously
stated I don't care.
So I'll just go, okay, this is
something I need to learn, or
this is something I need to have
an introduction to and I'll go.
They, again, this is an
industry where you knowing
somebody is way more important
than actually knowing what
you're doing, because along
the way, people can help you.
So it's one of them things
where it's like, just
go, like, nobody cares. Just go.
And you learn.
Like I learned way more
than I've ever learned.
Like, I made better friends.
I've made better connections.
I learned a lot.
I learned how to speak on stuff.
I stood in front of a crowd of
like a hundred people and spoke
about what we were working on.
My knees didn't work properly,
but I did it anyway because
I don't like public speaking.
Don't laugh that the
irony is not lost on me
Dan: That's so, yeah. Yeah.
So how many hackathons have
you have you like done?
Nerando: far.
As a long process, three
MARTA, however, broke
theirs up into four.
So technically it
would count as five. Yeah.
Dan: that's awesome.
I've never done one.
I, by the time I was sort
of interested in them I
had kids and it was just, I
don't know, it's much harder
to spend 24 hours away.
And, um, also I'm old.
And so being losing sleep really
Nerando: did you
Dan: for longer than it used to.
Nerando: Did he just drop in?
I'm older really quickly.
Dan: I was just going to move
on from that, but the recovery
time from a, from a all-nighter
is much worse now than it was.
Um, I had an accidental all
night or, um, the other day
and was just, uh, just a
horrible wreck the whole,
the whole rest of the day.
So it's like another
hackathon related, like as
like, ah, that sounds cool.
But now I'm just
like, I don't know.
I gotta think about losing
all that sleep, which then I'm
like, oh yeah, cause I'm old.
I don't know.
Nerando: I think for me
with hackathons, I'm more
energized with what we
learn and where what's
going on than anything else.
So I will, I mean, I'm the
guy I need five and a half
hours asleep to be okay.
I can survive on four and I
I've done college in Jamaica,
which is no fun some days.
So I learned how to
survive on no sleep, but
hackathons really like.
The pro you learn so much,
like so much so quickly, you
meet so much different people.
Dan: Okay. I think that's cool.
I've never really thought
about hackathons as, as
like a tool for career devs.
But now that you mentioned
it, I think that's a great
idea because, uh, like
you're saying, you just,
you're just stuck there.
So you have to learn.
I'm one of, you know, one of
the problems that I've heard
a lot from people learning is
like, I don't want choosing
what to learn or how to
learn or all that stuff.
And when you are stuck
in a room and, you know,
working with other people. Yeah.
I mean, you, you soak up the
knowledge from other people,
but also you're just like
pointed in one direction.
You don't really have, you know,
you know, have choice, I assume
not having done it, but I would
assume that if you are a less
experienced dev sitting there,
then the people will help with
like choosing what, to, you
know, what you should do, right.
Or whatever, and, um,
and kind of just have one
target and move forward.
Um, that seems like a great,
great opportunity for,
you know, people learning.
Nerando: So from that, you'll
also learn like the other side
of dev work, which is like
figuring out how to build what
to build quickly, figuring out
what we need really quickly,
um, figuring out like what
storage that I learned, how to
write stories in a hackathon.
I never knew about
user stories before. So from.
So from hackathon, like
with MARTA in Atlanta Mark
is technically the leader
in this thing and I'm his
right hand, Mark Noonan.
And from that they changed
policy like the city change
policy and I'm like, oh my
God, they listened to us.
We worked on paratransit
and how to make that better.
And that got better.
And then we took that and
when somewhere else and enter
just for the fun of it, same
concept, because we wanted
more awareness to the problem
we're having that, that, that
process of like six or seven
months are a bit longer.
We ended up winning
that hackathon.
And because we never, because
MARTA literally made us
never winning anything.
We signed the agreement between
all of us to give away the
money in case we won anything.
The trick is that we won.
We won 40 grand and gave it away.
To this day, I'm still beating
myself because we could
have all put it in Bitcoins,
walk away with Mac books and
still give away 40 grand.
But it's a really cool
conversation to have. Okay.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome.
I mean, it seems like
you're no, go ahead, Dan.
Dan: I was just laughing.
I don't have anything to say.
Nerando: Go go ahead, Dan,.
I'm still, I know
you're laughing at me. It's okay.
Dan: I was mostly just laughing
at you hanging your head
at the end of that story.
Nerando: I'll I'll I'll drop
the article when this is done.
So you can read the
article cause Mark actually
wrote an article on it.
Bekah: Yeah, we'll
put that in the show
Dan: definitely send that.
Bekah: Um, okay.
So you've been involved in
all of these things and.
I feel like you're constantly
moving and you never stop.
And so now you said that,
I think you said, what
are you like a level one
and a half developer? Right?
Like, and one of the things
that I found is that there's
not that many people that
are talking about like, what
that means like that stage.
Cause I feel like it's kind
of a hard stage, right?
You're like you're beyond that
level one and you're trying
to make it to level two.
And so there's these
growing pains going on?
But nobody's talking
about those growing pains.
So I don't know if you have any
thoughts on that or, you know,
like what your experience has
been, but I'd love to hear it.
Nerando: so you want like, like
mentally I've had this talking.
So now 1.5 for me means you have
to pick up a stage of mentoring
being mentored and discipline.
So. You have to write
about what you learned.
This is not the conversation
you have to teach.
You have to get better
at a core stack.
So if you are a modern
stack, I'm React/Ruby, if
you are something else,
you'll have to get better.
I will never stop
emphasizing this.
JavaScript is on an ending
like JavaScript for me is
like the 12 levels of hell.
And we keep going down into
it and you're just going
to have to keep going. It's cool.
It's fun.
It's annoying because it
changes every couple of years,
but you will have to get
better at your core language.
It's building stuff.
It's walking away from tutorials.
However, pretty they look it's
asking way more questions is
volunteering for stuff that you
might not be ready for, or it's
failing horribly at something
it's asking for way more help
than you're comfortable with.
I have a toddler
in the background.
I probably should get up and go
lock the door, but I'm too lazy.
So I'm around my
nephew right now. He's here.
Yeah. his time in the morning.
Um, so it's that stage of
being aware that I'm not junior
anymore, but everybody will see
you as junior and that's fine.
What do you think
in your head rules? Way more.
And then you will have to prove
that you're there to yourself.
It's collaborative coding.
It's learning how to run our own
GitHub without losing your mind.
It's learning git like that.
It's being comfortable
with the terminal.
It's finishing projects.
It's having conversations
about code it's like when you
reach the stage of having the
code dream you have, right.
I don't, I don't know if
I've had the code dream.
Bekah: I mean, I have nightmares
about testing all the time.
Nerando: Yeah.
Oh, dream it seeing like
basic stuff, like elevators
and literally working out.
How would this work in my
language, my coding language.
I've done it in
Python and JavaScript.
Dan: I am not sure I want to
get into a JavaScript elevator.
Nerando: Okay. Ah, come here.
It runs the internet.
It's not that bad. God.
Bekah: Okay.
So, so you have your doing all
of these things, and that was
just a ton of great advice.
I want to say, first of all.
Um, but, okay.
So how has this been
looking for new jobs?
Because you're saying like,
well, people will see you as, as
a junior, but you're like really
reaching for this next goal.
And I imagine that's kind
of where you're going
in your job search too.
So that been a thing.
Nerando: So the first trick
I learned from job searching
was by this guy called
Eliot Sanford, I think is
his last name . So I was
supposed to go to Eliot's
conference and didn't make it.
And we became friends
and he gave me advice.
So he literally goes.
Watch Danny Thompson's
thing, optimize your
LinkedIn, then walk away
for anybody who doesn't
know who Danny Thompson is.
We are in for a wild ride
because he's awesome.
Bekah: He just got
a new job, right?
Nerando: Congrats to him.
Anyway, um, that now, literally
gets you to the place of
interviewing over and over for
positions that makes you that
you think you're ready for some,
you might get some, you may
not get it's annoying because
everybody wants five years,
but nobody is junior developer
at five years experience.
So first thing I learned from
my days off Career Karma,
because that also helped me.
So my Career Karma,
that was really awesome.
Ruben Harris, um, for our
sake, um, Keisha Lake, who you
should talk to one of these
days, she was my batch mate.
And she's awesome.
Bekah: talk a little bit
about what Career Karma is?
Nerando: So Career Karma.
If I'm to distill it to
simple essence, it provides
connection to an individual,
to foreign individual to get
into tech in a variety of ways.
So if you're a developer,
if you're a software
engineer, if you are a data
scientist, if you want to
get into tech sales, which I
learned was an actual thing.
A couple months
ago, they provide.
Will match you to the,
probably the right school
for you they'll even help
you find funding if needed
or find a proper agreement
for you to go to school.
Cause you have some
schools that do ISAs.
Some have  really good ISAs,
some suck and that's, but
they will help you find
the right place for you.
So that's one, that's one part.
I think I was one of the first
persons out of the group first
like good batches to actually
like really work with them
and I got the help I needed.
So yeah.
And it's not lost on me that
because of them, like I went
to Flat Iron, I had a full ride
scholarship, like all of those
coming work that I did helped.
Um, we, they also helped
me find all the funding
to do other stuff.
I'm like, that was cool.
So that helped.
So like with all of that,
and now it's like, you
know, A lot of things.
That's how I got to
have that in my head.
Bekah: no, that was really great.
And so how, how is this kind of
pushing you into that next stage
of job that you're looking for?
Nerando: It's...I just
classify it as work.
So it's the discipline to
finish this stuff, to get
better at algorithms to own
my truth, to be able to walk
into a room, I'm going, Hey.
I am great at this, this
and this, but I'm not
great at this, but I can
learn this and that's it.
That's, that's kind of
where I am when it comes
to a lot of those things.
And that's just fine, like
near my job coach on Flat
Iron said something that
really stuck to my head.
She says, everybody is cooking
and you are not going to be the
right ingredient for everybody.
You're going to fit one place.
And that one place is
what you're looking for.
So I have literally gotten
nos from one company that
has so many departments
that I've been refused
twice and were like, we're
throwing you in there again.
And I'm like,
Dan: I like that.
I like that metaphor.
I'm adding it to my,
my, metaphor collection.
it a metaphor analogy?
I think It's similar. I gotta, I
gotta
Nerando: It's an, it's
an English saying that
means something else.
We don't care what you title it.
Dan: Fair enough.
Bekah: Okay.
So along with that job search
thing, when you, when you're
looking for jobs, do you have an
ideal job in mind or is this, I
am just looking for work because
I'm curious, like, what does
Nerando's ideal job look like?
Nerando: I work from Wednesdays
to Fridays two hours of day,
and you pay me half a million
dollars just to look cute.
However for code sake.
Um, An ideal job for me right
now is using my stack, which
is React and Ruby, or just
JavaScript and front end
stuff for while teaching.
Like it teaches me other stuff.
So it's a level, 1.5 or
Ruby React developer, or you
want to throw me into the
JavaScript stack, understanding
that I can learn it. And it's.
Like I've had good team
experiences and I've had
bad team experiences.
I mean, it's like having
the ability to like go
to somebody and go, I
don't get what's going on.
So like, that's what
I'm looking for now.
So I just have to be able to
like go through everything
and just keep going.
But that's like somewhere
where my learning potential and
abilities there where I can.
Like I have the track record
to show that I can build stuff,
but also to understand that
look, he's still growing,
but I also have other skills,
which is like somebody said
socialization as a service.
I'm still let them
serve, wrapping my
head around this thing. But yeah.
Dan: you're looking for, you
know, a job or are you looking
for something where it's just
code or, um, like or something
where you can use some more of
your, you know, communication
abilities and teaching
experience, stuff like that.
You know, cause there's some
jobs where even on a good team,
your job is really going to be
sitting and coding, you know?
Um, and there's some jobs, I
think we're probably, you're
going to be doing a little
more personal, you know,
interpersonal work with coding.
I just, I'm just curious if
like, if that's the sort of
thing you're like sifting
through you're searching
for, jobs or are you, um,
Nerando: I think for, I think for
me right now, between
I'm like, I say 1.5.
So between 1.5 and 2.5,
I'm going to spend a lot
of time honing my craft.
The trick is that
I'm a social person.
So between freeCodeCamp, which
I may step away from, but still
be an active participant in
.Virtual Coffee is not losing
me anytime with anytime soon.
So y'all life suck because
I'm going to join Mike
as a hype man, next.
I will do more teaching.
Teaching is second
nature to me because.
There is so much more persons
who need the knowledge
who need somebody to say,
Hey, um, this is how you
do this, or talk to me.
So I'll still be using my social
skills, but for a job job.
It might not be the top priority
when I write stuff if needed.
Yes. Will I be able to speak for
my company if the time comes.
Yes. But it might not be the
priority, but eventually I
think dev rel is looking really
interesting to me down the road.
Dan: That's kinda what I
was wondering if you were,
if you were starting to
look at any of those kinds
of positions, um, if, um,
I haven't like done a job
search for a while, you know?
So like, I don't know if those,
like, if devrel positions,
I don't even know, are There
a lot of, like, I don't know
what the landscape looks like
out there, you know, is there
just like a couple and they
get snatched up right away
all the time, or, you know,
Nerando: They are close  knit.
I think devrel people are
close, close knit group.
So I tend to, I know a couple
of them and I talk to them from
time to time about the job, but
I think I wanted to spend more
time mastering my craft first
because to be able to speak to
the code and teach the code,
you have to know the code.
It's like science.
Like I was a middle school
science teacher for what,
eight and a half, nine years.
I've been a science nerd since
I was about nine, so I can
teach science in my sleep.
So I know it's, I can teach it.
I need to know my craft a bit
more before I'm able to say,
Hey, we have this new tech
and this is how you use it.
And yeah.
So yeah, stuff like that.
Bekah: I also think there's
something valuable about
people seeing you learn as
you go too, though, right?
Like, because sometimes it's
inaccessible to watch people
who know all the answers or who
get to places really quickly.
And so, I don't know.
That's one of the things that
I can appreciate about people
who are live streaming, their
coding process, because they're
working through these problems
at the same time, kind of that
you are as you're watching them.
Right.
And it's nice to know that,
all right, this wasn't super,
um, packaged and perfect.
There was a lot that
went into that process.
And so I do think that you
can hone your craft in some
way at the same time while
teaching other people in a
way that is really authentic.
Um, as opposed to like,
oh, I've been doing this
for a long time and.
This is how it looks
because that's just not as
relatable to people who are
learning for the first time.
Nerando: True.
I think you'd literally
just did something that
I've been trying to avoid.
So I've been trying to avoid
tweeting out what I'm learning
every day and you just share,
enforced the idea that the
action we need to do it.
So good luck Twitter.
Here I come.
Dan: mean, I think
it's good advice.
I think it, I think writing
and sharing what you're
learning, even if you're not
going for a devrel like, like
even not to do with the devrel
in general, but said before
about how teaching helps you
learn and stuff like that.
And, think watching
people's journeys through
learning is, is great.
It's helpful for people
and it's helpful for people
to get to know you better.
I, you know, I feel like
it's helpful for, prospective
employers, you know, to
understand, um, where are you
at and to understand that you
are learning and the, you,
you know, like as opposed to,
if it's just a black box or
whatever, you know, then you'd
have to hope your resume.
I suppose, speaks,
speaks enough, you know,
Nerando: I think speaking
to the whole teaching,
what, you know, like it came
full circle to me too, is.
I had to help teach one of
my sisters how to drive and
driving to me is one of them
unfunded pleasures that I have,
but explaining to her how, what
works is, was totally different.
Also I'm a fan of the
whole Dresden Files book.
And there's a part in there
that, um, main character,
Harry, is teaching a new
wizard, how to be a wizard.
And he goes, it's all fun
and games until you have to
teach somebody, something
new, because now you have to
justify why you would prefer
it to have a conversation,
then curse somebody or
something to that effect.
And I'm like, yep. That's all
Dan: I about that series.
I think I read the first
couple they were fun.
And then I about them.
Nerando: If you want, I'm not
going to throw any spoilers,
but Mouse is now terrifying.
I love Mouse.
Dan: well, after to swing
back, I think I have a,
Nerando: Um, I'm,
I'm personally waiting
for the next book.
I have all of them. Yeah.
Bekah: Okay.
So I think that you are always
super positive about things,
but I imagine that some point
you have been feeling lots
of challenges, too, right?
Like you made a lot of
transitions, a lot of changes,
you're looking for a job.
So how do you stay positive
through those challenges?
Or like what's your process
for working through that?
Nerando: I don't stay
positive some days I
have really bad days.
What I do have is that
over the years I have had.
Really good people who
literally will watch out to
see if something is wrong.
Like my friends know if I
get too quiet, they call.
So I build the network.
I have family support.
I have de-stressors.
I have days that I turn off.
It's hard.
Like job searching is hard
because after a while you feel
like I'm not good enough, I
have had those moments to go.
I quit.
I literally almost quit code
twice because I've put in so
much effort and time after
a while I'm like, okay.
But my, my, my support
system will go.
Go over there and cry.
You get 10 minutes.
That's allyou get. Now.
Let's get back to work.
And would you like
ice cream or coffee?
And I'm dead serious.
I have persons like those in my
life who stand up for me when
I can't stand up for myself.
I'm a part of a community
like Virtual Coffee.
Like I go, I went quiet two
weeks ago and from Virtual
Coffee, Meg went, where are you?
And Mike did the hype man
thing and like a couple of
my other friends call and my
friend, I have a friend now
who I'm helping to learn code
called G G has been my friends
since E in 17, so awhile.
And she'll reach out
and see if I'm okay.
And my other male, I have male
friends.I have female friends.
And so we reach out and see,
who's what you're, it's never
going to be easy all the time.
And you just have to keep going.
You have to find your why.
I think while we were
at bootcamp, two persons
point this out to me.
Our lecturer back then,
his name is Brett Butler.
I think he's at condor right now.
Um, he pointed out that why
you are doing this is way more
important than how, how fast
or how much you learn, because
when I failed, my mod one, he
goes, you just need more time.
I thought this is a
giant mistake and I don't
know how to do this.
He goes, you just need more time.
So sometimes you need more time.
Sometimes you're having
something else that's
hindering what's going on.
Sometimes you just need somebody
to like, yeah, you need a
hype-man or a hype-person or
a mantra or like affirmations.
I'm old school.
So I will go pray.
I will go walk.
I'm like, okay, how
do I do this now? Okay.
But support system.
And you literally finding
your why the other person who
literally highlights all of this
was I remember I was taking a
train with my batchmate, then
Keisha, Keisha would read a book
called, um, Grit by Angela...
I think her name is  or
something I can't remember.
And I listened to the
podcast for it, and it was
basically understanding
that all everything you've
ever wanted to do is doable.
You just have to break them down.
So, no, you don't have good days.
You don't have it. Great.
I'm not always super positive.
Sometimes I have bad days,
but I have, I've taken time
to build a support system.
That's it?
Bekah: I think that's
such great advice.
And I think that's the
thing that nobody kind of
teaches you in school, right?
They, these are the subjects
and this is how you learn them.
But having that support
system is so key to being
able to keep moving forward.
And I was having a rough
day the other day and
somebody in my Mom's in
Tech Slack group DMed me.
And just out of nowhere,
just to, you know,
provide an affirmation
about what I was doing.
I was like, you don't
even realize how much
I needed that today.
Um, But it's such an
undervalued thing and you do
it for so many people, too.
I mean, any conversation
I have with you is a good
conversation and I always feel
happy after I've seen you,
even if it's for like three
seconds and the big, the big
zoom room or whatever, but
it's always great to have you.
And I'm glad that you have
a support system that's
able to take care of you.
And that you're open to
talking about that with us.
Nerando: um, I don't know how
much time we got left, but two
things you just mentioned, um,
please don't ever get me started
on talking about how horrible
school equipped us all for our
surviving as adults, because
you teach me math and not taxes.
I'm upset or support
systems, like stuff like that
bothers me, but also like.
A lot of us keep not
understanding that sometimes
you just need to reach out
to people like, yeah, just
reach out because you don't
know how much you saved them.
Like you don't.
Dan: Yeah, somebody else just
said the same kind of thing.
I think it was Gant , was saying
just, if you like a tweet even
or something was meaningful.
Or a blog posters, you
know, it's just like, send
them a message, send it,
send a quick one sentence,
you know,  I really like
this thing that you wrote,
you know, or I don't know.
I think that's important to you.
I it's something I, I don't
know, I forget to do or,
or struggle with doing.
And, um, but it's right.
When it, when it comes out of
nowhere, it's it's I dunno.
It's, it's always nice
to hear good things from
people from your friends
Bekah: Nerando, this
has been really great.
We appreciate you sharing
with us and we look forward
to seeing you at Virtual
Coffee in the future.
So thanks so much for being here.
Dan: Thanks, Nerando.
Nerando: No problem guys.
Bekah: All right.
Well, I'll talk to you later.