Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season two, episode eight of the
virtual coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you. Here with me today, is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. We have a
fantastic episode today. We got
the chance to sit down with Sarah
McCombs. Sara is a software
engineer and a team lead at
Aiera. But more importantly to
us, at least, Sara is one of the
original organizers and current
Community Maintainer at a little
online community you may have
heard of called Virtual Coffee.
We talked about Sara's unique
career arc, how she was able to
leverage past experiences to
differentiate herself and how she
has found some success by
embracing her history and her own
unique skills and strengths.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. Today's
question is: If you could have a
theme song, what would it be? We
hope you enjoy this episode. Hey,
I'm Bekah. I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could have a theme
song, this is a little bit hard
because I, my music is based on
mood. And so I like to listen to
a lot of sad music. Um, but I
would probably want something
that gives me energy and. I guess
we'll go with, We Will Rock You
by Queen. Cause that sounds good.
Sara: that's a good one.
Bekah: Or Rocky soundtrack, you
know?
Dan: Um, hi, my name is Dan. I'm
a front end developer from
Lakewood, Ohio. Yeah. If I could
have a theme song. So is this
like an aspirational theme song
or a, um, accurate theme song?
Um, the first thing, the first
song that popped into my mind was
a song. By a band called The Head
and the Heart called Lost in my
Mind. Um, it's a pretty good song
and that's, that's what I'm going
to go with. It's probably
accurate. And you know, it's not
actually really sad or anything.
It's, it's pretty good. But
anyway, that's it.
Sara: Hi, I'm Sara. I'm a
software engineer from Boston,
Massachusetts. If I had a theme
song, um, I would have to pick
something that I a always sing to
because that's what a theme song
should be, um, be sing horribly
too, because you're just, you
don't care. Um, and I kinda, I
don't know, I feel weird
admitting this it's a Post Malone
song. Um, is it sunflower? Um,
that just makes me so happy and I
don't care what I'm doing, what
I'm in the middle of. I will stop
and turn that up. And that just
feels like that that should be my
theme song.
Bekah: I love it.
Dan: Yeah, that's
Bekah: I love sunflowers. I, when
I was a community organizer, I
used to drive to this small
community in rural Pennsylvania,
and there was this huge field of
sunflowers and it was like, it
was fun to watch it through the
stages because it grows up and
then they're all happy. And then
like when sunflower flowers die,
they get really sad. It's a full
moon.
Sara: they look depressed.
They're like depressed flowers,
they're flowers with anxiety or
something. I don't know. I love
it.
Bekah: I enjoy it. I think I
wrote a poem about it once. Um,
thanks so much for being here
with us today, Sara, we are very
happy to have you on the podcast.
Um, and we'll just, we'll just
kick it off. Uh, we like to start
with the origin story and you've
got a very interesting one. So we
love to hear how you got from
where you were into software
engineering.
Sara: Absolutely. Um, yeah, I do
have an interesting story. Um, I
never know where to begin. Uh,
really, uh, so this may be all
over the place, but that's kind
of the point of a podcast, right?
You just, you just talk and you
end up wherever you end up. Um,
so. I did actually intend to go
into computer science many, many,
many years ago. I had a love of
computers since I was very
little. I have memories of my
mom's saving money to buy a Tandy
computer. I wish I could remember
the model, but I don't. That's
like, I always want to pick the
1000, but I don't think that was
it. Um, but sitting next to her
while she was learning DOS and
I'm learning letters from a book
that is like three inches thick.
And I would just read the
commands off to her and it was
great because it was like, ah,
changing directory. Okay. There's
a C there's a D you know, um, so
she learned that I learned that
way. Fast forward many, many,
many years graduated high school
with a full scholarship for
computer science to WVU Was not
exactly welcomed there,
unfortunately, uh, I have, uh,
lots of things to be said about
that, but it discouraged me
greatly. And I left, I, uh,
rescinded my, or gave up my full
scholarship and decided to pursue
other interests of mine, which
were agriculture. Obviously my
interest in tech being what they
were. I ended up working in a
nice niche of ag and technology.
Um, I worked, Oh my gosh. I, I
loved what I did. Um, working
with ag tech tools to identify,
feed efficiency in livestock. I
could have a whole podcast
episode on that. But that really,
really showed me, like I was not
done with this. I was not over
it. I ended up actually had to
learn rails. Working as a
research director, because the
communications team wouldn't
spend time to build the
templates, to display my data
properly. And it was just like, I
can do this. It's fine. Um, and
that was really when I realized I
wanted to do that. Um, instead
try to get back into it. Did some
freelance stuff. Um, really
didn't gain traction living in
West Virginia, it was just really
hard. Uh, the local market
industry is, um, I guess pretty
small, pretty close remote,
really. Wasn't a thing, um, that
I had my daughter and, you know,
there's that moment when you have
a baby and you're holding them
and you're looking down and
you're just like, What do I want
to teach them? You know, I want
to teach them not to have any
regrets. And then you start
thinking about, you know, regrets
that you have. And it was like, I
have unfinished business, you
know, I have unfinished business
in the tech industry. Um, so I
decided to fix that. And I went
into Flatiron, I did the Flatiron
online program for software
engineering. Um, graduated with
that met great people in the
Virtual Coffee community and.
Ended up with the job where I am
now, um, through some great
networking and, and I could not
be here.
Bekah: So awesome. Um, so for
those of you who are joining us
and haven't been around for an
entire year, uh, Sara is one of
our original organizers of
Virtual Coffee and she and I met
in person almost two years ago at
a conference in Pittsburgh. Um,
and I'm Flatiron in grad, too. We
had like the little Flatiron
group going on and, um, Sara is
much taller than I am.
Dan: it's funny. You guys look
the same height here on my
screen.
Sara: well on zoom, nobody has
legs. So
Dan: We're all just the same
height, right?
Bekah: Yeah. So it's been really
great to, you know, pair with
Sara and both of us, like kind of
growing at similar times, right?
Like I was learning and you were
learning. And at some point I
think I was a little bit ahead of
you, but it just was really nice
to, you know, have that
relationship with someone who was
going through these things and
understood all of the challenges
that we were facing. And to have
someone like jump in and say
like, Hey, let's do this, you
know,
Sara: Yeah. Yeah. And it was, it
was really your learning in
public, um, on Twitter. I mean,
that was, that was how you and I
connected, even with as close as
we were geographically. Like
there was nothing that forced us
to meet other than you posting on
Twitter learning and public being
vulnerable saying, Hey, I'm
learning to try and make a
tutorial on how to create an SVG
in Figma. I'm just like, I don't
know anything about Figma. I'm
the perfect subject matter expert
on if this tutorial is great or
not. Um, and I watched it and
gave you feedback and then you're
like, Hey, we should talk your,
your, your semi-local to me, uh,
found out we're both going to
this conference. So we, we made
it, we made a point to grab
coffee of all things,
Bekah: And that is where it
started.
Sara: and that's where it
Bekah: Yeah. So you're, I, I feel
like you just have so much
history that you're right. We
could have spent like four hours
on just like how you got here.
And Sara is the, um, the head of
random agricultural facts at
Sara: I think, yeah, I think it's
called Cow Facts. Uh, they all
have a tendency to be cows, but
it's really livestock related
facts. Yeah. That's me.
Bekah: And so you've, you like
made this really big transition,
right? And like, I love how
you've bridged your past
experience with your experience
now, like even like in
conversations, but what you're
doing. And I know that talking
about transferable skills is
really hard and that's something
that, like, we hear a lot about
that. So, you know, like how have
you been able to leverage that
experience to support where you
are now? Or like, what does that
process look like?
Sara: um, Transferable skills is
a soap box that I willingly jump
on. I think every opportunity I
get, um, if you've ever been in
and been in a breakout room with
me at Virtual Coffee, you will
know I go there. Um, it, it was
kind of a multifaceted process. I
mean, I don't think there was
ever like an intentional, like, I
must do this process to see these
things, but. We all have imposter
syndrome. Like you hear it. W I'm
glad that people talk about it.
I'm glad that it's a public
thing. I mean, let's talk about
imposter syndrome as much as we
talk about mental health, you
know, because for me, they're,
they're one in the same believing
that you can do something and
recognizing that you are already
skilled for something before you
begin is a huge weight lifted off
of anyone's shoulders. Um, but
it's also sometimes hard for us
to recognize that. There are
skillsets that we have from other
industries, other jobs, other
aspects of life, um, that
empowers to do our job, you know,
in the, in the tech industry.
Well, um, the biggest one that,
you know, I always think about
is, uh, one that I can relate to
is, is becoming a mom. I mean,
there's no like. Aspiring moms,
like, you know, I used to say I
was aspiring, you know, software
engineers, just like, well, what
is an aspiring software engineer?
Like what, when does an aspiring
software engineer stop being an
aspiring software engineer? Like
what, what's that threshold?
What's the success metric for it?
And I realized, you know, with
being a mom, it was like, I had a
baby. So now I'm a mom and I'm
going to do mom things. I have no
idea about how to be a mom. I'm a
first time mom, but I'm going to
reach out to other individuals
who are more experienced to me.
So my senior developers, I'm
going to read any documentation.
I can find AKA every book that is
free from the library on what to
do when your baby does X or what
to expect when you're expecting
that's documentation for
motherhood. There's going to be
support groups. You know, there's
gonna be a local mom's group.
That's going to help you navigate
things that you've never dealt
with before, or, um, processes
that you don't know how to deal
with. Like, I'm still running
into things, you know, with my
daughter in preschool, it's like
this week's teacher appreciation
week. I don't know how we do
this. Like, how do you, this is
my first time, but I'm doing it
and I'm doing it because I
recognize that I can find the
answers myself or find somebody
who can help me find the answers.
I know I can ask the questions. I
know I can. Research enough on
the internet to try to find some
semblance of an answer and then
take that research to someone
more experienced than myself. My
mom, you know, anyone else with
parents that have more than one
child and you know, than I do,
um, and say, Hey, am I close? Is
this right? Um, to ask those
vulnerable questions of just
like. I don't know how to change
a baby. How do you change a baby?
Nobody. There's no YouTube video
on how to change a diaper. So you
reach out and the nurse at the
hospital will show you because
she did. She looked at me a
little, a little strangely and
laughed, and I'm just like, I
don't know how to do this, but I
was never an aspiring mom. I was
just a mom. You know, nobody made
me less than because I was
completely inexperienced, but I
had the drive and the desire and.
I guess, I don't know the
pluckiness to just figure it out
because honestly, I feel like
that's what software engineering
is. It's just figuring out one
thing after another, you know,
things change things evolve so
quickly. Same with children, you
know, how things work, how school
systems work. Um, especially now
since we're virtual, like we were
all learning how to be parents of
virtual school children, now.
It's just recognizing that. We're
not dictionaries. We don't just
sit here and, and, you know,
vomit out code for something that
we've remembered in our head.
We're recognizing patterns. We're
recognizing when we don't know
something to ask somebody else.
It's just, you figure it out. You
know, you engineer it, you find
the solution. And it's hard to
recognize, especially for a
career changer like myself. That
you already have skill sets and
you already have abilities that
you have harnessed for years
because you've been a parent for
X years, or you've been a manager
in another industry for X years,
or you've been in customer
service for other years or you've
been a customer in other years.
Like it's sometimes it's just
having your eyes open to like,
Oh, I am, you know, empowered to
do this. I do have skillsets.
It's just a different. Industry.
It's just a different problem,
but the solution steps are
potentially still the same. And I
like, I like to have
conversations about that because
when I had that realization that
I was not an aspiring engineer, I
was just an engineer because I
was doing the thing and it was
dedicated to learning. And I was
dedicating to doing it to the
best of my ability and dedicated
to taking feedback for when I
could've been doing it better. I
was just an engineer. And I want
everyone else to kind of have
that, that comfort, that
satisfaction. So, yes, that's a
soap box. I will willingly jump
on.
Bekah: I think it's great. And
you've done such a good job
supporting the members and
telling them exactly these things
that they need to hear. And I
think last night I think it was
last night. Somebody had been
listening to the podcast from
Virtual Coffee and they
referenced a previous episode and
said, Bekah, you said you never
had any manager experience, but
you're a mom of four kids. Like,
what do you think you're doing?
Yeah. It was hard to think about
it in those different ways, but
it is, you're always learning.
You're always pivoting and making
new decisions. And, you know, a
lot of people will say like,
well, you have four kids, you
know, I don't know how you do it.
And it's the same way that you do
it in a job. Like if you have to
do it, you will do it. You know?
Sara: you just do the thing.
Because you have to do the thing
and that's no different than
whenever at work. If I get, you
know, um, assigned, you know,
particular features that I have
to implement, there's a lot of, a
lot of the product that I don't
even understand the finer
details, the finer inner workings
of how it works and that's okay
because I figured it out. I know
who to ask these questions of and
you break apart the problem into
achievable steps and you just do
it, you just do the thing. And
then when you're done, you sit
there and you look at it, you're
like, yeah. You know, pat
yourself on the back, you, you
achieved something. Awesome. And
then you're going to get another
task. And that process is going
to start over and you're going to
panic and you're going to be
like, I don't know how to do
this. Oh my gosh. Where do I
start? Just like the previous
problem. You start again.
Dan: yeah. I love that. And like
the idea of leaning back on those
experiences like diaper changing,
right. Is I had never changed a
diaper before my first kid was
born. Um, I don't think, uh, and
definitely didn't know how to do
it. Right. And definitely asked
the I'm like, what is the right
way to do, like do this? I'd read
books, I'd read, read the docs,
whatever, little different when
you're there, but it, and it
seemed. Hard and stressful, I
suppose, thinking about it ahead
of time. I mean, I know it did
right. And now I've changed like
7 billion, billion trillion
diapers, and it's like not a big
deal. Right. And, you know, so
it, so the idea of like leaning
back on previous experiences from
different fields and transferring
skills, even if they're not like
I don't have to change any
diapers here at the office. But,
but I have just like you were
saying, I've been through that
experience of like a thing seems
scary and unknown. And I was
like, and then I learned how to
do it. And then I did it a bunch
of times and now I'm like good at
it. And that's something it's
it's I love how you said that.
It's, it's like very important
and cool to be able to like, I
don't know when you're feeling
like that. Just to think back on
other things that you have, you
have done, you know, cause
everybody's any, even if you, I
mean, not even if, but if you
don't have kids, you're still
like a person who has moved
through life. So, uh, th there's,
there's lots of things to lean on
in that way,
Bekah: Yeah, I'm just kind of
like going down this path of, I,
you know, I wonder why it seems
like such a struggle for so many
people, um, to be moving into
careers as software engineers.
And I don't know if. It's, we
don't learn a ton of new stuff as
adults in the same way that we do
as when we're kids, right? Like
you're constantly learning
something new and everything
feels like a risk, but in adult
life, there are, I feel like
almost fewer of those risks,
because you've kind of like built
that up to this point. And I
don't know if that's what makes
it seem scary to move forward,
but it is like, you know,
essentially that idea of, you
know, Being afraid, or I don't
know if it's being afraid of
failure. It's probably different
for everyone. I guess it's being
afraid of failure for me. So
Sara: I would say it's probably
different for everyone. I mean, I
think that's a very valid
comparison as well too. And one
that I hadn't even thought of
yet, but as children, every new
day, every new life moment is
something new. We potentially
have never encountered it before.
Or, you know, we've played on a
playground before we fell off the
slide, you know? And now we're
just like, Oh, slides are scary.
Yeah. But then we go to a new
park and it's like, Oh, there's
another slide, but maybe that
slide's not scary. And that's
like a natural as children. We
don't think about that is, you
know, learning and leaning on
previous experiences to like
navigate current experiences. Um,
but we're trained to do that as
children and as we get to
adulthood, we may not do that as
much anymore. And is that because
we may stay in careers longer. I
don't, I don't know is that
because things are rapidly
changing in this industry that
it's like, I blink and there's
new framework and there's, here's
a new tool that I need to learn.
Um, or you have individuals like,
you know, us we're we're career
changers, you know, we're, we're
going from one industry to
another, and now we're navigating
a completely different set of
construct rules, everything. Um,
yeah,
Bekah: I feel like I love that
the whole, uh, the playground
just makes a lot of sense to me,
I think because you know, part of
that playground, I think if you
fall off that slide and you're
the only kid on the playground,
it's much harder to get back up
on that side. Right. But like you
see all these other kids and
they're doing it and that just
kind of gives you a little bit of
confidence. And for a lot of us
and a lot of people that we talk
to they're navigating the
transition into tech Oh alone,
whether they're self-taught or in
an online bootcamp. And there's,
you know, a lack of value placed
on community. But when you see
other people around you doing it,
like it does something, it gives
you the energy sometimes that you
need in those moments where you
feel like, wow, I, you know, like
fell off the slide and I need to
get back on.
Sara: it's also important when
you have community, because I
have never. I've never succeeded
at a hard thing alone. Um, I've
always needed community in some
aspect, whether that was like a
micro circle of friends that I
leaned upon that just, I w I was
vulnerable to, or like Virtual
Coffee, a much larger community.
Um, using the playground as an
analogy, you know, as an example,
when you fall off that side, you
sometimes also need a person that
says, Hey, I'm scared to do the
slide again. Can you help me? And
you need to have a great
community and empathetic
understanding compassionate
community that doesn't laugh at
you because you're saying the
side is easy and the person
you're telling that to, it's just
like, Oh, this slide's not a big
deal. It's just, you know, it's
only two feet long. It's like,
no, we don't need that. You know,
we need someone that grabs your
hand says, Hey let's do it
together. And that's, that's
something that I've needed to
reach where I am and something I
will always need and will always
provide to other people.
Bekah: Yeah. And, you know, I
think that, you know, capturing
that idea of self doubt, being
such a big obstacle for career
changers and for new developers
and, you know, people who have
been in the industry for a long
time, but maybe are going up for
promotion or didn't get that
promotion. That's really hard to
navigate when, when you're by
yourself, you know,
Sara: Yes. Uh, even if you wanted
to potentially go ask somebody,
is this right? Can I get advice?
Can, can I have some mentorship
or can you just hold my hand when
I go get on this new slide? Um,
Nobody needs to do anything alone
and nobody needs to feel that
sense of isolation. we're all
learning. We're all doing this
together.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think too, you
know, this idea of like
leveraging your past, all this
stuff that you were saying about
that, that clicks for me here in
a lot of ways too, because I know
that sometimes when I'm afraid to
try something new, then I it's
important for me to lean on the
things that I know really well.
And it's leveraging that
experience or, you know, I, I
spent a while thinking like, I
taught English for 10 years and I
was a community organizer for a
little while. Like I want to run
from that. I don't want to do
that anymore. This is why I'm
making this transition. And
within the last, I don't know,
even a couple of months, I felt
like, you know what, leaning on
those things and, and remembering
what I've learned from that can
really benefit me from this, from
it in this moment. So it's not
like a rejection of that past.
It's like, let's embrace these
two things together.
Sara: Yeah. Yeah. And for me
personally, in those moments,
it's when I reflected on it after
the fact, it's helped me to
understand how far I've come as
well of just like, Oh, okay. Even
though this the situation, you
know, I, you know, in my job,
current job was, was new for me,
that thing in the past, you know,
my, my previous career helped me.
Like I've grown. Like it's a,
it's a metric to really say,
like, I I've, I've grown up, I'm
achieving things. Like I
recognized how much personal
growth I've had that I hadn't
really been aware of until I hit
a moment when I would have paused
a little bit more, I would have
had a little bit more self doubt
and, everything in my past is
helped me get to where I am now
and recognizing that I can use it
is very comforting.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. And I
think, you know, sometimes it
takes a minute to get to that. I
think in a lot of circumstances
and that's hard. I don't know how
to teach that. Like, is there a
way to teach that? I think that
maybe you just have to discover
that for yourself, but I wish
that I could help more people
discover that
Sara: That's why there's
community it's to have people
around you that are your personal
cheerleaders that care, that will
remind you why you're awesome.
And remind you that you can do
the thing because you've done X
other hard thing. It's I think
community. It's there's no,
nothing really to teach. It's a
feeling it's a sense of
belonging. It's a sense of being
supported. It's a sense of, um,
being a powered as who you are
not because you need to learn X
or you need to learn Y. Like we
all need to learn X and we all
need to learn Y. We just have
different experiences that we can
leverage to find a solution. So
leverage them because. If you
learn X and you learn Y and
you're just like everybody else,
you're going to achieve the same
answer, potentially just as
everybody else, it takes diverse
backgrounds. It takes leaning
upon diverse previous experiences
and those transferable skills to
find new solutions to things, new
processes, you know, new features
for a product that potentially an
existing team had not thought of
before. It's these transferable
skills that bring diversity to a
team, you know, in regards to how
an individual approaches a
problem and finds the solution.
Bekah: Yeah. And so I feel like
there's a twofold problem here or
not a problem, but situation. I
don't know. So it's. In your own
mind thinking like I can leverage
this and then like the second
part of that is now, how do I
leverage that and get other
people to see
Sara: Yes. Right,
Bekah: I don't know. Do you have
any tips there that would
Sara: Uh be your authentic self.
Um, it has always worked for me.
I, I find embracing my past and
sharing what I've learned, hence
the random cow facts, uh,
happened Virtual Coffee. Um, As a
safe way to show everyone else in
the community, and those that I
interact with that, like my past
is still relevant. It's still
part of who I am. Um, and
embracing that and having
conversations around that
demonstrate some of these skills
to individuals. That's what sets
you apart from everybody else
right now? And that's you, that's
not something you can learn.
That's not, not a certificate
that you can achieve and then put
on a resume. It's it's, you know,
the fact that, you know, for an
ag tech company, I'm an
extremely, you know, good looking
candidate because I have.
Agricultural background. I have
knowledge that I can lean upon,
you know, and I have skillsets to
potentially better understand how
a farmer might use a particular
product, because, well, I worked
with that farmer and I, you know,
I supported that farmer and, um,
it's those points that we need to
not hide and showcase. Um, I, I'm
struggling to remember a quote
that I saw on Twitter this
morning, but it was spot on, but
it was talking about leaning into
what makes you unique because if
you don't lean into it, somebody
else will. And that person will
be who gets set apart from
others. and I, I find that to
always be very true a for the
fact that it highlights my
transferable skills, it
highlights these additional
knowledge sets that could be very
beneficial to an employer, but it
also. Reminds me of who I am. And
why I'm, you know, I don't want
to say off, cause that sounds so
unhumble, but like, you know why
I am awesome. It's like, and it
makes me feel comfortable to be
myself more in communities that
it, it helps me to overcome the
negative feedback that I've heard
in the past of like, well, How
can you be a software engineer?
If you have a degree in dirt,
which is literally been what I've
been told, um, what can we now,
um, you can, you know?
Bekah: Do you go back and like
find those people and just send
them your resume. Is that, is
that what we're supposed to do?
Sara: isn't that what LinkedIn's
for mean? I don't know. Um, no, I
haven't, trust me the want's
there, um, But I did get to turn
down a job offer to an employer,
but I didn't quite, I wasn't
rude. Um, I, as much as I wanted
to say it just like, yeah, you
undervalued me and you gave me
stress for the fact that I didn't
have a CS degree. And, um, I'm so
sorry that I only have a
bachelor's and a master's degree
in another, you know, uh,
technical field. Apparently not
enough and not relevant for my
ability to somehow tell you that
I can learn a lot. But yeah, I
just said, no, I would like to
Dan: Seems like a good call,
maybe.
Sara: Tik Toks for that, you
know, where you just flex, like
overcoming those things,
Dan: I was thinking more like,
um, like mailing them a box of
dirt or something, you know?
Bekah: Okay.
Sara: wouldn't be dirt. It
wouldn't be
Dan: Well, sure. Right. Yeah. Cow
products.
Bekah: Bye. Oh, can we just get a
shade button on LinkedIn? Like I
would,
Sara: I know, right?
Bekah: that feature. Okay.
Dan: Yeah. Flex, flex button.
that. Okay.
Bekah: yeah, and I think, you
know, this idea of transferable
skills and really showing what
makes you unique and awesome. It
really. A good way to figure out
how to, I think, leverage that
maybe is really through
networking, right? Because you
can walk into a room full of
people. And if everybody is
talking about the same thing, Oh,
I made this to do app or
whatever, like that's great, but
who are they gonna remember?
They're gonna remember the cow
lady, right? Like.
Sara: Yeah. Yeah, I would, I
would agree with that. And, um,
that, that kind of is a little
bit of how I got my job now. I
reached out to Bryan Healey in
our Virtual Coffee community, um,
trying to get into the ag tech,
uh, side of things. Um, see if he
had any connections. Um, he
didn't really, um, but. You know,
it, it eventually turned into,
okay. Let's, let's talk about the
jobs that you're applying to.
Let's, let's, let's look at your
resume a little bit. Let's, let's
talk about these things. And the
conversation started to unfolding
more and more and more, as I
talked about what I've done and
things I built, um, both
personally professionally
processes I've, you know, made
and improved and it turned into
like, wow, okay. You, you might,
you know, not have two to five
years, you know, software
engineering experience, like
most, most jobs required. But I,
I recognize that you're a person
that I literally can throw into
the deep end and you're going to
swim. And I've done that. And I'm
happy as a clam that I get to
wear five hats at work. And I,
um, to have this, uh, what, what
was the phrase like to use the
fire hose of information to my
face constantly of just like what
is going on at work? What needs
to change? What needs to happen?
Things are moving so fast, but
I'm absorbing it all and I'm
loving it. And, um, it was that
networking that genuinely showing
up as my authentic self, talking
about my past, um, that really
helped me to showcase. I mean,
I'm not going to say that like
doing that, it's just going to,
you know, get you job offers to
everybody that you do that too,
but people will talk and you'll
get known as the cow lady. In
communities and they'll be like,
Hey, you know, I think she could
probably handle whatever you're
going to throw at her. So like
maybe go talk to her. and that's
what happens, you know?
Bekah: Yeah. When, like, since
you've been there, it's just
been, I feel like you've been
sprinting the entire time. Right.
Because I would love to like dive
a little bit into that timeline
because it was like, Oh, we're
going to hire Sara. Oh, she's
awesome. We're going to hire her
more. Oh, she's awesome. We're
gonna.
Sara: Yeah,
Bekah: not yet, but that's like,
you know,
Sara: I threatened that. Um,
Bekah: but like walk through that
because that process is intense.
Right? You have accomplished so
much in a very short amount of
time there.
Sara: Yes. So I was originally
hired as a contractor, um, and
that was supposed to be for,
cause obviously hiring during
COVID it was, you know, strange
times and, um, there was a need,
but with the way things were
going, hiring was frozen in a lot
of places. And I was, I was happy
to just have an opportunity. I
was happy to like basically say,
Hey, you know? Yep. I'll prove
myself. You know, I'll work as a,
as a part-time contractor. That's
great. You know, that'll a, it
ultimately helps me, um, Add
something to my resume, get some
experience, uh, learn how to work
with a large, large team of much
more senior engineers. But it
also gave me a chance to prove
myself to the company. And if it
didn't end up transitioning into
a full-time job, which was the
ultimate goal, great, no harm, no
foul, you know, I still come out
of it with experience. Um, I
think that lasted a month. Um,
things went so well. Uh, there
was a need, they recognized that
I could fill the need. Um, there
was a conversation of like, okay,
we're immediately going to be
doubling your work hours. You
will responsible for X, Y, Z, and
one, two, three. And that was
fine. It was a little
intimidating, but what's the
worst thing I could do. Like get
some experience and like learn
how not to do a thing. Um, you
know, that was, that was how I
approached it. And. I ended up
transitioning to a full-time
employee and yeah. Um, startup
life is, is rapidly evolving.
Every day is chaos. I love it.
Some days are more chaos than
others. But I got comfortable
with my team really fast. Like I,
for a while, quite a while was
the most junior individual there.
Everybody knew each other.
Everybody had worked together for
years. But I just decided to just
have a one-on-one with everyone.
Talk to them, recognize they're
human recognize of who I could go
to, for what reason, for
questions. I specifically made
that a point in my one-on-ones
with everyone to say, if I have a
problem, what can you help me
with? Um, and I just started, I
just started doing things and I
just slightly leaned into I
guess, a phrase that I was taught
when I worked for the university
of was it's better to ask
forgiveness than permission. So I
would just start writing
documentation of just like, well,
this is lacking, this is missing,
you know, write this down because
I'm doing it. And it was the
perfect time. Um, and then I
started recognizing that, Oh, Oh,
this is somewhere that I can
really contribute because
documentation's kind of out of
date because everyone here has
already got their environment set
up. And like, you know, this is a
place that I can contribute. Um,
And then I started as I'm
learning and going through other
parts of our product and our
process, seeing things that just
need tweaked. And it started just
being a lot of tweaking and then
a lot of tweaking turned into,
okay, well, we're going to, we're
going to give you this part of
the product now. And you're gonna
own this and you're gonna learn
it and you're gonna be
responsible for it. And. Again,
process improvement, tweaking,
seeing what I could do or asking
questions, um, asking for
examples in, in the existing code
base, whenever I would need to do
a feature that I was just like, I
don't know. I don't know how you
want me to do this. Like never
done this before, but I'll figure
it out. Um, yeah. And now I'm in
charge of a team of people and
hiring, unfortunately, firing.
Um, that's not fun part by the
way. Doing a lot of
documentation, a lot of process
improvement. Yeah, I love it. And
it's, it's been nonstop and it's
really started with kind of
leaning back on my agricultural
experience of like, when you show
up on a farm, the cows are not
going to tell you what's wrong.
You just stand there, look at it,
make a lot of observations, do a
little bit research, you know?
And then just start trying stuff,
see what works. Um, you might
have to MacGyver it. You might
have to get the baling twine out.
You might have to get the duct
tape out. You might have to like,
make it look ugly. So it works.
That's fine. You just might need
to fix the fence for five
minutes. Like, so the cows stay
in tomorrow. You're going to
refactor your code base and it
will be pretty efficient and
performance. And that's kind of
how I started. And. That's worked
very well for me. Um, I will say
there's no cows in our code base.
Um, but the process still works.
You know, I can do a thing that
achieves the feature and then
thankfully with the help of my
more senior team, over time,
I've, I've gotten better at
developing the proper style for
how I do things. So my naming, my
variables, uh, separating things
properly apart with how we're
currently doing it for code base,
all of these things. And it's
because I just dove in, because I
recognize that I've done this
before with farm animals when
they can't tell you what hurts,
Dan: a little bit of structured
YOLO
Sara: I've Structured YOLO. Oh my
gosh. Yes. I yes, it is always
structured YOLO.
Dan: Um, so Yeah, so I mean, that
was a lot, I mean,
Sara: Yeah.
Dan: you know, no, that was,
that's not what I meant, but I
just mean, like Bekah said, you
have accomplished so much, you
know, in, in what is it? Less
than a year? Something I,
Sara: yeah. Like seven months.
Dan: So one of the jumps in there
that you
Bekah: I just want to highlight
that Sara said seven months. So
all of that stuff that she said
she's done has been in the past
seven months.
Sara: I like
Bekah: deserved a moment.
Dan: That's what I meant by. That
was a lot. And, and, Yeah. so, I
mean, one of the, you kind of
like jumped over a little bit.
Um, but the going from like just
solely individual contributor
role to managing a team, um, for
me, it seems like a pretty big
step, And so I kinda remember you
talking about it when it happened
a little bit, but I was wondering
if you could talk a little bit
about like, what, what that was
like, how your job changed, how
you approached it, you know, that
kind of thing.
Sara: Yeah, absolutely. Um, it
was terrifying, um, because now I
recognize that, I'm responsible
for, uh, people, their
livelihood, you know, their jobs.
Um, and I think helping to hire
someone for our support team was
really how my company recognized
that, Oh, she can do this. Um,
cause I was the one that led the
interview. Um, I led all the
interviews for that particular
hire
Dan: So that was a hire. I'm
sorry to interrupt, but that was
a real, that was for a role that
was not your ma like that you
wouldn't be like, this is just a
separate role that,
Sara: yes, It was a separate
support role for our product and
they let me do the interview, um,
because I was learning this part
of the process product I was
going to be, um, being primarily
the person that they reported to,
even though I wasn't at that
point in time, uh, I guess I
don't see it designate their
supervisor or their manager. Um,
but I was just like the first
point of contact. So at that time
I probably would have been, you
know, a lead of some sort, I
guess, if you had to put a,
really a term on it, but, um,
just the person that they went to
before I went to the next level.
Um, but yeah, it, I did an
interview. It, it went very well.
Um, I started, you know, touching
base with all of them. And it was
terrifying because now I have
seven people that look at me of
like, Hey, I need help with X or,
um, my time sheets messed up or,
um, any, any other access issue.
Um, but I. I just kind of
approached it like I would
anybody else in the community
that I'm in of just like, Hey, I
have a problem. Um, but I, I also
kind of took note of who they
were, you know, I networked with
them a little bit. I, I wanted to
know what their interests were,
um, what their overarching goals
were, uh, with, with the job
here, with their career, so that
I can understand is there, are
there opportunities internal that
I can. See them grow into and
that's happened quite a few. She
got quite a few times with our
agents. Um, can I help them grow
internally with their career? And
that's, that's terrifying. Um,
but it feels great because, um,
again, I structured YOLO. I just
did it and I, I remembered what
it was like to be an employee
somewhere of what I would like a
manager to do. And I recognize
that, you know, I might be
restricted in certain situations.
I can't make everybody have a
thousand dollars an hour, you
know, wage, even if I would like
them to. Um, but I can advocate
on their behalf to make sure that
they're, they're not, you know,
making less than they should. Uh,
I will always do that. Um, but it
was. I don't know, it was
terrifying at first. Um, but
I've, I've grown into it and
I've, I'm enjoying it and I'm
enjoying seeing them grow. And
I'm enjoying seeing them slide
into, you know, different roles
that they're, they're excelling
in and I'm enjoying that
relationship, um, that I have
with all of them. I feel like
I'm, I'm, I'm meandering now on
the, on the topic. So
Dan: No, no, no. This is exactly
what I
Sara: wrangle me back on topic.
Dan: no, no, this is, this is
exactly what I want to talk
about. I like the. This
transition from individual
contributor to manager is always
a interesting thing, you know?
Um, and, and so every, every time
we have somebody that has gone
through that, I, I ended up just
trying to dig in a little bit
because I liked to learn about
it. You know, I like hearing
about it. And, um, it's one of
those interesting things in our
industry where it's like, Lots of
times, it seems like there's just
a ceiling, you know, um, on how
far you can go as an individual
contributor and then like the
only choices management after
that, you know, um, which I w I
would say is not always true,
but, um, but I do like, right.
And, well, absolutely. And, um,
but I like hearing about like,
and sharing what that transition
is like, like what the difference
is,
Sara: yeah.
Dan: between, you know, between
the two, the two roles, um,
Sara: I definitely reached out a
lot. Um, either the individuals,
um, within the company of just
like, how do I navigate X
situation? You know? How often
should I have one-on-ones, how
often should I do this process
with my team? Um, which was
incredibly helpful, but I also.
Looked to other individuals,
especially in that Virtual Coffee
community, um, who are managers
who onboard people, who, who, uh,
support new hires to just say
what is going well for you? Um,
and seeing if I can take that and
implement it internally, um, just
to be the best that I can at my
role, but also to support my
employees the best that we can.
Um, so being willing to. Take
advice from everywhere was, was
definitely helpful.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. Do you
find yourself writing like a lot
less code, like doing a lot less,
you know, IC kind of work.
Sara: Oh yes. Um, just by the
very nature, I'm now busy with
process improvement process, you
know, well creating there's some
processes that don't exist, um,
that we are creating now. Um, but
I actually. I focus more on
internal tooling, um, and just
ensuring that our tooling is
built, uh, and in a fashion that
can support our current processes
as well as any upcoming
processes, which is nice. Um, I
occasionally still implement
features within our product that
enable our current processes or
new processes to happen properly.
Um, so like I have minor changes
in our, in our existing code
bases now, but. Yeah, I do do
less coding and that's okay.
Because I recognize that my
strengths are potentially a
little bit more of, um, process
design, overseeing things,
product roadmaps, um, while still
being a technical individual. So
that's, that's where I see my
career going and I, I'm not sure.
Seven months ago, even a year
ago. That I would have said that
that's where I wanted it to be.
Um, I would have been like, no, I
want to code all day long. Just
put me in a corner. Let me to
closet. Let me code the thing,
leave me alone. Give me coffee.
Um, yeah. So yay for growth all
around.
Dan: that's awesome.
Bekah: I mean, they're so
important because I think there
are so they're undervalued and
having someone who's new to the
process, who's new to a company.
I think that you can really see
those pain points like you were
talking about of like, okay,
well, you don't have this or this
is outdated. And then that allows
you to, you know, See things
differently than people who have
been doing it for a long time and
to create those things and
understand the needs of other
people. And I feel like how
fortunate people are, if they are
being managed by you, because you
have a real sense of like what
people need and a really great
pro approach to supporting those
people. And that's also something
that we just don't see nearly
enough of, um, from the
community, from the tech
industry. And I really feel like
in general, Um, what you were
talking about preschool earlier.
And I was thinking, you know,
schools just don't do a good job
of onboarding new families.
Sara: no, they don't
Bekah: It never occurred to me
until
Sara: be a product for that.
Bekah: exactly. Um, but like
parents will reach out to me and
be like, they're talking about
this thing. And I have no idea
what this thing means, but nobody
has explained it to me. Right.
And it is that. Understanding and
taking note of and grabbing that
feedback and like being willing
to ask questions that, you know,
you might be afraid to ask, but
that creates those processes that
allow for a really, um, great and
successful work environment.
Sara: Yeah, I think something
that's always really served me
well, and it's something I always
try to keep in mind is
recognizing that. All processes
have a human element to them. So
there's human processes in this.
And when you think about, you
know, designing, uh, you know,
even a job description or
designing processes for current
employees, like you have to take
into account that there's a human
doing this, and you need to
support the human side through
this because you can write
amazing documentation, but it's
written from a place of
understanding. And then we bring
somebody new through the
documentation. They're going to
have a lot of questions and you
need to make sure that you
address the fact that they're
going to feel confused, that
they're going to need to have
questions. You need to identify,
you know, who to go to for
questions and, and recognizing
that there's a human element to
this and supporting the human
element. Um, I think really
creates a great cohesiveness and
teams to a have good
communication because we
recognize that. We're all humans.
Um, and that we have human
feelings about things when they
change. Um, but it just creates
more compassion and empathy in
regards to like, if someone has a
bad day of like, you know, Hey, I
recognize I've changed this
process on you. I recognize it's
new. You, you were doing it. You
know, the old way, potentially as
an example, like there's nothing
to be upset about. Like. That's
fine. We're human. Like I have
bad days. I forget what the new
process is. I, I forget things.
Always having that human centered
approach to everything you do,
whether it's product development,
whether it's engineering, whether
it's process development, whether
it's management, having the human
centered approach is so
important. And. Can easily be
forgotten because we just get our
heads. So in the weeds and we get
blinders on and we're just like
just process oriented and I just
need to do the thing. And we're
not robots. There's a human
element to it. We always have to
respect that.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I love
that. The what a great way to end
this podcast, the human centered
approach and why that's so
important. Um, I want to thank
you so much for being here with
us. This is really great. I know
I was like taking notes as we
were going through the podcast
and, um, so. Uh, it's been really
great to hear you talk about all
of these things and see how far
you've come and just like really
be an inspiration for, I know so
many people in the community, but
anybody who listens to this,
because there's just so much
growth that you went over in this
episode, and it's like a great
source of energy and empowerment,
I think coming here today.
Sara: Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely.
Bekah: All
Dan: I just also say, thanks. I
mean, this was, this was great. I
knew it was going to be great,
you know, but like, I don't know,
it was, it was very, very fun and
always. Just a pleasure. I feel
like I miss you in breakout rooms
every time. So, you know, I'm
going to have to force my way
into one of your breakout rooms.
One of these days,
Sara: See me get on a soapbox.
That'd be great.
Dan: energy. I almost interrupted
before you, you were saying about
soapboxes. I'm like, I love when
Sara gets on her soapbox. It's
one of my favorite things. So
thank you for, uh, thanks for
coming
Sara: Always glad to be here.
Bekah: All right, we'll talk to
you soon. Bye.
Sara: Bye.
Dan: Bye.
Bekah: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, plus you can
sign up for our newsletter to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening. And
we'll see you next week.