Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season two, episode nine of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
cohost Dan
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Um, we have a
cool episode today. We thought
we'd do a little, something a
little bit different. It's our
last episode of season two. Um,
it is our what? Eighteenth...
I've lost count many? Yeah, 18th
episode. Um, and. Last time we
are last season one finale, Bekah
and I talked about our own coding
journeys. Um, and so we didn't
want to do that again. Uh, so we
thought this time we would talk a
little bit about what we've
learned, over the last year
building Virtual Coffee, what
we've been thinking about, with
Virtual Coffee, vis-a-vis
communities and, some of the
struggles, challenges, things
we're excited about, um, and
stuff
Bekah: Yeah, we love being
available to talk through kind of
our approach to what the things
that we've been doing and the
challenges that we've faced. And
to share that with everybody,
because I think that we have a
lot of stuff that happens behind
the scenes. And it's nice to be
able to talk about that in a way,
and to talk about all the support
that we've had from the
community, and to be able to
share that as well.
Dan: Yeah, Um, it was maybe a
little bit of a long
conversation, but it was, uh, I
don't know, as very fun. And I
think that, I think people are
gonna enjoy it.
Bekah: Yeah, I sure hope so. I
enjoyed it. We start every
episode of the podcast. Like we
started every Virtual Coffee. We
introduced ourselves with our
name where we're from and what we
do, and a random check in
question. Today's random.
Check-in question is if you had a
remote control, it was only one
button that controlled something
in your life, what would the
button do? We hope you enjoy this
episode. I am Bekah. I am a front
end developer from a small town
in Ohio. And if I had a remote
control with one button, I would
do the Zack Morris button from
Saved by the Bell. You can't see
it, but Dan rolled his eyes. Like
Dan: I did not I was nodding
Bekah: You rolled your eyes. I
saw it
Dan: well, if I did, it
Bekah: doing the timeout button
because sometimes my kids need a
timeout, but also I need the
timeout. So I am having a pause
on life button.
Dan: Yep. Well, if I did roll my
eyes because that was going to be
my answer too. Although the Zack
Morris part, I did not make that
connection. Um, honestly that
might be, that's like a good
upgrade because, um, you know, he
had somebody to talk to, right.
Like he says time out and then
he's like, talks it out with the
audience, you know, the pause,
the pause idea that that would
definitely be mine too. There's
many times where it's just, you
know, whether it's like, maybe I
need a break, but lots of times,
uh, I would like to pause to just
sort of figure out what is
happening in the moment or, you
know, what I'm going to say or,
uh, things like that. So, or just
to get a little extra time in the
day, I suppose, although with the
pause thing, um, you know, do you
get older? Like, do you continue
aging while it's paused? You
know,
Bekah: I wrote a screenplay about
that.
Dan: Well, what happened in the
screenplay?
Bekah: Well, the protagonist, she
could move through the time
pauses. And so for her. One time
was paused for everyone else, she
just sped up through those
pauses. And so she kept up with
everyone else, but she just had
the ability to kind of like do it
on her own time without anybody
noticing.
Dan: Okay. So she didn't like
Bekah: I did some deep research
into physics, so
Dan: yeah.
Bekah: it could happen. Also
Dan: All right. Well, there you
Bekah: teacher from high school
was the worst, so
Dan: I'm sorry about that.
Bekah: I'm not a physicist.
Dan: That's exactly it. Yep. It's
the same. Yeah. I had to get
actually I'd have, I liked her
physics teacher, but he was cool,
but I also ended up not a
physicist.
Bekah: Hmm. My physics teacher
hated me. And so my lab partner
would always get A's on lab
reports and I would write the
same thing and she would give me
CS. I don't understand. Are we
going to do a therapy session
about my physics teacher today?
Okay.
Dan: I don't know if we need to.
We can.
Bekah: It will save that for a
different time. Um, as somebody
asked me recently about Virtual
Coffee and like, what are the
pain points that you feel what
are the things that are
challenging for you? And I said,
well, there's not 40 hours in a
day. And that's the most
challenging thing for me. There
are so many ideas and so many
things I would love to be able to
do. Um, but just cannot happen
because there are hours in a day.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. I mean
like that's, I mean, that's the
biggest, the biggest issue. You
know, I mean, we both work for
living, not for like, not for
Virtual Coffee. Right. I mean,
uh, and so that's, that's, I
mean, that's always going to be
an issue. Right. And so one of
the things that we've been
working on really hard for the
last, however many months is, um,
trying to, uh, get people
involved in, in helping out, um,
you know, but in, in, in ways
that both support them and
support us, you know,
Bekah: I mean, it's such a
important thing, right? Because
we're. Doing this thing and we're
building community and we're
coding along with it. Like
whether it's part of the
community or what, or whether it
is part of a paying job. And I
think like it's a real challenge,
no matter where you are, if
you're starting a community,
sometimes you start it
intentionally sometimes like
Virtual Coffee, it just kind of
happens authentically and then
you try and go with it. And
there's so many lessons that are
learned along the way. I want to
backtrack a little bit though,
and just kind of, um, explain
what Virtual Coffee is, because I
also get that question a lot.
Like, what is Virtual Coffee?
Like, what do you do? And for me,
like the hardest part of that is
describing what we do at virtual.
like, I think that I can describe
it, but I really want to capture
like that energy and like all of
the beautiful interactions that
we have with people and like
getting to know people and to
understand them. And I just have
a really hard time being saying
like, oh, well, we meet up twice
a week and we chat and we have a
slack and then we usually have a
brown bag every week. And we do
these events and newsletters and
podcasts. And those feel like,
like I'm like doing a checklist
of all the things we do. And it
doesn't quite capture, I think
who we are. And I'm not really
sure how to do that. So I don't
know if you have ideas for that,
Dan, but, um,
Dan: Yeah, I, mean, I, would say,
well, if I wanted to, succinctly,
you know, summarize what Virtual
Coffee is, I guess, uh, this is
just off the top of my head, but
I would say it's an intimate
community for developers.
Bekah: oh yeah. Is that off the
top of your head?
Dan: Um, no, I mean, that's,
that's it though, right? I mean,
it's, it's, it's just an intimate
community, right. And it's, uh,
I, and I, and the intimate part
is, is, uh, important and
distinctive part of Virtual
Coffee, um, to me and all of the
things that you described. I
mean, some, I'm sure there's
communities doing all sorts of
different pieces of those, or,
you know, uh, like individually.
Um, but the way that we have
ended up, you know, both, both
through our direction and through
following, you know, w the
member's direction and, um, and
everything is, is this commute
people who know each other pretty
well, we have stuck through the
two days a week meet up, which
is, um, nobody's really doing.
Um, and it's an integral part of,
uh, our community identity. Um, I
feel like it is the face-to-face
conversations. Um, you know, we
have a slack there's. Everybody
is part of a million different
slacks, developers, slacks, or,
you know, Discord stuff like
that. Um, and one of the nice
things about our slack is that
I've seen all these people's
faces. You know, I I've talked to
them, um, you know, in, in not
just like sitting next to them at
some presentation or not, you
know, anything like that. Right.
It's the w our, our
conversations, we have
conversations. Um, our events our
brown bags, are presentations,
but they are, you know, member
led things, right. They're not
just us, the organizers, you
know, pumping out content and
expecting, you know, expecting
our members to join, uh, or
something like that. Right. It's,
it's that the members that are
doing the presentations, um, have
something to share and they want
to share it with our group. Um,
and you know, I was. Uh, we, we
just did the Magnolia conference.
Um, we, we were a community
sponsor for Magnolia JS and I
missed a second one. My son was
sick for the second day of the
conference, so I missed it, but
what Virtual Coffee did there
was, um, did a Virtual Coffee
style, lunch table, zoom meeting.
Right. Um, and, and went, and we
did breakout rooms with small,
small, you know, I had six people
in my room I think. And it was
great. I, I, I've never been to a
online thing that is on anything
like that before, you know, we
I've been to online events, uh,
where there's a, there's a
discord or a slacker or some sort
of chat, you know, and that's
always fun. And I was, I was
having fun at the Magnolia one
and I have fun in our slack too.
Right. Um, but. And, and the
talks were really, really good.
Uh, I've been to a lot of good
conferences, you know, over the
years. Um, and this was one of
them. Um, but like the lunch
conversation was, I w I was just,
I had, I was in a table in a
breakout room with people I'd
never met before. And Kayla was
in my room, uh, who organized the
event and she's awesome, but I
had never talked to her before I
chatted with her, but I never,
um, I don't think she's come to
Virtual Coffee. I know she's come
to Virtual Coffees. I'd never had
been in a breakout room with her
before. Um, and it was really
great. And w with the six of us
just like talked, we talked about
what we were learning. And we
talked about, um, some struggles
that we've been going through,
and it was just half an hour or
something like that. Um, but it,
I came out of that. Like, uh, it
it's one of the things, that and
Kenneth, um, one of the things
I'm going to like, remember about
that event for a long time, you
know, um, the. Like the way the
Virtual Coffee's ended up with
fostering these conversations,
and, um, with small groups of
people is I feel like that's,
that is the, like, that's the
key, right? Um, the intimacy and,
um, to keep like people have
people. Um, and we can talk about
this more later, I think, but
like, people have talked to us
about scale and like prepare for
scale and all this stuff, you
can't have this at scale. And, I
just disagree. I think we're
going to, I think we're going to
figure it out and we're on our,
on our way down the path of
figuring it out, um, because this
community is, um, is great and we
have, we have been holding onto
the things that make it great.
And like we have also, and I'd
like to hear more about what you
think about this, but I feel like
over the last. Six months, um,
really been trying to figure out
what it is that makes us great,
you know, it makes this community
great. Um, besides the members
who, who, who are great, uh, you
know, but they could have gone
somewhere else or right. Every
single one of them and including
us, I suppose, and why they, you
know, like what, you know,
finding, finding out what it is
like, why they keep coming back.
Why they're here is, is, uh, has
been interesting too.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. I there's
something I think of all the time
and I always bring up to people
like anybody can open up a zoom,
right? There's um, you can start
a meeting, you can start a chat
with other people, but we're here
and it's been such a nice thing.
And. You know, Dan, you pretty
sure you're the one that came up
with the tagline: "An intimate
community for all devs, optimized
for you." Right. And early on
when we were like, just really
trying to figure out like, okay,
like what are we, how can we
define that? And, and that's
right. Like, I feel like I
that's, that's where I need to
put my emphasis on this idea of
an intimate community, because
you don't really hear that ever.
And if you're talking about like
tech communities, but it's true.
And I was asking some of our more
senior people, so somebody had
asked me, okay, I understand why
new or early career devs are
there, like networking, trying to
find jobs and stuff. And that's
part of it, but that's not like,
that's not the essence of what
Virtual Coffee is. And so they
had asked me like, well, why do
your senior devs come? And so I
reached out to a couple of them
in there and the answer was like,
We're friends, you know, like I,
I know who your kids are, and I
know about you personally and
that personal connection is, is
what makes it special. I think,
because it's not like, yes, some
people will come through Virtual
Coffee and they won't be able to
come back or they'll find a new
job and they'll leave. And like
every time we have a person that
comes and they're looking for a
job and they find a new job, I am
simultaneously super happy for
them. And like super sad, because
I don't know if they're going to
be back here, but like, I don't
think that I'm the only person
that feels that, right? Like
these are our friends and we have
this time to spend with them and
to share with them. And I'm like,
I always defined myself as like a
shy introvert and this, this
week, my, my introvertedness, um,
Was taxed a little bit because I
had so much stuff going on, but
still it's like, these are the
people that I look for forward to
seeing all the time. And we
decided fairly early on ish. I
think that if you wanted to
become a member, you had to
attend Virtual Coffee because
there's something very special
that happens at those coffees
because you hear other people
because, um, you can see other
people in those moments and we
really just try to embrace people
where they're at. So, you know,
like we are also say like, you
don't have to participate. You
can just come and listen, you
don't have to turn your camera
on. But for me, you know, one of
the most important things is
like, let's recognize every
single member where they're at.
And, and yet like exactly what
you said, Dan, people say, well,
this can't scale. I'm like, well,
we'll figure it out. You know,
because. We know there's
something special here and we
want to keep moving forward with
that.
Dan: Yeah, And that's, you know,
that's a good point about how we,
we decided about, the way into
Virtual Coffee is through the
coffees. Right. You know, we have
the slack, um, and it's great,
you know, but it's, it's sort of,
uh and it's almost, almost,
almost a side. It's not right. I
mean, cause people there every
day, but you know, it's, it's um,
we never wanted it to this to
just be a slack developer
community. Cause they end up
being the same, you know, a lot
of times. And um, you know,
that's been a kind of a struggle,
right? Cause I mean, you, you,
you have people, you want people
to come and, and you want people
to, be able to join. Um, so
that's something we, you know,
we've also been trying to figure
out, right. Is, is, uh, how can
we do that? How can we expand a
little bit, you know, how can we
slowly grow? Uh, you know, and we
have, it's funny, we have, um,
there's some annoying hoops you
have to jump through. Um, I think
to join right now and we have
sort of purposely kept those up
for, for awhile, to slow down,
um, the rate of people, people
joining, um, artificially just a
little bit, um, you know, w. We
have, we have some plans, uh,
some concrete, some not so much
concrete, you know, to improve
all of that stuff and to improve
the flow and to make it easier
for people to join. Um, and, but
I think that's, I think that my
suspicion is that is still going
to be the case for us is that
we're always going to be, you
know, the, the Virtual Coffee
will be the entrance. Um, whether
it looks exactly the same as, you
know, as it does now, it might,
might or might not. But, um,
that's like, that's the key that
the coffees for us are the key to
everything else. Um, am I, am I
like, in my opinion anyway, you
know, and I'm sure some members
will find, you know, find more
value in certain parts and some
members find more value in other
parts, you know, but the, the,
the coffees themselves, I feel
like are unique. Um, the coffees
and the enthusiasm for, um, being
together in a room, um, is like,
that's, you know, that's it
right? So the coffees are like
the automated always scheduled
ways to do that, you know, and we
have, we have other ways to do
that too. Even the brown bags,
um, the w the brown bags are
generally more presentation
style. Um, but they are still on
zoom for us, um, on zoom most of
the time. And which means it's
still people, you know, kind of
that, you know, already in a room
together. Um, and then one of our
members will be just presenting
something that they want to
share, which is, uh, which is
cool too.
Bekah: Yeah, well, I think it's
so nice because it, because you
know, so many of the people and
you have seen them in Virtual
Coffee, it, when you give a brown
bag, it's a little bit different
than, you know, so a brown bag is
about 60 minutes. You can talk
for anywhere between a half an
hour plus, um, and you are
talking about one particular
topic and sometimes there's times
for questions. Depending on the
speaker, the questions might be
throughout otherwise they're at
the end, but there's always that
continual relationship, that
content that happens in slack.
And so you can ask the questions
there or it's like, okay, I know
that person talked about that and
I can touch base with them. And,
um, you know, the, the nice thing
is when you are doing these
things, it feels like less of a
risk because you're doing it in
front of people that, you know,
and that you're supported by. And
so I talked about this, I don't
know where I talked about it
recently, but you know, for me, I
give conference talks and I keep
doing it to myself, but I was
super nervous and anxious before
and like burn out by the end
because the anxiety just like
consumes me. Um, But when I can
see other people's faces,
especially the faces of people. I
know, um, it provides this more,
more comfortable atmosphere, I
guess. So like I gave this talk
recently about my journey into
tech and when I gave it, I, I,
the last two times I gave it, I
just like started crying from the
very beginning. And I'm like, oh,
that's, that's what you want from
a conference speaker crying. But
what helped me to be able to
refocus is looking out into the
people that were there and it
wasn't a Virtual Coffee event,
but there were Virtual Coffee
people there. And I knew like,
okay, like, these are my people.
They're here. They've heard my
story before, but they're here
because they're supporting me and
they're willing to support me as
I grow through this and cry
through this 50 minute
presentation of things. Um, and
it just. You know, allowed me to
kind of stretch myself and to
grow in that moment and to lean
on them. Like I know the first
time I gave the talk, I, Karen
Dickinson was there and Karen
just like her, she was just
giving me the head nod, you know,
and the smile and the
affirmation. I'm like, okay. Um,
I'm just going to look at Karen
and I'm not going to look at
anybody else because all I need
in this moment is Karen. And that
only happens because, you know, I
met Karen at Virtual Coffee
because I'm comfortable with her
because I have shared with her
before. And so me as a person who
really struggles with forming, I
think, um, authentic
relationships with other people
to have that and to be able to
lean on that was, you know, just
one of the nicest moments in my
life.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. That's awesome.
Yeah. Virtual Coffee, real strong
at other people's events, for
sure. As I always, I love seeing
that. I, you know, I, even my,
um, my, I have a Cleveland react,
you know, meetup group. And since
it has started, you know, since,
um, photocopies kicked off and
whatever, um, there's always,
there's always a few people there
too, which is, which is just
great. I dunno. It's, it's, it is
fun. It's, it's great to have
your, your friends and these
people, you know, um, and my
like, outside of tech, aren't
going to come to my tech, you
know, related talk, you know, and
you know what I mean? Like, uh,
they don't want to hear it.
Excuse me. I talk about react or
whatever enough around them as it
is. Nobody wants to, you know,
you know what I mean? But like,
so, so it's, I mean, and that's
people talk about how, how
important it is to have
community, any, any, you know, a,
I'm gonna say any community, any
community of people who care
about you, you know? Um, I feel
like it's very important for
Chicago is obviously not the only
one. Um, but we do have a large
amount of very awesome people.
Bekah: I mean, we have so many
great people and I think like
some of the lessons that we've
learned over the last year,
that's, that's another question I
commonly get from people. Like
what lessons have you learned? So
my lessons, the lessons that I've
learned, like one of them is
communication. I've grown as a
communicator so much, and last
year it was hard and it felt very
terrible and awful the entire
way. So I'm not saying that it
was an easy process, but like.
Being able to communicate with
people and to talk about those
hard truths. I think sometimes
it's still a work in progress.
Right. And, and Karen, who I
mentioned before led the book
club conversation on Radical
Candor. And I was not going to
read it just because I had a lot
on my plate. And Dan, like, you
kind of brought it up when we
were talking about things.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. Well, I, wasn't
excited about reading. I didn't
know anything about it other than
the title, like, and that's
literally all I knew about it and
I've judged it on the, I did I
judge it on the title? I've
judged the book by its cover. I
did it. Uh, but the, um, I got
into the intro and I read the
second edition and she actually
talked in the. Intro or forward
or whatever, um, about how she
wished she had chosen a different
title. Uh, which was interesting,
but no, I got, I got through the
I'm maybe halfway through the
intro and that's when I texted
you and I was like, Bekah, wait,
you need to read this to you.
Like, we need to, you know, this,
this is like, this is what we
need in, um, in our, in our lives
for the first coffee stuff. Uh,
I, I just need you to appreciate
it. And I appreciated it too. You
know, it's a very good book.
Bekah: so good. And it's very,
very useful because I think, you
know, like one of the core
concepts of the book is that
sometimes you don't have those
direct conversations with people
because you don't want to hurt
their feelings or you think like
they're going to grow on their
own or that they'll recognize
those things. And number one,
like you're projecting to that
person onto that person, maybe
what you do yourself, but also.
You help people grow by being
honest with them and letting them
know like, okay, yes, we've done
this thing or you've done this
thing. Here's how you can
improve. And you don't fix the
mistakes for them. And maybe this
is like a grade school teacher
kind of thing. But I think we
kind of lose us as adults because
we want to preserve these
relationships with people and
think that by being direct or
like, okay, so I'm projecting on
everybody else. This is what I
think like, oh, well, you know,
I, I don't want them to feel bad
about all of the work that
they've put into something, but
when I'm not direct with people,
then sometimes what happens is I
ended up taking on more of the
work. No, no, that's, that's what
happens all of the time. Right?
Like, and that's not helping
anybody, it's not helping them
for sure, because they're not
able to grow in that moment. And
so by saying things like, yes,
this is awesome. Well, you know,
you have a lot of reservations
there about the work that they've
created. It doesn't allow them to
understand the process. It
doesn't create clear
communication and it certainly
doesn't create trust because then
when they see their work with a
bunch of changes or if you just
don't. Put their work into
practice, then it can be really
challenging. And so it's hard to
kind of change those ways of
communicating with people. And
for me, I've been trying to do
more of upfront. This is how I
communicate. Sometimes this is
how it comes across and please
feel free to let me know how you
feel about what I'm doing,
because you know, I want to be on
the same page as you. I want to
work together. I want to grow
together. And sometimes that
works and Dan mentioned Magnolia
JS. And those, I think the first
email that I sent to Kayla after
Gant kind of connect us like
Kayla, this is awesome. This is
how I communicate. And so please
let me know, like if I'm
overstepping boundaries or if
we're not communicating in the
way that needs to be, uh, in, in
a way that is mutually
productive. But for me right now,
like I'm leaning into that until
I can. Kind of be able to employ
those mechanisms or to be
"Radically Candor" in all of the
ways that I think are useful to
everyone and helping them grow.
So that, that's my number one
lesson.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I it's something
I've and honestly, like I've like
noticed you improving that, that
sort of, I've noticed you're
working on it. I've noticed you
improving, in your communications
with, with everybody, um, and
including me, but I that's
something I struggled with you
and I, I don't know that I've
turned the corner so much, but
it's definitely something I'm
working on. Uh, another thing
that, um, that I sort of related
it, you know, that I've been,
that I both discovered was I was
going to say discovered that it
was harder than I thought. And I
think the real answer is more
that I discovered that I never
even thought about it or how, you
know, what I mean is, um, sort of
when you're planning and you're
communicating with, with people,
um, if you're going to ask
somebody for help, um, like. You
owe it to them, and to yourself,
um, to, to be sort of specific
about everything, maybe not
everything, but specific about,
you know, what help you want, you
know, what, like what help you
don't want maybe. Um, and Kim
Scott talked about this in
Radical Candor, too, you know,
uh, about laying expectations for
things, you know? Um, so if you
just give somebody a one word
task and say, go, um, you know,
you, I mean, if you're going to
be okay. with whatever comes out
of it, then great. You know what
I mean? Um, but if not, then
it's, you know, it's on you, you
know, on me, on the person asking
to improve that, ahead of time, I
feel like, and that's something
we've been even struggling with
the times here, as well as, um,
that takes work. You know, the,
the outlining that stuff takes
time. And, um, time is the thing
that we have the least that was,
I mean, that was our first both
of our answers for our, uh, our
remote control thing was just
like, all just we need more time.
Um, but anyway, it's so, so like
balancing that with, um, having
to manage day to day stuff, um,
and, and everything else has been
interesting. I feel like we,
that, I feel like we are, um,
turning a corner on at Virtual
Coffee. We have some great new
teams of people that are helping
out with things. Um, we have this
team that's been going for awhile
that has just been helping on the
coffee events, um, leading,
leading breakout rooms and taking
notes. Uh, and, um, it's been
great having a little community
of people that is just like,
that's their, that's the thing
they're working on. And they're
excited about it. And, you know,
um, we have like a slack channel
that's just for that. And It's
been, it's been really cool and
we've improved our processes.
Like we did have, we did put work
into putting things in, you know,
some documentation and stuff like
that ahead of time. Um, but since
people have gotten involved,
we've been able to improve it.
We've seen where things work,
where they don't, you know, what,
when things are confusing when
they're not. Um, and I mean,
that's just one piece of the
whole, the whole pie, but, um,
it's, you know, and this is like,
we, we think of Virtual Coffee a
lot as, um, an open source
community, you know, like we've,
we've, uh, we've used that phrase
before. And, I think everybody
realizes that being an open
source maintainer is hard, you
know? I mean, everybody sort of
knows it in the back of their
mind, you know, and that like a
lot of the struggles that, and of
course we have, our documentation
is open source. Our website is
open source. You know, we have
open source projects, um, as
well. Right. And so, uh, A lot of
the same things we ended up
having to work through, um, and
it's, it can be hard sometimes,
it can be a really great a lot of
times, uh, you know, and it's
definitely a learning, you know,
uh, like a very large learning
process. I've never, I've never
maintained a large open source
project before. Um, and I've
never been any kind of community,
community organizer, um, before,
so I've been struggling and
learning and, um, uh, you know,
over the last I keep saying, I
don't really know how time works
anymore. Uh, the last six months
or so months, you know, since,
um, since I've been in any sort
of leadership position here and,
um, yeah, it's been hard. There's
been some things where I've done,
you know, and, uh, I, you know, I
just sort of missed, uh, I had
like, I missed, I don't know how
to describe this. I was surprised
by, uh, you know, I think that
happened, you know what I mean?
And it was just like, uh, the
same kind of thing where it
hadn't occurred to me to think
about yet, you know, you know?
Um, and that happens that that
is, that's a common thing in my
life. Uh, you know, I, I learned,
I learned by, you know, falling
down, um, most of all and, um,
yeah, I don't really know where
it's going there, but there's,
there's been other times where
I've done something that I
thought was just like, oh, this
is kind of cool or whatever, and
they just kind of toss it out and
it's been, you know, like,
everybody's been very excited
about it too, you know, that kind
of thing. So it's, uh, I don't
know. It's been, it's been fun.
It's been, it's been, it's been a
journey.
Bekah: yeah, for sure. Yeah. And
it is interesting to kind of see,
so. I think because we were not
an intentional community to start
with some people, you know, I
I've described it in this way.
Like, um, well I was talking to
Tom Cudd, I think recently. And
he, maybe he, I'm sorry, Tom, if
I am taking this and putting
words into your mouth, but in my
mind, what I remember is, um,
Virtual Coffee is kind of like a
social startup, right? And so
startups are, we typically think
of them as like move fast and
break things. And so I like to
say, like, we move slow and
deliberately here at Virtual
Coffee. Um, we try to at least,
because, you know, we're, we're
focused on the people. And if we
talk about what Virtual Coffee is
and what the goals are for
Virtual Coffee, number one in my
mind is never let's grow Virtual
Coffee. Like yeah, that's on the
list. But my number one is let's
support the people who are here
right now and figure out how we
can continue to do that. As we
grow,
Dan: Yeah, I
Bekah: just like, looked
Dan: know I
Bekah: were going to respond to
that.
Dan: well, I was, uh, I mean, I
was agreeing with you, you know,
I mean, I, I, uh, that's the,
the, the top of our list is not,
none of our lists have at the top
of it, you know, increased growth
rate, you know what I mean? Uh,
and like, a lot of that is
because we don't have the
incentive to do that. Right. I
mean, we, we want, I want more
people to join because I want
them, like the people that aren't
members of Virtual Coffee, like
should be members of Virtual
Coffee. You know what I mean?
Like, I want that, I want them to
join for them, you know, but we
don't have, like the, we're not a
paid community. We're not like we
don't even. Right now have
advertiser, you know, we we've
been talking about and sponsors
and stuff like that. And I
suppose, um, if you you know,
some company, if you were
designing a company around this,
then that would be the incentive,
you know? Um, and that's not
ours. And that's what, like, one
of the things, like way, way back
when we first started talking
about any of this, like first
started talking about like, doing
anything beyond the slack, you
know, in the zooms. Um, I don't
know who put the line down at
first, but we, we all, I think
we're agreed that we're never
going to put content behind a
paywall basically. Um, I guess, I
guess this is all to say it to
support what Bekah was saying is
it's like everything that's like
high on our list are things to
just improve. Like what are, what
we got going on right now? So we
have things like improve, um,
event management, improve, you
know, improve our workflows for
working with teams. And, um, all
of that. stuff is much higher and
provide more value to our V to,
to our existing members, you
know, as much higher on our list,
then try to open up the flood
gates and, you know, buy some Ad
Words or whatever. And you know
what I mean? Um, and just started
pumping members in. We could, I
think, you know what I mean? Like
we, we could make a couple of
little changes and, um, increase
our like membership count very
quickly if we want to do. I
think, I mean, I'm, I'm not
saying like astronomically, but
like we could do that. Um, and. I
think we can. I mean, we don't
have very many members. We have a
couple hundred, I don't remember
what it is right now, active
members. And, um, I think if we
just decided right now, like
let's double that we could do
that in like two weeks, probably
honestly. Uh, if that was our
only goal, it's just not, you
know, um,
Bekah: for sure. And I think
like, and that's the thing that
like, I keep coming back to, and
sometimes I get super frustrated
with people who are asking about
like, okay, well, what are your
metrics? Like I know about
metrics of community building,
but I'm not interested in a lot
of them because they don't
include so many people. And so
for me, it's about making sure
that we get it right for our
people and for people who are
underrepresented. And, you know,
there's a trend in tech that
everybody who talks the loudest
are the people that get hurt.
Right. And we have so many
amazing developers and our
community at all stages, and they
don't have 40,000 Twitter
followers or whatever, you know,
they participate in the ways that
are meaningful to them. And
that's like so many systems of
judging, like, who are your top
members? They just like focus so
much on like, um, I guess,
quantity over quality. I don't
know. We had Courtney on earlier
this season and Courtney is not
ever going to be the loudest
person in the room, but she
provides so much value to
everything that we're doing at
Virtual Coffee, you know, by
mentoring, by, um, you know,
giving talks by supporting other
members and like, that's great.
And that's missed in so many
metric systems, but also like.
There are valuable community
members who listen, right? Like,
why are we placing value? Why are
we saying a community is
valuable? Cool. Only if you have
people who are out there, um,
speaking in all of the channels
and doing all of the things,
right? Like we should not be
discounting the quiet people or
the people who just choose to
listen because they, they deserve
to be served as well. They
deserve to be part of a
community. And this is me getting
myself box now. Um, but like,
this is, this is how changes are
made, right? Like you allow
people to participate as quickly
as slowly as they want to
participate. And you. Say it like
you're a unique human being. You
are doing things in the ways that
are more comfortable to you. And
like, we are here for that. Like
we're not here for that. If in
the future you decide to give a
talk. Right. Like, that's great.
If you decided to give a talk,
but also it's great if you decide
to be here and, and just listen
the entire time, like that's
okay. It's okay for you to be
there with your camera off. It is
okay for you to not drop
something in the chat. Um, yeah.
Will be maybe a little bit more
challenging to be interactive,
but maybe that's not what you're
looking for four. And so I don't
know. I feel this like consistent
struggle with that question of,
well, how has your community
impact people? Because I think
that it doesn't quite capture
that and I've been like slowly
working on this Virtual Coffee.
Um, model for community building.
And one of the things that I have
there is that, um, well, I'll
just read, it says the goal of
Virtual Coffee, the Virtual
Coffee model is to have a lasting
impact on your community. It's
create ripples that extend far
beyond your community. And so
like this idea of ripples to me
is really important because it,
it is, um, supporting people
where they're at and allowing
them to feel comfortable in the
ways that they feel comfortable
and then taking that forward in
the ways that are meaningful to
them. And so what's meaningful to
me as not meaningful to every
other person in the community.
And. That, you know, sometimes
that requires me to learn a lot
about how other people function,
but also to just embrace people.
Like where are you at right now
in your journey? And that's
totally okay. And so I think that
personal connection is so
important and also why people
say, um, well, you can't scale or
you don't have enough members.
Like never, I don't, I don't need
a certain number of members to be
meaningful because it's, it's one
person, all I need is one person
Dan: Yeah. Uh, I mean, I love all
of that and I agree with it, you
know, I mean, w w the, and I
don't know, sort of changing the
subject a little bit. Well, not
changing the subject, but related
segwaying, I guess. Um, anyway,
the that's one of the struggles
that I've found with learning
about community building and, um,
especially the tooling around
community building is that it's
almost entirely set up on the
premise that you want to make
money from your members. Um, w
whether it's, whether it's, uh,
you're a company trying to sell,
you know, um, sell things to your
members, or whether it's, you
know, just trying to take, uh,
getting, um, event fees or
membership dues, stuff like that,
making money from your members
directly. And, um, you know,
we're not there, right? Like
that's not us at all. Um, and so
this is what I was saying before
our, all of our incentives are
different. And the, if your goal
was to make money in some way
from your members, then the
incentives are to ignore those,
the people, the quiet people, or
the people that aren't, you know,
there's a, um, We started using a
service called Orbit, um, which I
like a lot actually. Um, but I'm
going to pick on him a little
bit, but, uh, one of their, one
of their things, so orbit is, um,
sort of a community. I don't know
what to, how to exactly describe
it, but it's a way to, um, to,
Bekah: management
Dan: yeah, it's not so much for
managing, um, w what it is, is a
way to keep an eye on what your
members are doing across your
different services. Right? So we
have slack and we have GitHub and
we have Twitter and we have
whatever, and it's hard to know,
you know, it's, it's hard to
like, know what people are doing,
um, when it's all spread out
across different services. Right?
And so what Orbit can do is you
can just, um, have one thing and
then add your services in, and
you can, uh, and then it'll track
events and, and say where they
happened and who did them. And it
will sort of identify, you know,
or you can add them in. But, uh,
so if we have a member, um, I can
usually find on orbit there,
their Twitter and their GitHub,
you know, and their slack are all
like in one person, you know? So
you can see if, oh, this person
commented on slack and then, oh,
they liked something on Twitter,
that sort of thing. But one of
the things that I don't like is
they have a metric called "reach"
and that is all what you were
talking about before. was the
high, um, Twitter followers, you
know, uh, that sort of thing. And
that's like, that's a metric I'm
not interested in at all, for
Virtual Coffee, um, I would be
interested in it if I was
incentivized to, you know, like,
like I was saying, like, if those
are the like orbit is trying to
say, those are the high value,
um, members, but we knew, we just
know that that's not, um, you
know, that that's not true for
us. Right. Uh, I mean, my, I
don't know. I have, like, I have
a followers on Twitter, you know,
I'm not even saying that I value,
but like, man, remember, but you
know what I mean? Like it's just
like, not, not a thing. We don't,
we don't. It's great. If people
want to talk about Virtual Coffee
on Twitter or whatever, to their
friends, uh, when do you want
people to do that? If they want
to, you know? Um, but not because
we want to make more money, if
that makes any sense, you know?
Um, and so like, that's, that's
been a struggle with that. All
the, a lot of the, um, event
management stuff is, you know,
sort of based around ticket
sales, um, things like that. Um,
community management stuff is
like a cheap, you know, free
tier. And then after that, it's
like, they're taking a percentage
of your member dues, for
instance, you know, we just know
we're not gonna have member dues
ever, you know, so I don't know.
It's, it's been, it's been
interesting.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean this idea of,
I mean, we're not, we're losing
money on Virtual Coffee, right?
Like we're paying things out of
our pockets and we're taking time
out of our day. But also like,
what we want to do is, you know,
support people where they're at,
especially so many people that
have come to Virtual Coffee have
said things like, I never felt
like I belong to a community
until this one. Right. And I
would, I'm going to just guess
that our average age is about. 35
ish, metal, thirties. Yeah.
Anyway, that's me. And also same.
Like, I never really felt like I
belonged to a community before
this. And it's just so nice to be
able to have such a diverse group
of people. And we've gone back
and forth about like what
expansion for Virtual Coffee
means. And like, should you be
able to have Virtual Coffee React
or Virtual Coffee? Um, that
belongs to a particular group of
people. And I think, you know,
like it depends, but also what we
love so much is the diversity of
people, people being at different
stages, people being here to
support each other. And so, you
know, when people ask me like,
okay, well, if you had to choose
a metric, what would you choose?
And like, well, authentic
connection. So go ahead and
figure out how you describe that.
But I like one of the things.
People ask questions in slack and
they get a response, right. There
is almost never a time where
nobody gets a response. Um,
Dan: And one of the, this was, I
had thought about this before,
but one of the things that
happens with that is that I love
is, Um, lots of times there's the
response is:"I'm not really sure.
Let's jump on a zoom and talk",
you know? Uh, and it's just, it's
not a Virtual Coffee official
thing, you know, it's just one
member talking to another member
and th they just throw a zoom
link in and they're like, Hey,
let's, let's go talk. yeah. And,
um, that almost always works out
too.
Bekah: Yeah. And I want to say,
like, you know, as I'm working
through my own Virtual Coffee
model of doing things like there,
there are two major tenants here,
right? And there's this idea,
this is, this is my idea of like
a person centered approach, I
think is kind of what I've been
talking about this entire time
and why it's so important to
recognize each person where
they're at, but also like there
there's this. Second part of like
the tools and the structures that
are there in place to support the
people. And so you can see each
person individually and you can
recognize them, but if you don't
have support in the tools, in the
structures, you're not going to
get very far. And Dan, I know
like you've worked so hard on
that. And the, the co-working
room especially has just like
taken off as one of the most
important things I think we've
ever done in Virtual Coffee. So,
um, if you want to just give an
overview of the coworking room
or, you know,
Dan: yeah. yeah. Excuse me. This
was another, um, this was another
instance of, um, our members were
just doing this, like. On their
own, um, just posting in whatever
general or, you know, just
posting in slack. Hey, um, I'm
just working, just sitting here
working if anybody wants to work
with me and posting that zoom
link, you know, from their own
Zoom. Um, and they're just doing
that often and it seems like
people were, um, enjoying doing
that, you know? And, um, we
talked about, I don't remember
who shoot, I'm sorry. I can't
remember. Who's somebody shared
an article about a way that
somebody had done this before
with Zoom and, um, who's Joshua,
uh, sorry,
Bekah: of
Dan: I'm gonna, I'm going to have
to look it up. I'm gonna have to
look it up. Cause I wrote it
down, um, a while ago. Um, but so
so yeah, so we thought, um, well
let's, maybe we can just make a
coworking room. That's just like
basically a conference room, um,
that people can go in and work
and leave and whatever, you know,
no pressure. No, no. Um, you
know, I don't know. Yeah, no
expectations, you know, and, um,
and it turns out you can. And so
like one of them, one of, I mean
like, so, so this is combined,
um, a bunch of different, a few
different services, uh, but, um,
in zoom and we can, you can
create a, uh, sort of ongoing
recurring meeting. So it's
actually really funny. It's, it's
a recurring meeting and it recurs
at any select, uh, "no particular
time," right? So this is a
meeting that has the same ID or
whatever, you know, it's the same
meeting, but it has a bunch of
instances that just start when
somebody joins and stops when
they leave. Um, cause that's what
we wanted. We wanted to be able
to, to have members join. Um, we
wanted to not have to have a
host, you know, cause that's one
of the struggles we have with,
um, other, other events, right.
Is, uh, having to have a licensed
user, be a host to start them
into two controls, but for the
coworking room, um, you know that
we did, we didn't. We wanted
members to be able to start them.
Right. And so obviously you can
have, uh, zoom meetings have
people joined before the host.
Uh, and so what we ended up doing
is creating a licensed user that
is just a bot that is just like,
not any person. Right. And, that
user just has one meeting. It's
just this meeting and that person
is not a person, right. That user
never joins, never logs in never
does anything, but, um, they just
own that meeting. And so when
somebody has the link and they
join, then a new instance starts
and then people can join. And
then when the last person leaves,
that instance ends, um, and then
to tie that into slack, you know,
we want it to, um, like creating
the room was, was cool. We did
want to have some, it, you know,
the, the next part was like
letting people know when people.
were in the room or not. Right.
Cause there's no way to do that
with zoom. There's no way to just
like look. Um, and, and so we, I
ended up, uh, zoom has, you know,
web hooks are and, um, slack, you
know, we created a slack app, um,
awhile ago, Mike Rogers like was,
was, was the one that pushing
that like pushing the slack app.
Um, you know, when we started, we
have the slack app, uh, does like
event notifications, stuff like
that. And so we use that slack
app to, um, between the zoom web
hooks, the slack app, and, um,
Netlify functions, uh, basically
notifying our slack room. We, we
created a coworking room and
then, um, notifying that room
when the room opens and closes,
you know, when people join and
leave that kind of thing. Um, and
it was, it was kind of fun. I
have a blog post that is a.
Planned and not at all written
about this, about this, you know,
the technical details of this,
because it was kind of fun, but,
um, but yeah, so, uh, and people
have been using it pretty
regularly. Very
Bekah: All the time. It's
constant. They're constantly
people in there.
Dan: We, uh, we, I do wish that
you could do, there's no way to
do breakout rooms, um, which is a
bummer. Uh, it would be nice to
cause, cause sometimes, you know,
people are, it's like, if you
imagine you're in a room, you
know, in a co-working real life
room working with somebody and
you're like, want to have like a
chat about something like, okay,
let's go step over here and talk
to me. Don't bother everybody.
Um, I wish we could do that. Uh,
unfortunately there's no breakout
room control right now in zoom,
um, through the
Bekah: feel like the, the, like
the, um, easy way to do that is
just mute. Like if people come
into the room and they're chatty
and you're working just
Dan: you can just mute. Yeah,
sure, sure. But then you won't
know when the conversation
stopped, whatever to you it's
like. The breakout rooms would be
cool. It's not like a deal
breaker. Obviously people are
using the coworking room a lot,
um, and, and seem to enjoy it. So
that's been kind of fun. I don't
know if this is a thing that
would grow our members. Like, you
know, if we were focused on, on
profits or whatever, um, I don't
think this would have ever
happened or it would be on the
bottom of the list, you know? Um,
but since our members were doing
it already and then our kind of
goal is to support them, it was,
it was a pretty easy choice, um,
to just kind of go and set it up,
um, spent a couple days on it.
Yeah,
Bekah: Yeah, I mean, it's been
nice. I wish I can spend more
time in the coworking room. Like
I just low key hover over and see
like, oh, they're all in there
having fun without me. So there's
some FOMO there, but, um, I think
it's been nice to be able to go
in and I've been in both
situations where I come in and
somebody is working quietly and
they say like, well, this is
where I'm at in my Pomodoro
session or, or whatever. You
know, like, okay, cool. I can
work. And then there are other
times where I just start talking
to people or they start talking
to me and we just deep dive into
things that I want to be able to
talk about with community
members, but just don't have that
opportunity to all the time. And
it's been really, really nice to
have those conversations and to
be able to think about like,
okay, like, you know, how do we
keep moving this forward? How do
we keep pushing? How do we do
things that people need, and that
are not being done right now, or
at least like, not in ways that I
can see. So it's, it's been
really, really nice to be able to
have that. And I think like two
in one way, or looking through
these things, or we're talking
about community and we're talking
about code and we're talking
about tools, um, There's this
like very fine balance of
automation of things, right?
Like, um, I was in this community
building conference recently and,
or maybe it was made up, I don't
know, whatever. And they were
talking about, oh, well we
automate all of these things, man
or not, man. Wow. That feels
really impersonal. You're asking
people to give of themselves
personally in their responses and
you are collecting that data,
very impersonally. And to me that
just, just doesn't quite match
up. And I think that's just in
general, like a problem with
tech, but something that we try
and figure out like that balance
of automating things to make it
easier on a very small team of
volunteers. But also recognizing
that like the personal
interaction is super important.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. Um,
you know, there's. I mean, yeah,
we we've stepped into the
automating stuff and, another one
of the challenges, um, is since
we're a developer community, you
know, everybody, everybody gets
very excited about, um, wanting
to help and wanting to have, uh,
and having ideas and things like
that. And, um, and I love it, but
it's like, it's, it's never,
there's so many moving pieces,
you know? Uh, and it's, uh, I
don't know, it's not always
simple. Um, or, you know, if you
have one event or one problem,
you're like, oh, here's an easy
fix for this. Right. But it, it
kind of all kind of cascades
together. And the other side of
that is that every single service
that's out there I'm like, that
makes it makes things easy. Like,
like Zapier is Zapier as a cool
service. Um, but it's so
expensive. Um, if you want other
people to help and that's how all
of these, all of the, uh, all of
the, like no code and stuff is
set up for that. Right. So
they're set up to like pull in,
um, somebody who's just working
solo. Right. But then they assume
that if you're, if you have a
team that you're like a startup
that has like, started up and
have money coming in, um, and
that's not, obviously not the
case, um, for us. And so that,
that's another struggle too, is,
is, uh, trying to find services
that we can add. Like have people
help, you know, I can't add any,
like, we have a couple of things
happening on Zapier and, um, I've
been trying to get off of it
because of this. Um, and I can
literally, like, my choices are
to pay a large amount of money
that we can't like, I'm not going
to do, um, to add people to a
team, you know, or, um, share my
password, which like, I don't
really, we don't tell anybody,
but we do this on a couple of
services and it's not fun. It's
like a pain, you know? Uh, so
it's. That's. I mean, that's
another part, like that's another
struggle too. And so we, we we've
actually been on the tool side.
Um, I have been working on some
in-house some in-house tools to,
uh, solve some of these problems,
you know, and, and build on top
of that. Um, and that's, that's
kinda fun too. I I'm going to be
doing a preview, I think in a
couple of weeks. Like we're not
quite there yet, you know? Um,
but to get off of some of the
extra services that we're using,
um, and use our own stuff, um,
will help us, because it'll solve
our own problems and, you know,
scratch our own itches or
whatever, but it'll also, um, be
cool because we can open source
parts of it and, get the
community involved, um, things
like that too. So that's, uh,
that that's coming up, uh, some
sometime in the next. Whatever,
I'm not making any promises. So
it's coming.
Bekah: Well, and it's, it's a
challenge like to be at this
stage. I think of growing where,
like, there are lots of ways to
do things when you're really
small. And like, I don't want to
say we're middle because we're
not, we're not really middle, but
where we're at this point where
there, we certainly feel those
growing pains. And so it's like
it's with tooling, but also we
have a lot of people that are
excited and want to help. And
that's great. We love that. But
also we know that that's a
challenge too, because when you
are onboarding new people to
help, like you're onboarding them
and you, there has to be
processes set up, there has to be
structures set up, right.
Otherwise, it's not going to go
bad. It's not going to go, well,
it's going to go badly. Like
you're, everybody's going to feel
let down in that situation. And
so those growing pains of like,
okay, like there's tools that we
wanna be able to use, but we
can't use these as a team. And
also like, hey, we want to be
able to onboard new team members,
but we have to be able to have
these things set up for them.
Otherwise we're not setting them
up to succeed. We're not setting
them up as partners, as teammates
or in a way that allows them to
understand like, okay, like what
is the goal? And can we
accomplish this thing? And so
like when you're in that like
middle spot that we're in now
that it requires just so much
work and effort to be able to
support people and like yeah,
long term, it's going to be
better if we're able to do those
things. But like right now in the
midst of it, it is a challenge
because like, like we said, in
our random check-in question,
there's just not enough time in
the day to be able to do all of
the things that we want to be
doing with the knowledge and
understanding we have of who our
community members are and being
able to support them in the ways
that they want to support us. And
so it's, um, it's a good problem
to have for sure. But also it's
something, again that like we're
working really deliberately to
do, to be able to empower all of
these people in for them to, um,
be able to succeed in, in what
we're handing off to them or what
they're, we're asking them to do
to support us. And so that's,
it's just like the, the middle
ground of growing pains. I think
of that's where we're at.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: think we're at
Dan: Yeah, no, I agree. I agree
with that. You know, it's.
Bekah: we're 11 years old. That's
the growing pain age. I got an 11
year old. That's how it feels.
And a little smelly.
Dan: Fair enough. Um, the, yeah,
I mean, I, I agree though, it's,
it's, we're in an interesting
phase, um, you know, but it's
exciting too, you know, we've
just created some of these teams,
um, to do some cool stuff. I'm,
I'm very excited to see how that
goes. Um, we, you know, we have
a, an ideas team, you know, I
think that we started, right.
Bekah: we, we do have the
Dan: yeah, we kicked it off.
Cool. And a, um, but what are,
what are the teams that we do
with the monthly, the monthly
challenge
Bekah: monthly challenge team is
rocking it right now. So shout
out to all those people because
you're amazing
Dan: Um, but it took a long time
to get to that point. You know,
we we'd been wanting to do it. We
started talking about teams in
like, exactly like this, except
well, yeah. months and months and
months ago. And, um, we had a
couple false starts and, um, I,
you know, I mean the only thing
to do from that is learned.
Right. And, um, we have, you
know, and I feel, I feel really
good about, uh, you know, about
like, about what's going on right
now. Um, and, and the direction
we're moving forward. I feel like
it's a little bit of a new phase,
you know? So, um, I don't know.
I'm excited.
Bekah: 2.5. Oh, how that works?
Dan: I don't, I, it, isn't a
major version of, I feel like
it's still just a minor version
now,
Bekah: We're in the middle. I
feel like the Hacktoberfest for
me, like kicked off Virtual
Coffee 2.0, and we're
Dan: Yeah. So
Bekah: halfway to next version.
Dan: that's, that's another thing
I was going to say that I'm
excited. Speaking of things I'm
excited about is, I mean, it's,
it's still. Farther away a little
bit, but like it's getting closer
and closer is Hacktoberfest and,
and, and, you know, we don't have
any specific new plans, um, for
that yet, but we have had some
ideas pop up and, um, I'm like, I
am, I'm pumped up. The
Hacktoberfest was a blast last
year and for, for Virtual Coffee.
Um, and for anybody who doesn't
know, this is, um, oh shoot. Who
does, um, who does
Bekah: Digital Ocean and Dev I
think
Dan: and Dev is partnering with
them. Okay.
Bekah: last year.
Dan: Well, either way, um, you
know, they've done that for years
and, um, we sort of thought it
would be cool to get our members,
you know, involved. Um, and it
was cool. It was so much fun last
year. And, uh, I think this
year's gonna be even even better.
So that's another thing I'm
excited about that is on the
near, near horizon for us.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. It is.
It's October about like, we're
already talking about it now,
which is nice. Like last year
when we were doing Virtual
Coffee, Virtual Coffee started in
April. So at this point I thought
like we would be done by the time
summer rolls around and then we
were not done and we're still
going today. And so like, it's
nice to be able to think like,
this is what we did last year and
this is how we can preplan for
all of these things. So it's, you
know, last year we started
planning Hacktoberfest and it was
amazing. But now like knowing
we're going to do Hacktoberfest
again, it's just extra exciting
because I know we have so much
time to work through some plans
and ideas and to do these things.
Dan: it's gonna be awesome. Um,
another thing that our community
members have been doing on their
own, that we've been enjoying
watching, uh, is, is something
that we, we eventually identified
as interest groups. Right. Um,
but this, this is our members.
Um, there's been a few different
ones where members have basically
started talking about something
that they're interested in and
then, um, started doing more
regular meetings with people, um,
things like that because other
people weren't interested too.
Right. And so we have, um, Marie
has been doing a tech interview
study group. Um, and it's been
awesome. Like there's been so
many people that have been, um, I
feel, I feel like I've gotten a
lot of value in, you know, um,
and they've made some friends,
things like that, you know? Um,
Karen's been running the book
club and we were talking about
before. Um, that's been amazing.
Um, Ray has been just like
killing it with, uh, he's created
a, uh, React sort of help support
group and, um, also an, uh, an
indie hackers. Um, I don't know
what you want to call it support
group as well. Um, And that's
been a really cool thing to
watch. It's been cool thing to
watch happen. It's it's been
something that we've been trying
to figure out how to support, um,
while not getting in the way or
anything like that. So right now,
uh, these, these, our members are
doing are doing these all on
their own, you know, and it's
very cool to see
Bekah: Yeah, it's been really
nice to also be able to go in
there and listen to the things
that they have to say and to
learn from them. And, you know,
in, in those groups too, I'm
going to just like, Go back to
the soap box on metrics of
community building, because Ray
has been here for awhile and he's
watched things and Karen too, um,
Marie's been pretty active since
the beginning, but we have
members that have been here for
awhile and just took these
initiatives and went with them.
Right. And so if you look at
traditional metrics of how
communities are measured, I think
that, um, some of these falls
through the cracks and they are
not weighted as high in points as
other people. And this is like,
this is the whole thing. Why
these systems are not great or
they're. Not open to people at
different stages of where they
are, because sometimes it takes
like sitting back and listening.
Sometimes it takes a moment in
your life to open up to these
opportunities, to be able to do
these really great things that
are impacting so many members of
the community. And like, yeah,
they are, would be weighted right
now in this moment. But prior to
doing these things, you know, we,
we have quieter members and I
that's like a totally valid and
great place to be because the
value should be placed on like
what you're getting from the
community, not what the community
is getting from you. And I know
like I've learned so much from
each one of these members and I
couldn't. You know, possibly I
like try to say how much I've
learned from them. And I try and
talk about how amazing they are
and the words just can not
capture how I feel about them as
people and what they're doing.
Like they're just amazing.
Dan: Yeah. I absolutely agree.
I've started talking to, um, the
members that are doing these
kinds of things, you know, to
learn just a bit, um, is, is how
we can support them, how we can
make it so that they can do this
easier or whatever, or how we can
make it, um,if another member has
something similar that they want
to do, you know, but don't have
the tools, maybe we can come up
with some sort of process, you
know, um, to, to allow that to
happen with less friction or, or
just, you know, less, less
worrying about the details, you
know, and, and more just
concentrating on the good stuff,
right? The actual talking, the
interactions, the learning stuff
like that.
Bekah: And I think that leans
into the authenticity of the
group, you know, like these
things just come about naturally
Virtual Coffee happened
naturally. And like, if you look
five years this is part of it,
you know, just being able to
support people and what they want
to bring to the organization and
like, yeah, that makes it
challenging because you're.
Constantly pivoting, but if
you're not, then I don't know
what kind of community that is. I
mean, it's not really a community
that, that I would be a part of
because I like that idea of
growing and learning from each
other and being able to go with
what the community brings and
support them where they're at.
Dan: yeah. no, that's an
interesting point, you know? And
I, I don't feel like we've been
constantly pivoting, we've been
doing course corrections. Um, I
feel like that's a little closer
to, to what we've been doing and
that's part of, and that's part
of, one of the challenges that
we've you and I personally like
specifically have struggled with,
right. Is sometimes, you know,
how far do we steer one way or
the other, do we steer at all?
Right. Like that sort of thing.
And I, you know, I know I've had
long nights where I've just been,
I don't know, stressed about
that, or, you know, like
community members want people
like want us to even be steering
at all, you know, that sort of
thing. And I mean, I say steering
is, I'm just like leaning really
hard into this metaphor because
there's it cause it's easy to
talk about. But, I personally
feel like we've done a good job,
you know, w with this overall,
and that doesn't mean like, we
have definitely made missteps
too, you know, along the way. Um,
and it's been. You know, th th
this is why I'm so excited about
the interest groups for instance,
is, uh, that it's like a very
clear, like, signal, like, Hey,
steer this way, you know, um, you
know what I mean? Uh, and the
people have floated off. I mean,
we get, I mean, like whatever our
members are excited, we're
excited all the time. You know,
we, we floated ideas, people,
other people float ideas, but,
um, you know, like we always want
to take into, and we do take into
account, you know, the health of
the community, how we can support
them, um, things like that. And,
um, Yeah, it's, it's been, I
don't know. It's been, it's been
wild. It's been, uh, it's, uh,
it's been cool and I'm still, I'm
still very, very excited about it
and where we're heading, you
know,
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. It is very
nice to see people comfortable in
our community and being willing
to grow and to support each
other. And that's the biggest
thing for me. So if you're going
to ask me, what metric do you use
to tell whether or not your
community is healthy? It is the
supportiveness of the community
for every member that's here.
Dan: Well, did you have anything
else you wanted to cover? We've
kind of gone for the traditional
amount of time,
Bekah: here's your last question
of the day: Virtual Coffee in
five years? What does it look
like?
Dan: Hmm. Yeah. I don't know.
Five years. All right. So in five
years, um, that will be 2026. I
mean, what I have to do for any
of these kinds of things is place
myself, right? So like? I'll be
even more old. Uh, Ben will be 10
and Samson will be seven, that's
going to be,
Bekah: different,
Dan: be something.
Bekah: or
Dan: And, um, yeah, I don't know.
Hopefully, I mean, hopefully it
looks kind of the same, you know
what I mean? But I mean, feels
the same is I guess, more more
what I think, you know, um, I
imagine Virtual Coffee, having a,
sorry, a larger presence as a
platform, you know, um, you know,
we've, we've talked about
different satellites. We talked
about a million different options
for everything, you know? Um, but
the essence of it is still, I
feel, I feel like it's important
for us to, um, hold onto, you
know, the intimacy and everything
like that. And so I just hope
Virtual Coffee, it looks like a
place that you can go and have
real conversations with real
people. And, uh, um, that's,
that's it? Yeah. You know, I, I
can't, I can't even picture it
five years from now. Um, like on
a, on a low, on a practical
level, you know, I have, no, I
have no idea. I mean, who knows
even what kind of frameworks or
whatever will be out there, you
know, maybe it'll all just be AI
stuff and it'll all just be, uh,
us learning how to, um, you know,
feed datasets to things or
something. I don't know.
Bekah: and like, I set you up to
fail. I think the idea of, you
know, the real relationships is
the best answer. So you got that.
Dan: Um, okay. So speaking of
Hacktoberfest and, um, awesome
members, I literally just got
this Twitter notification that
just popped up on my phone, um,
from Lucia who's one of our like
long-time, uh, OG members and she
just like, this just happened.
She said, "woke up this morning,
looking forward to Hacktoberfest.
Yes, it's May. Thanks to Virtual
Coffee IO." And, uh, I don't
know. That was, that was awesome.
Um,
Bekah: notes.
Dan: I, um, yes. And that this is
what I'm talking about though, is
like, you know, she is, she's a
person who like came, I feel like
she was in bootcamp, um, and, and
starting the job search and, uh,
Hacktoberfest is like this great
experience that we all did
together. And, um, Lucia is just
like woke up this morning,
thinking about how Hacktoberfest
It's awesome. Well, well, cool. I
think that was, I don't know that
I think that was really fun and
really great. Um, this is the
last episode of season two,
right? Um, We did it Yep. We did
it. When are we going to be back?
We'll be back in
Bekah: three weeks.
Dan: three weeks. with three
weeks, whatever. I can't do math.
We'll be back soon. Um, we're
gonna take a little break and
went back and with the new lineup
of, you know, um, members and
episodes.
Bekah: If there's anything you'd
love us to talk about, or you're
interested in hearing about
Virtual Coffee, please feel free
to hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO, or you can
email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io, because
we are here for what you want to
know.
Dan: Okay, cool. Um, well have a
good few weeks and we'll see you
in June. Yeah. Is that what you
said? We'll see you the end of
June.
Bekah: sometime in June, we'll
see in June.
Dan: That can't be right.
Bekah: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, plus you can
sign up for our newsletter to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening. And
we'll see you next week.