Bekah: Hello, and welcome back
to the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their coding journey. And
they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories. And what they've
learned. Here with me today is
my cohost, Dan.
Dan: Hey, Bekah. Um, season
three, that's exciting. We had a
really great season two. We
heard from all sorts of people.
Yeah.
We had a lot of great
conversations. Um, in the last
season, you know, we talked a
lot about finding your voice and
building confidence as a
developer. And I heard a lot of
great stories from different
people and it was a blast. And
we
are pumped to be back for season
three with some great episodes
Bekah: I am very excited to be
back too. And I thought would be
Dan: We're pumped,
Bekah: Okay. I am excited and
you are pumped. Okay.
Dan: very pumped.
Bekah: Very excited. As we move
into season three of the
podcast,
I thought it would be fun to
talk a little bit about what
we've
learned as podcast co-hosts. I
think we can talk about all of
the seasons
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I mean, well, w
when did our first episode air
in
January, something like that. So
it's been half a year or
whatever. Um, I've I've learned
a lot. I've learned a ton from
the
technical perspective. Um, you
know, producing this, you know,
with, with you is, has been, I
don't just like the new thing to
learn every, every week. Uh, it
seems like, um, and it's now I'm
at the point where I know all
the things I don't know, you
know
what I mean? Like, you know,
sound quality stuff, editing,
um,
things like that. I, I, uh, I've
gotten. To the point where I can
do it, you know what I mean? And
so now it's like, now I know all
the things I don't know, or at
least I know that there are a
lot
of things. I don't know, you
know what I mean? Um, but it's
been
fun. I feel like I've been, I've
been at least from the technical
standpoint of, you know, podcast
stuff. Um, kind of getting my
feet under me. Um, so that
part's been cool
Bekah: I can start the intros
without laughing all the time.
Dan: Yeah,
Bekah: Most of the time.
Dan: I feel like we we've been
using Zencaster and they
released
a new version of their software,
which was pretty cool, which we
enjoyed a lot. Um, and they have
a countdown thing now. So when
you hit this, you, when you hit
start record, there's a little
countdown. And I feel like that
almost helps us, you know, cause
you, I dunno. I feel like that
was where we get tripped up is
cause it hit record and then
there'd be some pause and nobody
knows if they're supposed to
talk or not. You know? So it's a
small, small touch. I feel like
that has helped us.
Bekah: Yeah, well, I think
getting more comfortable to, you
know, in the beginning, it was
just, it's different being
interviewed for on a podcast
than interviewing other people,
because you have a different
role as a host and you're there
to try
and tell the story. And I think
it took a little while for me to
kind of wrap my head around that
and maybe going into season
three, I feel like I've got a
better grasp on storytelling as
a
podcast. Rather than like, okay,
I have this list of questions
and
we have to hit all the
questions. Like we have some
backup
questions, but where is the
conversation going and how can
we
keep that up and tell the story
of the person on the show and
think about what, what would
benefit anyone who's listening
to
the podcast?
Dan: Absolutely. Yeah. From the,
from the host point of view, I
have, uh, I don't know, I felt
like I've, I've tried to learn a
lot too, and I'm at the same
point where it's like, okay, now
I can see the things, you know,
that I don't quite do well or
that I, you know, think I can
improve on. Um, and you know,
some of them it's clear how to
fix and some of them, some of
them, it's not always, but, uh,
it's, I don't know. It's a
journey and, um, it's, it's been
fun. It's been, and it's also, I
mean, everybody that we talk to
are people that we like and are
part of our community and, you
know, they're friends, some of
them close friends, some of
them, you know, new friends, um,
for
me. And, uh, it's been just a
blast to be able to talk to
everybody and learn more about
them personally, too, and
hearing
everybody's origin stories and,
um, crazy, uh, boat plane
training incidents and, uh, you
know, just hearing more about
from, you know, from people's
lives. Um, it's one of the
things
that I like and that I like
about the, um, in our, in a
Virtual
Coffee, is when these
conversations get off track and
not off track, but, uh, get
whatever, you know, that don't
have a track. Right. Um, like
you were saying. And, um, I feel
like
those always ended up being the
most valuable conversation. So
Bekah: Yeah, I love it.
Dan: And it's been cool trying
to apply it here.
Bekah: I love chasing a tangent.
It's a good time. And usually
come out with something
interesting, at least.
Dan: Yes. Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: And it has been fun. You
know, getting to know people a
lot better and to learn about
their lives and the things that
they've gone through. It's
really been great for me. Like
you said,
there, there are things that you
take away from. Every episode
and
every person that we talked to.
And I just love that after we're
done recording a podcast for
every season where we've
recorded
almost all of the third season,
but there's always been
something
in every episode that I've taken
away and just thought about for
the rest of the week. And it's
really helped to inform the way
that I've done things and the
approaches I take. So it's been
great to be able to have that
live learning experience.
Dan: Yeah, I agree. And they,
uh, it's just been like little
tiny
breakout rooms with just you and
me and one other person. Um,
and,
uh, it's, it's been really very
cool, very cool experience. And
I'm excited about season three.
Bekah: Yeah, we're really
excited to be sharing this
season with
you all too. Um, we're going to
be talking about recognizing
your
potential, navigating
interviews, overcoming career
stagnation, how
to do a proper Tim Tam Slam, and
a lot more.
Dan: That's right. So kicking
off season three, episode one,
we
have Jono Yeong. Jono is a
senior software engineer. He's
originally from Australia. I is
currently based in Seattle, um,
USA. And he. Okay. So he's
primarily a backend developer,
but is enjoying re-entering the
crazy world of front end
development. He loves giving
back to communities and
empowering
others on their developer
journeys and, um, without such a
supportive community, he
wouldn't be where he is today.
Uh, and he
says, hashbrowns are his guilty
pleasure food. Um, and so, yes,
so today he'll be talking to us
about, digital gardening,
learning elixir, and how to do a
proper Tim Tam Slam.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's
random check-in question is if
you could have one person
narrate
your life, who would it be? Hey,
I'm Bekah. I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And I am going to change
the question a little bit, cause
I feel like it. I am. I decided
I
didn't want a narrator, I wanted
a musical background and I would
just like to choose everyone
that sing in Frozen 2 musical
background to just sing my life
story for me, because that
seemed
more fun.
Dan: Sure. That would be cool.
So is. It makes me think of
Monty
Python. Like the, uh, the, the
guy, what is his name, Sir
Robin?
you know, the guy following
around Sir Robin: "so boldly
goes, Sir Bekah, she's doing
something. I don't know. I can't
think of it, but like, yeah, I
like that musical narration I
can
get by that. Um, hi, I'm Dan. I
do front-end development. Um,
I'm
in Cleveland, Ohio, and if I had
to pick a narrator. I was
thinking for a couple of minutes
about this. And, uh, honestly,
Sean Connery is who I landed on.
Um, I think it'd be pretty cool.
I, and I just listened to a
podcast about, um, The Rock, the
movie and, um, w which of course
he's, he's in it. And that made
me think, oh, man, what about
Nick Cage narrating your life?
Which, um, would be, uh, would
be, it could be pretty
interesting too. Um, I'm
sticking with it. I'm sticking
with, uh,
Sean Connery, but I, I. I would
like to know what that would
sound like, Nick Cage just kind
of narrating somebodies life in
their head.
Jono: I feel like that's like
two very opposing voices
Dan: Right, right. Yeah. Right.
Which is why that movie is so
good, you know?
Jono: Yeah. Oh, amazing. Um, hi,
I'm Jonathan. Uh, I am a senior
developer at Shopify currently
based in Seattle and jeez, Bekah
threw the curveball and with a
musical number. I am not that
musical, so you're totally fine.
Um, I, you know, I think I would
get a fictional character being
Yoda potentially could get
annoying after a while, but, you
know, I think there would be
like
wisdom. Right there. And then a
real person, Nick Offerman. I
just hope he laughs at some
point during my life story. Just
to get
that sound clipping
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. He's he has an
excellent laugh, um, with the
Yoda. yeah, It be worth even.
I'd be, I mean, it would be like
great, you know, um, sound wise.
That Yoda would be, just be
judging me all the time.
Jono: yeah,
Bekah: I feel like you'd really
have to pay attention. Like you
have to think. Cause he wouldn't
straight forward narrate what
would happen? He would just be
dropping Yoda wisdom about what
happened
Jono: Yeah, I think he'd make my
life sound
Bekah: I don't know.
Jono: Yeah.
Bekah: I have enough of those
already. Um, so welcome, Jono,
we're very happy to have you
here on this third season of the
virtual PA Virtual Coffee
podcast and doing an excellent
job
already. Um, so we really like
to start with a little bit of
the
background, your origin story.
So if you could give us your
short
version of how you got to this
point in your.
Jono: yeah. Um, I have a pretty
boring or I guess standard
technical background. Um, so I
did a four year degree at
university, um, interned at a
company. Um, but during that
time, and then at the company, I
was doing iOS work initially,
um,
for a few months, and then they
got me on a Ruby on Rails
project. And that's really when
I really fell in love with web
development and decided to kind
of pursue that route. So from
there went to kind of be another
kind of Ruby on Rails shop in
Sydney. So I'm originally from
Australia. Uh, and then I
actually moved to the States.
Um, so working with Rails all
the way
through and uh, yeah, now I'm in
Seattle and now on Shopify.
Bekah: I don't feel like I could
have you narrate my life, you
and
Mike Rogers, like can we go back
and forth between the two. It
would be a very happy time for
me.
Jono: just so much happiness.
Bekah: Um, well that, that is
awesome. And we are glad to have
you at Virtual Coffee. I don't
remember when you joined Virtual
Coffee do you?
Jono: Um, I, I D I remember, I
remember the circumstances. I
was
in a Code Newbie chat. And I was
talking about seeing Virtual
Coffee and I tweeted about it.
They're like, Hey, this seems
like a really cool community.
And then I think you mentioned,
you
tweet at me saying like, Hey,
come join at this time. And, and
let's yeah, I think it all
kicked off and spent almost
maybe like
six months, maybe more. I don't
know. I can't, but it's time.
Bekah: Right.
Dan: Yeah. we were, we, we just,
uh, recorded our podcast
episode,
wrapping up, um, season two,
right. We're talking about that
too. Like looking back on time.
And I was just, I just kept
throwing out random numbers of
months. Cause I literally, I
have
no idea. I have no idea. It was,
uh, you know, it was after the
pandemic started. I know that
much. And then after that, I'm
just like, I don't know. It's
all just a big cloud.
Bekah: Yeah. Um, so one of the
things that I think would be
cool
to talk about, I know you
updated your site yesterday or
sometime,
and it looks really awesome. So
we'll post that in the show
notes, but you, um, there's this
concept of digital gardening
that
you talk about, and I think you
practice, so I'd love to start
there. First of all, what is,
what, what does that even mean?
Digital gardening.
Jono: Yeah. Um, so digital
gardening is really about
curating your posts. Like you
don't need to have fully formed
or finished. Um, written work.
It's, it's really about having a
thought and then building on
that thought over time. Um, and
it's
kind of the opposite of a blog,
which is almost like a feed with
that sorted in chronological
order. Um, so with your digital
garden, you kind of pick and
choose what you want to present
up front. And it's really about
that curation. Um, I definitely.
Got heavily inspired by Maggie
Appleton. So definitely go check
out her blog as well, which is
also a digital garden. Um, her
artwork is beautiful and she
explains it really well over
there.
Dan: Yeah. I've seen a couple
other examples like that and
Maggie Appleton site that is the
first one I, I think I saw too,
um, they don't let it out of
this whole concept. I think
that's
really cool. So do you, um, And
this is something I've been sort
of interested in for a while
too, but, um, haven't really,
you
know, my blog is old and I don't
update it that often. Um, but it
is still like old, you know,
that regular style. Um, so when
you're
doing like the curation process,
right, for older posts, do you
just re like remove them or
what, like, or do you tuck them
away
somewhere or, uh, you know,
like, can you explain a little
more
about how you handle like that
sort of stuff that maybe isn't
super relevant anymore, but, you
did write it, you know, five
years ago or something.
Jono: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
Um, so I think the curation in
my
mind, uh, yes, to some posts
going away. So I actually
removed
a bunch of posts that, um, when
I was migrating over to this new
site redesign. And then also,
um, being okay with putting a
big
"work in progress" box. So it
actually on the, uh, I have a
post about GitHub and Notion and
notion this was pre Notions API,
and this was really just about
how I organize our projects. Um,
but. Now that Notion has an API,
it would make a lot of sense to
make something, wake it up and
nurse, and actually talk to each
other. So I put it like a big
alert and box saying like, Hey,
I
am going to be working on this.
Um, you expect things to change
Dan: So as you update that post
and I did I read that post, I
really enjoyed it. Um, as you
update it, plan is what will be
to literally update that post as
opposed to doing a part two or
see this or whatever. Um, things
like that.
Jono: Yeah, exactly.
Dan: That's, that's pretty
interesting. And it is, and like
I have seen other people do it.
It's it's, uh, There's the
question of like time with
regards to technical content,
especially, it's always sort of
interested in to try to handle,
right. And I have, um, one of my
...and I mean, a lot of this is
because I don't write that
often, but still one of the
posts on my
site that gets the most traffic
is, um, some old CSS like float
hack thing, you know? And it's
still like, I mean, it still
works, but it's like, you know,
not at all anything, I would
tell
somebody to do now. You know
what I mean? Um, and yeah. I've
thought about, I've thought
about how to handle that or, um,
so,
so, so if this was a digital
garden, I suppose the answer
would be to, uh, well, either
toss it and just point them back
to the main page. Right. Or just
rewrite the whole article at
that
same URL or something like that.
Jono: Yeah, I mean, you, um, I
mean, you can keep that old
posts
around, like it's, it's really
your playground. You can really
do whatever you want with it.
Um, there's no really hard and
fast
rules. Um, I think like if you
wanted to toss it or update it
and utility could, you could
also write like, uh, a new
update
paste. I think the key idea is
really just not waiting for
perfect to publish. So you don't
need to, you can just publish a
thought. And it will be okay.
Um, and I think this reminds me
of
someone in Virtual Coffee, maybe
it was Vic, who just did a timer
and was like, I'm just gonna
write what I can. And by the end
of the time, I'm just gonna
publish this. I think that like,
feels like that digital garden
essence to me,
Dan: Yeah, Vic has been doing a
lot of that kind of stuff. And
he's been someone that I've
admired his work with that too,
that the not perfect. The, uh,
get, get it out the door kind of
get published. Um, thing has
been, has been really cool. Um,
I
would say inspirational. I don't
know if you can be inspired if
you haven't actually gone and
done it. I mean, I haven't
actually gone, um, done anything
with it, but it is, uh, it is
cool to see. I do like that
attitude, you know? Um,
Bekah: I mean, for me, the hard
part would be going back and
updating things. Like I get them
out and then I don't, this is, I
mean, I have a master's in
English and it was the same
thing. Like I, I got excited. I
wrote the paper and then. Like
to
go back and edit was the worst.
So I don't know, like how do you
motivate yourself to do that? Or
are you like, well, I'm not
motivated. So then this isn't
something that I need and you
can
take it away or just say, like,
this is a weed,
Jono: Yeah. Yeah. That's a great
question. I think it's, it's
definitely going to be. A work
in progress as in like, I'm
still
trying to figure out that, um,
process a little bit more. Um, I
know that when I was trying to
write like a blog post every
week
or every two weeks, and just
trying to like push out a new
content, it became. Really hard.
And I was in a bit of a rut.
Like, it just felt like I was
going from deadline to deadline.
So like giving space to not need
to write a new post every single
week, but be okay with like
updating whole pace, mainly just
also I'm lazy. So like, it'd be
nice if we could just tell you
something that's already rating
and then just add a little bit
to
it as, okay. So like writing a
whole thing thing.
Dan: Yeah, I was. You know,
speaking of doing that, you
know,
lots of people will make a goal
like that, of a blog post or
whatever. I think that, you
know, thinking about it, it
seems to me
like the most important part is
actually just writing, like the
habit of writing and publishing
something every week is, uh, you
know, sort of a straightforward
goal right. To do. But I was
listening to podcasts, uh, maybe
the indie hackers one a while
ago. And, uh, they're talking
about, I don't remember who the
guest was, but he was talking
about, um, like long form
writing
instead of, um, instead of lots
of lots. Posts, you know, one
post that takes them months to
do, and it's long, you know, a
long read or whatever, but that
they found it to be much more,
um, for himself like writing,
uh, to be, to be much more
enjoyable,
which I, which I've been
interested in too recently. And
I
th I feel like that could fit
really well into the digital
garden model, because you could
even do your drafts if you
wanted
to, um, or parts or whatever,
you know, and keep it going. Uh,
like
that'd be kind of cool to see.
It would be cool to see it like.
To
like, watch it grow. You know,
if we're going to keep down the,
the, like the metaphor, the
garden metaphor.
Jono: Yeah, I really liked that
point of, um, you know, doing
what you enjoy, because I think
that is really the key to it
all.
Like you could write deadlines,
you could have deadlines and
write blog posts, but like, if
there's no way or like, you're
just doing it because you have
to, it's not that fun, then
you're not going to keep doing
it.
Dan: Right, right. I mean,
that's been my that's my, my
personal
experiences a lot of times.
Yeah. Things. And like, that's
what,
that's one of the reasons why
it's good to build habits, you
know, because the, sometimes
it's just over, it's hard to sit
down
and write, you know, but if it's
like a thing you're used to
doing, then. Then that part is
not hard anymore. And then it's
like, well then it's actually
writing that you have to deal
with, but it's your mind makes
it not as big of a deal. At
least
for me.
Bekah: And I liked the point
about like, writing what you
enjoy, because I also see a lot
of people that are writing
things
that they don't enjoy and they
hate doing it, but they just
keep
doing it. Cause they think that
they need to do it, which just,
um, just sounds really
miserable. So how do you find w
okay, one,
what do you enjoy writing about,
like, how do you go after that?
When you're writing.
Jono: Yeah. Um, man, that is a
great question. So I've figured
out that I really don't enjoy
writing tutorials. Um, they take
me a lot of time and I feel like
I don't do it very well, so
there's that. Um, but I think
like, what am I most enjoy is
really just exploring new tech
and then just kind of getting
into like, How I align and what
my process is. So I really like
writing about personal stuff as
opposed to like technological
stuff.
Bekah: Do you think that you
write, or would you say that.
Right, because you think you
should be writing as a developer
just to kind of, um, extend
yourself into the community or
it's just something that, that
you want to.
Jono: yeah, it actually started
off being like, oh, I should be
doing this. You know, I should
be writing. You should have a
blog,
just so you get the exposure and
you can tweet about something.
Um, but it's kind of
transitioning a bit more into
like, I'm trying to find the
enjoyment out of writing and
like
figuring out like why I like
doing this and then realizing
that. Writing or getting better
at writing and reading
communication, just kind of
everywhere. Like it's pervasive.
It's not just in a blog post.
Um, but like, I'll do this at
work
where I'm writing documentation
and like emails and stuff like
that. Like that's all really
important. And I've only really
just started realizing that a
year ago or something
Bekah: Yeah. So I talked to the
tech interview study group a
couple of months ago, and we, I
was talking about networking and
one of the things that I said
was that. A lot of times we have
this
very, um, narrow idea of what
networking is, but in our
industry and the things that we
do, we can create a wider
network. So networking can be
writing a blog post or tweeting,
or, you know, like curating that
digital garden. And so that
allows you to have a community
that you don't know. And
sometimes it's really fun to
like, especially at virtual.
Someone will come and be like,
oh, I read your post this one
time. You're like, oh, that's
cool. Um, so it was really nice
to kind of extend yourself out
there and in kind of meet people
without even knowing it.
Jono: totally agree.
Dan: I was just looking back at
your blog posts. So in your, for
the readers, I will obviously
post this, but, um, the blog
posts you were talking about how
you use Notion and, um, GitHub
Projects together right. To, to,
to track side projects. So, um,
so one thing I was, I was just
like, kind of curious about was,
um, what, like what you like to
do with side projects or what
kind of things do you have going
on? Are they, I don't are they,
are they just like fun? Are they
like hobbies? Are they, um, you
know, possible revenue sources
like that sort of thing. Um, I
was wondering kind of how you
approach, um, the side project
life.
Jono: Yeah. Yeah. That's uh,
yeah. I have a lot of, I think,
fun side projects and there's a
lot that I've just started and
like have never like finished or
touched after the initial start.
Um, as I'm sure a lot of
developers do. Um, but yeah,
most
of them are around like how, how
can I learn this thing? So we'll
have a sub project around like a
concept or something like that.
Want to learn. Um, I hate, so
this is where, cause I am on a
visa, so it's kind of weird. I
don't know if I can actually add
another revenue stream. So I
haven't really been pushing
towards like doing that stuff.
Um, but yeah, that's, that's
where I am.
Dan: That is interesting. I have
no idea. I mean, I have no idea
how that works. Probably a good
thing to check out, I suppose,
if
you were going to, if you were
going to step into that, but,
um,
honestly, maybe it might, that
might make, uh, some of your
decision-making easier could,
right? Cause you don't have to
think about it. Don't have to,
don't have to worry about that
part. Uh, you know, for awhile
that's kind of fun. Is there any
specific one that you've been
into recently? Any of your side
projects?
Jono: Yeah. So, um, well this
personal website was, I guess a
side project, just because like
I was building svelte kit, um,
something that I've never really
built before I'll use before.
Um,
and then on the other side, I'm
learning a bit more about Lixa
ElixirPhoenix. So I've been
building. This thing that I'm
trying to document on YouTube,
which is a, uh, like a, a social
media app for, for puppies. I
don't know if that makes sense,
not, but essentially it's like,
you can, you have like a bunch
of
puppies that you add to the side
and you can follow dogs and you
can have like little meetups and
stuff. That's, that's the grand
idea, but it's really just about
a learning project.
Dan: That's that's
Bekah: Can you just talk a
little bit about what elixir is?
Just
give some definitions for the
things that you talked about.
Jono: Yeah, no, that's great.
Um, so Elixir is a functional
programming language. Um, it's
written by José Valim and it has
a lot of. Um, Ruby ish syntax.
So if you come from Ruby, you
kinda,
you feel like that initial layer
feels a little like Ruby, um,
but
then when you really dig down
into it, it's all about
functional programming
languages. So, uh, immutability
is kind of
like a, a big component of it.
Yeah, there's all these like
little extra features. Um, and
the language itself is an
interpreted language. So it's
built on top of Erlang. Um, so
think like Ruby is kind of built
on top of C almost. Um, so
everything can compile as down
to Erlang.
Dan: That's pretty cool. Yeah.
There's a lot of, a lot of
interest in the functional
programming languages, you know,
uh, space, you know, these days,
which, which I enjoy. You know,
on a nerd level, I haven't
really dug into any of them. Um,
you
know, I know Kirk is into shoot.
I can't remember it was called,
um,
Jono: uh, F no, no shop hassle.
No, throwing out
Dan: uh,
Bekah: No.
Jono: Nice.
Dan: it's just silly because I
actually like contributed to it.
Project and I can't, I'm totally
blank on the name. I'm sorry.
I'll come up with it. Um, but
anyway, it's, it's, uh, I don't
know. It's neat. The functional
stuff I really enjoyed when I, I
did computer science for a
couple of years in, um, in
college and
enjoyed it. There was a language
called scheme that we used, um,
in school and it was just fun. I
don't know. It's neat. It's a,
it's a cool little, uh,
paradigm. Um, I ended up, I
ended up, uh,
in JavaScript. JavaScript itself
is not functional, like
strictly,
but you can. You can like lean
that way pretty hard, you know,
it's, it's fun. It's kind of fun
to, to do that.
Jono: Yeah, absolutely. I think
those, like, I see the whole
reason why I moved. Like started
learning about Elixir was, cause
I kinda was burned by, by few
things in Ruby and JavaScript
where it was mutable, but it
wasn't obvious that it was
mutable. Um, like the example
comes to mind, which is I was
working on my personal site. Um,
was the JavaScript Sort(), it
like sorts in place and it
changes the underlying object
and
it just like break everything.
Yes.
Dan: Yep. Yep. Uh, yeah. Thank
you, Bekah Elm. It was, uh, it
was Elm. That was the language I
was talking about. Um, the, Yes.
uh, I came up with, uh, on PHP,
uh, and it's even more absurd
than JavaScript in that regard.
It's got a lot better, but, um,
yeah. Uh, you know, the, you
never really know if it's going
to be like, if it's gonna
mutate. Object and place or
return a new
on it. It does both really. And
so, yeah, I see you like you
get,
you get the new one and you
think in cool, but you know, you
go
back to the old one, it turns
out that one's changed. It's not
fun.
Uh, PHP also has like, they, I
mean, they, like I said,
they've,
they've improved a lot, but, um,
you know, all these different
array functions, some of them
came from Perl and some came
from
like, C, and so named, like,
there was like, you never knew
if
it was gonna be array underscore
sort or like. With no array and,
you know, like all this
nonsense, uh, that I loved, but,
um, it was
very hard to deal with it as
well. Sometimes. Yes.
Jono: How do people write
programs back then? Like, I
don't
understand.
Dan: Yeah. Um, like lots of,
lots of, you know, trying and
failing
and lots of bugs that nobody
knows about until it's so much
later and you know, all that
sort of stuff, no tests, FTP,
you
know, hit save, and then FTP up
to the server and see if It.
works. Uh, that's how I did it.
Anyway. I don't know.
Bekah: When I was first building
my blog, I didn't know that you
could run things locally. And I
also didn't know, like, so I was
just like committing things and
seeing if they worked or not. So
I don't even want to go back to
when I first started that repo
because all of the stuff in
there is just me making like
these
minor tweaks or seriously
messing things up. Oh, how do
you want to
do that? Because I also didn't
know that you could take back to
meds. You can change things. It
was a, it was a wild time, I
think back then.
Jono: Yeah, I still make those
kinds of commits. Like I made a
bunch of commits where I'm just
like removing a trailing slash
just to see if like my HTML tag
is working properly. I'm like,
okay, well this isn't working, I
have no idea what I'm doing.
Dan: Yeah. That's all right.
That's what like squash merges
before, right. Just hide all
that stuff. Yeah, no, I was, um,
I was
working on the, um, um, get up
our, uh, I mean, I'm sorry, our
co-working sort of room, um, and
involves, uh, like a slack app
and a zoom app and Netlify
functions, um, up until a point
you can kind of point it to
local your local stuff. Um, but
eventually you have to like
point it to a server that you
have to
point the, the zoom app or the
Slack App, to a server. And that
was incredibly hard to test. I
was, I ended up doing. the same
thing. I was just like, I was
sending stuff up and have it,
you
know, deploy and then see if it
works. Um, I have A I have a
slack, like a test slack
workspace, you know, that's just
like, Dan's whatever test Slack
and, uh, there's like 4,000
Dan's
in there. Cause I was testing a
new, you know, like what happens
when a member joins, you know?
And um, if I didn't get it right
then I had. Make the change,
commit it, let it build and then
join again, you know, with the
new account and see if it works.
It's like the matrix with Agent
Smith is like, uh, it's just
like
a slack that's just full of a
thousand mes. Don't go there.
It's frightening. I'll say I'll
send you an invite. You uh,
yeah.
Oh
Bekah: So you also talked about,
um, doing videos. And so I
wonder
like one does, can you digital
garden videos? Is that a thing?
Is that like Instagram live? I
don't know.
Jono: Maybe.
Bekah: how does that like play
into this role of content
creation?
Jono: Yeah. Oh man. Interesting.
I, I would say digitally
gardening videos is harder. Then
writing because you have to do a
lot more editing in the video.
Um, you can't really just cut a
piece out and then like add a
new piece in it. Wouldn't like
tend
to make sense or missed, um,
Dan: Have you tried, have you
tried, uh, have you
tried,Descript yet for video
editing
Jono: I haven't. No, I've been
sticking with a
Dan: you can literally copy and
paste like text and it'll do the
video and the audio and
everything like really well. I'm
sorry. They don't, they don't
sponsor us or anything. I just,
I've just been excited about it
Jono: wondering. Yeah.
Dan: Sorry, I didn't mean to,
um, while I did, I guess I did
mean
to interrupt, but, uh, I didn't
want,
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: I didn't, I don't know why
I said, I don't know why like
interrupt on purpose and then
say, sorry, I didn't mean to
interrupt. Uh, anyway, um,
Jono: okay. No. You're good.
Yeah. I mean, yeah. I think
that's a really, there's so many
tools out there, which is great.
And like, I think Bekah
mentioned live streaming as
well, which I
guess like you can kind of pick
and choose Nicky T is doing a
really great job with live
streaming and he's kind of like
rolling with the punches and
learning Rust, which I think is
really cool. Um, I do think like
where, where I see video,
because
it is completely different
platform. It's kind of like
YouTube, so that. You can't
really curate YouTube videos as
easily. It's like that they own
that platform. So they tend to
show it how they want to show
it. Um, so it is a little bit
harder
in that sense,
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. And I think
with YouTube, you can't change
them
either. Right? I mean, if you
change them and then, then it's
a
new, you have to create a new
video and delete the old on or
so
you know, something like
Jono: right? Yeah. Although
yeah, exactly.
Dan: yeah.
Bekah: Create new ones.
Dan: That's interesting though.
Jono: Yeah.
Bekah: Now we're going to invent
digital gardening for videos
Jono: That would be cool.
Bekah: or it wouldn't at all.
So, okay. So you're doing these
videos and is this just kind of
along the same lines as what
you're doing with your digital
garden, your. Working on these
things, learning them, and then
just providing another avenue
for
people to kind of learn along
with you.
Jono: yeah, I think like, yeah,
exactly that, and it was also a
challenge for me, cause I'd
never really done video stuff as
well.
So at the start of the year, I
really wanted to kind of explore
it a little bit more. Um, and
then. Um, I kinda, uh, realized
that I really enjoy doing it. I
don't enjoy actually filming the
videos. It's really hard, or I
can't speak in front of a
camera.
Like, I don't know how people do
it. Um, but the whole process of
like editing and like getting
all the music and all that stuff
is,
is really fun. Um, so yeah,
it's, it's been a goal and a lot
of the
content is pretty similar to
what I would put in. The blog,
but it
does go through more in-depth
tutorials because I hate writing
about tutorials, but I think
showing is just a lot easier to
follow and a lot easier to
explain in my mind,
Dan: Yeah, that's, that's pretty
cool. and so you can I suppose,
yeah, you don't have to like
create all the screenshots or
the, uh, you know, grab the code
examples perfectly if you're
just
showing, you know, when you're
doing like a screen-share and
showing the, um, the app like in
place, right. Just take somebody
for a tour. I can totally see. I
can totally see how that it,
that
would be.
Jono: Yeah, and you can go on
like tangents and you can get
lost a little bit, and it's all
easy to come back to the main
thread. Then it isn't like a
blog, like you can't just write
like an extra thousand words on
a tangent and then expect them
to
like keep reading after that.
Okay.
Dan: You could, but, uh,
Bekah: I think I just, uh, wait,
I have to go back and delete
some
of my blog posts.
Dan: um, have you been doing,
I'm sorry if I might have
already
answered this, have you been
doing much streaming as well?
Um,
aside from the produced months,
have you dug into that?
Jono: no, I haven't. Um, I've
been thinking about it. I don't,
uh, we come back to Nick. Um, I
can't speak and like learn or
like do something at the same
time. So it really just be like,
it would just be silence. He
used to be watching me on my
computer.
It's a skill. I don't know how
you do that.
Dan: Yeah, no, it is. I've been,
I've been have been wondering
about that. too. I've been
thinking about, you know,
digging
a little bit, and this is paying
attention to myself. Coding,
not,
I wasn't streaming, you know,
but I was just like, oh, I
haven't
like talked to moved for like
three hours. Like this is not
going to be fun for anybody.
Bekah: I think, I think one of
the things that's about it is
it's nice if you can do with a
partner, because then they can
kind of fill in, like, Nick does
it with Christina and Seth and I
are going to be doing it in a
couple of weeks. Um, and the
first time Seth and I did it, it
was like I had not ever
live-streamed and I'm, I'm
terrified of it. Like it's not
something that I feel
comfortable doing and
immediately I froze up.
And Seth was right there, kind
of like talking through it,
like,
okay, well, this is what we're
going to do. And this is where
I'm like, okay, now I feel
comfortable and I can kind of go
along with it. And so to be able
to have that conversation, I
think makes it a little bit
easier because then you have way
less pressure on yourself to be
doing all of this.
Jono: 100%. That that makes a
lot of sense.
Dan: Yeah. I've, I've enjoyed
times when we just jump on a
zoom
or whatever, and, and people,
you know, like,if somebody posts
in
help and pairing or something.
It has a problem. Right. And
pairing
up, like doing the pair
programming and just sort of
recording it. I think that's,
you're talking about Bekah and
like, it's easier for me to ask
questions or to answer questions
then to like on a, don't think
of all possible questions and
then
produce content, you know, like
that, the, uh, the thought
process for me. Um, it's like,
um, I don't know, you know, you
just like answer what's in front
of you. Right. And then, and
then
just talk, but the, I feel like
when you're streaming, it's. Um,
the expectation is maybe it's a
little more okay. If you make a
mistake or if you, you know, um,
start saying something and then
you're like, oh, wait a minute.
I just remembered this other
thing.
Or, you know, something like
that. Um, a little more, like, I
don't know if it's a little more
into that. The it's okay to make
mistakes mindsets, right. It's
like not perfect mindset is the
streaming. Um, which I try to
remember to when I, when I
consider it and right, is, um,
it's like the work in progress
kind of thing. Um, I could see
how it could all fit, fit, fit
together, you know?
Jono: Yeah, I think that's the
beauty of live streaming as well
as the fact that you can kind of
make these mistakes and like let
other people see how you kind of
move on from there. Um, I think
with videos, um, I'm actually
trying to do a video where I'm
trying to show that process a
bit more. Um, but with videos it
is
very edited.
Dan: Right,
Jono: Um, so you don't see that.
Dan: right. Well, yes. If you
went onto YouTube and push play
on somebody's video, you
wouldn't want to see them
saying, um, you
know, I'm not really sure how to
do this, but like watching the
thought process in a stream, the
expectations a little bit, like
you go into a stream knowing
that it's live right. And
knowing
that. Probably going to be doing
that sort of thing. You know
what
I mean? Figuring it out in front
of you. And that's part of the,
part of the draw, I suppose. I
mean, definitely part of the
draw, but, um, a little bit
different mindset, I suppose,
when you're creating, you know,
as a creator. Right. Are you
going to add your videos to your
site, to the, to the digital
garden. Um, and in some way
Jono: Yeah. I, um, I had a, like
a fleeting thought about adding
like the most recent video. Um,
I think like, ultimately I'd
love
to create like a, a platform
where I can add tutorials like
my
own course platform kind of
thing, then have everything
just,
you know, work in one place,
Dan: Yeah, sure. Sure, sure. So
you have like a collection of,
uh, yeah. Step one, step two,
step three kind of thing. Yeah.
Jono: Yeah.
Dan: Um, that, well, I mean,
there's, I mean, I could, I
could
see that being fitting pretty
well into the digital garden.
You
know, I idea I could also see
it, you know, there's lots of
obviously lots of different, uh,
approaches to that, to that, um,
that that people have done. So
that's pretty cool.
Bekah: So for these, it seems
like you have a lot of you're
working on a lot of things that
you are learning about
personally. Um, and then when
you are, are working in your day
job,
you're working with rails,
right? And so how do you just
kind of
like make that jump back and
forth or, you know, are there
things that you're learning from
what you're learning that you
can
apply to your day job?
Jono: Yeah. I think like both of
that is like totally valid
point.
It's like jumping back and forth
between functional to like
object
paradigm is, is really hard
sometimes. Um, I'm not very good
at functional language, I guess
that helps, you know, like I
gotta have those like muscle
memory, um, yet. Um, but yeah,
there's definitely things you
can learn from all these
different
sources that, um, You can bring
into any new project, um, had
there a quote somewhere where
it's like, you never starting
anything from scratch. Like you
always taking those past
experiences with you. And I
think that's very true. Um,
whenever
I'm learning any of these new
things, is that from Vic as
well?
Bekah: I was going to say,
Jono: I'm like, gosh,
Bekah: I remember Vic talking
about that.
Dan: Yep. And we talked about
that with Sara, a bunch too, on,
on when, when she came on the
pod is, you know, I mean, she
came
from, you know, the agriculture
tech field and, uh, you know,
was
able to apply a lot of that, Um,
to her current. yeah. It's moved
from that to, well, FinTech, I
guess. But, um, I do like that
idea. We've talked about it
before, you know, it's that idea
of leaning on your past
experiences, you know, and how
it
can all be relevant, um,
relevant to you or to your
current, um,
platform. It's funny thinking
about that switch in between,
like when you're learning a new
paradigm sort of, and you have
an
old one, it's like that balance
point of when your muscle memory
tips over and you start actually
like reaching for functional
things when you're in back in
Ruby or, you know, uh, vice
versa. Um, When you're so when
you're learning, um, so this is,
uh, wait, I'm sorry. Oh, Elixir.
Right. Um, so you're learning
elixir. Do you find yourself
doing things like, um, how do I
do some Ruby thing in elixir
like that kind of Google, Google
search, a thought process, or,
or do you try to, um, sort of
erase
your mind for, for, for the
moment, you know, when you're
trying to learn a new thing, uh,
and, and do the, you know, pure
like elixir way or whatever, if
that exists.
Jono: Yeah. Um, Definitely have
a bad habit of like, how do I do
Ruby in X? Um, cause I'm just so
used to Ruby and Ruby and rails
and stuff. Um, but I think
they're getting into the weeds
of
the language is really
important. So like I'm trying to
like switch
our mindset to like, be more of
like, okay, how do I do this in
a
functional language rather than
how do I do it in Ruby and then
transport it over.
Dan: Yeah.
Jono: Um, yeah, and I, and I
know like in the Elixir slack,
people
talk about it a little bit,
where you run into a lot of
issues when
you try and just like port over
Ruby, into Elixir, like a lot of
things just don't make sense and
don't work. Like anti-patterns
almost
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. That's
interesting. Have you, uh, has
there been any like specific
things that you can think of
that
like you approaches you can take
when like back into the Ruby
world from, from the new stuff?
Jono: Yeah. Um, great question.
I think the biggest thing is
really
just the immutability aspect of
it. So like, you know, making
sure, like I am being really
explicit with what is changing
under the hood in Ruby has
really helped. And the Elixir
concurrency model is, um, I
would say like is built a little
bit
differently than how Rudy's
concurrency model work. So it's
all about passing messages and
not about changing the data
that.
Threads share. So kind of taking
that functionality into review
as
well. Um, at least on an
architectural level has really
helped.
Dan: Nice. That's cool.
Bekah: You are, you also
mentioned you had done some iOS
development early on,
Jono: yes. Yeah.
Bekah: have you, how has that,
okay, so you've done it. So you
did iOS and then Ruby, and now
you're learning Elixir. So is
there like a pattern that you've
seen that you've worked through
those changes or as you've grown
or things that you've learned
and
can apply as you learn the new
things?
Jono: Yeah. Um, well, I. Have
not touched iOS since late 2015.
And
that was like on the cusp of
like Objective C switching over
to
Swift. So I didn't even know
what the new IRS languages, um,
so I
think like I remember early on
the way I learned was really
just
about repetition. So it was
like, how many times can I run
rails
new and just like, understand
how all of that works. And then
I
remember having just so many
rails new projects with just
like
one model in there just to kind
of. Well, because I just never
finished some projects, but also
I felt like it helped build that
muscle memory of like what a
model looks like, where it goes,
how will this fits in? And now
I've started thinking about how
can I like shorts. I taught that
because it takes a really long
time. You just doing a lot of
repetition. Um, so really
thinking about how the pieces
fit together and making those
analogies from like previous
experiences. Um, like with
Elixir, obviously Ruby doesn't
always fit, but I, how. How
would
this look in object oriented and
what the differences are, has
really helped. Um, and then
finding the naming of things has
been really useful, both with
like onboarding, um, a new job,
just understanding what the
definitions are, and then also
with like learning languages,
because there's things you can
there's things I want to Google,
but cause I don't know the name
of the thing I'll be like, okay.
So question mark.in JavaScript,
like, which is that.
Dan: Um, yes, that syntax,
especially so hard to Google
for.
Um, wait, is that, see, now I
can't even remember. Is that the
newest one or is that. the, this
is every time I, I, I, I, uh,
Yes, learning new languages is
hard learning old, keeping up to
date with, um, you know,
languages that you've been
writing in for a long time. It
turns out also hard sometimes.
Jono: Just
Dan: Right? Learning, learning
is hard, but Yeah. that idea of,
um,
like learning the, the Google
language for language, um, it's,
I feel like a very interesting
concept and something that, um,
it's something that sort of. Uh,
the, the way that people who are
experienced with a language or a
concept, um, the way that they
Google for things is different
right. Than, than the way it's
somebody who's, who's learning
from scratch, you know, for
learning for the first time
does. And, um, I feel like
that's one
of the things that is cool. Um,
Show in like pairing or, or, um,
streaming, uh, is those Google
searches, you know, what are the
kinds of things I searched for?
Cause I, you know, in JavaScript
I'm like a pretty effective
Googler, you know what I mean?
And it's not, um, and I've done
this where, uh, I have in slack,
you know, if somebody is asking
for help, you know, and I've
tried to. Um, well, you know, I
find the answer pretty quickly.
Um, and then I'm like, here is
what I searched for to like,
find
that, I don't know. I never know
if that's helped like that.
It's,
it's probably not that, I mean,
seeing the process is probably
kind of helpful. I don't think
you can just like teach yourself
how to Google and JavaScript
before you, before you know it,
you know, I think it just comes
along with learning, but, um, it
is a, it is an interesting thing
that I don't think you think
about, um, often when you're,
when you're in the middle of it
or when you're trying to. You
know, trying to help somebody
learn, you know, things like
that. It's, uh, the, I wonder if
there's a phrase for that
because the Google language is
not that
doesn't like this, right. Not
very clear, but,
Jono: like how to Google that
Dan: how to Google and
JavaScript, you know, like,
Jono: Yeah.
Dan: um, but it is, uh, um,
Dan: I don't know. It is cool
that you mentioned that cause
it's a, you know, it is like an
important piece of of learning I
think is. Is finding out how to
find things out.
Jono: yeah. And it's, it's hard
to think about that sometimes as
well, because once you've done
it, a bunch of times, it becomes
almost like you just do it. It's
like a thing you're even
thinking
about. Um, but yeah. And then
trying to explain that to
someone
who's just starting, it's like,
there's a bit of a disconnect
that sometimes, um, it can be
really hard to explain.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. And
you know, when you're coming
from
a place where you. You know,
pretty experienced with some
language, right? I, uh, you
know, I feel like it makes
learning new
languages a little easier
because you have some, there is
like some
shared vocabulary across pretty
much all programming languages.
And so if you can remember some
of them, uh, the, you know, the
syntax will be different, but
the, the concepts, lots of times
will be the same, but you know,
like string string
interpretation
for, for instance, is, is a
thing. You know, what that means
in JavaScript is basically you
have one string and you can
stick
variables inside of it. Um, I
mean, that's what it means
everywhere. Right? And
JavaScript does it one way and
other
languages do a different way.
But if you Google, you know,
string
interpolation, elixir, you'll
probably find the answer right
away. And if you. But if you
can't remember that phrase,
which
is what happens to me a lot, you
know, then it's like, Okay. uh,
put two strings together with
variable, you know, it looks
there or whatever, and that
Google search will not be as
good, you know? And it's it's
an, I mean, this happens to me
because these phrases, as you've
seen during this, uh, pocket's
recording these phrases,
disappear from my brain, um,
very
quickly, uh, you know, and then
they come back, but. And it's
it's um, it's another thing
that's hard. I feel hard to when
you're learning, especially as a
beginner, um, that you don't
think about it as, you know,
like you have a power as an
experienced developer that you,
you know, you probably don't
realize.
Jono: Yeah. And it also Oak
place. Good.
Bekah: I was going to say, this
goes back to your point about
communication and you know,
you're writing and that's part
of
communication and learning how
to do that. But like even
Googling
is part of communicating, um,
being able to speak into the
world, what you need or what you
want. Right. And so sometimes.
It's easier just to go to a
group of people. Or I know like
yesterday I was working on how
do I get a slack reminder to
this
channel every single day? And
I'm like, well, I know Marie did
that. So I'm just going to ask
her first because it's late and
I
need to get right to the source.
And I know that she can point me
in the right direction. And she
did, she was like, this is what
I
look for. And it took me right
to where I needed to be. And so
sometimes, you know, knowing who
to ask the questions to. That
can
help you understand how to ask
them. The next time is a really
good step in communication and
in learning or, you know,
writing
whatever. But all of these
things are ultimately skills
that we all
need to be using.
Jono: yeah. Asking for help is
so hard as well. When you're
first
starting. I remember I did not
ask enough questions when I was
signed to learn Ruby on Rails.
And I felt like there was almost
this like stigma of like, it
felt bad to ask questions. Like
I had
to struggle with Google for a
bit before I did. Um, and yeah,
it
just, it's a terrible way to
learn. Like, just ask someone.
Dan: Yeah,
Bekah: it is really hard. Well,
and you went to university, so
you had the traditional English
classroom experience. And so I'm
curious, cause I'm a bootcamp
grad and I learned by myself. So
I don't, I didn't really have
that experience of people asking
questions around me. Did, did
that happen there? Maybe I'm
imagining in my head what, what
I think it would be.
Jono: Yeah. Uh, yeah, I mean,
people definitely ask questions
and those plenty of people that
are just like, Very, I guess,
questions with answers that just
went out of my head. Um, so
there's definitely a lot of
courses in uni that I have not
found that useful in real life.
Um, so yeah, it's both. It is
like, I guess it is time of told
him that, that, um, ability to
ask the right question.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean, I guess, I
mean, it's very different being
a, being in a university where
you're expected to ask questions
versus like in a job, it seems
like the stakes are a little bit
steeper or something. You know,
I know that a lot of bootcamp
grads
are like, yeah, I'm done with
bootcamp. Like finally, this is,
I can breathe in like No.
Jono: Please. Did you ask all
the questions?
Bekah: No. I mean, I didn't have
the opportunity to ask a lot of
questions, um, because it was a
self paced thing and there were
some opportunities for meeting
with people, but there weren't
that many, and I just didn't
really know about expectations.
Like, should I be working with
others, students on things? And
I
don't know, as a mom of four
kids. So some people would be
like, yeah, we're getting
together for five hours. Come.
No, I can't do that. Or that's
late and I wake up early because
I've got kids. So I just never
really kind of found, I think
maybe the group of people I
could have learned from in that
situation. Um, but I mean, we, I
talk about this all the time.
I've gotten a lot better with
communicating. I don't usually
spend. Many hours on the same
problem without asking a
question. And if I do, it's only
because of my stubbornness, like
I know I can get this, you know,
so that's, that's more of a me
problem, I think.
Dan: Okay.
Jono: Um, I think like you also
touched on a really great point
where it's like, you didn't
couldn't find the right people.
I
think finding a community,
especially when you're like just
starting out that really made a
lot of difference. Um, in my
learning journey was finding
like the code VB community and
then
getting a bit more involved with
like Ruby meetups and stuff,
just
so I can have the people around
me to actually also ask
questions.
Bekah: Yeah, and I love the Ruby
community. I really thought
after
boot camp, we did Ruby and rails
and I thought, well, that's what
I'm going to get a job in
because everybody was so nice.
And I
liked it and I understood it and
JavaScript and react. I was
like,
oh, this is awful. Um, and, and
here we are.
Dan: Yeah, JavaScript is
awesome.
Jono: here's a thing.
Bekah: it,
Dan: I feel it, JavaScript fits
my, you know, my way of doing
things, which is. Which is, you
know, out whatever.
Bekah: I mean, I really enjoy it
now. I like to be able to.
Problem solving the ways that
I'm doing and think about things
differently. It just, I think a
lot of it was, it just took me
time to understand all of the
things that we're talking about,
like how to communicate it and
how to understand it. And I
don't
know, people just seem less
friendly and JavaScript.
Jono: I think there's just a lot
more JavaScript developers and
no
knocking javascript, javascript
is a great language to use
everywhere. Um, but yeah,
there's just a lot of people
using it. So
you get a much wider range of
characters.
Dan: Yeah. And I think, uh, the
full stack nature of JavaScript.
So you can write in, you know,
Node and you can write in
whatever browser, you know, or
react to it. Everything is like
you say, you write JavaScript
and that doesn't even mean
anything
anymore. I mean, it means it
doesn't really tell you a lot of
information about what they're
actually doing. Whereas, you
know, if somebody is doing
rails. I can imagine pretty much
what
they're doing, you know, uh,
like from on a day to day, you
know,
uh, basis, you know what I mean?
It's like, if somebody says, oh,
I write Node, you know, okay,
that's cool. Like that means
you're doing some backend stuff.
Um, but maybe just, you know,
there's all those people are
writing in JavaScript as well,
you know? And all of the people
are writing reacts and all the
people writing Vue and just
writing vanilla JavaScript on,
you know, on simple webpages,
uh, In the same pool of people.
Right. So, um, and Java
JavaScript doesn't have like,
well, I don't know. The, you
know, Ruby started with at
least,
uh, or rails started with, you
know, that the, this sort of
community lead around rails, um,
that built up as well. I know
they had some struggles
recently, but, um, I feel like
that's, I
feel like, honestly, that's part
of the, um, and I'm not deep in
the Ruby community, so you can
correct me if I'm wrong, but I
do
feel like that was part of the
community. They. Back in, um,
when was that? 15 years ago or
something like that, uh, around
rails, you know, cause that's
when that's when I started
hearing about Ruby was when
rails, you know, um, got going
and, um, a lot of people just
kind of excited about the same
thing all at once, you know, in
a positive way.
Jono: yeah, a hundred percent.
Yeah. I mean, Yeah. Obviously
there's definitely some topics
to be discussed around rails and
the
community. But I think like a
lot of that started to, because
everyone wanted something better
than PHB. And I think it was
really groundbreaking at the
time. Um, and it still is like
everyone, there's still big
companies like Shopify. So you
still use as rails. Um, so yeah,
there's, I think a lot of people
kind of wanted that change,
especially from the Ruby
community.
Bekah: So I going to back up
maybe a little bit, just a
second
too. So we talked about, you
know, you're doing rails and
there's an expectation maybe of
what that looks like, but. Can
you walk us through what that
does look like, like
practically,
like what are you doing at work?
What does your day-to-day look.
Jono: Yeah. So I think the
day-to-day really is around. Um,
I think it's pretty similar to
most other jobs where you take
an
issue and you, you pick it up.
And, um, a lot of the rail stuff
is really just about connecting
with all our different, um,
Components. So we have kind of
this rails engine type
architecture. So just making
sure that and rails engine is
really
just like a library that you can
just like plug into your
application. Um, so making sure
those connections work, um, and
then using, we use graph QL a
lot Shopify. So I'm just like
learning about that aspect too,
and how everything kind of fits
together. I'm not sure if I
answered the question though,
Bekah: Um, I think that's,
that's a good way to think about
how,
how you're approaching your day
to day and what's going on. So I
feel like I don't want to leave
this podcast without giving you
a
huge shout out for sending me
Tim Tams,
Jono: You're welcome.
Bekah: changing experience. So
can you explain to everyone what
a Tim Tam is?
Jono: sure I can. They are an
Australian chocolate biscuit
that
is covered in chocolate. And the
two layers of the biscuit also
has chocolate in between the two
layers. Um, so it's pretty
amazing. And there's different
flavors in Australia where you
can get different stuffings in
the middle. Um, you get double
coat. I think I sent you a
double coat
Bekah: did send me a double.
Okay.
Jono: Yeah. Okay. Which is like,
Just a thick layer of chocolate.
It's yeah. It's, uh, it's been
really good. I've been rationing
them out as well. We've like,
we're almost out
Bekah: Which I should have
ration them out. I will not tell
you how
many of them I ate for breakfast
every
Jono: Yeah.
Bekah: Okay. So do you prefer
the double dip tip and Tams or
the
single
Jono: the double K for sure um,
but
Bekah: enjoyed the single here.
Jono: Ooh, interesting. I just
love the more chocolate to swing
one chocolate. Um, sorry, Dan.
I'll just send you something
Dan: Yeah, no, I'm just, uh,
Bekah: missing
Dan: Tim, Tim Tam -less over
here.
Bekah: glad there are not Tim
Tams and Kroger because
Dan: sounds dangerous.
Bekah: they are very dangerous.
Jono: it was so easy and it's
not that many in a pack.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: there were not enough
Jono: Yeah.
Bekah: simultaneously asleep too
much. Do you now, do you eat
your
Tim Tams with tea? Because I
heard that's how you should do
it, but I had mine with coffee.
Jono: Yeah. Um, so I think tea's
the way you go. You probably
have
the coffee. I just not sure. I
guess coffee chocolate would be
a
pretty nice flavor combination.
Um, but there's a thing called
the Tim Tam Slam where you bite
it, like each end of the Tim Tam
and you like suck the tea or
coffee through the Tim-Tam like
a
straw and it like melts the
chocolate a little bit. And then
you just like shove the whole
thing, your mouth, and you just
have like a multiple and
chocolate with some crunchy
texture and also the flavor of
the tea or coffee.
Dan: Sounds amazing.
Jono: Yeah. It's very messy.
Bekah: I feel
Jono: You have to find that
Bekah: stream coming up or where
you're going to be trying out
some
Dan: Yeah, we gotta, we gotta,
we gotta, get some to some
people
and we'll do a group, you know?
Bekah: wasn't like I fully
intended to save them for
virtual
coffees and have them a little
bit at a time just going to do
it.
Jono: that they're just too
good. Yeah. There's a balance
with Tim
Tam slams. I've definitely
waited too long in the toughie,
in the
tea dunk and the whole Tim Tam
just like slid off and I've been
like, well, now I just have a
Tim-Tam in my, and that's less
delicious.
Dan: Oh, practice. Right. And
practice a little,
Jono: Yeah, exactly.
Bekah: I've got a practice.
Jono: It's like the best
practice you could do.
Dan: a man. That sounds really
good.
Bekah: We're going to do that at
our conference. We'll do some
Tim-Tam slams. That'll be a
Dan: Yeah, can we get, uh, I
mean, we should reach out it's
Tim-Tam um, sorry, a brand or,
or like a, you know, a product
that
a brand makes.
Jono: it's a product that a
brand makes so on. It is the
brand, um,
Dan: So that's what we should
reach out to you for a sponsor.
Jono: Exactly.
Dan: Either get the podcast
sponsored by we'll just start it
start every podcast episode with
the Tim Tams.
Bekah: they don't have to give
us money. They just need to
Jono: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah, no, no, no.
Bekah: that's it.
Jono: Oh yeah. That'd be
amazing. I could be, yeah, Tim
Tams
little. They also have. So, if
you take a flight back to
Australia, they'll have like
little single pack, Tim Tams
that
they give you as like, you know,
the plane snack food. So we'll
have that in the VC swag bag.
Dan: Oh
Bekah: Yes,
Dan: Yep.
Bekah: so many great ideas.
Dan: Good.
Bekah: Okay. So I feel like
that's a, a really, oh man. I
was
going to punt so bad right
there. I'm not going to do it.
Nope. Not
doing it. It's a really great
way to wrap up the podcast. I
think,
um, with something, Nope. Still
somebody stopped me from
putting,
Dan: need more puns on this
podcast. I'm I'm pro I'm pro pro
pro pun.
Bekah: I could embrace that. No.
Did you just say no?
Dan: I did not. I, I was I'm in
favor, as I said,
Bekah: Okay. All right.
Dan: a bus just drove. I don't
know if that's what you heard.
Bekah: the bus said no, the
universe has
Dan: I just ignore it. I just
ignore what the, what the bus
says outside it's you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Okay.
Bekah: That seems like the right
thing to do. Um, anyway, thank
you for the Tim Tams and thank
you for being on the podcast. I
feel like, uh, this was a really
good exploration of the digital
gardening and learning and
growing, and this was a lot of
fun. So thanks for
Jono: Yeah, thanks so much for
having me.
Dan: Yeah. Um, yeah, I'll also
add my thanks. It was fun.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, plus you
can sign up for our newsletter
to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a
review. Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.