Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode two of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we are here to
share it with
you here with me today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today we are
joined by Abby Perini, a full
stack web developer, and a
delightful human being about the
impact building and public has
had on her developer journey.
Uh,
what our experience as a
recruiter taught her and how
rehearsing before an interview
can actually make a big impact.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Virtual Coffee we
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do and a random check-in
question. Today's question is,
would you rather be stuck on a
broken ski lift or a broken
elevator? We hope you enjoy this
episode. my name's Bekah. I am a
front end developer from a small
town in Ohio. And if I had to be
stuck on a broken ski lift or
broken elevator, it depends if
we are allowed to add conditions
to
that, I really do not like
heights. So I would not want to
be stuck up very high.
Abbey: Yeah.
Bekah: I feel like I've seen
enough movies where you can
escape a broken elevator. So if
I had to choose between a high
ski
lift or broken elevator, I would
MacGyver it out of the elevator.
Dan: Um, yeah, that's, that's a
good point about escaping it.
It's like, but I feel like
that's also like bad guys can
come in
that way too and stuff, you
know? So you
Bekah: Are there bad guys in
this scenario? Because.
Dan: Well, you got to always be
ready, but I mean, if you're
stuck in an elevator, then, you
know, bad guys are probably
coming, you know, that's just
like one of the things
Bekah: I think I still would
rather be in an elevator than a
high ski lift with bad guys. How
do you get out of that?
Dan: Oh, I mean, if you're stuck
on a ski lift and there's bad
guys around, you just stay there
cause they can't get to you, but
the elevator, they can just go
down
Bekah: Why can't bad guys get to
you on a ski lift climb
downloads. You have thing
Dan: Uh, oh yeah. You mean like,
oh, hand over hand, like monkey
bars kind of like scoot down.
Well, you'll be able to see them
coming along the way.
Bekah: I wonder, like if you had
a shirt and you wrapped it
around
the ski lift thing, can you
slide down?
Abbey: like a zip line.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. Can you make
a zip-line that I might
Abbey: that's making your case
for the escaping the ski lift
though.
Bekah: Yeah. Well, I might be
okay if I could make a zip line,
then I might be okay with trying
to escape the ski lift.
Dan: Um, all right, we're going
to move on. Uh, I'm Dan, I am a
front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio. And, um, yeah,
so my answer is ski lift for
sure. Um, I've actually jumped
off a stuck ski lift before, uh,
when I was snowboarding, um, we,
we were like kind of close-ish
to the thing. And we were in the
part where like the snow had
been it, a big pile of like
loose
snow. And so we, we just like
toss our boards off and. Uh, in
high school. And so I have
escaped the stuck, stuck ski
lift
before. So, um, that's easy, but
yeah, I mean, going back to the,
the, like the bad guys and
stuff, it's like the visibility
thing is
really my, you know, if you're
stuck, you just kind of know
what's going on, but you're
stuck in an elevator. You can't
see
anything there's just buttons.
And you don't know if it's a
computer that's stuck or like a
mechanical thing or whatever.
And
you're just in a little box. And
I feel like my guess is that
movies have misled all of us.
The panel that's up there in the
ceiling, you know, in every
movie. Cause I've looked up, you
know, sometimes in elevators you
look up and there's never a
panel
like that. So, I mean, it's
possible. I'm just going in the
wrong elevators,
Bekah: and elevators. You just
got to take that drop ceiling
and
Dan: maybe, maybe, but also we
all just know that movies, you
know,
Abbey: they do
Dan: lie about that sort of
thing.
Abbey: They lie about a lot of
things.
Dan: My, uh, Ben asked me like,
how do people fall on bananas?
Because.
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: He saw it in curious
George, I think. And I'm like,
well, you
know, they're kind of squishy
and stuff or whatever, but also
like,
literally I've never seen that
happen in my entire life
Bekah: peel, not, not going to
lie. I've got enough kids that I
believe I have fallen on a
banana peel in is slippery.
Dan: I'm just
Bekah: So can confirm you, just
let them know.
Dan: movies, like bananas. I can
see bananas being slippery, but
just like, as a reg, as like a
thing that always happens, you
know, it's like,
Abbey: It's not as frequent as
movies would leave. You lead you
to
Dan: Right. Exactly.
Abbey: And on that note, I'm
Abby, I'm from Atlanta. I'm a
full stack web developer on
month, two of my first developer
role. And, uh, I have also been
stuck on a ski lift before, so
I'm going to pick ski lift, um,
and I've seen enough horror
movies to never pick elevator
like that. The whole pregnant
lady walks into an elevator
she's immediately giving birth.
That's.
Bekah: I feel like I would Excel
in that situation. I would
deliver that baby.
Abbey: You would, I believe it
you're a champion
Dan: if the question is, would
you rather help a baby be
delivered on a stuck ski lift or
a stuck elevator? I'm going to
Abbey: then we're Yeah. we're
voting elevator because movies
have led us to believe, but it
happens perfectly fine
Dan: that'll work out. Yeah,
right. Um, I would, I don't
Bekah: It would be hard to catch
a baby in a ski lift. Yeah.
Abbey: Can confirm..
Dan: yeah, that's what I'm
saying.
Abbey: I just, yeah, I also
don't like Heights, but for some
reason, ski lifts are fine.
Cause like you're strapped into
the
chair and you're just swinging
in the cold air. Well, no one is
coming to rescue You It's fine.
I was not close to the ground
and
also like eight. So it was not
happening. We just got to
experience the views for a very
long time.
Bekah: It's like, what is a
Ferris wheel? Right? Like if
you're ever on a Ferris wheel
and then they're unloading the
Ferris
wheel and you get stuck at the
top forever. I don't like that.
That's that's enough. I could
probably climb down a Ferris
wheel. I
Abbey: I panicked on one of the
swingy boats one time and like
the older I get the closer to
the ground, my vertigo kicks in,
which is very unfortunate. And I
know my aunt has it. So I'm
screwed.
Bekah: Oh,
Dan: no.
Abbey: Um,
Bekah: well, welcome to the
podcast. went through 10
different versions of that
question. So now everyone is
very
well versed in how we would
respond to various scenarios of
that,
Abbey: thought about all the
angles
Bekah: all of them. Um, so we
would love to start by exploring
your origin story, how you got
to this point, what you have
done
and where you're at now.
Abbey: This is funny. Cause like
once a week, Kirk is like your
origin story just keeps growing
because
Bekah: Yeah.
Abbey: I have a lot of hobbies
of dabbled in a lot of things.
Um,
Bekah: about being a DJ. And I
did not see that on anything
that
I've seen about you. So that is
new to me.
Abbey: Yeah. I did. Uh, I was on
WSPF FM, Clemson for about three
and a half years. Um, did a
bunch of cool shows. I have an
award.
That wall for like most unique
radio show because we did radio
plays, but that's not my origin
story for programming. Um, so
let's see, I had been working in
recruiting the recruiting
industry and for the recruiters
out there, I did high volume MSP
recruiting for five years. Um,
and about year two or three, I
was like, okay, well, it doesn't
look like I'm going to be the
manager of a team anytime soon.
Cause we're not growing like
that. And it also. Doesn't look
like I'm getting anything I want
outside of the company, because
my resume being a psychology
major with a minor in economics,
just kind of sales roles and
MLMs
is what comes up. So I started
applying within the company and
like seeing if I could find
anything outside the company.
And
by March, 2020, um, I had been
rejected from a role I knew
inside the company that I knew
was like the best way for me to
move within the company. And I
was perfectly qualified and I
wasn't getting anything. So it
had become very clear that I
needed to do. Something else,
like I needed to get training or
something. And I had been
looking at data science and full
disclosure. I'm not great at
math that looked like you needed
another degree. So I got of
stalled out there. And then my
husband said, well, what about
web development? Like, you're
good at making things pretty.
You like colors, you'll move a
box
pixel by pixel. I can tell that
already. And I was like, yeah,
you know, all right. So I
started looking and there was a
bootcamp.
That kind of checked all the
boxes. Cause with the data
science boot camps, I already
had a list of questions that
would
fail a bootcamp. Like you're not
getting my money. Do the
teachers
care about the students? No. Are
probably not doing that. And uh,
so I, I w I was talking to Dan
before the podcast started about
how I used to be very much a
planner. So, um, I was like, all
Right. well, it's March. I got
in, I'm going to do this. And.
October, I'm gonna start
studying this pre-work that they
gave me,
which was like pretty in depth.
I spent six months doing all of
the
pre-work, which no one else did
no one, no one else even looked
at the pre-work as far as I
know. So by the time I walked
into the
bootcamp, I knew HTML, CSS,
Python, and synchronous
JavaScript. And, uh, we started
with going back through Python.
And then HTML and CSS. And then,
uh, we started into async
JavaScript and then like, you
know, react. We did some, uh,
templating before react, stuff
like that. Um, And during the
bootcamp, when I thought I was
going to be like, you know, it
was it front end and like, you
know, passable at everything
else, I guess. Cause I don't,
I'm an overachiever. I knew I
was
going to at least pass. Um, it
turned out that I just love
programming. Like I love
full-stack. I love everything
from back to front I, anything,
anyone tosses at me is just
another puzzle to solve and. I
just, you know, the relief that
floods in when you take a leap
like that. Cause I quit my job
in
August, 2020 after this is not
the most coherent version of my
backstory, but after a man
argued with me about the date of
the day
we were experiencing currently
in the same time zone, via
email,
which has the date in it, he was
like, No. you're wrong. Your
candidates not getting an
interview. You're you're
talking.
The wrong day. And I was like,
no, I'm not,
Dan: Oh, no.
Abbey: I'm really not. And, uh,
so then I moved the bootcamp up
a
month and quit my job, um, in
the bootcamp, obviously
everything
loved it. And then, um, the
founder had actually challenged
us to write four blog posts. By
the time we were done with
bootcamp, which was four months
long. And. Again, overachiever.
I
was like, thank you for
personally giving me a goal. And
I started writing blogs. And the
first one that I was like, oh,
people actually seem to like the
blogs I'm writing was an
animated
CSS button that I was just like,
oh, I love animated CSS buttons.
Look, you click it. It moves.
Isn't this great everyone. And
everyone was like, you know
what? This actually is kind of
great.
And I was like, oh, great. And
kept running. And then I think
around the time that I joined
Virtual Coffee was when I had my
portfolio. I had that blog get
top seven on dev Tio, all that
stuff, and just completely blown
away because it's just literally
just me being like, I love
programming. Oh, I'm going to
write a blog about this thing
that I like about programming or
the one that is, has the most
like staying power is the one
where I was like, there's not a
straightforward example of this
anywhere. It's react. Here have
an example with Shebaz in it.
That's my goal to put more
Shebas and programming. Uh, it
took. Me
about three months to get a job
after graduating bootcamp. And I
did that almost exclusively
through, uh, networking, um, the
blog building in public, um,
which I recommend. And, uh, mark
Noonan who's part of Virtual
Coffee, looked at my stuff and
was like, oh, You're doing
great. And, um, I went through
an
interview process with him and,
uh, when I posted my website
itself on LinkedIn, that also
got like 8,000 views on
LinkedIn,
which I don't know where that
stands in ACA in LinkedIn stats.
But, uh, my old boss saw it and
that's how I have my current
role
because she put my, uh, resume
back in the cycle of my old
company. And now I'm working. I
quit in August 22. I was a
recruiting admin. Technically my
title is talent services
manager,
and I joined Ronstadt again in
April as a software application
developer, which is pretty
awesome.
Dan: That that's very awesome.
It's um, I love that the, the
bootcamp was, was helping you
with the goal of, you know,
writing blogs and stuff, because
I think that's, I don't hear
about that very often. And, um,
some of the. People that I've
talked to, um, over the last
year or whatever that have come
out of
bootcamps. Um, the, the ones
that I feel like the ones that
I've
had a lot of success, uh, have
parents that like a lot of their
learning with writing. Um, and
it's been pretty cool.
Abbey: They also did. Um, like
you had to have your LinkedIn up
to date, you had to have a
resume that was, uh, applicant
tracking
system compatible, that kind of
stuff, which is good. Uh, I wish
we had done more algorithms or
they had told me that I could
just not do algorithms for
interviews. I just turned down
interviews with algorithms.
Dan: Did you yet? So that was,
did you run into that a lot when
you were interviewing.
Abbey: Yeah. I cried every
single time someone sent me a
time
browser ID algorithm, and like I
can program, I can build things.
I, if you and I, if the three of
us sat down and you were like,
Abby, we need to write an
algorithm together. I'd be like,
yeah. Okay. Let's do it. If you
send me a link, it has a timer
and it's an algorithm. I just
cry.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, I can totally
see that. I mean, the, the timer
like kicking off of the wrong,
the wrong chemicals in your
brain,
Abbey: Yeah. And like, I think
we did, I think we were supposed
to
do it every Friday and we just
ended up doing like a handful of
days. We were supposed to solve
some algorithms and I was
solving
them. Uh, fast. They weren't
like really good at doing things
fast,
but they were solved and I
thought that was sufficient. And
then it would be like, here's
the first step of an interview
process. You desperately want
this job for some reason you're
terrible at this thing that has
nothing to do with the job that
you're trying to get. Uh, it's
just, you know, C feel that real
hard. And the February, the dark
February before I found Virtual
Coffee and I was just sitting in
my house unemployed during the
pandemic.
Dan: You mentioned that you wish
somebody told you, you could
just
turn down interviews that have
those, is that advice you would
give to people like now that
you've kind of been through it a
little bit,
Abbey: Yeah. definitely. If you,
if you like, if it's just a
cycle
of you failing, don't engage in
that cycle. Like, uh, the two
offers I got, neither of them
required me to do a time
algorithm and. Like that just
may be that you do a lot more
networking than you do, uh,
throwing your resume into the
void, which you know, is, you
know, better. I'm not, I've got
a
whole blog out there that says
that you can do the throwing
resume into the void thing. It
is possible. I've seen people
get
seen many people get jobs that
way. They also apply to
somewhere
between 400 and a thousand jobs.
So.
Dan: Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: A really good point to
make, because I think that there
are so many different approaches
and you have so much different
information coming at you about
what the interview process
should
look like. And. Plenty of people
out there that there that say,
oh, learn how to code in three
months and then you'll have a
job. Right. And maybe that
happened for them, but that
certainly is not the story for
most people. And so talking
about
that and talking about, you
know, turning down interviews,
like
that's scary for a lot of people
or at least shifting your
mindset
to, um, it's not. It's a
practice interview, right? Like,
I'm going
to go into this because I need
practice interviewing and if
something happens great, if it
doesn't I got practice. Right.
Abbey: Yeah. One of my mentors,
Asana was like, it's a. It's
every interview is practice for
the one that works. It's exactly
like sports. Like you're just
like pretend it's the one every
time, but this is also practice
for the time that it actually
works. And, uh, I had another
point about. Oh, Yeah. I had, I
had the privilege to go to a
bootcamp and quit my job. And my
husband was like, it's okay if
you don't get a job immediately.
But I was putting a lot of that
pressure on myself. So I was
extremely desperate for jobs. So
that's coming from someone that
knows the pain, but B had the
option to do it this quickly and
do it in this manner. Like if I
didn't have that, I definitely
would be like, okay. Yeah. Just
start teaching yourself to code,
start building, start building
in public and expect it to take
years. But I like stuff I put
out on the internet. I got job
offers
from startups for that. Knitting
is programming job or knitting.
Knitting is programming blog.
Like you never know it's luck
and
timing, especially.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's so
important. Go ahead, Dan.
Dan: yeah. Luck in timing. But
also, I mean, also the, I don't
know exactly what the right word
is, but sort of consistency of,
of doing the, like actually
applying the learning. Um, like
you said, and I suspect that
some people, um, wait on that
part,
wait on blogging because they're
still learning or because they
maybe feel like they don't, um,
have anything new to, you know,
like to talk about or, or, um,
or whatever. But my, I just love
seeing people like, like either
have come through and we're
blogging just like from the
start and. Actually leaning into
the
learning right. And learning in
public part. Um, because it's,
it's great. And I, it, it
expands your borders. It helps
you learn.
Um, and like I said, the
networking and everything like
that, it just kind of comes
along for free. Right. When
you're,
when you're, when you're doing,
putting the work in. Um,
Abbey: And when you joined the
Virtual Coffee,
Dan: And when you joined Virtual
Coffee,
Abbey: The Sheba counter blog. I
referenced earlier. My thought
when I hit publish was man, I
just really hope I don't sound
like a, like a really dumb book
enter or something. And like,
people are learning from that.
Like, you don't have to be.
Perfect. You don't have to be a
senior. You don't have to be an
expert. Just start writing, just
start putting it out there. And
like when, um, I, I struggle
with confidence. That's the
reason
that I was able to give a whole
talk and blog on what, like how
I
built up the confidence for the
job search. And the first thing
I
did was I applied. I started
applying to developer jobs. I
didn't even have a portfolio. I
didn't have an ATS compatible
resume. I was immediately
rejected and I was like, oh,
that's the worst? Application
I'll ever do. I was wildly
under-qualified. I had no idea
what I was doing. So now every
application after that slightly
better doing great. And it was
the difference I saw between
when my resume had a portfolio
that
was a template. And when Myers
may had a portfolio that I wrote
was really impressive. And like,
I've heard that from other
people
and that doesn't, it doesn't
have to be a perfect portfolio,
but
they'll look to see whether or
not you. Built it, if you're a
web developer, that's, that's
the copy. I have, I am my web
developer.
Dan: Yeah,
Bekah: I think that, I don't
remember. I was going to say.
Abbey: I definitely have to
like, be like, okay, here are my
points.
Dan: So what kind of things did
you put on your portfolio when
you were like, when you were
first applying when you were
applying for jobs?
Abbey: So I had four projects
that I had to do for bootcamp.
Um, I S I started seriously
applying when I had three on
their belief. Maybe we did five
projects. There was one that I
didn't include because I wasn't
happy with the result and it was
a group project. Um, so I have.
For a while until I had my
portfolio, I did just a straight
here's an, uh, an old nineties
XML site converted to a HTML CSS
site, like pixel for per pixel.
And then like, here's how I made
it responsive. Here's how I did
this, which was like a side.
Like a, like an extra assignment
that
they had given us that not many
people did, because I was like,
I
know basic issue your own CSS.
I'll just do all the fun stuff.
It was that, uh, and, uh, then I
think it was all react to
projects. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: that's cool. I was just
asking, because I was, I don't
have like a portfolio at all and
like, I'm not, I'm not applying
for jobs or anything right now,
but I never even know what kinds
of things go on them anymore.
Abbey: Yeah, I mean, if you've
built something and you're like
this shows, well, I mean, we can
go into how I pitch your
experience to employers, but
like, uh, yeah. As long as it's
something is like, this shows
that I can do this technological
concept,
Dan: I guess my,
Abbey: go on your portfolio.
Dan: point was, was going to be
if I was, and this is true, the
first time I hired a junior, um,
and it was back up, but like
the,
that I don't, I have no idea if
he even had a portfolio at that
point, or if I looked at it or
not, but I definitely looked at
the blog. This is what I mean,
like. Projects that you do in
school or in boot camp and stuff
are like good. And, you know,
it's good to share, but if you
have like writing about those
projects, that is like, you
know, tied with the portfolio,
um, or
just that are happened to be on
your blog, you know, that's
Abbey: I don't know that my
current employer even looked at
my blog. I got asked in-depth
questions about every single one
of my
Dan: your, your current,
Abbey: this work? Yeah,
Dan: I'm sorry. So they looked
at the portfolio, but they
didn't
Abbey: they looked at the
portfolio, but they didn't look
at the. bug. No.
Bekah: And I think, I think it
depends too, because I've
certainly been in interviews
where people have just mentioned
my blogs or have just mentioned
podcast episodes that I've been
on that they've listened to. And
so I think, you know, having a
balance or trying to do all of
those things. Can be really
important. And then I know we
had to write for flat iron
school
blog posts, and a lot of people
were not happy about having to
write those posts. And for some
people it's a, it's a very
different skill. It's like,
well, I'm learning this skill to
code.
And now you're asking me to do
this rather than thinking of it
as this is a tool for
networking, or this is to
demonstrate how you
can communicate something. Um,
so it can be overwhelming. And
an
additional skill that you feel
that you have to learn, but I
think just trying is worth it
because it does grow your
network
of people and the people that
you can talk to about these
things.
Abbey: Well, and to that point,
uh, I w I went to a middle in
high school that like, if I
didn't know how to write, like
that was a problem. So. I've
I've just been like, Hey, people
are
actually like interested in my
writing that I've always had to
do for every aspect of my life.
And I've never been complimented
on it before. Um, But the thing
that we're all ignoring is your
GitHub, because that can show
all of these things. And more
like if
you're reading, these are
descriptive and that's just you
describing exactly how this
technology works. That's totally
fine. If you've got a bunch of
projects in there that you
haven't blogged about. Like I
had an interviewer pull up my
GitHub
repos and have me walk him
through step-by-step over the
phone, a bunch of those stuff.
So like, Use the tools you're,
you're fancy you're on the
internet you're program or use
the tools that you have.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: your bootcamp talk about
writing, read MES.
Abbey: Yeah, we were, uh,
strongly encouraged. It wasn't
necessarily required, but like
we had to have a good get hub
profile that had, uh, the, the
headers were a thing by the time
I start. Yeah. Let's talk about
how, how spoiled I am. There's
always been Flexbox there's
always been. Um, so they're,
they're getting hub remains and
it was like, put like a picture
of you and like some description
of your stuff, bare minimum. And
then every single project it
would end and our teacher would
be like, so go make sure you
read me it's up to her to like
And he
really stressed a lot of things
like, um, make sure that anyone
going to your get hub can
immediately with like a minute.
Or a maximum of two clicks, get
into your app and play around
with it. If it's something
that's on your portfolio. And he
strongly suggested having like a
guest login for everything, and
you read me, filled out with
screenshots and walkthroughs so
that they didn't even have to go
to the live app and all that
stuff. His was, his whole career
was built around, like he does
Udemy. LinkedIn courses. And at
this point, people will call him
and ask him to do a job, having
just seen those courses and be
like, oh yeah. I mean, I know,
you know what you're talking
about. So.
Dan: Yeah, I think that's great
advice if you, I mean,
especially
if you have a project like that,
because lots of times you see.
Projects and, you know, I
suppose this is more of in
tutorial and
then in, um, uh, maybe in a boot
camp, but you see somebody
learning and doing a project,
you know, an example project.
And
it's hard to tell sometimes if
it's just been cloned from the
example, or, you know, if
they've, if a person has just
been going through the steps and
pasting in, um, or if they. Done
a lot of the work, you know,
and, and the steps that you're
describing, I think go a long
way towards, um, solving that,
you
know, and actually displaying
like that you have done this
work
and you do understand this
project and you do understand
like why it does what it does.
Um, et cetera. I like the idea
of.
Abbey: We keep talking about my
fancy blog, but let's be clear.
That's me being like, oh, I
built this thing here was my
first step
code block. Can't my second step
code block. Like it's. And then
I
was like, why are people
responding to this so much? And
then I see other blogs that are
just like code black code black
code block. And I'm like, oh, so
just say the steps you took and
people will believe you I'm like
your blog. This is the secret to
my success.
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: no, go ahead, Bekah.
Bekah: I was just going to say
one of the tips that I got when
I
was starting to apply for jobs
was to create, um, a short walk
through of each of your
projects. And actually somebody
had told me
if you're not very confident in
the code that you wrote
sometimes. Linking to the video
is better because you can talk
about it. If you're confident in
how you talk about it. They're
probably not going to ask you
questions about what you did
with
their code, with your code. So I
don't know. I mean, it makes it
like a quick reference point.
You can talk through things, but
also
that might be another way to
communicate what you've been
working on.
Abbey: Uh, I'm going to go ahead
and credit my husband with, uh,
how good I am at describing my
projects to people. Not great.
Let's be clear. Uh, we had to do
presentations of all of our
projects for the bootcamp. And I
was the only one that got
prompted to like explain the
business case at night. Like
maybe talk slower.
Bekah: Right.
Abbey: So there were times where
he like watched the recording or
something. Cause I'd be like, I
just like, what am I doing
wrong?
And he was like, so all these
people are spending five minutes
on one. That's like a fraction
of any of the features that
you've
built in here. And you're going
through everything, everything
in
the same amount of time, like
you need to actually explain how
difficult things are to like
figure out and like your process
and like aspects of the code
that you enjoyed writing or
didn't
enjoy writing or stuff like
that. And applying that to
interviews.
A whole nother step, because if
by the time I was in my final
interviews, like I had rehearsed
all of my answers so much, which
is another point, um, that I
wasn't like, I was like
exhausted
in my last interview and had all
the answers and it went fine
because I was just not panicked
and practiced all of this. And.
If you, Yeah. Explaining your
code to people, especially like
link, explain your code to your
dad. Like you don't have to use
all of the technical concepts,
but explain that you wrote, like
you had to sit there and write a
button that would listen for a
thing and then do this thing and
response. And once you can start
explaining it to lay medic, it's
a lot easier to then jump into
all of the heavy technical
concepts. When someone asks you
in an interview.
Dan: I love that. I, I, uh, I
was going to say, and this is
just
going to tie back. Great to, I
keep saying about how great it
is
to write, but somebody, I can't
remember if it was on our
podcast
or a different one, but it was
talking about, um, the writing,
a
blog post about that. Like, if
you wrote a blog, post
explaining
kind of the steps that you did
for a project, um, it helps you
be prepared for when somebody
asks you about it, you know, and
it's just like the, maybe even
just a script for your answer.
It
helps you talk about it more.
Um, Uh, I dunno, thoroughly and,
you
know, with more detail, um, and
probably also help you remember
if you have it, you know,
helping you remember the steps.
Cause if
I wrote something a year ago and
somebody asked me to talk about
it, I, if I hadn't done any
prep, I would be like, uh, I
don't
know. Well, let's go look at it
and see,
Abbey: let's be clear in
interviews. I've been like, uh,
that was four months ago. I
wrote a lot of code in between
now. And
then can you give me like a
little bit more specific on your
question, please come. What are
you, what answer are you looking
for For me? And I've got what
two blog posts talk now where
pretty
much my answer to everything is
practice. Practicing the thing,
practicing the thing without any
caveats, like you wrote a thing,
it doesn't have to be like, oh,
I didn't write the complete
thing
and I didn't write this and I
didn't write that. Like, you
can,
you can have that anxiety
yourself if you want, but
there's
no point in telling an
interviewer because he's the
only
person, like the only thing they
care about is you coming in to
the role and being able to do
that same thing.
Dan: For
Abbey: And like, at that level,
so.
Dan: I think that's great. I
get. For me personally having,
or even
just outlined having this sort
of thing down, um, helps me
because
I just go like galaxy brain
immediately, you know, and I get
caught up, you know, my brain is
like hopping all over the place
and if I'm just, and I'm sure
packets listeners have heard me
do this on the podcast, but, uh,
my, you know, not having
something to follow my brain
just goes all over the place and
with
code in, you know, it's. Uh,
there can be a logical way to
walk somebody through and there,
but if you just go follow every
import or something, and you're
like, well, this component, you
know, and then he gets
sidetracked and blah, blah,
blah,
blah, blah. I don't know. So
having it all written down and
practicing it, it's just such
great advice.
Abbey: Yeah, I uh, I talked
about being prompted to give the
business case and that's because
like very frequently, like on a
daily basis, I'll tell a story
with exactly zero context. I'm
just assume people are in my
brain and know what I'm talking
about to the point that like our
friends will just stare at me
the
one that. You know, married to
someone like me and be like, and
Matt will be like, so here's
what she's trying to say. Here's
where
she got the idea from here's
what's happening. And I learned
from interviewers mid interview,
rant, rant, rant, rant, rant,
rant, rant, rant, about code. So
to summarize my top three things
that I would use in the answer
to
this question, this point, this
point, and this point, and the
level of understanding and
interviewers faces went up
exponentially.
Dan: Yeah.
Abbey: And there are times where
very kind interviews. Prompt me
to be like, and could you, could
you summarize that answer
quickly
for me? And then like, I could
do it totally fine, but like, if
in
the, with the anxiety and like
being asked the question and
wanting to tell everyone about
code, I would just rant for like
three minutes and they'd be
like, well clear, clearly she
knows
what she's talking about. I'm
not sure if this was related to
my
actual question, but here we
are. So. You can do it. It's
really
apparently my point to everyone
getting a job.
Bekah: I'd do the same thing.
And I think for me, it's such a
challenge when I have been going
off for a while and I don't
realize that I am. And then I
see, like I noticed their face
and I'm like, oh, I need to
figure out. To bring this back
or, and, but then it also makes
me more nervous because I see
the
look on their face and it just
like has upped the pressure to
come back and like be better.
And I just was for the last
three
minutes, it's it's a whole
process.
Abbey: It really is. It's all
practice. Uh, I was in an
interview process. It was a fee.
It was the one the cycle before
I
got my job and I made it to the
final interview for two
mid-level
roles. Impressive. Uh, I like
the second one. The first one
had no
intention of hiring me at any
point. Uh, the second one, uh,
the hiring manager offered to be
my reference and I made them
think about it for an extra
week. And accomplishment. It's
not the
job that I wanted, but it's an
accomplishment. And there was a
point where I was in, oh my God.
That was the one where I was in
a
three hours straight of people
asking me questions. And there
was one point where they were
like, here, you could have a
five
minute break to get some water.
And, um, they, they were trying
to see if I was the type of
person that would go to a star
wars movie in the middle of the
day with them. That's the
question they should have asked.
They asked me. What are your
hobbies? And, uh, I saw their
eyes glaze over as I was
answering this question because
it was like, you can't, you
can't
ask me that question. Like, let
me just keep going on for like
literally hours. Like I could
do, if you get me started on
one,
like that's just at the end. I
was like, Yeah. And fantasy. And
they're like, oh my God. Oh my
God. I was like, Okay. ask
better
questions.
Bekah: How many interviews did
you go through?
Abbey: Um, I think I got up to
like 160 something applications.
Um, I think that was the final
number. I can look it up at some
point, but, um, I went through
like getting to the final
interview, probably five or six.
Um, there was one in the very
beginning where. I was
interviewing for a dev ops role
because I had applied to the
company and they saw my resume,
uh, like a month later and were
like, oh, well, she could do a
dev ops role, which like,
honestly, that's what I was
expecting to go into, uh, with
my background. Cause eight and a
half years of customer service,
I was like, I can break it into
the
Texas tech industry and then
eventually get into a developer
role. And the longer I was not
doing customer service, the more
I was like, I never want to do
it again. And, uh, In that
interview. My very first
technical interview, the hiring
manager looked at me and was
like, yeah, I can't, I can't in
good conscience, like recommend
you for this role. Like,
obviously I would hire you for
this role, but like, you need to
hold out for a developer role
and then like, promise me that
something would appear. And I
just never did. And I was like,
well, that's unfortunate, but
yeah. There were other dev ops
roles where like, uh, one of my
friends, I pass the lead on to
him and he's, he's in it now.
Cause I was like, look like,
this
is a great role. You're not
wrong. And like looking at my
resume and being like, I would
be a great fit, but I honestly,
like
I would just be looking for the
next fill, like the first
developer role I could find. And
he was like, yeah. It's like, he
was like, I'll pass your resume
on. Yeah, sure. Thanks. Um, as
far as like not final
interviews, I probably did a
handful more. So
let's say. Like 10 to 15 total
interview processes from like
plus applications.
Bekah: And how many months was
that?
Abbey: Um, I started applying
seriously and November. I didn't
get any bites until January. Um,
and I graduated from the
bootcamp
in January at the very
beginning.
Bekah: Okay. And this is like in
the middle of COVID. So there
was
hiring freezes everywhere.
Abbey: Exploded in like, uh,
January 20, 21, especially like
tech. It was nuts because I had
been looking since August,
September, and then all of a
sudden it was like daily, like
five coming out for junior
level. So,
Dan: Yeah.
Abbey: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I was, I had seen
that before, too. And was
interesting
to see because you know, part of
it is. New budgets, you know,
and
stuff. And then I think
companies finally figured out
like the,
the, um, that they are okay with
the remote stuff, you know,
which
has been
Abbey: well, Q1, Q too. Like you
could talk to recruiters. I was
in the recruiting industry,
right. It'd be like everybody.
We're going to be Okay. We're
going to make it through, like,
it's gonna, let's just rally
together. And I don't know, do
something with our new free
time. Honestly, I had eight
hours to
study programming in like April
20, 20. I'd answer like two
calls
a day. And, uh, by like Q4, uh,
you could see people were like
relaxing a bit. And like
recruiters were like, oh, I
actually have things to do.
Cause again, like if you want to
connect with recruiters, connect
with me on LinkedIn because
Bekah: Hm.
Abbey: hundreds, hundreds of
recruiters in my network. So.
Bekah: Were you able to take
some of the stuff you learned
from
recruiting and apply it to your
job search?
Abbey: definitely. Um, uh, so
my, one of the main aspects of
my job
was breaking down, uh, job
descriptions and writing them
and
so that we could post them on
the internet and the right
people
would apply. So from that, I not
only could pull out and again, I
was in engineering. So like
there was some, there were some
differences, uh, in engineering,
if you job hop from after, like
one year, people are like, is
something wrong with you? If in
Texas, A given. And I was like,
oh, hello. the other part, the
other one that was, I was also
in frequent calls with hiring
managers, retooling the job
description that they had given
us because they weren't seeing
the right candidate. So I knew
how incredibly frequent it is
for the job description, not to
match
what the hiring manager is
looking for. So that made it
very
easy for me to take the advice
of someone saying, well, if you
see
one book. Go for it. Cause like
the hiring managers don't know
what they want. My current job
description was. Three years
experience CS degree, master's
preferred, uh, the recruiter
that, uh, I worked with heavily
implied that I would never get
the job. And then did the same
thing to my friend who was in my
bootcamp, who has also gotten
the job. So like, it's a whole
thing.
But, um, the other thing was,
uh, I was trying to do the math
earlier. Let's say on average, I
over, I was involved in 12
interviews a week, right? And I
was in that for five years. So
like, there was, there were
times in my own interview
process where
I'd be like, I'm not getting
this job just from like the way
feeling out the way that a
hiring manager responds, because
th the
one where they waited a week to
tell me that they'd be my
reference. Like, I was like, I'm
not, I really wanted this. And I
know I didn't get it at this
point. And everyone was like,
no,
you've got to wait. And I was
like, Hmm, I would have heard on
Friday. Uh, but beyond that, You
hear feedback from the
candidates? Cause I was supposed
to be every single time a
candidate went through an
interview. I was supposed to get
on the phone with them and at
least hear them out about how it
went. And you hear about like
the questions that they got
asked and
like, if we sent three
candidates through a process,
then I would
know. What they had the, like
the person that got it had
versus the
two that we sent in previously
and stuff like that. And there
are some things that I highly
recommend that are very
controversial, not because I
think that the U S hiring
process, the way it is, is
great, or like, has any
standards
whatsoever, but. can use a thank
you note to push for feedback.
Like even if you're not getting
the job, you are more likely to
hear why you didn't get the job.
If you're emailing someone like
politely and asking questions
and like a thank you note as
just a
wrapper for that, you can be
like, Hey recruiter. Here. Can
you pass this? Thank you. Note
on for me also, can you answer
these
questions for me? And then like,
I would get, um, my current role
with my first interviewer
responded back with like, oh,
thank you for sending this.
Like, it was so lovely to speak
to you
too. I'm I'm that was like, that
gives you a little confidence as
you go into the next interview
and stuff like that. So, uh, the
other, what was the other point
that I had? Oh, I would do
hiring
and firing.
Bekah: Yeah.
Abbey: So I, I would get to
like, get the feedback as to why
they
wanted to go with the candidate.
I would do, uh, negotiations on
behalf of the candidate. Like I
would call it laminate and, um,
say it's Joe Schmoe, mechanical
engineer. And he's been doing
mechanical engineering for 30
years and he's been doing
contract work for 20 years. And
he was like, no, where are those
places? Uh, the commute I would
have to do plus this, this, this
and this, I need $3 more. Yeah.
Um, like once you get really
comfortable with that kind of
negotiation and everything on
behalf of someone else, it's
slightly easier to apply to
yourself. I still feel like I
lowballed myself in a couple of
interview processes, but that
was also me being very desperate
for
my first job in tech. Uh, and
me. But like, even then I was
doing
it based on like market
research. Like you go to indeed
you do plug
in the job title, you plug in
your location, and that gives
you
the average hourly rate or
average salary for any job. Uh,
it's on the indeed salary tool
or whatever. And that's how we
did
estimating for the rates that we
were putting out on our job
descriptions for. Anytime that
the client didn't set the rates.
So like I knew how to find that
kind of information to make
myself a competitive candidate
by low-balling myself, or just
saying that, no, I'm not going
to accept anything below this.
And,
uh, that ended up being my first
job doubled my salary after
seven
months of unemployment.
Bekah: Nice.
Dan: Yeah, that's awesome. I'm
sure that sounds like a nice, a
bunch of information to have in
your back pocket when you're
going through this process. Um,
Abbey: yeah. And like just a lot
of stuff where like demystifies
the whole hiring process,
because they're all, I mean, I
had a
psych professor who would rant
about this frequently. Like
they're not trained. Like when I
had to hire people for internal
roles, they were just like, here
I are interviewing, hire
someone.
They weren't like ask them these
questions or here's what we're
looking for. And my role was a
little bit difficult because
like, we couldn't even do KPIs,
which are like, uh, Setting
goals
for people to meet so that you
know, that they're performing
well in their role, because it
would be like, well, a lot of
this is dependent on what comes
in. So. I just asked the same
questions and we hired a couple
people and I failed miserably
two
out of three times. Like, and if
I, someone with experience in a
lot of interview processes,
can't look at another human and
be
like, Yeah. you're definitely
going to write it. In a timely
manner, like how is someone else
going to do that? So a lot of
it,
it turned it into me knowing
that like a human is sitting on
the
other side of this call or
whatever. Uh, and I'm convincing
that human, but I will do
whatever they want me to do for
money. Hopefully I'll leave. And
development related, but like
that's a
Dan: set of skills.
Abbey: exactly like that's a,
that's a totally different
approach than, and who's like,
obviously this hiring manager
knows everything there is to
know about developing and I'm
this
beginner developer trying to
convince them that I will also
know everything about developing
and that's not at all what you
have to do. If, if I haven't
very fully explained by process,
which
was one bullet point I apply. I
don't know. I tell him, I study,
I rant a lot. Sometimes I
summarize the rent. Like the
most, the most positive feedback
I got was, wow. You're just,
your
enthusiasm is really there. Like
you've got a passion for
learning
and that's what a lot of people
want to see in these developer
roles. And I was just, I was
just like, I like coat. Here's a
Sheba
counter.
Bekah: I really liked that last
thing that you were talking
about, about showing the
enthusiasm, because I was
talking
about this with a couple of
different people recently in
how.
When you're interviewing for a
position, how your personality
comes across, whether or not
that affects, you know,
decisions and
whether or not people with
stronger personalities kind of,
um, get taken out of the
interview process just because
there are, um, I don't know that
people just think of them in a
certain way. Like, well, if
they're responding in this way
or, wow, that was really
intense, you know, maybe this is
not the
person that we want to be
working with when, um, you know,
realistically you don't get a
full picture of personality in
the interview process, but do
you think that that can be an
issue
when you're interviewing, like
how you present your personnel?
Abbey: So this, this goes back
to my point that they're bias
written humans. Like you have to
find the human on the other side
of the table, but like you can,
you can jive with, because there
were plenty of, there was I'm
going to remove all identifiable
aspects of this story, but I
know someone that recently got a
job
with the company that they got a
job for, because. And I quote,
well, we've hired developers
with strong accents before, and
it's
worked out totally fine. And
genuinely, he's one of the
smartest developers I know, and
wasn't getting a job longer than
the rest of us because he had a
very thick accent. And that is a
bias that a lot of interviewers
have. And I've heard it from,
I've heard a different version,
which is like, this is
offensive.
I apologize. But like, That
hiring manager was Asian. He's
only going to hire Asian
candidates. That's why I didn't
get the job. And like, I can't
speak to the reality of whatever
that is in that industry or
whatever, but yeah. There every
human that you get on the other
side of the table with is going
to have some sort of bias. And
like, like, I hate to phrase it
this way, but like your goal is
to be as vanilla and inoffensive
as possible. So definitely don't
go in and like curse out your
interviewers.
Bekah: But you want to be like
vanilla with a little sprinkles,
right. So they can remember you.
So like how, how much is too
much
sprinkles?
Abbey: I don't know, cause I
would take notes and then write
a
thank you note with interesting
details from our interview in it
and send that to the
interviewer. So I asked every
interviewer, uh,
how did you get your first tech
role and got some really fun
answers and would work that into
my thank you note. So like you
want it's you want to be able to
show that you are someone who
could come into a corporate
environment or whatever it is
like the standards and tech
interviews are so much lower
than
they were in injury engineering.
I had interviews show up,
showing
up in like a baseball hat and a
t-shirt and I was like, what is
happening? So like present
yourself. Well, like get up, get
an interview outfit. It doesn't
have to be a full blown suit. I
don't think. And for tech
interviews, but like, you know,
present yourself as you want to
be presented. It's like, bring
your best self, uh, Again, curse
out your interviewers. Like I
say, this it's happened and, uh,
answered the questions to the
best of your ability and really
show that like you're dedicated
and passionate about doing the
thing that you're trying to do.
Uh, like if you're trying to
learn something new, so that
you'll be better at ramping up
or anything like that, like,
those
are the things that you want to
talk about. And then you want to
answer every question, like as
positively as possible. And then
if you're not. You're going to
have to elaborate a little bit
on
what you mean by strong
personality, because like I only
think about engineers yelling at
each other,
Bekah: I don't even think, you
know, there, there are people
that come into a room. Right.
And they kind of just, they,
they
automatically take over the room
or I'm trying to think of an
example with out, like
Abbey: like giving
Bekah: using a name of a person.
Um, but, but something, somebody
that comes in and they're ready
to talk and they're there. Um,
Abbey: Little T
Bekah: really hard.
Abbey: like you Keep going You
keep going too fast and you
like,
talk over people and it's a lot
of.
Bekah: yeah. Or I don't know,
Dan, come on. Help me out. I
know
that
Dan: um, I'm wondering, I I'm
actually not sure what, which
way
you're going here, but like, are
you, are you saying, are you
like
worried that, uh, strong
personalities and negative.
Bekah: oh, for sure. Right?
Like, oh, I'm not sure I can
work with
this person because they've got,
they're really
Dan: mean, my advice for this is
it's hard. It's, it's hard for
me
to nail this down because I
think that, um, where you are in
your
sort of journey and also like,
depending on, you know, your,
your specific like privileges
and stuff, like, like we were
talking
about before, where like where
you are in life and what's going
on, um,
Abbey: lot of the things that I
ended up talking about were
like,
uh, getting back into the
workforce after being a
stay-at-home parent,
Dan: right. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
So, but my, my point is, um, my
advice is usually to present
yourself how you are, um,
because
if, if they're not going to like
you like that, um, they're not
going to have a good time. Like
if you, if you, um, sort of act
like a different person and they
hire you and then. Like you
can't
just act like that forever. Um,
that's not to say that. That's
not to say that like,
Bekah: a notch
Dan: Well, well, sure. I mean,
yes. I mean maybe I guess, I
mean, and this is where my point
is like as a junior developer,
it
might be more important to get
the first job regardless of it.
I
like, and this is where I get
wishy-washy my on advice. You
know what I mean? Because that
first job interview is not
interview. I'm sorry, but the
first job, like the first actual
job is like such a big step and,
and your second job, like the
interview process. He's probably
still going to do interviews and
all of that stuff, but I like
coming from a place of
experiences is, uh, I imagine
the experience is much
different.
Right. Um, but like me
personally, and also I'm just, I
I've been a developer for a long
time. Uh, you know, so I don't,
I'm not really worried. I'm
also, you know, in a spot where
I am
not desperate for a job or I'm
not, you know, I don't need one.
My, if I lost my job or, you
know, whatever, for every, all
of
my paying work went away, um, my
wife also works, you know? And
so
it's so like, I'm like in the
spot of privilege where I don't
have to, um, I dunno, but like,
we're, we're, I don't like,
there's some things that I know
specifically that I don't have
to
worry about, but I, if I'm
meeting somebody or doing an
interview, stuff like that, I'm
probably not going to, uh, maybe
I'll, uh, you know, like dull
some edges a little bit, but,
um,
I'm just going to try to be
myself because that's who I am.
Right. And like, I I've, I'm
starting a relationship with
somebody. I don't like, I'm not
gonna, I don't know, fake it,
but.
Abbey: your point, your point.
And, uh, and first I'm going to
phrase it a little bit, a little
bit differently. Uh, so it's
like, it's like meeting your
partner's parents for the first
time. Like you want to be on
your best behavior. You want to
look
nice. You don't want to be too
drastically away from your
regular personality, but you
still want to be like, you know,
a little more palatable than you
would be like with your friends
out in the backyard or something
like that. And then not every
interviewer has to, like you
like. There is someone out there
that will be like, Yeah. I can
find a spot for you on my team.
And your chances of, if you have
a strong personality and you're
finding that your interviewing
is not going especially well
because
of your strong personality, then
it's time to start networking
and
find someone that you can get
like a rapport with and
understands that you're not like
a hundred percent, this person
that you are when you're nervous
and your interview. And then
they
can start taking you through an
interview process because like
we
see time and time again, through
networking through Twitter,
through whatever. Like if
someone likes you and they find
an
opening and they have enough say
in the interview process, so
you're going to get much further
than you would have if you're
just coming in and no one's
watching for you and you have
this mysterious, strong
personality that you wouldn't
want to show to your partner's
parents.
Dan: Yeah. And you mentioned
something in there about, um,
uh,
you know, being anxious, uh,
during an interview and that
affecting your personality and,
and that's sort of something
different, right? Like, uh, If
you have an I do, if you
struggle
with like anxiety and, um, the
especially anxiety around
performance and stuff like that,
then that's something that's a
little different than like your
true personality, right? That's
like, that's like your anxiety
or other issues affecting. The
actual, like the actual
presentation of your, to
yourself. Right. Um, and getting
away and getting in the way of
that even. Um, so if you have a
habit of when you're anxious
over-talking, or, or, or doing
things like that, um, that is
something to just, I would say
to practice on, you know, um,
and do
like Abby was saying, uh, lots
of practice, I think helps and
probably there's other things to
help too. I, you know, um, and
Abbey: My interviews would have
gotten so much worse if I had to
drive to the place at a certain
time. Oh my God. Like all of my
interviews are on zoom. And at
first I was like, this sucks.
And
then I was like, wait, this is
amazing.
Dan: Yeah, no, I, and I love
that. I was thinking about this
the other day with coming out of
the pandemic. Um, there are
actually things about zoom that.
Like, and prefer, um, with
regards to anxiety and
performance issues and stuff
like
that. I don't have to, when I'm
on zoom, I don't have to worry
about what I'm doing with my
hands or my feet or my body
really, you know? Um, and. Let's
actually think about this with
masks and now like our daycare,
you don't have to wear masks
anymore if you were vaccinated.
And, uh, I was walking around.
I'm like, what, what do I do
with my face?
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: You know? But like all that
is to say, like the, um, it's
just my, you know, I, I said be
your true self, um, before, and
I
was specifically. Not that
doesn't mean, you know, like
there aren't, if your true self
is like, you lose control of
some
things because of anxiety and
thinking like that's something,
you know, that is definitely can
be worked on and you can
practice
it and probably get better. Um,
have an easier time. Um,
Abbey: And I want to be clear. I
was a puddle of sweat after
pretty much all of my
interviews. yeah. Uh, like I.
Recently,
remember the desperation, the
anxiety, the everything being
like my one chance. And I'm
ruining it again in February. It
was a really dark time for me.
And, uh, like there were, there
were things where like my
husband would have to. Could you
be good
at algorithms? Could you just
study the algorithms alone?
Bekah: Okay.
Abbey: There's so anxiety
written at this point and he was
like,
could they be less anxiety
ridden if you practice them? And
then I
was doing 30 days of algorithms
on Twitter and like, people were
interacting with that. And you
know, you see things all the
time
that are people like, oh, you're
still looking for a job. So like
the building in public is also
the practicing.
Dan: I would also say that. I
think it's fair, to be honest
with your person you're
interfering with, if, you know,
especially if you have, um, Well
really about anything, but, you
know, if you're like, I'm very
nervous and because of this
interview and I very much want
this job. Um, so I apologize
because sometimes I talk too
fast when I'm nervous or
something
like that. Um, I think that
would go a long way to, um, to,
Abbey: Yeah. I've been like, can
you give me a second to
formulate
my answers so that it's slightly
less panicky and Franti. And
they
were like, oh Yeah. please.
Like, and, uh, when I was honest
about
like, Oh, I like, I can't take
this role cause I'll just be
wanting to move on immediately.
Thank you for your honesty. I
really appreciate that. Let me
see if I have anyone that has a
developer role for you like
that. That's the kind of
feedback you
get from being honest and open
about all this kind of stuff.
And
if you do that and I'm proven
wrong, please give me their
names
so I can yell at them
personally. Like
Bekah: Okay.
Abbey: you can find a, my handle
is sorry. Go ahead.
Bekah: as you say, it's been
great to have you here. You
talked about so many great
things and there are so many
great tips
here. It's like trying to
highlight as we went along. All
of the things that I could say
were great about this episode,
but there, then I just quit.
Cause like there were too many
of
them. So thank you so much for
being here. It's been great
hearing you talk through this.
Abbey: Of course, I'm like the
one thing that I really wanted
to
highlight is I got into this
because I was good at making
things pretty. Like if you are
the person that's like, I don't
know, like if I'm cut out for
this. or whatever, See, just
try,
like, uh, I did not expect to
have a popular blog or be a
great
full-stack, uh, person, but
that's how it happened. And it's
just because I was like, well, I
know about pictures and colors
and let's do this. So thank you
guys for having me.
Bekah: Thanks Abby.
Dan: Thanks Abby.
Bekah: Bye.
Abbey: Bye bye.
Dan: and there's the awkward by
part. Okay. Bye.
Abbey: Okay.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, plus you
can sign up for our newsletter
to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a
review. Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.