Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode three of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we're
talking with Ayu Adiati. Ayu's
originally from Indonesia and now
based in the Netherlands. She's a
self-taught front end developer
and prolific technical blogger.
And she's on her way to break
into tech after being a stay at
home mom for her daughter for the
past four years. We talked with
Ayu about the impact of
community, being a blogger while
she's learning web development
and her recent experiences with
burnout.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. Today's
random question is: "If you could
teleport to anywhere for 15
minutes, where would you go?" We
hope you enjoy this episode. Hey,
I'm Bekah. I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio and I could teleport to
anywhere for 15 minutes. I don't,
I like, I can't decide if I want
like a nice, beautiful location
or if I want like really good
food. I, well, I don't know. I
don't have a really good specific
place, but I would go somewhere
that has a beautiful location
that has good food and drink. So
my answer.
Dan: I, uh, man, that just made
me start thinking like, okay,
well now I need to know the
rules. Can you take things with
you when you teleport back?
Bekah: You can do whatever you
want.
Dan: Okay.
Bekah: It's your
Dan: Um, I mean, it just changed
my whole. Alright. Hi. Um, hi,
I'm Dan. I am from Lakewood,
Ohio. Do front end development if
I could. So I was going to say
something. Uh, somewhere, maybe
like the top of Mount Everest or
somewhere where it's generally
like, not great to be, or the
it's really hard to get to, you
know, but it would be cool to
just like be there for 15
minutes, kind of see everything,
whatever. And by the time 15
minutes are up, um, you know,
oxygen deprivation is probably
setting in I'm pretty cold, so
I'm ready to go home. Um, but you
said food, which made me think,
okay, well, You know, can you
take things with you and in, so
maybe my answer is more like, you
know, Fort Knox
Bekah: bank.
Dan: and also have a bank, right.
Uh, somewhere else, you know,
other secret, and now I'm
thinking, oh, maybe there's like,
uh, like that secret room in the
library of Congress that was in,
um, you know, one of the national
treasure books, you know, or may
national treasure movies, um,
somewhere to like find a bunch of
secrets or something, you know,
anyway, um, I'm going to stick
with my original answer
officially as Mount Everest and,
um, we'll we can move on from
there.
Ayu: Hi, I'm Ayu and I'm front
end developer from, uh, Indonesia
or originally, but, uh, base in
Netherlands now. And if I can
teleport myself or 15 minutes, I
would split it into two. I would
visit the, my sister in Australia
and my brother in New Zealand.
That would be nice because we
haven't seen each other for
almost three years now.
Dan: Oh, wow.
Bekah: Wow.
Dan: Yeah, well, that's, that's a
good answer. I live too close to
all of my family, so
Bekah: My brother lives down the
street a little bit, literally
have run to my parents' house and
to my other brother's house. So
Ayu: That's
Bekah: not that
Dan: no, it's, it's nice. I w we
do it on purpose, but you know,
it's fine. I could take 15
minutes and probably get away
from them.
Bekah: Yeah, I like the take up
splitting that's. That was good.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. There's
Bekah: Welcome. We are very happy
to have you here with us and for
everyone who is listening, just
want to say a special thank you
to Ayu because she's doing this
super late. Um, so we can make
sure that the time zones, um,
mashed up and we could get her on
here. So we are very, very happy
that this works.
Ayu: Thank you for having me.
Bekah: Um, we always like to
start with everyone's origin
story, kind of how they got to
this point where they're learning
tech or in tech. So if you could
just give us your background.
Ayu: Well, I. Have a hobby as a
photography and it was starting
from my photography hobby. And I
did the freelancer for stock
photography. And then I have my
daughter and then when she starts
like one and half year, and it
becomes like really fun because
she start to, you know, uh, be
aware of the camera. Yeah, it's
it's from there. And then I
thought it would be nice if I
have like a blog or something,
like to have this personal
documentation. So I was like,
browsing anything about WordPress
or any blogging things, but then
I bumped into frequent camp and
then I just tried it. And from
there, I just like it. Yeah.
There's no going back from there.
It's like, I want to know more
and more and more. That's how I
finally got into coding.
Bekah: that. It's always so great
to hear how people discover it,
like through other things that
they've enjoyed doing. And then
it just kind of becomes something
that you want to do more and more
of. Um, so you said, you
mentioned free code camp. Is
that, um, how long did you stay
in free code camp or are you
still doing free code camp or,
you know, what are the resources
that you found really helpful?
Ayu: I actually not, I mean, like
for something that I learned for
the first time, I'm more an audio
visual person. So I like video
more. And so a friend of mine,
she was like, why don't you try
Udemy? So I start with Udemy and.
I like it. I mean, like when,
when I see, you know, like I see,
and then I, I code along with it
then, uh, it's just. Um, but they
still use free code camp to get
the certifications. Like you
don't have to finish all the
modules. Right. And you can just
jump into like, make all the
projects that, uh, that are
needed and, uh, finish, uh, uh,
certification. I did the first
certification, um, uh, web
responsive this design, I think.
Yeah, it was it. And yeah. I use,
uh, more physio, uh, from YouTube
or something like that. But after
I understand something, then I
can use the other resources, like
a blog articles or something like
that. Yeah. But for the first
time it's always video.
Bekah: I think that's great. And
it's always interesting to hear
the different approaches that
people take, because I know for
me, I can't watch the videos at
first. I'm the opposite. So I
need to read through it and then
I can watch the video, like what
is happening here. So it's, and
that's just another reason why
content creation in all forms can
be so great because everybody
learns differently and those
different approaches, um, one
works for me and one works for
you and something. Different
works for somebody else. And so
it's great to be able to have
that out there.
Ayu: Yeah. True.
Bekah: So Ayu, I think that I may
have known you longer than
anybody else at Virtual Coffee,
Ayu: Yeah, I think so, too.
Bekah: because I think I, I, I
met you shortly after I started
learning to code. I think we were
both doing, we were both in the
group, moms can code and that's
how we met. And we were both
learning to code with kids at
home. And as we all know, that
can be a challenge. Um, So, so
what, what was it like for, what
has it been like for you? Because
you are also, self-taught, you're
pursuing this, not in the
confines of a bootcamp or in a
traditional school setting and
you have a kid at home too, so
there's just a lot of different
moving pieces there.
Ayu: Yeah. I start to, uh, learn
to code when she was, uh, my
daughter was. Two years old and,
uh, I was self-taught and then,
uh, I think that I tweeted, I
tweeted one time. How to juggling
between the house chores and the
kid, and also, uh, learning. And
then I remember that one of, uh,
who were response to my tweet was
you back out, so yeah. And you
said you join mom and then it's
like, oh, there's a moment. Cool.
That's nice. You know, so yeah.
Yeah, I joined it, but yeah, with
the time differences. I got more
coworking with the European times
on moms and we. Hmm, learning,
uh, things that are different.
One to another, like, uh, one is
like doing in the back end and
the other is the front end, but I
mean, like that's for the first
time that I felt like I'm not
alone, you know, like, I don't
care what they're doing, but it's
like, I'm not, I'm not learning
by myself. And I, we can have
like all our, our kids. You know,
my kids were crying and then they
were like, Hey, stop it there or
something like that. But yeah,
it's, it's not easy. And, um,
when she was two, my, um, the
time for me to learn was only on
her neck. And then I have to wait
until the whole house is
sleeping, like around them at
night. And then I start learning
from that until 12 one in the
morning. And yeah, uh, it's
getting easier now after she
start with her elementary school,
but it was like, hell before.
It's like, I, I couldn't find any
perfect time to learn and. Two
hours in total for the whole
learning. So, yeah. So I cannot
imagine that you have four,
Bekah, you still.
Bekah: You know, it was one of
those things. Where you start to
get used to being able to pivot
pretty quickly like, oh, my kids
are playing, I'm going to sit
down at this computer. And then
my mind would just like switch
on, like, it knew it has to do it
right in this second. But, you
know, I had a lot of help from my
parents would watch the kids or
if I had a project to do, I
remember one weekend, my husband
was out of town speaking at a
conference. And so they took the
kids and it was the same thing
like you were talking about.
You're just trying to. Fit in
this time. And so I stayed up so
late and then woke up the next
morning to try and get it done.
Cause you're trying to fit it in.
But at the same time, you don't
want to be formal. Bad self care
habits, because then that just
leads to frustration and not
wanting to do the thing that you
want to do. And then being mad
that you don't want to do the
thing that you know, you want to
do. Right. Um, so it's all, it's
a whole, I don't know, thing to
juggle and it's not just about
learning. It's about. You know,
the growth and the changes that
you're facing yourself. And it's
a different role that you're
taking on and trying to figure
out how all these things work
together. And so it can be really
great, but certainly it can be
really frustrating.
Ayu: True. True. And especially
that I don't have my family here.
Right. And my husband works, so I
have to do everything by myself.
So yeah. It's like, and people
said that, oh, you have like lots
of time because you only stay at
home. And, oh my God, I feel like
I want to cry every time I hear
that because no, if we can have
like more than 24 hours in a day,
that wouldn't be perfect, you
know? But we don't
Bekah: Yeah. I always say that's
like my biggest challenge.
There's not 36 hours in a day.
Ayu: Yeah.
Dan: I imagine it at least,
knowing you, I, if you had 36
hours in a day, you would find a
way to fill all of that. And
still that's still what you wish
there was more. Yeah, it's just a
Bekah: accurate.
Dan: Uh, Yeah, it's that, that
switch off. I mean, we, my kids
are in daycare, you know, my wife
and I both work. But during the
pandemic, you know, at the
beginning, um, everything was
shut down. Daycare was shut down,
you know? And so we were trying
to do that. We're trying to
juggle the kids and work and, you
know, uh, Emily, I would switch
off, you know, watching the kids
and, um, For me, that for me, I
struggled really hard with that
context. Switching like Bekah,
you said you got, you got good at
it. That was really very hard for
me, you know? Like, um, and
honestly it was less some, it
wasn't that you sitting down at
the computer part, it was the,
the going back from computer to
kids switch. That was the, that
was a struggle for me. Um, you
know, I, I just have so much
respect for people who are
parenting like full-time and
trying to learn or work like
through all this I, that I don't
know how you do it, but it seems
like you've been managing it.
Ayu: I don't know. I still don't
know how to do it Dan. I don't
know.
Bekah: it's the truth too. I
mean, people will ask, like, how
do you do it? I don't know, you
know, you just do the things that
you, you have to do.
Ayu: Yeah, exactly.
Bekah: We talked about these
frustrations that can be that
you're facing that we're all
facing as we're learning these
things and as we're parenting and
going through a global pandemic
together. And, and so I think.
Sometimes, really leaning into
the things that encourage us or
inspire us can be really useful.
Have there been things or people
along the way that you found have
helped you continue the journey
or, um, prevented you from giving
up and maybe some of those times
that were really hard
Ayu: Yeah. I mean, like, I got
burned out like so many times.
Right. And, and, um, well, I've
been active on Twitter and that
helps, uh, I'm doing the, um, A
hundred codes of challenge. And,
uh, um, every time I sit like, oh
my God, I don't know what to do.
And then some people like random
people, like, no, you can do
this. And yeah, I got, I get my
spirit back and. There are also
times, especially when you were a
self-taught. Right. And you, you
don't, you don't have anybody to
talk with. Like my husband, he
doesn't know anything about web
dev, so I can not like, oh, I'm
having trouble with this code.
And he was like, what, what do
you mean? Correct. So, yeah, I
mean, uh, I got the one time burn
out. Like that's pretty recently
that I think. Okay. I don't think
that this is for me and like, I'm
going to, I'm going to just quit.
And I was like, I got so, so
surprise actually with, with that
thoughts, because I never thought
like, yeah, I got burnt out, but
then like, uh, uh, you know, like
I'm taking break and stuff and I
would be fine again, but this
time it's like different. I
already took break. I mean, like
I already procrastinated, but
still. I don't know how to get
myself together this time. Like,
uh, I got panic attack. It was
like, I learn. And then one time,
like we were having this, uh, Uh,
theme, right? I I'm trying with
some VC members to have this, uh,
group project about vanilla
JavaScript. I mean, I got burned
out with react with learning
react before, and then I thought,
oh, this is a good chance because
it's funny, like JavaScript. So I
can like take a step back and
then do what I know, you know,
but because so far I learned by
myself doing everything by
myself. When it's in a group,
it's a different story, right?
You have somebody else to
collaborate and everybody has
their own thoughts, like on how
to approach something, which is
not the approach that I probably
would take, so it's kind of made
me confused and then I got like
so freaked out and I was like,
What is happening, where are we
in? I don't know. My God, this is
funny, like JavaScript. And I've
done this like so many times, but
how come I'm not following this?
You know, it's like, I cannot do
it. And this feels like I want to
stop. So I kind of pull myself a
little bit off from everybody for
like a week or so. But then I
thought like, no, I need to talk
to someone about this. Right. So
I start to talk to some of my
friends and they were all like,
okay, we are all struggling. Like
you can do this. And then like
one of them even say to them,
It's actually good that you, you
have that thought of quitting
because you don't understand
things because if you have that
thought, it means that, you know,
so many things, so you get
confused, you know, it's not like
you don't know anything, like
yeah, you're right. I was like,
okay. And that's, you know, like
people don't want to share
they're struggling. Right. I
don't know. Maybe because. Um,
they don't want people to think
they're weak or I don't know.
They, they have their own
reasons. As for me, I feel more
or less embarrassed. Like I've
been learning for so long and
then suddenly, like, I know
nothing, you know, and I don't, I
just don't want to share that. If
I really want to do this, I want
to step forward. Then I think
that I should share this struggle
with at least, uh, somebody that
can, that I know that can hear me
out. Listen to me, you know? And
it was a good decision that I
made that I just, you know, share
here are my struggles. And then
people support me. I mean, like
if you, if you don't share,
nobody knows and you just have to
deal it yourself. Yeah. It's,
it's been a journey.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Certainly a journey. You
said some things in there that
that really struck me. And so you
talked about this idea of
community and isolation and
sharing, and I think that, you
know, all of these things go
together and especially when
we're in those. Tough moments
where we tend to isolate from
other people, for those reasons
that you spoke about, you know,
it's self doubt and not thinking
you can do it and being
embarrassed or afraid to share
things. And I got a piece of
advice pretty early on from
someone and they said, Um, you
don't share it for your show
yourself. You share for other
people because other people who
are going through the same things
can recognize that, oh, I don't
have to do this in isolation. I'm
not the only one that feels this
way. And then that's how
community is formed. And I just
always loved that idea because it
can be so hard to share those
things and to feel alone and to
feel like. I dunno, you're you're
not where you should be. Right.
Like, I it's, it happens every
week. I look at someone else and
I'm like, oh wow. I, I should, I
should be able to know what
they're talking about. And I
don't. Right. And then it's like,
oh, don't fall into the
comparison trap, number one. But
number two, like embrace that
community of people that's around
you. And you know, for me, I
you've been such a huge part of
my community and I don't know how
you do it, but I feel like. There
are times when I am really,
really struggling and I won't say
anything. And then I get a DM
from you checking on me and I'm
like, oh, okay. Like I use here.
This is what I needed, you know?
And so for me, that's been such
a, um, uh, an important piece of,
of all of the things that have
happened to me since I met you,
because it's nice to have that
connection. And to know that
there are people that are, are,
are willing to, to care about
you.
Ayu: And, and I learned so much
from, from, uh, your trauma
stories, spectrum, and like,
you've been so open. Right. And,
and you reach so many people with
your story. And, and I mean,
like, there are plenty of people
there that. Have the same feeling
like how you feel, but they
cannot let it out. So I thought
like when, when I was struggling,
I thought like, okay, this is
for, for me, for myself, you
know, I mean, like, and, and, uh,
I also think that maybe I'm not
the only one, maybe, maybe
there's also people out there
that having the struggle the same
as I do. And if I open up, maybe
those people can open up as well
and they, and they could like
feel a little bit relieved that,
okay. I'm not the only one. And
I, I can, I can talk about it.
Like it's, it's okay to not feel
okay. You know, so yeah. I thank
you so much because you taught me
how to do that.
Bekah: No, I'm going to cry.
Dan: You, you talked about
sharing, you know, your story,
especially regarding the burnout
and, you know, the we'll post on
the, on the show notes, but you
wrote a really great piece about
it. Um, but two week, a couple
weeks ago or a week ago, whatever
it was. And, um, I, uh, I, I just
wanted to call it out because I,
I love to reading it. And I loved
that. Uh, you know, you shared,
you shared the struggle part,
which is. I agree is very
important and very helpful for
people. Um, but I, I very much
loved how you, um, a lot of the
article is more about how to
survive it, you know, how, how to
sort of recognize those feelings
for what they are and then how to
sort of survive and move on. And,
um, I just really appreciated it.
I don't I don't have I don't
really have a question or a
point, but, but I appreciated it.
I mean, you know, it, and a lot
of it is just the, um, allowing
yourself to. Be not okay. Or
whatever, allow yourself to take
a break or step back. Um, and I
think it's so important. Um, it
was, it was a good.
Ayu: self care is really, really
important. I mean, like, this is
like one point in my, in my
learning journey where I really,
really want to rush things, you
know, like, um, I've been
learning for. Two years, two and
half years now. And I feel like,
why am I so slow? So I'm trying
to, you know, speed up a bit. But
I think like, because I start to
understand things, so I really
want to speed up again, speed up
again. But I didn't, I, you can
say that I ignore my. Well, I
should take a break, but I don't
because no, I want to be in this
momentum, you know, like I, I
want to keep it up, but now this
is my limit to take a break for a
bit, but I didn't. So I think
that's where most people also
don't aware where they really
want to push and push and push
forward. Um, they need to, you
know, like take a step back and
just refute the center's slowing
down a bit, then they don't think
about themselves, you know, like,
like, um, they can get burnout or
can get frustration. So, yeah. My
experience skin, like reminding
people as well, that the, they
need to, you know, take a step
back once in a while.
Dan: Yeah, it's hard to do or it
can be, you know, it can't be
hard to do. Um, at least in my
personal experience.
Bekah: Well, and I think too,
when you take that step back,
sometimes it's hard to get
started again. Right? There's
this fear of losing momentum,
like, well, I was there and you
have to backtrack a little bit if
you take a break. And so for a
lot of people, I think it's, I
don't know. Exactly how to
describe that feeling, whether
it's being upset with themselves
or having to go back or getting,
being hard on yourself and
thinking like, well, I should
know this stuff. Right. But it's
okay to have to backtrack. It's
okay. To start from a different
point that you ended up. But I
think, like you're saying,
there's just not that many people
that are talking about those
things, you know, it is okay to
take a break. It is okay to be at
a different point than someone
else's going to be. And I don't
know this is going to sound
silly, but I always used to
compare myself to Kent C Dodds,
which is like, not fair in any
way, shape or form. Cause he's
been doing this a long time, but
I'm like, he's got four kids. How
come he can do all this stuff.
Right? Like what. It's a little
bit different. He actually, he
wrote a newsletter for mother's
day, one year. I think that
talked about how much his wife
does to support him and their
kids. And it was like, oh, okay.
I get, I get this right? Like
there's a lot of support for the
things that he's doing and he's
been doing it a really long time.
And it's. A reasonable
comparison. I'm not really that
reasonable, so it's not
surprising that I would do that.
But, um, it's not even like, look
at the people who are learning
alongside you. It should never,
if that's the motivation, then
there's always going to be a
point where you start to really
get down on yourself because
everybody moves in different ways
and in different paces. And you
know, sometimes you'll hit a
plateau. And it'll be really hard
to get back up like the mountain.
Um, but then, but then you'll
gain some momentum and then
you'll go fast again. Right. You
know, maybe your, your study all
the time, everybody learns
differently. Everybody, um, can
apply things in different ways
and has different strengths. And
I think we just failed to
recognize that complexity and we
try and make it this really
simple story of success. And we
forget all of the, you know,
things about being human that go
along with that story.
Ayu: Yeah, true. And I kind of
forget that. I mean, like I was
thinking I'm learning for two,
two and a half years and, uh,
I'm, I'm going so slow, but I
forgot that. Most of the days, I
only have two until three hours a
day to learn. Right. So I cannot
compare myself to someone who can
spend like more than five hours a
day to learn. So, um, yeah, I
need to remind myself that
Dan: Okay.
Ayu: You're, you're going
forward. Only that you have like
less time than other people. So
you cannot compare yourself to
other people, but this is your
time. Right? I mean, I do, uh,
the best way. I mean, like the
best that I could within two and
three hours a day, and that's
actually good, you know, like
when I got exhausted, I still
can, um, save some time to learn.
So I think. Uh, I've been too
hard on myself or something like
that and not appreciate myself. I
don't know. But yeah, I'm trying
to remind me myself about that.
Like You're, you're doing good.
You're you're doing okay. You
know, so.
Dan: Yeah, I, I mean, you are,
you're doing great. I can't, uh,
trying to fit that learning and,
and it's not just the hours,
right. Is you've talked. You were
talking about how it's like a
little bit during nap time and
then late at night. Um,
Ayu: Yeah,
Dan: Which probably not the best,
you know, your brain's probably
not in the best shape for
learning at that point either.
Right. And so that's what I mean
here. You know, you're, you're,
you're working with what you
have. Um, and the progress you've
made seems I don't know what to
say from where I'm sitting. It
seems incredible. Um, you've also
been just a prolific blogger,
like over the last, however long,
a couple of years. Uh, and I've
always been, I mean, like that.
Yeah. I don't know, I've read. I
think probably most of everything
you've written, but like it's,
it's, uh, very impressive. I was
wondering how you approach, like
mixing that into your normal
routine of like learning and
stuff like that.
Ayu: No blogging is, is
completely different thing. I
mean, like I really have to, uh,
make a time to write a blog and
English is not my native, right.
So I'm not native English
speakers. So, I mean, I need like
three to four hours to arrive.
600 to 800 words. And you imagine
so. Yeah, mostly like when I do
blogging, um, if I have an idea,
I will do the bullet points and
then from there, then I will try
to, uh, you know, like talk about
the bullet points, little bit,
like explanation, something like
that. Uh, it, it helps me to, to,
um, Uh, a little bit faster. And
if you see like my block style,
most of them always have like the
bullet points.
Dan: Okay.
Bekah: Well, I think that's great
for readers do.
Dan: I think it's a really
effective way to, to write.
Absolutely. Um, that's how I,
that's how I usually write the,
when I blog once a year. Um, I
did the same thing, uh, as
opposed to once a week. Um, yeah,
for me it's once a year maybe,
but, uh, I, I, I've just, I'm
impressed, especially on a
limited time schedule. Like you
have, um, that you have both the.
I don't know the dedication, the
willpower, you know, to, to, to
do the blogging because it's, I
it's optional. Right. Nobody's
making you do it, or it's not
like part of any of your, I don't
know, certifications or anything
like that. Right. And so you're,
you're, um, you're just doing it
on your own and it's impressive.
Like blogging is one of those
things where I'm always like,
yes, this month I'm going to get
into the habit, you know? And it
never happens because it's,
nobody's making, you know, you
know, nobody's asking me to write
on my own on my own website. So.
I'm always impressed by people
who can.
Ayu: the, it's actually one of
the things that get me into
learning to code as well,
because, uh, besides that I want
to, um, uh, have my, uh, photos
showcase. I also want to. Wanted
to write about my experience,
like living, living in another
country and with a toddler and
stuffs. Um, but I finally didn't
write anything until thank you
for DC for having that a monthly
challenge of November, where we
have to write. Right. And it's
actually, that's one of the
things that can. Hmm. Uh, how do
you say, uh, uh, how do you say
that accountable? Make me
accountable. Hold me accountable.
Yeah. Yeah. It's uh, when we do
something together, right. And
then like, yeah, everybody's
like, oh, I already wrote this
and I wrote this and I was like,
oh yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm going to
do that. You know, like it's,
it's fun and yeah. Even after
the, the monthly challenge, then
I was still like in my, uh, you
know, I was like in my mood to,
to, to write. And that's why I
keep writing, but it's
Dan: That's awesome.
Ayu: all PC.
Dan: from VC
Bekah: As in November, we ran our
first monthly challenge and that
was, um, November is NaNoWriMo.
So national novel writing month.
And the goal is to write 50,000
words, which is about the size of
a novel. And so we said, Hey, why
don't we all work together and
try and pick, get hit 50,000
words this month writing and
adding to our blogs.
Dan: Like collectively,
Bekah: Yes, not individually.
Dan: right.
Bekah: Um, and it turned out to
be a lot of fun. It was kind of a
last minute thing. And a lot of
people participated. A lot of
people were writing for the first
time and we didn't hit 50,000,
but I think, you know, we didn't
really gear up either. It was
like, okay, we're going to do
this. But I really think this
November we could hit 50,000
words and it'll be a lot of fun.
It was great to see everybody
sharing and asking for feedback
and, and getting like new and
exciting ideas out there. Um, But
I also want to bring up, so
you're writing across platforms
and not only that, but you're
like recognized on all of the
platforms that you're writing on.
Like you're consistently one of
the top bloggers in, um, you were
recognized, well, why don't you
talk about that first or get
ahead of myself. I'm so excited
about it. Um, Writing on all of
these different platforms and
your choice to do that. And you
know, how, how are I want to say
that? I don't think you give
yourself enough credit, right?
Because everybody is giving you
credit here and saying like, I,
you is an amazing writer and all
these ways. And.
Ayu: No. I mean, like I w I
write, because I want to write,
right. It was, it was only for
the sake of the monthly challenge
at the beginning. And I don't
have any, you know, like a
website or something like that.
So I started with a platform of
hashed note where I can have my
own, um, Uh, address, but, uh, I
can use their platform. And then
from there I cross posted two
deaths and then, uh, and then
there's a code newbie, and then I
cross posit as well to go newbie.
I never think about like gaming.
Defending readers or something
like that, because I thought, I
even thought that no one will
ever read my blog and I write, I
write the blog posts purely only
for myself, you know? Like I want
to have my notes out there
because my notes are so
cluttering and, uh, I want to,
uh, look back to it and yeah. I
would write for myself that that
was the first thing. So I didn't
even know like, like when you say
back, I like, oh, how do you do
that? I have no idea. I mean,
like, I never even thought that
one with read, so
Bekah: Well, everyone is reading.
And also you were one of the code
newbie spotlights in April. Yeah.
April. You were a code newbie.
Spotlight. Talk a little bit
about that. Cause that's awesome.
Ayu: Yeah. I mean, like, it was a
nice surprise. Um, Code Newbie,
like sent me a DM on Twitter and
Hey, do you want to be our April
spotlight? And I was like, oh
yeah, sure. Like, how come
Dan: Yeah.
Ayu: I have no idea? Like, it's,
it's a big surprise and yeah. So
that
Bekah: Yeah.
Ayu: was pretty much about it. I
mean, like, I, I didn't see that
it's coming, you know,
Bekah: I mean, I just love that.
I love the picture of you and
your mom in, in that spotlight.
It's just such a beautiful way to
kind of end that there. And,
know, I don't, I don't know if
you want to say anything about
your mom, but I know that she was
a big
Ayu: Yeah, Yeah, yeah, It's, it's
actually, it's actually. Um, kind
of, kind of nice story. I think
like, uh, my mom, we were, we
were really like best friend. I
mean, like we were really close
and, um, she suddenly got, uh,
diagnosed with auto-immune. Um,
it's actually pretty much, uh,
maintainable, if you have like a
good medicine, right. And one of
it is like steroids, but at that
time in, in, uh, where, uh, where
she lived, uh that's, there's not
enough staff. So she got worse
and worse and worse, like really
fast. So, uh, like one day, and
she didn't want to receive my
call for like a couple of weeks,
because she was like, so in so
bad, bad condition and she didn't
want to say anything, but one
time, like finally she received
my phone call and then. I told
her, like, we talk a lot with, we
talk almost two hours so that
they, um, uh, I told her like,
Hey, I want to, uh, participate
in this, uh, photography, um, you
know, photography challenge. And
if I won, I said, uh, then, then
I would be like, in this magazine
in Germany. Yeah. And they, they
would pick up like 20, 20
pictures and the top winner would
be like, uh, going into the
magazine in Germany and just
like, oh, you should make me as
your model. You know? And I think
that you would win with my, with
my foot on it. And I really want
to see you on the magazine. I was
like, yeah. All right. I didn't
even get into the, the talent of
the photography. And, uh, like
not long after that, it's like
the week or two weeks, something
like that. Then, um, I got a
phone call from my arm, uh, and
she said like, I think that he
should go. All of you are like me
and my siblings. You all should
go back because like, she's
getting worse. And we're like,
oh, okay. So we flew, right. We
flew there. And after I was
there, five days late, later she
passed away. So I didn't, I
didn't get into a day magazine of
course, because I didn't, I
didn't, uh, Participate in, in
the photography challenge and
with this called newbie. And
suddenly now, after, after the,
uh, my profile got into prose
work called Nubian, then I
remember this, you know, like
this conversation, like when she
said, I want to see you on that
magazine and this time. It's not
the magazine, but I mean, like I
want an article and that's me,
that's me there. And that's why I
took my mom picture there because
like, Hey, mom is like, you're
there now? You know, like it's
not, it's not on the photography
thing that we talk about, but
there on, on my, uh, on an
article about me. So yeah, I hope
that.
Bekah: It's such a beautiful
story and it's so nice to hear
you share it and to talk about
your mom and, and, and that
support and to see how it just
all kind of come around and, you
know, um, yeah. I just, just
really, really beautiful.
Ayu: Yeah. I just hope that she
proud of
Dan: Okay.
Ayu: I mean, like, Yeah.
Bekah: Okay. I mean, are you,
you're doing so much. I mean,
you're taking care of your
daughter, you're learning, you're
bringing up, helping so much with
the community and being such a, a
great person to have in our
community and to, you know, have
your support and all of the
things that you share. And, you
know, you've, you've touched so
many lives. So I feel like she,
most definitely is proud of that.
Ayu: Thank you. Thank you so
much. And I'm, I'm, I'm very,
very grateful to find, uh,
fertile coffee, to be honest, and
like, thank you back that Dan and
Kirk and Sara and yeah, everybody
in VC, like very, very supportive
and very, very loving. I mean,
like this is the first time that
I feel like I'm not alone, not
only in the journey of learning,
but VC is more like a family to
me. And even though we haven't
met in real life, but I feel like
I'm so close to everyone as if
like, yeah, I, I I've met you all
for a thousand years, so yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean, that's been
my experience too. You know, I
always struggled with finding
friends and fitting in and kind
of understanding like my place in
things. And it's just been really
nice to be able to share that
with other people and for other
people too, except except me
where I'm at in that. Place and,
and to be able to talk about
things more openly, because I
don't know if, if he knew me five
years ago, I'm a much different
person than I was. And before I
never would have shared any of
that, I just would've like
bottled it all up, but it's nice
to have a community that you feel
safe and supported with and to be
able to talk about those things
like, wow, I'm just really,
really having a tough day today.
You know, and, and just to even
just somebody giving me a heart
emoji is like, sometimes that's
all I need. I just need someone
to acknowledge that I am having a
hard day. Um, and it's, and it's
just a really special place. I
haven't found anything else like
that.
Ayu: True. True. I feel, I feel
the same. I mean, like when was I
find Virtual coffee, it was from
your tweet, right, Bekah?. Hey,
I'm having this, uh, Virtual
coffee and, uh, you, uh, you post
the slack, the slack link, and I
did join the slack, but I wasn't
saying anything at all. And I was
like, I don't know. I mean, like
I'm still learning. All people
here already developer, you know,
and I got, how can I, I, I didn't
even dare to say hi. I was like,
oh my God, who am I? You know?
But yeah. So I finally, after, I
don't know, a couple of months I
seen and finally. I say hi and
introduce myself, uh, in the
slack. And then I went to the
meeting for the first time when I
was like, no, everybody's like so
nice. And everybody's like, maybe
already have more than 10 years
experience, but they're still
like so humble and so caring. And
I was like, yes, I think I know
that I'm in the right. In a
heartbeat. I just know that,
yeah, this is, this is my
community, you know? Right. Nice.
It's always nice to be in VC like
you can see me almost every day
on slack. Oh, sorry for that.
come up. Help it.
Dan: Oh, we are certainly glad
you are here. Um, in slack and,
and at the meetings. Uh it's it's
I don't know. It's always good to
see you there
Ayu: Oh, oh one time. Like, uh, I
usually like do co-work at
nights, right? Because I've
learned at night and most of the
time. I cannot really talk
because my husband and my thing,
my daughter's super sensitive to
voices. But the, for today I
already told my husband, like,
don't get bothered because I'm
going to talk loud. And yeah. So
usually in the coworking channel,
like people don't really hear my
voice because I always typing,
like people say something that
has weight, right. And then one
time Glenn. I will give ten bucks
to anybody who can make her talk
because I never hear her voice.
Dan: That's amazing.
Bekah: That is so funny.
Ayu: Yeah.
Dan: Now we can just send him
this podcast episode, Right.
Bekah: That's right. Who gets a
10 bucks.
Dan: Oh, yeah. Who gets it? That
we'll split it.
Bekah: Okay.
Ayu: it.
Bekah: I guess you've given a lot
of advice throughout this podcast
and through all the blogs that
you've written. So I have, I
guess, two more questions for
you. And the first would be what
has been your favorite blog post
to write if you have one and then
the second question would be, if
you had advice to give to
somebody in your shoes, what
would that advice.
Ayu: My favorite. My favorite
post so far is the last one to be
honest system, massive burnout
ones that when I, uh, that's the
fastest one that I, that I wrote
because it's really coming,
coming from, like, I don't, I
don't really filter it. It's just
coming out and yeah, that will
one is my favorite blog posts.
And if I have. Uh, oh, what, what
did you say again?
Bekah: If you had one piece of
advice to give to someone in your
shoes, what would it be?
Ayu: well, if you, if you're a,
self-learner like try to. Find a
community because it's, it
really, really helps you. I mean,
like it's, uh, it helps me a lot.
Uh, I get more confident and, and
I have people to support me. And
when, when I can, I also, I also
can support someone. Right. And
it makes you feel like you're not
alone, but also fell you bowl or
somebody else. And if you want to
start your own. Don't think
twice, just, just write it and
don't think that maybe nobody
will really read it or maybe it's
not good. No, it is just write
it. I mean like it's, uh, you
write it for yourself. That's,
that's the first thing that you
only have to think, like write it
for yourself and then the rest
will come.
Bekah: Yeah, that's so great.
Well, I thank you so much for
being here with us today on the
podcast, but for being such a
great part of the community, it's
been so wonderful to have you
here with us.
Dan: thank you
Bekah: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, plus you can
sign up for our newsletter to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening. And
we'll see you next week.