Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode four of
the Virtual Coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah.
And this is a podcast that
features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned, and we are.
To share it with you here with
me today is my co-host.
Dan.
Thanks
Dan: Bekah today.
We had a fascinating
conversation with
Joan Marie Verba.
Joan shared her long journey
with us, including her
early days in tech using Fortran
and how refusal to
accommodate her allergies has
prevented her from having
a lifelong career in tech.
She talks about pushing forward
and the importance of.
Not taking no for an
Joan: answer.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast.
Like we start every Virtual
Coffee.
We introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're
from, what we do and a random
check-in question.
Today's random question is if
you could be an expert in
one thing, what would it be?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Hi, I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from
a small town in Ohio.
And if I could be an expert in
one thing,  can
I choose the human person?
Is that, is that acceptable?
Totally.
I was trying to decide if I
wanted to do like brain or
hormone, but if I can just
totally be an expert in humans.
That's where I would go.
I think
Dan: that's, I think that's
valid and would be a very
cool thing to be an expert in.
Hi, I'm Dan I'm from, I don't
know a medium
sized city in Ohio.
from Lakewood, Ohio.
I do front end development and
yeah, if I could be an
expert in one thing, I, I think
my answer's going to be
what's like plants and stuff.
You know, there's, there's,
Arbery, there's
like Arbery botany.
Maybe that just covers
everything.
Cause I like the trees, I just
humans.
Bekah: So you can just say
Dan: plants.
I think I like plants  no, it's,
you know, and I've, I've
learned and forgotten stuff,
especially tree related,
you know, like identifying trees
based on different
properties and nothing like that
ever sticks in my brain.
You know, if I don't use all the
time, but.
We had an abust at our house to
clips and trees.
And I just made him walk around
in my yard for half an hour.
putting a trees and tell, making
me tell, tell me, you know,
what kind of tree this one is?
What's that one?
What's that one, which he, he,
he didn't seem to mind
too much on, it was fun.
So yes, plants, this plants is
my answer.
Joan: My name is, uh, Joan re
Verba and I'm from Minnesota
and I'm a front end developer.
And if I wanted to be an expert
in something, I
think I would want to be an
expert in astronomy.
I know enough so that I did
teach astronomy at Indiana
university as an associate
instructor for one year,
but there's a lot more that I
could know and a lot more
that I than I'd want to know.
So I'd want to know even more
than I know now.
Dan: That's awesome.
Astronomy is so cool.
That's another one of those
things where that's my second.
Yeah.
I, it was always so interesting.
And for me, I could never keep
any of those, the details,
you know, in my mind, but I
always, I loved going to the
planetarium and, you know, I, I
took a couple astronomy classes,
intro classes in undergrad.
And actually I saw in your, I
mean, you just said it,
you were from, or you.
Was it undergrad at Indiana?
Or was it grad school?
No, I was
Joan: undergrad at the
university of Minnesota and
I took graduate courses at
Indiana university, but I did
not get a master's degree.
I did not reach that point.
Okay.
Were,
Dan: were you in Bloomington?
Joan: Yes, I was in Bloomington,
Indiana.
Dan: I love Bloomington.
I, we lived there.
My, my wife went to grad school
there.
We lived there for, I don't
know, five, five or six years.
It's a great, great city.
A great, great area.
Bekah: Thanks so much for being
on the podcast with us today.
Joan, we're really excited to
hear more about your story.
And we always like to kick it
off with the origin
story, kind of how you got to
the point where you are
now, how you got into tech.
And so I know for you, this kind
of is a long story.
So if you just wanna.
Talk about up to the point where
you got your first job in tech.
Maybe we can ask some more
questions and
then go from there.
Joan: Okay.
I'll pause.
At that point, then I have been
interested in
tech for quite some time.
My dad was a marketing manager,
a controlled data corporation
in the 1960s and seventies and
eighties and up through the
nineties and he sold mainframe
computers to companies.
And when I was in high school,
the first computers
came out and the high school had
sort of a time share
with a mainframe computer.
And so there were some after
school activities for people
who were interested in computers
and I attended those.
And the way that we pro
reprogrammed them in basic, and
there was paper tape, we would
punch holes in a paper tape and
then run the paper tape through.
And that was the software.
And then we would get results.
Then from there from high
school, I went to college.
My freshman and sophomore year
was at the university of Chicago
and I had some extra credits.
So I took a computer programming
course, and that was fun
with the mainframe computers.
At that time, we were not
punching paper tape anymore.
We were PA.
Punching cards.
And so each line of the code had
to be on one card.
And so if you had a large
software program, you had
pretty much a long box of cards
to bring in and put through
the computer and then the
computer would read the cards
and then give out the results.
And then I went to junior and
senior year.
I transferred to the university
of Minnesota and I got my
degree in physics, but I also
took computer courses.
The reason I took computer
courses was not only because
I was interested in them, but
because at the time they
were telling us, well, you know,
you can get your degree
in physics or astronomy or
whatever, but there aren't
a lot of jobs in there.
So quite possibly you will have
a job in another area.
So I took computer programming
interested me.
So I was taking computer
programming courses after I got
my degree and went to graduate
school at Indiana university.
I continued to take courses.
When I finished at Indiana
university, I took a couple
of more graduate courses in
computer science at the
university of Minnesota.
And after that I was ready to
get a job.
So I applied for a job and I got
a job at, uh uny and the
job was in the airline division.
And I was in the group that was
programming flight schedules.
That's what I had at first.
And then the programming group
that I was in was
expanded to cover also hotel
reservations for the airlines.
By that time we were not using
cards anymore.
We were doing what.
Computer program is due.
Now we were keyboarding our
instructions into a computer
and, you know, sending it in
that way and getting
it compiled and bug tested and
all that sort of thing.
That was a lot of fun.
And so you asked me to stop when
I got my first job in tech and
that was my first job in tech.
That was in the late seventies,
early eighties.
Dan: Oh, that's.
My dad did just in school, a
little bit of the, of
the program with the cards and
the whole, you know,
punching holes in the cards.
And he always talks about, I
guess he, you know, cuz one of
the, one of the things that is
important is you have to keep
them in the right order, right?
Oh yes.
When you are carrying them
around and yeah.
And so he is at least once,
maybe more than that.
Definitely.
Drop the stack of cards and
still
Joan: what was recommended at
the time is that we take
a highlighter and on the top of
the cards draw a
diagonal line so that if the
cards ever got separated,
all we had to do was line them
up so that the line was
Dan: strange.
Oh, that's a good
Joan: idea.
And that, and that would, that
would mean, you know,
if we dropped the cards and they
got out of order, we
could put them back and it was
easier to do that way.
Bekah: What did the industry
look like for
you getting into it?
Was it something that was hard
or did you find that you
were at a disadvantage or were
there challenges that you were
Joan: facing?
I didn't find a disadvantage at
all.
There were, and you know, other
people who have studied
the history of tech have, have
also confirmed this.
There were quite a lot of women
in the computer
programming field at the time,
maybe about a third.
Of the people who were working
in the airline division
at uny were women had no
problems there in my group.
I was the only woman, but there
were lots of groups
in the airline division.
And about, I'd say about a third
of the, the, the
programmers were women.
It was not considered unusual to
be a woman in the field
doing programming at the time.
Bekah: And so as you moved
forward in your career,
was there a shift at all?
Or did you feel like the
environment started to
change or did you kind of leave
the industry before.
Joan: Well, I'll tell you what
happened with the industry.
Uh, what happened in the
industry in the eighties was
that, well, first of all, I
changed jobs in late 1982
because of the recession and my
group in the airline.
Was discontinued, I guess it was
given to, to somebody else,
but I was transferred to a
financial thing and it was asked
I was programming in Fortran and
I was asked to program in
Cobal and I didn't really want
to do financial programming.
It didn't really appeal to me in
cobalt.
Did not appeal to me at all.
I mean, there are some people
who say that, you know, you
ought to be able to learn any
programming language,
if you are a programmer.
And I learned a lot of 'em.
I learned many in college and
graduate school and I was
prepared to do anything, but I
was not prepared to do cobalt.
Somehow cobalt just never fit my
particular skill.
And as I said, though, they say
that you can learn any
programming language cobalt just
never made sense to
me in any way whatsoever.
So I went to Republic airlines
because I was used
to doing airline programming.
They programmed in.
I'm blanking out on the term,
but it was the, the very
basic programming language that
we, that we had.
So I was, I was in another
programming language.
That was fine.
I learned it fine that didn't
work out for various reasons.
And so I sort of bounced around
from job to job until I got to
a, uh, tech startup in 1980.
And this is where the
environment changed, but
probably not in the way that you
think, because by that time,
Steve jobs and apple were, were
trying to revolutionize the
computer industry and do things
differently and have a different
work environment and have a.
Working philosophy.
Now I have food allergies up
until Steve jobs started
introducing all of these
innovations at the workplace.
Food was forbidden.
You were not to have food.
Definitely not to have food in
the places where you were
doing keyboarding, because it
was felt the chromes
would mess up the computers,
mess up the keyboards,
mess up the computers.
You weren't supposed to have
food anywhere
at all at your desk.
They might look the other way.
They looked the other way.
Cuz I had tea, you know, I
brought a Thermo of tea.
I, I was looked the other way,
but otherwise you're
supposed to eat in the lunch.
You were not supposed to eat in
the computer areas at all,
but when Steve jobs started
doing things, one of the things
that he started doing was
introducing the fact that you
had food all over the place.
You had free food for everybody
at the workplace, and you
could have food everywhere.
And there was food everywhere.
And by the time I got to this
startup in 1987, there was food.
Every.
And this was a problem for me,
you know, I'm definitely
allergic to peanuts.
They were eating peanuts at the
keyboards where I was
supposed to do programming and I
got definitely ill.
My lung capacity dropped by
half.
I had to go see a doctor.
I was ill for an entire year.
I had to quit the job because I
simply just to recover.
I, I simply could not work there
anymore.
And that was a big change for
me.
After that I wanted to get back
into programming, but the
personal computer, the mainframe
was going out of phase.
And the startup that I had
worked for in 1987, went out
of business a couple of months
after I quit, because they
were into mainframes and nobody
wanted mainframes anymore.
Everybody wanted personal
computers.
And I did not have the
instruction to program personal
computers and I was broke.
I didn't have a job.
I had moved back with my parents
and I was ill.
And so I, I couldn't afford to
go back to college and learn
the new PC programming skills.
So I went to other jobs, worked
for a publishing company,
trained as an editor, got into
publishing a little bit.
After that I worked as an editor
for about 15 years,
and then I, I also worked for
another company more or
less in customer service.
And then in 2015, I learned
about coding boot camps.
And I had never heard about
coding boot camps before,
but someone was starting a
coding boot camp locally.
And I thought, okay, maybe I can
retrain to do this because
I had learned basic HTML by
myself in the late nineties
to build my own websites.
And I knew enough to build a
website, but you know,
nothing that would suit me for a
job, but the, the
recruiting boot camps and the
person who started the coding
boot camp was interviewed by the
local press and said
that the reason why he was.
A a coding bootcamp was that
there were so many jobs
in web development open, and
there weren't enough
trained people to fill them.
And I thought, okay, I should be
able to learn coding fairly
easily because of my computer
programming background, the
bootcamp is not terribly
expensive and I, and it
would be like 16 to 20 weeks.
And then I would go to a job and
then I could get hired.
Well, okay.
So I applied for this bootcamp
in 2015, and it was
pretty difficult to get in.
I had to have two interviews.
I had to take some free coding
classes to prove
that I could code.
I had to prove that I was, had
an aptitude for coding, and
then I applied for a scholarship
and I had to pass a number.
Various tests to get the
scholarship, but I finally
got accepted and I finally got
the scholarship and the
coding boot camp for me was
supposed to start at the
end of August a couple of weeks
before the coding boot
camp was supposed to start.
And I, and I got the
scholarship.
I, um, called the person who was
in charge of the coding school.
And I said, okay, I need
accommodations.
I have food allergies.
I would like there not to be
food in.
School room in the classroom.
If you have food elsewhere,
fine.
I'll avoid those areas, but I
can't avoid the classroom.
So there has to be no food in
the classroom.
Well, the guy sort of went
ballistic and we had a half
hour conversation in which he
was just apoplectic.
And, and I was trying to explain
this, this really
isn't a big deal, but he was
still apoplectic.
I said, look, let me go to your.
Location.
And, you know, I'll be able to
tell pretty easily if, if
it's suitable for me or not.
And so I did go to the location
a couple of days
after that and looked around and
I said, look, you know,
this looks pretty good.
All you have to do is, is make
sure that there's
no food in the classroom.
And I think I'll be okay.
But no, a couple days later I
received an email
from him saying that my
enrollment had been canceled.
My scholarship had been cancel.
And in addition to that, I was
totally unsuitable to be
a student at a code school.
Jeez.
Okay.
Not to be deterred.
wait, can we just pause for a
minute here?
There, this is a good place to
pause.
Bekah: I just feel like we've
covered a
couple of decades here.
So I wanna, I wanna jump back to
like your first experience
with that, because you talked
about these environmental
changes and it's a lot of things
that one, I don't think
people really think about.
Dealing with challenges that
they're not faced on a day
to day basis all the time.
And so when you had to quit that
first job at the startup, did
you talk to your employer about
the situation with the food?
Joan: Oh, there were a number of
conversations.
My doctor wrote a two page
letter to them explaining
my food allergies and that I
couldn't be around nuts
and I needed the Nury area and
all this sort of thing.
And they finally got down to
saying, we're going to offer
you a nut free area, your desk.
Mm-hmm  and that really was not
sufficient  yeah, it
was, it was not sufficient.
So I really had to quit because
they said, you know,
it's it's this or nothing.
So I quit.
But there were a number of
conversations.
I had conversations with my
supervisor.
I had a conversation with HR.
The doctors had conversations
with them.
The doctors wrote letters, you
know, stuff like that.
It.
It didn't, we weren't able to,
to reach an agreement where I
thought that I would be safe.
So I, I simply quit.
And I was, I was so ill by the
time I quit.
Anyway, as I said, my lung
capacity dropped to
half and it stayed that way for
quite some time.
It took me about a year to
recover from that.
So it was, it was a really
traumatic experience for.
Oh, for
Bekah: sure.
And then the, the traumas
relived, I think when you
were trying to enter that
bootcamp in the middle, when
you were working as an editor
and the other things you were
doing, were they accommodating
Joan: to you?
The editing job was ahead of its
time because it was remote work.
There wasn't really a lot of
remote work at that time.
That was legitimate.
This was legitimate, remote
work.
All I had to do, I, I worked at
home.
They wanted you to work at home.
It cut their overhead expenses,
tremendously for their
employees to work at home.
All the editors worked at home
and all I had to do was to.
Just go to the pickup area and
pick up my
assignments in the morning.
And then the next day I would
drop off my assignments
from the day before and pick up
my new assignments.
So it really, there really was
very minimal contact there.
And so I worked at home where I
was comfortable.
The other job that I had did
accommodate me.
But them.
And remember I said, I worked
for a publishing
company too, for a while.
They in the publishing company
did accommodate me, but there
was an overall feeling that they
felt it was a nuisance.
And that I was a nuisance and
that they really would
rather not do this, but they
sort of had to, because I
had to be accommodated and they
sort of had to fill,
fulfill the employment law about
accom because the
ADA had not been passed.
When I lost my job in 1987, it
had been by the time I'd
gotten these other jobs.
And so they accommodated me, but
it was not a comfortable
situation in either of those.
Bekah: Okay, so you left tech
and in this very traumatic
experience and then 20 ish years
later, decide to try tech again.
And so I wonder, like what kind
of inspired you to try for
this again, after having such a
bad experience in tech prior.
Joan: I guess I was desperate at
the time that that I
enrolled in the bootcamp, I had
lost my previous jobs.
The editing job came to an end
and I was told that I
was not eligible for rehire.
I won't go into the reasons.
And then the other job, again,
as I said, the accommodation
was very reluctant.
And I felt unwelcome.
I just felt that the, the time
had come for
that job to end too.
So I didn't have any work and I
felt that I could,
and I thought, you know, if
there's such a demand for
web developers, good, because
this is a job that I can do.
All I need is the instruction on
the latest techniques.
Bekah: So then you're back in
this situation again, right.
And you've kind of are reliving
this trauma in a
new way and you are stuck
because what you thought was
going to happen, just got.
Totally taken away from you.
And then you decided you were
gonna keep going forward, right?
That
Joan: is correct.
Shall I go on?
Yeah, I wanna know do that.
Bekah: You still are looking for
those jobs.
That was still the inspiration
here.
Joan: I still felt that a coding
boot camp was the way to go.
So I kept on researching coding,
boot camps to see if there was
one nearby or one that I could
take remotely or whatever.
And so at the end of 2015, I
discovered that there
was a boot camp network called
the iron yard.
That was all over the country,
but was just planning to
get started in Minneapolis.
And I thought, okay, let's get
on in, on the
ground level on that.
So I did.
So I went and I went to the, get
acquainted meetings,
get acquainted with the iron
yard meetings and I applied.
And again, I took another
bootcamp later, but
we'll get into that, but it
seems that that the
bootcamps have a, um, long.
Intake process by which they
want to make sure that you
have the aptitude to do code and
that you have at least
the enthusiasm to do code.
So there was a long process by
which I had to
meet these requirements and I
did fairly easily.
And so I was accepted into the
iron yard.
In early 2016.
And again, I waited until the
last minute and I
said, I want to meet with the
campus director.
And I met with the campus
director and I told the campus
director of the iron yard.
I have food allergies.
And I need accommodation.
And as soon as those words are
out, we're out, the campus
director said, okay, here is
what we're going to do for you.
We are going to have no food in
the classroom.
We are going to notify all the
students.
They are not to bring any food
into the classroom.
They're not to bring any food in
any of their backpacks.
They're only to eat in a, in
designated areas,
outside the classroom.
And she said, and if you have
any trouble with that or
have any problems whatsoever,
you come and talk to me.
That was very different than my
previous studio.
That sounds
Dan: better
. Joan: So I did go to the iron
yard and the conditions were, as
they said, and again, the campus
director and the instructor
said, you know, we are where you
have food allergies.
If you have any problems, you,
you, you come to us.
I never had any problems because
the students were very diligent.
About observing the rules and
that was fine and
they didn't seem to have any
problems with it.
That was great.
So I started the, the iron yard
in June and
graduated in September.
Then I started applying for jobs
and they had, you know,
the part of the program was job
coaching and all this sort
of thing, which was great.
And then I did apply for a job
at, at a certain company.
I won't name it.
I, I applied for a job at a
certain company.
They said it was a front end
development job.
Mine was, I just got a
certificate in
front end development.
Wonderful.
Let's go for it.
All of the intake was remote.
Every single bit of the intake
was remote.
I did not see a single employee
face to face until my first
official day at the job.
Everything was remote and the
induction process was long.
It was a couple of months.
They did a thorough background
check and I had to pass
the background check, which I
did, but then again,
that took a month and then
finally they gave me an.
I accepted the offer.
I signed the employment
contract, and then only
after that, I said, I need
accommodation
for my food allergies.
So I was put in touch with the
executive.
This, this is a big
multinational company and
I was put in touch with the
executive in charge of
employees with disabilities.
And she said, okay, to
accommodate you.
We have to have a doctor's note.
We have a certain form.
You can have the doctor fill out
and fax it back to us.
That's fine.
They emailed me the form.
I printed it out.
Fortunately, my doctor had an
appointment on the same day.
I went to the doctor, she filled
out the form.
She, she faxed it in.
I faxed it in  to, to make sure
that they got it.
I also scanned it and emailed it
to make sure that they got it.
They told me that they got.
That the accommodations were
there.
They were going to have signs
up.
They were going to, to put me in
the place that was the
most remote op the most remote
desk from the lunchroom.
That's what they promised me.
They said there would be signs
up for people to, to say,
there's someone with food
allergies here, please confine
your food to the lunchroom areas
and don't bring any nuts
and peanuts into the, into the
AR in the work areas at all.
They said, this was all going to
happen.
So I went there and I had a
week's orientation at
the headquarters, which, which
was fine and the
environment was okay.
And they did pay attention to my
allergies though.
I had to remind them a couple of
times.
And then I got to the first day
on the site of the job where I
was going to be at and welcome.
Got my badge.
Showing my desk.
Okay.
First thing I do is of course I
wash off the desk in case
the, the previous occupant had
crumbs or anything.
So I'm washing off the desk and
my supervisor comes up to me and
says, oh, I need to, to inform
you that we share desks here.
And I said that, well, that's
fine.
But the person who is sharing my
desk will have to be very
diligent because I have food
allergies and can't have
nuts and peanuts in the area.
And he said, oh, no one told me
about that.
And also there were no signs up.
And also my desk was not the
farthest one
away from the lunchroom.
Wow.
Bekah: So all of the
accommodations
Joan: that did not happen.
And then a week later, my
supervisor asked me to come
into a conference room and meet
with me privately.
So I meet with him privately.
And he said you can't work.
So basically I was sent home to
await an assignment.
I waited for a year.
They did not have an assignment
for me that they felt that
they could put me into, and then
they laid me off.
Dan: Ah,  so they sent you home
just because they didn't
wanna deal with accommodating
Joan: you or they didn't wanna
deal with the food
allergies situation.
No.
Gosh.
Is that what
Bekah: they said?
What was the,
Joan: the reason, the reason was
the food allergies.
Oh wow.
They said you, you, you can't
work here.
We have food all over the place
all the time we were, and we're
not, that's not gonna change.
Bekah: And you know, the thing
here too, is.
First of all.
I'm sorry, this is something
that you should never
have to go through at all.
Let alone.
Over a period of many years to
have to push
through these challenges.
But also, you know, I've heard
other people who need
accommodations for health
reasons who have experienced
the same thing where they've
been told, well, go home
and then we'll contact you when
we have an assignment.
And then there's never an
assignment for them.
And it is just, I wanna say a
shame, but it's, it's,
it's, it's terrible, right?
It's way worse than a shame.
It's not okay at the very least,
you know?
Okay.
So now you've navigated through
yet another challenge and
somehow not given up hope.
Right.
And where does that take you
next
Joan: about the time that I got
laid off, the university
of Minnesota was offering.
A bootcamp locally and the price
was right.
So I enrolled in their full
stack bootcamp thinking
that, you know, I have front end
development experience.
If I get full stack experience,
that will expand the number
of jobs I'm able to apply to.
So I enrolled in that bootcamp.
They did accommodate me.
I did have to remind them a few
times, but you know, they did
accommodate me and I graduated.
I started that in, uh, March of
2018, about the
time that I was laid off.
And then that wa that ended at
the end of July in 2018.
So I graduated from that and all
the time that I was going
through the bootcamp and
learning through the bootcamp,
I was also looking for work.
All the time.
And I have been looking for work
ever since I was
laid off in March of 2018.
And I have kept track of the
number of jobs that I have
been applying to because I was
sort of curious as to how
many jobs or how long that I
would have to apply before
I got a job this morning.
I filled out my 532nd job
application.
That's how many jobs that I have
applied to since I was laid off.
So I am still applying for jobs.
I have done some freelance work.
In between, but when the
pandemic came last year,
those dried up pretty quickly.
So I didn't even have any
freelance work to do so that's
pretty much where I am now.
I am still applying for jobs.
Still hoping that someone will
hire me.
I don't know if you want me to
go on the podcast
and relate my terrible
experience of last month.
which you heard about at the
Virtual Coffee?
I can, if you wish.
Bekah: I think that's really a
part of your story and
you face so many challenges.
And so if that's something
you're willing to share,
I would love for you to talk
about that too.
I am
Joan: certainly willing to share
this because I was told
when I made the call and I'll
get into that in a moment that
this was a very common scam that
people who are applying
for check jobs, run into.
So.
At my 521st application, I got a
note saying that they wanted to
interview me, which was great.
I mean, I've, I've been on your
interviews.
Haven't gotten hired, but I've
got, I've had some interviews.
So they, they asked me to
interview and I
responded to the interview.
It was a set of written
questions, written interview
questions that they asked me to
return and I returned them.
And then, then after I returned
them, you know,
there was an interview and then
they said I was hired
and I was just thrilled.
I thought I, I was hired now
this, this job was posted on
Glassdoor, which is a reputable
place for posting jobs.
The name of the company was
genuine.
They took the name of a company
of a genuine company in Austin.
Texas gave me the genuine name
and address the employment
contract, which they gave me was
a standard tech
employment contract, looked like
any other tech employment
contract that I had signed.
I signed it and sent it back to
them.
By email, all this remote stuff
was not unusual because I had
gone through this with this
other company where everything
in the onboarding was remote.
The email address looked like.
The email that would be from the
HR, from this company, uh, no
trouble with the email address.
Although the person that was
supposedly my supervisor had
a non-company email, but you
know that I've had freelance
jobs where that's happened too.
So that, that didn't raise any,
any alarms with me.
So I thought, oh my goodness, I
am finally hired.
Wonderful.
I've got an employment contract.
They said fine.
And it's for a remote job.
Great.
That's what I need a remote job.
And they said, you've gotta set
up a home office.
Fine.
That's that's great.
And we want you to use company
equipment that you buy from
our designated supplier.
That's not unusual either.
So they said we will send you a
check.
And you will use that check to
buy the equipment
for your home office.
Fine.
So they sent me the check and it
came through the
post by priority mail.
It looked like a priority mail
envelope, but the
address, the name and address on
the check was not
the one of the companies.
So I emailed the person that was
supposed to be my supervisor.
I said, this check is not from
your company.
And he says, oh, that's one of
our trust vendors.
Don't worry about it.
It's a good check.
I said, okay.
But I also looked at the address
on the envelope and the address
on the envelope did not match
the address on the check.
Which did not add none.
Neither of them matched the
address from the company.
And I looked up on Google maps,
the address, the return
address on the envelope, and it
was a vacant lot.
And so my supervisor was, was
saying, my supposed supervisor
was saying, okay, we want you to
take the check to the bank.
We want you to email the
receipt, the deposit receipt
to us so that we know that
you've deposited the check.
I said fine.
So I went to the bank and I said
to the banker, I.
I've been told trust, but verify
there's, there's something about
this check that I questioned.
So what I would like you to do,
this was on a Friday.
I said, what I'd like you to do
is call the bank and see if
it's a legitimate account and
that the funds are available.
And they said, well, this is
Friday after three o'clock and
it was so, so we really don't
expect a response until Monday.
I said, that's fine.
So on Saturday my supposed
supervisor gets back to
me and he says, has the check
been deposited?
I said, yes.
And I scanned the receipt and
emailed it.
Did not have my full bank
account number
on it, those seats.
So like felt safe in that.
So he says, well, we want you to
get started right away.
So we want you to buy the
equipment right away.
I said, fine.
He says, I'll put you in touch
with our supplier.
Fine.
So it was a text message
conversation.
So the text message says, I am
George or whatever from a
one computer supply company.
And, uh, we want to deliver the
equipment to you by 5:00 PM, but
we want you to pay for it first.
And we want you to withdraw the
money in cash from
your bank, and then deposit it
into our bank.
I said, okay, now I had checked
my bank account
thing and it looked as if the
check had gone through.
So I thought, okay.
It looks like the check has gone
through, so I.
I drove to the bank and I said,
remember that check.
I want to withdraw it.
She says, you, you can't.
I said, uh, why not?
It said on my, on your website,
when I checked my account on
your website, that the money was
available, she says, oh,
that that's, that's an error.
That was misleading.
I'm sorry that it still isn't,
we're still waiting
for it to come through.
And we're still waiting to hear
from the other.
And I said, okay.
And so I texted the supplier and
I said, they won't
let me take out the money.
I'm I'm sorry, I can't do that.
And I never heard from the
supplier or the supposed
thing again, Monday I called
someone who was, who I
felt was knowledgeable in these
sorts of situations.
And I said, look, here is what's
happening.
And she.
Called the Minnesota attorney
general right away.
And so I did, and I explained my
situation and he, he
said, you've been scammed.
He said, this is a common scam.
He said, what job title did they
hire you for?
And I said, software engineer.
He says, this is a common scam
for the software engineers.
He says you were lucky that the
bank didn't allow you to
take out that money in cash,
because otherwise you would be
held responsible for that money.
It was $6,000  he said, and, and
file a report with the
FTC and the FBI, which I did.
Did the
Dan: FBI have anything to like
similar things to say,
Joan: or I filed the reports
online and neither of them
have gotten back to me.
And both sites said, uh, you
know, when you file a
report for us, we might not get
back to you on this.
We'll do our best, but you know,
don't expect us to,
to get back to you, but.
Thank you for filing and excuse
me, here's a copy so that you
know that you have a record of
filing the report with us,
but that was pretty much it.
And as I said, I never heard
from them again.
So I was all excited to, I
thought someone was finally
going to hire me and then.
Someone didn't and I had never
heard about this scam before.
I mean, I've heard of other
scams, and so I've been aware of
people trying to take advantage
of me, but this one I had
not heard of bef ever before.
And it was just not something
that I expected.
. Bekah: No, I had never heard
of that.
And I think, you know, as you're
telling the story, number one, I
never would've noticed that the
addresses were different for me.
I just probably would've taken
it to the bank
and did what they said.
So, I mean, I think that on top
of everything else, you
took such careful steps, which
of course you never
should even have to do.
Right?
Like this whole entire story.
So much extra work and stress
and conflict is being put on you
as you're trying to get a job.
And I just wanna say that, you
know, I think.
Your ability to continue to move
forward and to talk about
it and to openly share it is so
inspirational, I guess.
I mean, to see you moving
forward is, is something that
I really appreciate you talking
Joan: about.
Well, thank you.
I'm happy to share my story.
And I hope that the, I hope that
others are able to get
something out of it anyway.
Dan: Oh, absolutely.
And it's it's I just like this
approach is just like,
so I don't know, evil.
I'm trying to think of a good
word for it.
You know, you know, I've, I've
heard of this scam, not
this scam, but I've heard of.
The way, the check part of it
worked, right.
You know, deposit a check, take
the cash out, give it to me.
And then they cancel the check
thing.
But targeting people, looking
for jobs is like,
uh, you know, I don't know.
I dunno.
It's just, uh, shameful
Joan: using a legitimate site
for job postings using the
name of a legitimate company.
Oh
Dan: yeah.
I mean, that was going to be
another question I was
going to ask was if you had
reached out to Glassdoor
through all this, or mean after
it happened at all.
Joan: I went to Glassdoor and
found that the job
posting had been taken down.
And I felt that they probably
knew about that from that the,
the job posting did, did not
exist anymore, but I mean, they
were slick in the fact that they
used a legitimate job posting
site that they used the name and
a, the actual name and address
of a legitimate company that
they used a legitimate looking.
Employment contract and that at
least the HR, the
supposed HR person seemed to
have a legitimate
company email address.
Dan: Wow.
Yeah, the criminals, I'm sure
they're making a lot of money,
you know, scamming people like
this, it's just the emotional
place that people who are doing
the job seeking is in, cause
we've talked to people who have
done a lot of applications
and this long process and, you
know, everyone of them
has shared how hard it is, you
know, how the struggle
it is emotionally draining and
everything like that.
And so I would imagine your
defenses are kind of lower
than they would be normally
anyway, you know, so.
It's tough, but I would echo
what Bekah said is
just thank you for sharing.
That's this part of the story,
because, uh, knowing about it is
like probably the best defense
for, for other people at least.
Oh yes.
You know, I'm spreading the word
about it, so yeah.
It's, it's scary though.
Yeah, it is.
I don't like it.
Bekah: Okay.
So now you're here, Joan.
And what is your hope
Joan: for the future?
I'm still applying for jobs.
, I'm, I'm hoping that that
someone will hire me somewhere.
It's pretty much all I can do at
this point,
because I, I do need a job.
I want a job.
I would like to work, but
because of my limitations,
I do need a remote position that
limits the number of.
Jobs that I can apply for, but
I'm, I'm still applying
and that's all I can do is just
move forward.
Bekah: And what kind of keeps
you going?
Is there, like what powers your
motivation or your perseverance
to keep pushing forward?
Joan: I'm just that sort of
person that, you know,
if someone says, well, you know,
you can't do that.
And there's a lot of obstacles
and you know, there's,
are you sure you wanna do?
I'm just the sort of person who
says the heck with it.
I'm doing it.
I wanna do it.
I'm going to do it.
I'm I'm do it.
You know what?
A couple, some people have asked
me.
I've gone to events where I have
re related that, that I got my
bachelor's degree in physics,
that I was the only woman quite
often in the, in the classroom.
And I've been asked, you know,
well, you know, how
did you feel about that?
And I said, well, I thought, you
know, if they didn't
like it, that was tough.
I mean, no, I mean, I guess I
was fortunate in that, that
nobody discouraged me from
getting a bachelor's degree in
physics because I was a woman
or, or looked down down on me
while I was getting my degree
into this because I was a woman.
But I, I have heard that other
women who are trying to get
degrees in sciences have had a
real, really tough time.
I didn't, but I was prepared for
it.
And I thought, you know, even if
they did to heck with
them, that's their problem.
I don't care.
I've always had that, that
attitude, that if I had
a, um, a goal and it was a
legitimate goal and it
was something that didn't
compromise my moral principles,
I was going to go for it.
Bekah: Okay.
So I know also you're a prolific
writer, you've done science
fiction and some other things.
Have you ever written your life
story?
Joan: I have not.
What I have written as far as
life story is concerned.
I am a, a star Trek fan and I've
been a star Trek fan since 1966.
And in the 1990s, I wrote a
history of star Trek fan
activity, a fan history.
From 1967 to 1987.
And this is probably as close to
a biography as
it gets  because I told my
personal journey through it.
But also what was happening.
This book has gotten a lot of
attention, not a lot of
public attention, but a lot of
attention from people
who are like, um, scholars in
the field of popular.
And I'm very well recognized in
the field of popular culture.
My star Trek fanzine collection
is at the university of
Iowa special collections.
I was interviewed last month and
the interview was
posted Monday about this.
So I've gotten a great deal of
satisfaction from
that, but the problem is.
Publishing and writing is not a
very profitable
endeavor, unless you're one of
like the 2% of authors
who can make a living at it.
But it's something, it's
something that I do
because I enjoy writing.
And for people who enjoy
writing, it's something
that you can't not do.
So I keep writing I'm writing
right now.
Set aside, my writing for my
current novel
just before this podcast.
So it is something that I do and
it's something that, that keeps
me going, but it's not something
that you can make a living with.
And I enjoy, uh, I enjoy, I
enjoy web development.
I've got.
A dozen sites, dozen life sites
that I keep
up and keep working on.
And my GitHub repository is
solid green for this year.
So this is something that I
enjoy too.
And I'm just going to keep going
until I can't
anymore.
Bekah: Have you thought about
going back into freelancing?
Well,
Joan: yes, I'm always available
for freelance work, but nobody's
calling  that's the problem.
Yeah, that can be hard
Dan: too.
Bekah: so have you thought about
what your ideal job
or what would it look like?
I
Joan: guess.
Well, if you want to talk about
ideal job, ideally, I would
like to be one of the 2% of
authors who makes a living off
of my writing and publishing.
But again, it's so hard to get
into that 2% of authors.
So failing that.
I really enjoyed my first job as
an airline
programmer programming, the, the
hotel reservations
and the flight schedules.
That was a lot of fun.
I enjoyed that so much.
And I was so disappointed when
the company took
me off that project.
I mean, something like that, a
web development project,
where I can use my skills, where
I can make a nice front
end for somebody that would be a
wonderful job to have.
Dan: Now, what was it about that
airline project that
Joan: you liked?
First of all, I was programming
in Fortran, which is, which is a
language that I enjoy very much.
I've forgotten most of it by now
though.
So I couldn.
Be a suitable fit for a legacy
Fortran projects.
And I've been told that they're
out there, but I
was programming Fortran
programming in Fortran was fun.
The airline scheduling was, was
a lot of fun because it was
just something that you could.
Put your hands on and look at it
and, and get satisfaction
out of, you know, people are
using my stuff every day.
Yes.
And, and, you know, it's, it's,
it's something that's
useful and it's something that's
good looking.
And I did it, you know, that,
that kind of satisfaction
that you get from the job, the
hotel reservations.
I mean, I actually.
Did a lot of the hotel
reservation stuff from the
ground up, I designed a hotel
reservations thing, as well
as wrote the code for it.
I designed the concept, they
just said, give us a way
to do hotel reservations.
So I did the designing too on
that one.
And so that, that was something
that I was proud
of, but yeah, the, the, the
flight schedule was a, was a
lot of fun and very satisfy.
Dan: That's awesome.
I can totally relate to that.
Especially the, this is actually
useful and people
are actually using it.
part of it.
Yes.
You know, it doesn't always
happen, you know, in, in any
particular job, you know, so I
can totally relate to that.
Bekah: Joan, I wanna say, thank
you so much again,
for sharing your story.
And for being here with us, it
was really powerful to
listen to you, talk about it and
to hear how you're ready
to just keep moving forward.
And I hope, you know, some way
Virtual Coffee can help
continue to support you in those
goals and do something
that hopefully we can celebrate
you getting a job pretty
Joan: soon.
Well, thanks very much for
interviewing me.
This was fun.
Yeah, I had fun too.
Dan: Thank you, John.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
OT and Bekah harra,
Weigel and edited by Dan OT.
If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us
up on Twitter at Virtual Coffee
IO, or you can email
us@podcastvirtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee's been up to on
our website@virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure
to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.