Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode five of
the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we are here to
share it with
you. Here with me today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today we talk
with Kevin Truong. Kevin is a
senior software consultant at
Test Double and a coding career
coach at his company, Tap into
Tech. We had a really great time
talking with Kevin. He shared
with us his personal approach to
interviewing as well as some
really great methods and
approaches for people looking to
improve their interviewing game.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's
question is if you could hang
out with any cartoon character,
who
would you choose and why? So my
name is Bekah. I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could choose any
cartoon character, I was never a
huge cartoon kid, but I loved
the
X-Men cartoon. And so I
professor X, like I always
wanted him to be
my mentor and teach me all of
the things because, you know,
I'm
pretty sure that I would fit
right in there with the X men.
Dan: Um, I'm Dan. I am from
Lakewood, Ohio. I do front of
development. Um, Yeah. I'm, I'm
kind of conflicted on
this.There's like...Professor X
is, you know, a mentor kind of
figure. You know, my, my first
instinct was Optimus Prime, you
know, for the same reason, but I
also feel like he might not be
that fun to hang out with. So if
the question is like hanging
out,
Then my answer is gonna be, you
know, you know what I mean? So,
uh, so like I think I'm going
more, um, I think I'm gonna go
with Raphael from Ninja Turtles,
uh, or maybe Michelangelo. I
dunno, same, same problem with
Michelangelo, but Raphael's a
little serious sometimes, but,
uh, well the problem is he's
grumpy, everybody our age
remembers the movies more than
the cartoon. The movies He's
really like a really kind of a
grumpy jerk, but in the
cartoons. Not like that. Uh, so
I feel like
the movies, you know, did him
wrong anyway, uh, ninja turtle.
So I feel like it would be fun
hanging. So it says
Bekah: out with the Animaniacs.
Dan: if I was the learn from
somebody it'd be Splinter, but
like, he wouldn't be that fun to
like, hang out with, you know
what I mean? So it's like,
Kevin: Get some looks like
walking around the street with
that. Yeah.
Dan: right, you got
Kevin: one of the characters,
but you know.
Dan: Plus yeah, if you can go a
transformer, then, then they can
like drive you around and stuff.
So that's cool too.
Kevin: Okay.
Dan: Um, I think Michelangelo is
my fate. My, my, uh, is going to
be my official answer.
Kevin: Nice. Well, hello
everyone. My name is Kevin
Truong. I am a software
consultant at Test Double. I'm
also a coding career coach at my
own business. Uh, Tap into Tech.
Um, he located in new Orleans.
Not sure if I said that. Um, Hm.
My first answer. And I already
told you earlier was I said
SpongeBob, like, cause I was
thinking about SpongeBob square
pants. Cause I grew up watching
that a little bit and I'm like,
this is a terrible idea. Hey, I
can't hang out under water. So
this would not be a good idea.
And then it's SpongeBob like
this, isn't a, this isn't a good
character to appear. And then a
little bit more thought I'm
going to go with, uh, Rick from
Rick
and Morty. I don't know if I
could keep up with that kind of
person or what kind of crazy
antics like, or I just feel
super
inadequate hanging out with him,
but I think it'd be fun. It'd be
a total 24 hours of craziness.
And, uh, yeah, I think it'd be a
wild ride.
Bekah: Sounds like fun. I like
it. Well, thanks Kevin,
Kevin: answers is going to come
for all of us after this.
Bekah: Thanks for being here.
Um, we always love to start off
with
everyone's origin story, where
he came from, how you got to
this
point. So if you want to give us
your story, we'd love to know.
Kevin: Sure. Yeah, I've got it.
I've got somewhat of a journey.
So let's see. I'll start. Um, I
guess I'll start off as a kid,
maybe in middle school, um,
early high school, like I always
knew
what to do. Some sort of
engineering. Um, it was between
computer engineering, electrical
engineering. I remember like on
college board.com comparing
majors, like when a friend has
going to school and I was like,
I really don't want to do
coding.
So I'm really fascinated with
power. So I'll go with, um, with
electrical engineering. So I, I
kind of start off there. And
I've
always been fascinated with
power. Like just how power is
generated. I love solar energy,
wind energy, nuclear, and then,
and how it gets distributed to
homes. And
Bekah: Yeah.
Kevin: that was what fascinated
me. And, you know, with electric
engineering, there are some
programming classes. Now I've
taken a program class before and
I hated it. It was, it was in
Java. I would have failed the
class if my partner, Dustin, if
you're out there listening, like
thanks so much, like he saved
me,
but I still hated program. I
hated Java. Um, and. That was
kind of like my first name, like
this is not me. I do not wanna
learn how to program. This is
terrible. Um, but electro
engineering had some programming
classes to do some like
robotics,
a little bit of
microcontrollers. And it was
those kinds of
projects that for some reason,
like gave me my, my flow state.
Like I was staying up late hours
working, like I'm going to
figure
this out. Um, and that was kinda
what I got re-exposed to
programming a little bit. And
then you fast forward a little
bit to right out of school. Uh,
right out of college with my
electric engineer degree, I
worked in oil and gas actually.
Um, so I was working on the oil
rigs, like working in oil and
gas
industry, like flying out
helicopter rides two weeks on
two
weeks off, meaning you're out
there for two weeks coming back
in land for two weeks. Um, and
that was a summer programming
job, right? It was programming
we're we're programming valves,
right. Example, I can give, like
if a, the pressure in a tank is
rising too high, if statement
conditional right. Then shut off
a pump, right. That's or, you
know, if a fire is detected,
throw a bunch of Firewater onto
the, onto the platform kind of
thing. Um, so that was, that was
kind of another little
reintroduction to more
programming kind of side of
things. And. This is kind of
where web program kind of came
in. I was working there for two
years and I'm like watching all
these people like startups
happening, like people are
working from home. You, one of
those like crazy Instagram
pictures, like I'm just coding
here in my laptop on a hotel
pool. Like this could be your
life too. And I fell for that. I
was like, I want to do this.
Like, I'm seeing all these
billion dollar startup companies
making websites, web apps. And I
kind of, part of me always knew
I wanted to do something online.
Um, I, for some reason, just put
10 years, like I'm going to work
for 10 years and then I'll go do
my own business or something.
Um,
thankfully oil and gas, that job
kind of accelerated that. So I,
uh, I started teaching myself. I
was on the oil platform, like,
you know, you work for 12 hour
shifts and then you kinda go to
your bunk and kind of thing. I
remember like having my laptop
out, teaching myself, HTML, CSS,
get, um, and just kinda like
learning that in my spare time.
And I remember. Like, I call
this
the, I guess one of my top
dumbest best decisions I ever
made is I just quit. I didn't
have a plan. I didn't have like
a
software job lined up, but I was
like, I'll figure it out. And,
uh, I quit to kind of go into
training mode, which was
learning
how to code, uh, attended a
bootcamp. Um, and that's where
kind of web programming kind of
came out at. Um, and then in the
meantime, while I was looking
for software jobs, I was like
consulting, doing freelance
gigs. Um, making WordPress
sites, like,
you know, just kind of saying
yes to any opportunity. Good.
Which
kind of led to me learning
everything I know, like I, I
had,
uh, I think in one of our
previous episodes, you guys had
a
prompt saying, yes, I'm in drew.
Who said that? Right? Like you
just had a prompt saying yes.
And that was me. I was just
saying
yes to every opportunity I
could. I don't have a job. I'm
just
going to figure it out this. So
I learned WordPress. I learned
like
someone had a Squarespace, like
never did it, but I'll say I can
cause I'll figure it out. Um,
and so I was doing that in
between,
and then I started looking at
applying for software jobs and
getting better at doing that,
um, doing bootcamp instructor.
So I
ended up being a bootcamp
instructor for the bootcamp I
attended, uh, which led to other
roles at other different boot
camps. I got to see different
systems and different boot
camps.
Um, and you know, kind of seeing
other people go through the job
hunt process, as well as doing
it myself. So kind of a
long-winded
origin story, but fast forward
to now, um, I'm a senior
software
consultant at a great company,
um, using everything I learned,
but also the, all the skills and
experience I've learned. I've
managed to find a great company
of my own and applied for it.
And
history is history.
Bekah: That's awesome. I love
that. I think we both come from
different ish backgrounds, but
have similar ish journeys. And
so, you know, once I left, I
taught for 10 years, college
English, and, and once I left,
it was the same kind of thing.
You
know, I did the bootcamp, but
also I was taking jobs. I was
like, can you do a WordPress?
Yeah, I can do a WordPress site.
It was like one of
Kevin: the time.
Bekah: ever worked on. I did not
like WordPress at all. And then
eventually that project got
drawn out and then I was like,
well,
you know, that we're presses
outdated. So let's just do it in
Gatsby. And then like that got
outdated and I'm like, we can
move it to Jekyll. As I figure
out what I like doing and what
is
valuable to people, then I just
kind of follow that line. Also
saying, yes, I'm getting a
little bit better at saying no
to things
now, but, um, it's just a lot of
fun exploration of trying to
figure out, you know, what, what
you're going to do with all of
the new things that you've just
learned.
Kevin: And a lot of people I
coach, they always like say, oh,
I wasted so much time doing
that. And I don't want to call
those a
waste because now you know
exactly what you don't want to
do. And it's better to do that
very early on your career versus
wasting your time dropping
something to go chase this and
finding out that, oh, this was a
terrible idea. So now it's a,
you
always end up where you have to
be at, so it always has to
happen
the way it has.
Dan: So you are a consultant
with Test Double, right? And,
and so
Test Double is an agency that
does work for other clients,
right?
Kevin: Yes. That is correct.
Dan: with them, you're just
doing sort of client where
you're doing
development and stuff like that.
And then you correct. me if I'm
wrong, but you've founded, uh,
Tap into Tech.
Kevin: Yeah. Yeah. Tap into Tech
is, is something that came
before
maybe early 2020, late 2019. It
was something I've always done.
That's why I don't really have a
hard date. So with my years as a
boot camp instructor, um, I've
always just had mentees, I'm
going to call it, but just
people in my circles that needed
jobs.
And it kind of just started off
with just emails, back and
forth,
random, um, communities and
slack and just messaging back
and forth
text messaging. So it's like,
Hey, I have this interview.
Like,
what should I do? Is this resume
look good? Um, and I've always
just had a fascination with
that. And the idea of tapping
the tech
came in, I was giving a tour at
a local company here in new
Orleans
with my current cohort at the,
at the time. And it was about
six,
seven different, um, people in
this cohort. And we went to go
tour this company that was a
software company. And they're
literally telling us like, yeah,
like just finding talent in new
Orleans is tough. Like there's
just not enough good people in
the city. And I'm like sitting,
looking at my class. I'm like,
you know, not everyone's a
hundred percent ready, but I bet
if you gave this person a shot,
this person would fly. I'd bet
with this other person with
maybe two months of actual more
production ready work. As I like
to call. They would be someone
who could fly, be coached and do
well at this company. Um, and
that's where it kind of sparked
where I realized that we're
bootcamps are missing it. Right.
They're teaching the technical
skills side of things, but what
does production ready look like
in the real world? Right? Like,
I don't want to bash on anyone,
but
you know, anyone can make a
weather app. If you followed a
turtle, anyone can consume a
weather API and throw it out
there. If they follow the tour,
what to do list those kinds of
apps are all very true. But what
does actual production look like
in boot? Bootcamps? I think fail
at teaching this, oh, let me say
that some bootcamps fail at
teaching that. So I've realized
that I wanted to fill in that
gap. I wanted to fill in what's
your 80% of the way there.
What's that last, very important
20%
look like. Um, so I started just
kind of curating, finding out
the
needs of certain people and kind
of inviting them to this group
of, Hey, let's do this together.
Let's work on this and let's get
you a tech job.
Dan: I think that's really cool.
I imagine you last times were
given very similar advice to
different people, you know,
based
on where they were in their
journey, you know? Um, and I
think that's great, like being
able to tie that into basically
a
service you can provide to, you
know, to lots of people.
Bekah: Well, you know, in Kevin,
you and I had talked, this was a
while ago, I think about some of
the major problems that we're
seeing with bootcamps or, or
students who are coming out of
boot camps. There's a lot of
promises that bootcamps give and
there's a lot of, um, you know,
people out there saying, oh,
there's so many jobs in tech,
just go to a bootcamp. Right.
And
yeah, like there's a lot of
senior dev jobs out there, but
they're the opportunities for
junior developer. There's there
are not that many and you really
have to be able to differentiate
yourself. So I guess maybe where
I want to start is what do you
see as the biggest problem or
challenge that people coming out
of bootcamps face, as they're
trying to find that first job
where there's a lot of
competition.
Kevin: Yeah, that's a good
question. I fight this every
day.
So, um, I work on eliminating
all of that with people every
single
day. So. Um, I think the problem
is let's say with, we'll start
with atypical, bootcamper kind
of thing. I call it production
ready, right? Like, let's say
it's a three-month course. You
walk out with three portfolio
pieces, but at that point it was
like our users. If you had a
thousand users on that pro that
portfolio piece, would it be
ready for that? I would wager
most of the time it's a no
right. That would wager that. Is
it
something that people could use
and get something valuable out
of? And I'll, I'll start with
this one concept. That's one of
my main concepts of what did I
try to teach is I call it,
flipping the script, right?
Imagine the perfect job landed
right in front of you right now,
the hiring managers asking you,
would you be ready to take this?
Again, I'd wagers. Most people,
some people would be, most
people would probably lose that
opportunity because they weren't
just that production ready. They
made it not conveyed themselves.
Right. Maybe their online
presence didn't feel right. So
it didn't look experienced
enough
for this hiring manager to pick
them. Um, and so I, I start with
one just kind of filling in what
the ex that experience looks
like. In some ways it's starting
with a passion project. I know
that term gets used the way to
like a passion project, but then
really taking that project and
making it something valuable,
useful, where someone could say,
dang, a hiring manager saw this
on your, like, back to that
example, hiring manager just saw
you, Hey, I have this live
website up right now. You can
try
it out. We can walk through it
if you want. And that says,
damn, I
need to hire Bekah. I need to
hire Dan. Right? Like there's.
So, and that I I've merely, I
don't think that obstacle is
that
tall. Right? It's doable. It's
challenging, but it's doable
enough where someone says, well,
this is well thought out. It's
well-designed it shows that this
person can hook up a domain, can
deploy an app and can really
work with this technology. Let's
let's
say react, right? Like I need to
have this person on my team.
Right. Those are the kinds of
things that I try to get people
to aim for. Right? Like I need
you to be able to go in front of
someone, say, yes, I need to
have this person on my team. Um,
another one, you know, technical
side to skills is. Communication
skills. I feel like that's
something that definitely
doesn't
get touched on. Um, some boot
camps do good at it. Some most,
let me say this do not, they
don't even touch on it once they
get your 10 grand, they're just,
you know, here's your
certificate
out. You go, right? Like you did
your 200 commits then, which is
a
terrible metric, but some people
do it. Um, and in communication
is valuable because for early
career devs, Because you may not
have a hundred percent of the
technical skills, but by having
great communication skills,
someone that I know I could put
you on my team, my team will
like you, you have enough of the
technical skills that I know you
can fill in the gaps as you go.
Kind of thing I'd say is just as
important, if not, maybe
slightly
little bit more important than
the technical skills, right?
Like
coachability, I've heard this
from thousands of exaggerate,
hundreds of recruiters and
hiring managers. Right. That's
what they
say. They're really looking for.
Right. Don't need perfection. I
need to know that someone, I can
take someone and mold this
person
into someone that I can make an
all-star team member, but it all
starts with a union. Need to
know a little bit enough to code
and
problem-solve and be just being
able to communicate with your
team members on how to get
better.
Bekah: Yeah, I like that idea of
coachability. I think I've
probably heard that, but not
really thought about it very
much
until you were talking about it
just now. And I know for me and
a
lot of other. Developers who
came out of self paced
bootcamps, or
for developers learning on their
own coachability is a skill that
we don't talk enough about and
that we don't really practice.
Right. Because what you're doing
is you're learning independently
and that that's great. Right?
It's great that you can go out
there and find the resources
that you need to accomplish the,
the.
Thing. Right. But also you miss
out on a lot of that
communication. You miss out on
being able to learn from other
people and to ask questions
while someone's telling you
something.
So if they're breaking down an
issue for you and talking
through
it, then how do you know how to
ask questions? And I know for
me,
that was a real big challenge.
And sometimes it still is
because
there's. Um, you've developed
habits of staying in this world
of, oh, well, my job is to go
out and find the answers to
those
things myself, rather than like,
let's start by asking questions
that can get us halfway up this
path rather than having to start
from zero and moving forward.
Does that make sense?
Kevin: Spot on. Right. And it's
exactly why I like communities
like Virtual Coffee or created
my own because doing it alone is
rarely the best decision. Right.
And this is personal experience
for me. Not to go too far, but
like I grew up in a household,
just do it yourself. Right.
Don't pay for that. Learn how to
do it,
save a thousand dollars and do
it yourself. Right. And then,
and I
always, I still do have this
mentality. Right. Like, it's
very
hard for me to ask for help I'm
breaking through with that. But,
um, especially when you work
solo for, I did consulting for
three,
four years, right? Like it's,
it's when you're alone, like you
got to learn a heck of a lot.
Right. Me trying to be cheap and
not pay for a $10 a month.
Server has taught me so much
about dev
ops. That's
Bekah: Okay.
Kevin: not enough, but you know,
just ways to save $5 a month in,
in managing my own servers. And
now, as, as I look back, I'm
like, that was really dumb. I
could have just saved a lot of
time, but, um, but the idea of,
of seeing surrounded by a
positive community and asking
for help. And having that
expertise
on hand of, Hey, this is what
the real world's going to look
like.
This is what you should prepare
for, or here's how collaboration
looks with, how do you, you
know, do PRS properly, right?
Like I
think you guys with the Virtual
Coffee, GitHub repo, right? Like
it's teaching people, oh, I
create this branch. I do this PR
it gets approved. Right. That's
a process that. I think only
half
the bootcamps I've interacted
actually sit down, they'll give
you a, year's a link to how to
do it. But as we all know as
coders,
right, it's, it's always, um,
doing it over, just consuming it
creation over consumption as I
call it. Right. You gotta do
this
stuff, not just read a blog post
and expect to be able to walk
out
and say that was worth a
graduation certificate kind of
thing.
Dan: I was, uh, to go back a
little bit to the, um,
production
ready part of It Right. I've
seen this a lot where people
have the
portfolio pieces. Right. And
they're just kind of linked on
their portfolio, but, um, you
know, maybe a couple of
paragraphs or whatever, but when
you, excuse me, when you are
helping people take their
portfolio piece to be production
ready, do you find that they're
missing like, that there's
actually like holes in the
project itself? Or is it, um,
more like the stuff around it,
the ops, you know, the, the
hosting stuff like that, that
you find that people. Maybe not,
not
going all the way to get to
production. Ready.
Kevin: is a little bit of both.
And I also add in yeah, that
there's holes, which is fine. I
think people need to get
overlap.
It's not going to be a thousand
percent perfect. You know, I, I
think some people fear like, oh,
if I make this open source,
they're going to see the
curtain, like get over it.
Right. Like
it's something as a talking
point, right. I love using
blemishes as a talking point of,
oh, actually let me point out my
blemish for you and tell you
how, if I had enough infinite
time, I
would fix it like this, but I
actually don't have enough time
because I'm working on my
freelance side. Right. There's
definitely some holes. I would
also add that it's just not
pushing the envelope enough,
right. Again, it's, I'm taking a
recipes app and I'm adding a
little thing like this, right.
Like, okay, well, how can we add
design into it? Right. Like
let's
add in tailwind and see how you
like using that. Let's add in
some, um, again, that wow factor
that someone lands on as like,
okay, this is polished, right.
They actually, and not everyone
has to, you don't have to be a
massive design. I teach people
or
I do it myself to just steal
designs, right? Like, I'll go on
a different website. Like, Hey,
that font pairing looks pretty
nice. I'm gonna use those exact
same font or this color scheme.
Like I'm just going to use that.
Um, and I think by removing some
of those analysis paralysis
barriers, right? Like, oh, like
design, I don't want you to
design, like, stop thinking
about
it. Just go use something that
works so that you can move on
kind of thing. Um, I think it's
a huge mindset barrier to hold
people back when, when they're
not, they don't feel like
they're
things. Perfect. Um, but I say
embrace it and use that as a
talking point of this is why
it's not perfect. You know, you
may
not notice it, but I'll show you
where I see my problems at.
Dan: Yeah, I like that. Yeah, me
too. I like that kind of
thinking. And you know, I've,
I've seen some people have like
blog posts where they explain
stuff like that, you know, about
their projects, about the, when
they're, you know, when they're
on their like learning journeys
and stuff. I always find that
really, really valuable. Um, you
know, as, as somebody who has,
you know, hired people or
whatever, you know what I mean?
It's, it's like the, that, that
idea of using, uh, don't know,
kind of, like you said, like
using, using a hole in
something,
but like being aware of it and
explaining why it's there or
whatever, what you would do if
you had the time, what you would
do, if you, you know, or what
you're going to do next, that
kind of thing. I think that's
great. That's a great idea.
Bekah: Yeah, it's nice to be
able to break things down into a
process. And to also, I mean,
that does a lot to show how you
think through things, how you're
able to talk about those things
and communicate those things.
And you know, that just goes
back to
your point. Like that's an
underdeveloped skill in a lot of
the developers that are coming
into, into the industry, right?
Yeah.
Kevin: yeah. And this a thousand
percent applies to technical
interviews, right? When, when
being stumbled upon something,
right. I went through the
experiment of applying for a
bunch of different jobs, because
I wanted to see if can I even do
this right? How can I teach you
what to get a job of? I don't
even know. I can't get a job.
Um, and I, and one of the things
that
I love kind of just showing,
bringing up to people was like
during technical questions where
it's something really simple,
Like I always tell people just
to laugh it off and be like,
look, I
have no idea. Like, oh, that's a
really good question. Um, I
don't
know the answer now, but let me
kind of just stumble my way
through and kind of just make it
very lighthearted and playful.
Like, um, you know, let's
pretend we're we're in this
techno
interview and they just ask
something about some ridiculous
searching, sorting out of their
guns. And then I was like, look,
I can sit here for 30 minutes
and not give you a good answer.
So
let me just talk to you about
how I would go through and do
what
you said back, like just. Teach
like, go explain your thought
process around it. Because
again, I would say that's also
probably
just as important, if not more
important than the actual
solution itself kind of thing.
And that's kind of the mindset I
always get to just like own
everything you do. Like don't
worry about all those little
things like that own it kind of.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. And I
think one of the things that a
lot of technical interviews or
interviews in general don't
don't
take into account is that you
have the ability to ask. And
most
of your workplaces and you
should be asking questions,
right. And
so if you ask somebody, Hey,
just solve this thing that
you've
probably memorized because
you've been studying for this
technical
interview. Like what does that
even show? But to say like, I
think it is valid to say, okay,
well, this is kind of how I
would
approach it. This is the
question that I have for you,
because I
feel like I might get stuck at
this point. So can you tell me
how you would communicate that
to me when I asked you this
question, you know, Pushback. I
mean, but also I will say that I
will not take a technical
interview for those reasons,
because I don't think that
they're valuable in most
circumstances. And I think that
they, um, leave out so many, um,
underrepresented minorities in
tech because of the type of
preparation that has to go into
them. And they don't account for
the privilege that you have to
have to be able to spend. All
this time. So this is me getting
on my soap box again, and
Kevin: Go for it. Come on, back
up, back.
Bekah: but I also think, you
know, there's, um, this is going
back to a point that you said
earlier about, I can't remember
exactly where it was coming
from, but talking about this
idea of
learning on your own and how
that's almost never the best,
um,
the best way to approach
learning, how to code for a lot
of people. That's the only way.
Unless you have community
though.
And so this is something I keep
going back to, and I keep
thinking a lot about how to
encourage this, but have
community collaborative with
them in some way, right? Like
participate in a study group or
talk to some people and say, I
would really like to be able to
build a project together with
you. And maybe it is a to-do
app. Right. There's a difference
between building a, to do app by
yourself and building a, to do
app with four people. So I've
kind of gotten in my mind that,
that there's this like nice
thing about groups of four. I'm
not
exactly sure why, but for me,
the approach is, you know,
finding
those four people and forming
your own cohort. And then you do
whether it's projects together
or you walk through curriculum
together, but in the end, you're
all collaborating and creating
something. That you can show,
like I worked as a team on this
passion project and that's more
meaningful than working on
something on your own.
Kevin: Again, it ties to that
whole, again, collaboration
being
part of production ready. Right.
If you're going to be thrown
onto
this team, I need some do that.
You can work with this team. Um,
and it gives great opportunities
for during interviews, right?
Like the, all those, uh, kind of
cheesy scenarios. So tell me a
time when you blank, right? You
don't have to lie anymore.
Right?
Tell me about a time when you,
you guys had a dispute in your
team, right? Like you could have
those discussions, have some
ammunition ready to answer those
questions. Like, oh, let me tell
you about this group project
that I had, where, you know,
work with
this guy named Kevin, he had
this idea of this, what the
to-do list
should be like, but we sat down
and we talked it out. We, we use
some proper, you know, user
stories and we found out like,
Hey, maybe it's better to do it
this way. Instead of that way.
You know, that's, that's all
those experiences add up and
against your point, like,
you've, you've got to do this
with other
people. Like it's such a tough
journey already. At least we can
do it together and share our
losses and wins kind of thing.
And I'd like to ask it again.
I'd love checking in Virtual
Coffee,
slack. Like haven't been able to
participate too much, but every
night I open up and just see
like people share. This is what
the
new stuff I'm going to this
interview. This one didn't go so
well, but Hey, there's next time
everyone comes in times in,
right? Like it's nice knowing
that people have your back. And
I
think that's part important
facet of going through the early
career
job hunt kind of thing.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. And I
don't even think it's limited to
early career too. Right? Like
we've had a lot of senior
developers in Virtual Coffee,
move on to new positions in the
last couple of years. And
Virtual Coffee has played a role
in that,
you know, even talking about
salary negotiations or, you
know,
just cheering them on or saying
this was my experience in this
position or this other person
that I, I know did this thing.
You might want to try it too.
And that's allowed them to just
kind
of take that information,
especially if they haven't been
applying for positions. And in
the last couple of years, if
you've been in the industry for
awhile, And you're interviewing
for the first time. And I don't
know, even five years, things
Kevin: Oh, the world's changed
Yeah.
Bekah: So I know that, you know,
one of the we're talking about
communication, right. And
communication can be hard for
people. So what are some of the
different approaches that you
take to kind of coaching people
on how to communicate and to
present themselves in a, in an
interview in a way that is, you
know, the person that you would
want to have back for a second
interview?
Kevin: Gotcha. Yeah. Good
question. Um, it's a journey.
myself have gone through it.
I've super shy. I still am
introverted
and that's not a problem. It's
just that I was always very shy,
always afraid to speak up. Kind
of always passive with the when
during like, not even just
interviews in real life. Right.
Does business and in
relationships and everything.
And
that's it. Wasn't fun. Let me
say it that way. Right. Life got
a
lot more fun. Once you're just
allowed to talk and you be
comfortable with talking kind of
thing, um, with interviews
rightfully so. A lot of people
walk into a lot of anxious
energy, like, whoa, man, like,
you know, great grimacing at the
idea of, I've got to talk to
this person for 30 minutes and
it's
going to be tough. Right. And
immediately that's a losing
game,
right? Immediately you walking
into that is. Just ultimate
failure. Right. And I always use
this as an example. Right? Like,
imagine yourself going to those
dreaded networking events that
you go to. Never like, you know,
no one kind of thing. Imagine
yourself walking into that same
kind of room, just very anxious.
Like I'm just going to go sit in
this corner and just kind of
hold
my drink by the bar. Right. And
it's super uncomfortable. I've
been that person. It's the lamp.
Um, now imagine, you know,
stepping out that door and
playing this mental exercise
with
me, like, I always walk people
through this. Cause I think
mindset is mindset. Mindset is
module zero in my program,
right?
Like you're not going to get
far, unless you get your mindset
in
the right space. You can't go
through this whole experience.
Get one rejection then just like
go put the sheets over your
head.
And like, like, no, that's not
how it is going to work in
tablet
attack. Right. You've got to
keep chugging along. Um, the
back to
that example right now, imagine
if you walked into this
networking event, just knowing,
like you don't give a F about
what anyone thinks, anyone cares
what anyone says to you, like
imagine like how lifted you
would feel. Right? Like, just
like
whatever I'm just going and have
fun. Like I'm just go there and
meet people. Never go see these
people again, blah, blah, blah.
Let's go have fun. And you just
walk in. So imagine that. How
you
envision yourself, like I'm
there just having fun. Like
that's,
that's the point. And I try to
emulate this with people and get
them into the right state. I
call it, um, I'm borrowing from
a lot
of different psychology or NLP
concepts that I've learned over
my time, but, you know, getting
yourself in the right space.
Bringing your energy in gets
kind of where we will be at some
point, some people don't accept
it as much as others, some
people
do. And I am, I lean into that,
right? Like brand new energy
just
imagined you there to have fun.
And that's the kind of energy
that needs to be conveyed during
your interviews. Right? Not
saying being super quirky, be
super unprofessional, just like
dancing on the table. Just
saying, go in there. Just like.
I
don't really care what happens
at the end of his interview. I
just
want to get to know the company.
Like I just, you know, not being
tied to the result. I just want
to come here and have an
interview and have fun. And now
imagine again, flipping the
script, right. I'm the
interviewer and I see person a
come in kind of anxious energy,
like yeah. Yeah. I'm looking
forward. Thanks for having me
versus person B's like, Hey,
thanks for having me. Nice to
meet you. Great office space.
Like let's have some fun, like,
you know, tell me more about the
company. It's kind of one of
those hack ways of getting,
improving your chances of the
job. Right. Just being more
likable. And again, I'm, don't
try to teach you being some
wildly crazy extrovert. I'm just
trying to teach you to be in a
better state. Right? You don't
get stumbled. When a tough
question comes up, you do take
those pauses. You do take those
breaths. You don't freak out and
then your brain gets, you know,
it's happened to me many times
before where I've just one bad
question. Just kind of be slowed
down. Nowadays, I'm able to
catch
myself. If it happens, I'm just
catching myself and then bring
my
energy back up. And I actually
visualize a dial. Right. I, I
think visualization mindset has
been so important in my life.
Um,
shout out to Nick who taught me
all of this as one of my
coaches.
Right. I visually see a dial
like, okay, I'm being a little
too energetic. Let me dial it
down and I'll speak a little bit
slower. And my dots, my periods
of adopt on it. But if I feel
like the interview is getting
into a low I'll, turn it up a
little bit and kind of play
along kind of thing. And it's
not an
overnight thing. Right. You can
learn these through practice.
Um,
which is, I don't know if you
guys see, I always tell people
like, if you're not, if you're
in your early stage, um, or not,
or
you just haven't interviewed in
a while, or you're bad or not as
good as you want to be at
interview. There's literally
free
interviews on LinkedIn, right?
You do like one or two changes
on
your LinkedIn recruiters are
just bombing you emails. And all
you
have to do is just reply back
and say, sure, let's talk
tomorrow.
And boom, you have a free chance
to have that experience that I
was talking about at the bar,
right. Where I can walk into
this
bar, not give an F about what
person says to me, because it's
just a random recruiter. Right.
This person, isn't going to go
out there and say, don't hire
Kevin. Cause he didn't take this
thing very seriously, which is
what I did. I was going out on
LinkedIn, just seeing, trying
different tactics out, seeing
which got good responses and
just kind of seeing how many
interviews could I get to the
next round. Um, and those are
your, those are your reps,
right? That's free batting
practice
right there. Um, and I don't
think people, if you're feeling
like you're getting too nervous
during interviews, Go on
LinkedIn
and actually respond back to
those spammy recruiters that
say,
Hey, you want to talk? I have
the senior role position, even
though
I have zero years of experience
in my LinkedIn, I'm like, sure,
let's talk just for fun. And
that's the kind of, that's how
you get your reps in, right? It
was, it's a, it's not an
overnight process. It's can be a
monthly process and you'll get
better incrementally. And by the
time that dream job that I
mentioned before does land right
in front of you. You're ready to
nail it.
Bekah: I like that a lot. And I
like this idea of like getting
reps in. So as you're talking
about this, I was thinking, so I
like to. You know, lift heavy
weights and work out. But I
really, I like to jump high.
Kevin: too. I'm working on mine.
I'm trying to hit a 60 inch box
jump by the end of the year.
Bekah: Yes. That's exactly where
I was going with this. Okay. So
I'm short. So I always say like,
I have to compensate for that in
some way. And so I jump high and
so I'm like trying to think of,
I
think I hit 50 inches.
Kevin: Nice.
Bekah: I think maybe my highest
is 56, but
Kevin: Congratulations. Yeah,
Bekah: it was, it was, it was
work and it was reps, right?
Like
you're growing in strength, but
one of the things approaching
that box, like, okay, I'm 61 and
three quarters inches. And so
that box is pretty high up on
me. So when you're standing next
to
it, yeah. Wow. This is really
high. I don't think I'm going to
be able to do this. And I had
heard on a podcast somewhere,
somebody was like, just
visualize yourself doing it
first, because
if you set your mind up that
you're going to fail, you will
fail. And I was not a big
visualize as a person. I'm like,
this is kind of garbage, but
fine. I'm going to try it,
right?
Yeah. Close my eyes. Cause I
can't do anything with my eyes
open, close my eyes. I imagine
myself jumping on the top of all
of those boxes. And then I did,
and I was like, okay, maybe
there
is something to this, but it is
like, when you go in with that
failure mindset, you're not
going to be able to perform in
the way
that you want to. And so there
was something about imagining
what it looks like and what it
feels like. There's gotta be
some
kind of like physiological
reaction that happens when you
do
that.
Kevin: Yeah. Uh, what is it mind
over matter kind of thing,
right?
Like that's a saying for a real
reason, right? Like if you truly
don't believe that you're going
to do the best, then you're
definitely not going to be
right. But you're not going to
be even
at 50%, I'd argue. Right? Like,
or unless you just have all that
reps and experiences, which is,
you don't have to visualize, you
have what I call confidence
through competence. Right? You,
you have the confidence through
the fact that you've done it so
many times. But we, we could
rant on, I always do my
correlation
between exercise as well with,
with like right, with like how
Java is. I either do it with
like dating life or whatever,
uh,
exercise or business, all this
stuff correlates together.
Right?
Like that's why mindset is
module zero. Like this will
apply to not
just your job hunt. This will
apply to your landing on a 58
for
60, 56, 8 jump. Right. Um, and
on that note, they actually
actually
do teach that right. When you're
doing a boxer, like actually
stand on the box, get used to
that feeling of how high you
are,
kind of thing. Don't jump off of
it. Cause that's just going to
recipe for damaging over time,
but actually stand up on top of
it and feel how high you are off
the ground. So that when you do
do the jump you get, you're not
shocked when you get there and
you can finish, it don't fall
backwards. Like you actually sit
and then stand up kind of thing.
We can, we gotta do this. Bekah.
We gotta meet and just do box
jumps over and over and over.
Bekah: that's right. That's
right. I keep saying so Magnolia
JS this year was online. Last
year was online, but Kayla Sween
organize it this year and she
has she's certified in like us
powerlifting. She's got a
certification and I'm like next
year when this is in a physical
location. Yeah, I'm going to
come
and we are going to, we're going
to lift heavy things together.
So
Kevin, you need to you're in the
general area. You're closer than
I am in
Kevin: I'll make it somehow.
Yeah. Yeah. That's true. I am
close with.
Bekah: we'll find a way
Kevin: If you're going there,
Bekah, I have no excuse. Yeah.
Bekah: Okay. So you said that
you were doing coaching. You've
kind
of like always been doing this
coaching thing. And so at some
point it became more. Something
that you really embraced and
decided to take on and share
with other people. And I feel
like
that could be a really scary
decision to make. Was it just
something that just came
naturally? Or did you think that
well, you know, I've, I've been
doing this, I might as well do
it
in a more formalized way and
then just.
Kevin: yeah. Reflecting back on
it and feeling the emotions.
Right. It's anytime I do
anything new, it's always a
little bit of
scary, right? Like I'm not
someone who is very risk
adverse.
Let me say it that way. Um, I, I
tend to stop and think about it
for 10 hours before even picking
up a pen and kind of that kind
of
thing. Um, it's not good, but
I'm on it. But part of me is
always
been a little entrepreneurial.
Like I said, like I always knew
I
was going to do something on my
own. Um, I got to go and just
say, it's probably just because
of the surroundings, the people
I
was around, seeing people who
are much more brilliant than me,
much
smarter, like this is how they
create their own happiness and
wealth, right? Like I'll, I'll
say it. I love money. So they
create their own wealth and
their own happiness and their
own
freedom and, you know, creating
their own business. Um, so
coaching definitely came in
through rice surroundings. My
mentors, I am a. Results in
product of a bunch of mentoring
and books and experiences and
conferences and all of these
workshops, right? I've, I've
spent a lot on, you know,
investing in myself, which has
given me the ability to say, you
know what? I've seen all these
other people do it. A lot of my
idols, people I respect in the
community are doing it this way.
Um, I'm going to try it myself
and it again, it's it was scary,
but when you really break it
down, it's, it's, it's. The
steps
are simple, right? To start your
own website, get your own first
few clients. And all of that,
like, you know, create a
structure, create a program it's
simple. Right? We could write it
right now in like one or two
minutes. The execution is always
the scary part. Right. Things.
Getting a job can be simple. The
steps doing it are not easy
sometimes though. Right. So, uh,
Going through the step of, you
know, deciding I'm going to
create my own, you know, I was
already consulting doing my own,
like little private, you know,
website consulting. So coaching
wasn't too far off. Um, but
there was a little bit of. Uh,
yeah,
look, let me say it this way. I
still get imposter syndrome to
this day, right? Can I go out
there and start my own coaching
program? Right? Like, can I
messaged this person and
convinced this person I'm good
enough? Right. Like it still
happens to me. I think I call it
your associate path if you don't
get a little bit of it. So I
think you have to have a little
bit of it because it's, and
that's the good thing, right? I
know I'm going in the right
direction. Let me say it that
right. I know in the ceilings
coming, it's something I should
be. Um, or I should try to
challenge myself as kind of
thing. Um, and that's just the
whole mindset behind it right
now. You're reframing imposter
syndrome. I'm getting it. This
is
okay. I should be getting this
and now I should continue on
kind
of thing. And that's what,
getting your reps and feels
like.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. It's a lot of
pursuing what scares you,
Kevin: Yeah.
Bekah: which is hard, especially
if you don't have a good support
system or community around it.
Um, so I, I'm kind of taking
this
and a little bit of a different
direction, but you've got all
this experience working with a
lot of different people. You've
talked about taking interviews
and trying different things out.
So if, if you looked at tech
right now and you saw what the
interview process looked like,
and you could totally reset. And
from here on out, everybody
would just follow Kevin's way.
What
does Kevin's way of interviewing
look like?
Kevin: On the interviewee side,
like if I'm trying to get a job.
Dan: No from the interviewer,
like if you're.
Kevin: Okay.
Dan: The, the process of, you
know, the tech, the tech
interview process is like feels
kind of messed up to a lot of
people. I think. So, you know,
you probably have unique
perspective having seen both
your own and, uh, you know, your
mentees, um, you know, going
through the process. So what,
what can we do to fix it?
Kevin: This is an interesting
question. When think about it
and
ideas are going to flow to me as
I'm talking, I have some ideas,
so, um, With the idea of remote
being very, very important
nowadays. I think everyone's got
to kind of learn a little bit
better, be better on camera,
right? Sadly, Zoom's kind of the
way I don't love it to love or
hate. I love working remote, but
at the same time, I think I
don't want to fully embrace a
world
where we always have to stare at
a camera. Um, but as an
interviewer, I want to make sure
that person's comfortable.
Communicating on camera as well.
Right? So to be able to convey
ideas in this challenging times
of how well can you work
remotely
kind of thing. Um, I like the
idea of structured interviews.
As
in, if we had a thousand
applicants, every single
thousand, these applicants would
be asked the exact same
questions. Um, because I think
the idea and shout out to Test
Double, right? They did this
during my interview. Um, one of
the comms that did this to me
was Test Double. They, you get
to
talk, you know, as much as you
want and you have very
structured
rubric of what you've, what,
like what we're looking for kind
of
thing. Right? Because otherwise,
if you have. Um, what was it?
King of the hill. They had two
football fans, right. Talking,
right. Like if they hit it off
talking about football, ideally
like that person isn't might not
be the best fit, but because
they
kicked off so well, like that
person got the check mark kind
of
thing, and that's very
subjective. So I think we kind
of
have to have these metrics, like
very standardized questions
where
everyone gets asked. Um, other
ideas, let's see, um, you know,
we're seeing this big movement
of almost anonymous applications
of
like, you don't see the age of
race, the gender of anything
kind
of thing. Um, that is something
I think phase one needs to have.
I
think there's almost this screen
that doesn't show does this
person look like me? Does this
person have the same background
as me? Um, in order to pass the
test kind of thing. Um, I think
that's super important as part
of phase one of
Bekah: to pause for one second
there. I know, like I put you on
the spot with this question, but
I want to push back a little
bit.
Um, so I like one of the things
that, that I think about. I
don't
have my mind made up about this.
Right? Like I think that it's
very interesting to have this
idea of like blind resume
reviews, but at the same time,
there comes a certain privilege
with what gets put on a resume.
You know, so for people who
haven't had the same privileges
who have not had the same
advantages of people that are
growing up with, you know,
parents who have connections or
who have money than somebody who
has worked really hard to get
where they are. W maybe may, and
maybe there's a different way to
address this on a resume that
I'm
just totally missing, but I
could see their resumes being,
not at
the top of the pile, just
because they haven't had the
same
opportunities. And I don't
really, you know, I don't mean
to
put you on the spot here, but I
just wonder if there's ways to
capture that in. To allow you to
move forward and processes that,
that haven't done a really good
job of taking that into
consideration.
Kevin: And here's the response I
could get out with that, right?
It's not just resumes in stage
one, by the way, I'm going to
make that clear. Right. Um,
there are not even a cover
letter, but
just certain questions that they
can tell can this burden, does
this person have good written
communication as well? One
interview I did last year. I
think school is 15 individual
questions. It was a great
company, 15 individual
questions,
like, you know, typing out
almost a paragraph. Each I got
through
that interview based on just
those written things. Right?
Like, cause again, kind of
revisiting back on the idea of,
of remote work. Like, can you
communicate well through
written?
Like, can you convey your idea
of how this code works through
just
slack messages kind of thing.
Um, so on top of the resume, And
I'm
actually not a fan of resumes.
Let me say it that way. Like I
don't put, I think people put
way too much weight on a resume.
It
is very true. Recruiters really
do only spend five to 10 seconds
looking at them. I've asked this
amongst dozens of people and it
is very true. Um, so with
digital, if you're like just
lacking that experience, um, or
not putting it in the right
spot,
that's eye appealing. Right?
It's a big thing that I always
do all
too. Um, it does suck that
unfortunately you're gonna have
to. Put out, thrown out kind of
thing. Um, ideally people would
use that in tandem with certain
questions that can kind of,
again, going back to the replay,
this person touched on this
idea,
this person mentioned his or her
experience in this world. Right.
And that kind of ticks them off
to the next phase kind of thing.
Um, it's a very tough question.
Cause I I've asked, I've been
thinking about this a lot before
and it works for some
organizations where they do have
the resources. Let's just say a
hundred applicants, if not
thousands of applicants and can
kind of do it, unfortunately
kind of world, we live in where
it's
super busy. Right. We have to
have these certain it's the same
way I feel about standardized
tests, right? Like people, you
have to take the sat or act kind
of thing, but what, is there a
better way to do it that
doesn't, that can scale. Sadly.
I don't
think there's too many good
solutions out there that would
scale, but that's kind of the
world we live in. I'm not
embracing it. I'm not saying I,
I kind of say screw that and
don't
get your job through the
application process anyway. But,
um, giving, like you have to get
the application process, uh,
Yeah, well, ideally it's not
just your resume. It's your
answering
some certain questions. Then you
move on to some sort of 20
minutes. Let's get to know you
kind of co phone call kind of
thing. And again, depending on
the rule, like, is communication
vital, like in an agency where
you're consulting with your
clients? Well, can you pass
these markers or is it okay that
you're
just working with your team of
eight people developers and
you're good enough to work with
just these eight kind of thing.
Those are kind of things that I
would kind of look for. Really
drawn out nuts. Pretty vague
answer. I'm giving so far.
Bekah: Well, he has a a hard I'm
like, Hey, redo all the
interview
process right here. Right now in
five minutes. Go.
Kevin: I will say I will share
one that has worked pretty well
with me. Um, again, I'm just
experimenting. Let's see what
works. If I, I throw in a video
application, so I would actually
record a. I'm using a tool
called Loom, just record a two
minute
video and I see you nod your
head. Like I love Loom. I use it
all the time. They just lower
down the free tier though. So
I've got to go bump it up, but,
um, I actually would record a
Loom video and let it link
whatever. And I would send it to
people on the application. Like,
Hey, by the way, like, if you
want to see my video
application, I record a one or
two minute
video explaining why like that,
that little extra effort. Got me
so many more results, like so
many more like, Hey, loved your
video. Like let's talk kind of
thing. Let's set up an
interview.
Um, and this was back when I
didn't have as much experience.
Right. So I would just use Loom
link it to like
thekevintruong.com slash,
company name, have that redirect
to the
Loom video. And while you're
standing out one on the 99th
percentile, like, no one's doing
that. So you really sticking out
kind of thing. And I'm not
saying that's part of my ideal
world
because you gotta respect your
time. So that's the videos take
a
long time.
Bekah: I just, there was, um,
there was a thread on Twitter,
uh, and I'll link it in the show
notes, but the Dustin McCaffrey
was talking about working on
Upwork and that's what he was
doing. He was sending Looms to
people and he had little
experience, but he set his price
to a hundred dollars an hour,
but
it was enough that I think he
said the first job, he made $85
an hour, but he was pretty new
and that's, uh, A pretty good
hourly wage. And it all came
because there was this
personalized, I think it was
personalized, but this loom
message and it was something
that differentiated him and
built
instant credibility with the
people who were viewing it,
which
is, you know, I think like
taking risks and chances like
that. And
kind of what you're talking
about can be the thing that
separates
you from everyone. Yeah.
Kevin: That's really fantastic.
Thanks for sharing that. Because
again, it kind of proves it's
not just, it works for me. It
works
for Upwork, which you're going
at globally, competing against
people. So to get a gig through
that is fantastic.
Dan: Well, we're kind of getting
close to the end, I think, of
our
time. Um, so I'd love to the, I
mean, the thing that stuck out
to
me most is the visualization
step. You know, that you were
talking about that idea. You
have any other sort of general,
large
idea chunks of advice for
people? Um, starting out the,
you know,
starting out the interview, I
guess in the interview process,
you know, in any way.
Kevin: Yeah. Um, on the idea of
a visualization and in mindset,
that stuff is just, again,
module zero for me. It's the
stuff
that's going to differentiate
you more than most people,
right?
Like you can't just get hit once
knocked down and he called it
quits kind of thing. Um, another
trick of that I've learned
through someone else during if
you're feeling this anxiety
during, um, during interviews or
before an interview, right?
Imagine being hugged by your
most favorite person in the
world,
right. That Wharf that just kind
of comes over you again, it gets
really Louie kind of like this
weird world that people like
that. So BS, once you try it,
right, it's the whole. Um, you
know, power pose or like just
standing out of your arms over
your head and giant grinning
smile. Right. You can't help but
feel great. Right. So before I
would go into interviews, I
would
go in hype myself, up in the
bathroom, doing these little
traits before this podcast, I
was going to getting sure I
wasn't
like a hot mess, which I'm sure
I am, but, um, let's see. Other,
other tricks or general advice.
The big concept I love to teach
is that job getting a job
interview or getting your tech
job can be a lot of fun. There's
a wrong way to do it, which is
what I see. Maybe 67% of people
doing it. They play it as a
numbers game, which is like, I
have to apply to 20 jobs by the
end of the week. I'm like,
that's so silly, right? Like how
about
you applies to just three jobs
and give it your best effort on
each of those three, because
you're going to get a lot
further
than just doing. Blanketed
application process, which I see
a lot of people do. They don't,
you know, they use the same
resume. They use the same cover
letter. They kind of just copy
and paste things, which is fine.
You've got to do that
eventually,
but I always tell people if
given one week and you had the
option
between spending five hours
applying to 10 jobs or five
hours
applying to two jobs, I'd always
pick the two jobs. And that may
not sound like a lot. It does.
It is a lot of time for some
people.
You know, apply for the job,
find networks around to find
connections, go on LinkedIn
message people say, Hey, I just
applied for this job. Like, let
me know like what your thoughts
are kind of thing. And just
having those fun conversations.
And that's what I mean by
getting the job interview can be
fun.
Right? I've done it before. I've
enjoyed the process. I've
enjoyed
meeting random people. I've
enjoyed just walking out, not
caring if I got the job or not.
And that's the great mentality
when you're not tied to the idea
of. Man, this is my last hope.
If
I don't get this job, I don't
know what I'm going to do.
Right.
Like remove all of that. Just
say, you know what it wasn't
meant to be. Let's move on to
the next adventure adventure
experience. Right. Because I'm
sure you'll too can, can, can
attest to this is that all these
little experiences have built
you
up to who you are too. And those
were necessary, right? There was
a lot of graded experiences, a
lot of not so great ones, but
they made you who you are today
and embracing that it's kind of
very stoic stoicism kind of like
approach to it. You've got to go
through the, through those
challenges in order to come out
and by framing it as a fun
challenge, framing it as, oh,
well, let's see what happens.
Right. You can make it a lot of
fun. It doesn't have to be a
dreadful process. You can really
get a lot out of it and, and
see, not yourself just grow in
your
tech career, but also just
personal development wise. Um,
you'd be a lot happier, not
getting eight rejection letters,
only getting two, but then like,
Hey, how can I learn and improve
on those two verses got another
one hit delete and just kind of
move on, right. Stop, reflect on
it. What can we do improve that
process? Um, so I think that's
probably my next biggest point,
right. The way you're applying
for jobs can be really fun and
enjoyable so you can choose the
painful way, or you can choose a
way that you're going to grow
guaranteed. I guarantee if you
follow certain steps, you will
become a better person on the
end. You may not get a job, but
you will be ready for the next
one. I guarantee it.
Bekah: I love that. I love that
idea of it's personal growth.
Right. That's excellent. So
thank you so much, Kevin, for
sharing
all of this with us, there's so
many great things that, that
practical tips and advice and
things that people can go
through. So, um, we really
appreciate you sharing this with
us here today.
Kevin: And I thank y'all too.
Thank you so much for having me
really appreciate it. I had a
good time.
Dan: Thanks, Kevin.
Bekah: Bye.
Kevin: right. Bye-bye.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, plus you
can sign up for our newsletter
to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a
review. Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.