Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode six of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah.
And this is a podcast that
features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their stories
and what they've learned. And
we're here to share
it with you here with me today,
is my cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we're
joined by Ray Deck.
Ray is a trained data scientist
and occasional angel investor
and a software entrepreneur. Ray
is also a very active
member here at Virtual Coffee.
He lends his time and expertise,
as well as he leads a few
different interest groups,
uh, for our members, which we
very much appreciate.
We talked with Ray about finding
the right career path through
growth, learning and motivation.
Ray shared his thoughts
about the importance of trust
and listening.
And he drops a bunch of great
resources to help
everyone find their own path.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we
start every Virtual Coffee. We
introduce ourselves
with our name where we're from,
what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's question is what is
your favorite nonfiction book?
Hi, my name is Bekah.
I'm a front end developer from a
small town in Ohio.
And non-fiction is kind of
general.
So I'm going to go two different
directions here.
Um, if I'm talking like memoir
nonfiction, then
I'm going to go with Beauty and
the Broken Places.
If I'm talking like self-help,
then I'm going to go with
Scattered by Gabor Mat. I think
that's how you say it.
Um, it's a book that's about
ADHD and it was
super helpful to me after I was
diagnosed last year.
Dan: Hi, uh, hi, I'm Dan. I am a
front end developer
from Cleveland and yeah, I was,
uh, I was scrambling
because I was trying to remember
any nonfiction books
that I had read recently. I, I
don't, I don't read
a lot of nonfiction books mostly
because, uh, I have
trouble getting through them.
Um, And so I don't
think I have a favorite. I
certainly don't have, you
know, anytime you see favorite,
I think of books that every
read, you know, and so there's a
lot of like fiction books,
every read a bunch of times. Um,
but so now I'm like
scrolling, scrolling through
GoodReads, trying to see if I
have anything that I want to.
The Radical Candor was fine.
You know what I mean? It was
like, it was fine.
Um, I appreciated some stuff in
it.
I appreciate it. Um, the atomic
habits
book, uh, that was cool. I made
it most of the way
through both of those. Um, I
actually just
started, so this is on this is
that GoodReads.
I'm cheating a little bit, but I
read a book called, um, it's
called Shit Actually, which is a
play on Love Actually.
Um, and it's by Lindy West and
she, she basically
just, uh, reviewed old movie
favorites and talked about.
Basically like what held up and,
um, you know, what was nonsense?
And it was very funny. I, I
laughed out loud on number
of times, so that's going to be
my official answer.
Ray: And I'm Ray, uh, I'm a data
scientist by training.
I've been starting startup
software companies
for about 20 years. And I think
the book that
had the biggest influence on me
is the Visual
Display of Quantitative
Information by Ed Tufty,
who was one of my favorite
professors back in college.
Uh, and his book I keep on
returning to his way to better
explain complicated ideas.
Dan: Um, I saw a presentation
where they talked about a
bunch of stuff from that book.
And I actually like that.
Um, A part in there where he, I
think you can correct
me if I'm, if I'm wrong was
talking about, uh, this,
this diagram of Napoleon's like
battle, you know?
And, and like, there was like a,
like a very nicely what UX, uh,
you know, illustration and, um,
that has like stuck in my brain.
I don't know why it stuck in my
brain. I was probably
like 10 years ago. I had went to
that talk.
Ray: There is marvelous, um, you
know, visualization
of complex data that dates back
hundreds of years.
You don't have to do with
computers.
Bekah: That's really cool. I'll
have to check that one out.
Um, so Ray, thanks so much for
being here with us.
We're really excited to have you
on the podcast today.
And when we start off, we like
to hear your origin story.
So what got you to this point
where you are here with us?
Ray: Yeah. So, um, coming in
school, um,
I was doing social science and a
little too focused on
the quantitative side of it. So
I was doing more
operations with search as it
related to that.
That sort of led me down the
road to be doing a bit
of management consulting and
working in finance,
actually mortgage finance early
in my career.
Um, and what I discovered was
that the analytic techniques
I had were kind of limiting. So
I started learning
more coding, right. And learning
how to
develop using the tools
available back in the 1990s.
Uh, and this led me to, you
know, street smarts coding that
I turned into my first, second,
third, fourth businesses.
Um, eventually going from
someone who builds someone,
who's managing people who are
building back to
someone who builds again. Um,
it's kind of going back
and forth over that, um, until
about 2005 when I was diagnosed
with cancer, uh, and then spent
about six months being
told that I wouldn't see the end
of that particular year.
Um, and then sort of launched
out with my most recent company
that I ran for about a decade,
uh, before realizing I was
sort of not really contributing
to it anymore and looking
for my next thing to do. Um, and
they started a
company and been trying a few
different things.
Now I've got a prog studio
going, um, In the course of
this came to the pandemic.
Right. Um, and suddenly
everything
changed for everybody and like
the way people
manage the way people work, all
of it is different.
And I had this, um, revelation
that I was
more wrong than I was. Right.
And this is probably
true all the way through. Right.
And we all are.
Um, but I wanted to kind of
rediscover what it is
that people are doing now.
Right. This can project forward,
as
opposed to what I had known and
could project into the past.
Great experiences where
something, but there's
a question to like, where's the
world going?
And I heard about VC, um, and VC
is about people who are entering
the field and figuring out where
they're going to go next.
And so I came here with a
selfish motivation to learn, to
find out what people are doing.
That's just at variance with
what I thought was right, or
what I was doing, where a place
where, you know, I knew that I
was more wrong than I was right.
And I could listen to people,
um, and understand where
they're going and hopefully, and
this is sort of thing
that I've evolved into, um,
provide some service as well.
Right? How can I have a positive
impact on these people's lives,
even as I'm trying to learn from
them so they can have
a positive impact on mine. And
that's the feedback
that I'm in right now.
Dan: Hmm. I love that. I love
the idea of, um, you
know, realizing that you're
wrong more than you're right.
You know, and it's the way you
said it is.
Like, it makes sense in it. It's
like one of those
things that, um, I think you
said this, but.
Everybody in fact is probably
wrong, more often than they're.
Right. You know, but it's, it's
hard
to admit that to yourself. Um,
maybe sometimes hard
to, um, I don't know, make, take
action on that. Right.
Uh, other than just like
ignoring, trying to ignore
it, forget about the times that
you were wrong.
Um, what, was there something
like, particularly something
aside from just the pandemic and
maybe some of the soul searching
that a lot of us went through
that, um, resulted in that.
Realization or revelation as he
put it.
Ray: Uh, yeah. Um, I had made a,
a
couple of errors in the course
of 2019 and 2020.
Um, a lot of it having to do
with, uh, who I
would put my faith in. Um, that
was causing me to,
okay, well, what's, what's the
right thing to be doing here.
And then that all slams together
with a pandemic, which is
changing lifestyle quite a bit.
Right?
So that, you know, this idea of
how I would work of, you
know, go to an office and like
be with people and be
leading them with heavy. It's
just different now. Right?
Cause I'm now working remote,
which I appreciate is not as
new a thing for many others, but
for small companies are
actually trying to move fast. It
is.
I think more unusual than it's
usual or at least that was
true in beginning of 2020. Um,
and the, um, and it was a
whole bunch of new things for me
to learn and thing and patterns
that just weren't working for me
anymore on an immediate
basis, as well as having gotten
a little bit kicked with like
who I should be working with.
And, and, and what's a
good basis for trust. Right. So
these were all things I was,
uh, sorting out, coming into the
beginning of the pandemic,
um, and then figuring out, okay,
what am I doing next?
And then that would eventually
lead me, uh, later in the
winter, discover BC and be able
to have the pattern here
even as I was doing that a bit
in my business work, sort
of in the course of the fall.
Does that make sense?
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: You said this, this
there's this idea of what
a good basis for trust. And I'd
like to hear you talk
a little bit more about what
you've learned or if there's,
if you've kind of narrowed that
down or to find that in any way.
Ray: Sure. Um, I think of, I've
learned
a couple things about trust. I
think, uh, the first is
one needs to accept the idea
that one might be wrong. Right.
Uh, the, the, there's an idea of
a leap of faith, right?
You leap and then you kind of
hope there's something I, but
you don't have a guarantee. Um,
and I, I think there's
a, there's a bit of, can you
make those leaps a little
smaller, so you don't quite fall
all the way to the bottom
of the abyss when it happens.
Um, and so that one
can be earning trust. Uh, one of
the neat things about
this environment we're in now
being more remote is that people
can't really lay the Juju on
you, the way that they could.
Um, if you're just in person,
right?
There's a certain presence.
People can have that like
makes you more inclined to
follow them or to trust them.
And when you're over this kind
of pipe, that kind of
thing, doesn't work as well.
Right. Cause you need to
be more explicit. This both
makes it a little
bit harder to start trust
relationships, but also
makes it hard to start bad trust
relationships.
So that's something I've
definitely seen in terms
of how this thing changes. Um,
and the second is that
trust well earned takes time.
Um, and I will tell people
who are talking to me about
potential angel investment
type things that I only invest
in people that I've
known for over a year. Uh,
because if I haven't known
you for a year, I don't really
have that basis of seeing your
consistent behavior there's is a
place I should be putting,
you know, the capital that
otherwise is important for
the future of my family. You
know? So the, um, so I
think those, those. Those those,
those two
things have put yourself in a
place where you can trust
and be wrong and not have it be
the end of the world.
Um, and then be patient before
you're doing something big,
more, you know, bet the farm
style, um, are the lessons I've
taken away from it at this.
Dan: That's interesting. That's
very interesting.
And Bekah, yes, basically the
question I was going, I
was going to ask it the idea of,
uh, of, I mean, the idea
of trust is, um, I don't know
something that's always
important, you know, and I'm,
I'm, I'm, I'm just constantly
fascinated by the ways that, um,
sort of the, the zoom, you
know, culture has like changed,
um, how we communicate and
how we do different things. And
that, that I had never
considered this, the, the body
language and the things that
people can do to instill trust.
I don't know, in a, in a
fake way, like, there's probably
a better way to
phrase that, but like you were
talking about right.
There's, there's things that
people can do to like physically
make like, help make a person
trust them, you know, and those
go away when you don't have like
the body language in the room.
And probably, you know, I don't
know, fancy meals and
stuff like that too, I suppose.
But, um, the, the, the, the body
language thing has been really
interesting for me because I
I've actually felt, um, I dunno,
uh, some amount of more freedom.
Yeah. In like in zoom, like
locations,
because I don't have to, uh, I
don't have to worry about
my body language as much. Right.
I don't have to worry about,
uh, you know, talking about
doing presentations that realize
that I don't have to do, I don't
have to worry about,
um, what my hands are doing.
Right. And what I'm doing with
my
hands, what I'm doing with my
legs, how I'm standing
or home, you know, whatever. We
can see each other's faces.
I mean, we're right now in most
zoom calls.
Um, so there's still some of
that connection, you
know, it's not just the. Like
not just a text chat, but,
um, it does remove some of that.
Uh, I dunno, nuance, you
know, for better or worse.
Right. It's, it's really
interesting.
Ray: The, the tools one can use
to project trust at a
difference, or also trust that
distance or also. Right.
So for example, what you're
doing, Dan right now with that
bigger microphone that's sitting
in front of you picks up more
of your voice timber, right? And
is, um, uh, it is projecting
more trustworthiness than
somebody who is just using the
microphone on their AirPods.
It's actually one of the
reasons why I'm talking into a
microphone right now, I sort
of thought it was a silly thing
to have until I realized how
important it was for things like
zoom meetings, um, the
lighting that you've got behind
you, the setup you have, right?
We talk about like room Raider
and, and, and sort
of the silly things along those
lines, but these things
help you project trust. So the
tools that we have
that allow us to project trust
through context, as
opposed to just the message. Are
different now
than they were before. I tend to
think they're
less potent, right? We don't
have the same aura
effect that we can have like
directly in the room,
but there are definitely people
who are like super
compelling when they're on TV.
And not that much when
they're in person. Uh, I think
we had a
president who is a little bit on
those lines.
Um, and we have, um, different
tools. Now.
We just need to understand how
to put them to work
so that we can be getting
maximum value for the things.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. And
that, those, like some of
those, like the lighting and the
voice stuff, you know, is,
that's almost a cosmetic, you
know, trust is kind of like the
fake projecting trust stuff that
we were talking about before.
Right. Um, and so that goes back
to, I also very much like how
you said you to really like, be
able to know for yourself
that you trust somebody it's
like knowing them for a year.
Right. Because then it doesn't
matter how fancy.
My lighting set up is, you know,
after a year, after a
year you'll you'll know whether
or not, um, you can trust me
or anybody else, I suppose.
Bekah: It's interesting as
you're talking about this.
Cause I'm thinking I taught an
argument class, um,
back when I was teaching. And
one of the key things
that we looked at was the
rhetorical triangle.
And so you have like Ethos,
Pathos and Logos, right.
And Ethos is that idea of
trustworthiness.
It's the tone and the style of
the person.
And so in this digital world,
There has to be this like
shortcut way of projecting that.
And in a lot of instances
and social media and tech moves
so quickly.
And so what you're saying, these
things that kind of
establish that, that allows a
shortcut in order to do that.
And then, you know, Pathos
appeals to emotions and Logos.
That's where, you know, you, you
become really credible by.
Showing that you understand what
you're doing, that
you can demonstrate that, you
know, the things that
you're talking about. But I
think that we.
We leaned so hard today on Ethos
and Pathos that sometimes that
Logos gets lost a little bit. So
rather than really thinking
about whether somebody knows
what they're talking
about, we think about how we
feel when we hear that
person talk, how they appear to
be an authority or not.
And I think that tends to lead a
lot of people down a path that
it's not productive or useful.
Ray: Right. I mean, of course in
argumentation, you'll learn
that the appeal to authority is
a logical fallacy, right.
It takes you out of the, the
structure of it.
Um, and, and, and I think this
too, to bring it back to the
technology industry, uh it's
this is complicated stuff.
Right.
The code that you're looking at,
the, uh, the, the nature
of things we're trying to build
or edit or create, um,
are just very hard to hold.
Right to hold your head
directly, but not simple systems
even have a mental model of it.
So at a comp at a, a complicated
system level
is, is really difficult. And so
you wind up with,
okay, I have an edge of it.
Right. And how do I trust in
that
edge and how I trust in the edge
the other person has.
And that's a, that's a tough
thing because
you just don't know. Um, and you
don't know because
none of us, or very few of us, I
would say are smart
enough to actually hold it in.
So, how do you, how do you,
how do you build the trust that
like the sure you're holding
onto leg of the elephant and
they're holding onto the trunk?
Um, are you actually
communicating with each
other so you can put together
the floor picture?
Bekah: Yeah. And it's
interesting.
This concept of trust and how
important it is on our
journeys and our paths, but also
how it impacts
how we trust ourselves too.
Because a lot of times I think
that when we think about how we
trust ourselves, we do it based
on other people's perceptions of
us or our interactions with
those people that we do trust.
And so when you get into a
situation where, you know,
you're following someone or,
or working with somebody who
isn't really trustworthy, And
that impacts your ability to see
what path you could be
on or what your potential is.
Does that make sense?
Ray: Yeah. Um, the right people
to advise
us and to be our lightposts is,
is a hard and important thing.
Um, and I think, you know, one
of the things I conversations
sometimes have with
entrepreneurs is their reticence
to commit to a path, right? Like
they're afraid
they're are more afraid of being
wrong than they are
excited about being right. Um,
and there's an expression
that more was lost by indecision
than by the wrong decision.
Um, and the, there there's an
opportunity to be just giving
people some more confidence. Not
that they should
follow your advice, right? Not
that you should do the
thing that I say you should do,
but that you should do.
Right. That you should go
forward with
that, which makes sense for you.
Um, and that you have a trust
in them that they can then apply
that trust to themselves.
There's a guy named  Simon
Sinek. Uh, he wrote a book
called,
uh, called, um, Start With Why.
And he actually has a
famous Ted talk too. I don't
know if
you've ever seen it. Um, and he
talks about three
levels of, of what you're about.
He says the inside is the
why then around that you have
the, how then around
that you have the what. Right.
And you've got lots of whats.
You might have a few hows, but
have one why, what does the
thing that really motivates you?
And to the extent that we can
help people find their why.
Right. W what, what is the
important thing to them? Then
they're in a position where
they can be making important
decisions, the hows, right.
That are long-term decisions
that allow them to move
forward, as opposed to being,
you know, like we started
afraid of being wrong.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. I, that
indecision thing
is, is real, you know? And it's,
I think it's like
everybody is everybody's
affected by it, you
know, from time to time. Um, so
like, it kind of
talks about how you can. People,
what do you do when
you find yourself in that
situation of, you know, it
kind of stuck, maybe your
motivations are a little
different, you know, from case
to case, but like you're stuck
in decision, you know, you're,
you're, um, I don't know, lost
or whatever, like what do you do
personally, if you're, if
you're in a situation like that,
Ray: Well, it helps have people
you trust to
be able to talk about. Right.
Um, I think Bekah, you and
I had a conversation where I use
the expression believable
people, um, and that, that comes
from um Ray Dailo.
Um, who uses it in the context
of, he actually
has a whole app based on
believability that he uses for
decision-making over at his, a
hedge fund called Bridgewater.
Um, and who is believable in a
given context, matters a lot.
Now, if you're not sure who to
trust, that's a
whole different thing. But if he
has some people
who you can trust, who you can
go back to who are
believable, uh, and this is
something you accumulate
over a lifetime, right? Go back
to them and ask.
And what I have found in the
course of having those
conversations is that there is
two kinds of value.
The first kind of value is that
these people who I
trust will listen to what I'm
saying about that.
And then will feed that back to
me, right?
Feedback a, you know, their,
their, their, their opinion on
the situation or what have you.
But the second thing, and
this takes some training. But
the second thing
that I've learned to do is to
listen to myself.
The very thing that I'm saying
to them is most often.
At least implies the answer of
what I need to do now.
Um, and I gotta say, like, when
I'm talking to entrepreneurs
who are doing a one-off thing,
like we've done this before,
actually in the, um, in the
Indi, uh, startup hacker meetup,
um, I sort of listened to what
someone's saying about their
situation for about 10 minutes.
And then I kind of
repeat it back to them using
different words.
They say, wow, that's such great
advice.
I've really only been repeating
it back to them.
Um, but that can be worth a lot
too.
I mean, th th there's, there's
such a thing as the
value of a sounding board. Um,
and being able to just
listen to yourself can be one of
the hardest things
to do, but that can be the job
of your best friend.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. So this
is like rubber
ducking, except for not. Tech
stuff. Right. Almost right.
You know? So, so like rubber
ducking in
tech, I guess when you're stuck
on a bug or something as you,
and I explained to somebody or,
or, you know, or an object,
the, what you're trying to do.
And then sometimes the answer
becomes clear to yourself. Um,
just based on that, right.
Ray: rubber ducking your life.
Dan: Yeah.
Ray: And now you have a podcast
title.
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: I love that
Dan: concept of rubber ducking.
Most of the time in a tech,
um, context and, you know, a
development context, but.
A lot. Um, and in Virtual Coffee
and,
and in our, um, and in the
podcast, I feel like it's, it's
made a, it's made a number of
appearances that rubber duck,
we got a picture of Drew's. Drew
has a, you know,
actual rubber duck. He sits on
his desk.
We got a picture of him cause he
was holding it up
and talking to it during the
podcast episode that he was on.
And when you did get a shot of
it.
So I got a shot of it for the,
for the show notes.
Um, I like that. I like that
idea though.
Just that finding that, that
trusted person, you
know, that can kind of.
Bekah: So there. Especially in
tech, when we have
so many people who are working
remotely or who are self-taught,
there can be a lot of isolation
and there sometimes can be a
really hard, it can be hard to
find that soundboard right.
Hard to find the people you
trust.
So what advice do you have for
people who are
in the situation where. That
would be really great
if I had somebody that I trusted
and can talk to, you
know, how do you get to that?
Ray: Well, it's a hard thing,
right?
I, I, it's not going to be
automatic.
I would say that if you've met
somebody in Virtual
Coffee, that's not the person,
um, because you don't have
nearly enough depth, right. To
have that kind of, you
know, soul bearing trust. Um,
and. This is where a family
has become helpful. This is
where a childhood
friends can become helpful to
the extent that you keep up
with any, um, this is where
people in your community
can become helpful, right? This
is where you have that
kind of depth, uh, that doesn't
need to come from work.
And I think one of the things
people think is that they
need to talk to somebody who's
in the context, right.
That they are talking about.
But, you know,
particularly talking about. It
could be a rubber duck, right?
So it could be your, you know,
it could be a minister.
It could be, you know, an aunt,
it could be, you know,
whoever it is that, that, that
is important to you
in your life, who you would
trust to not repeat it. Right.
The things that are bothering
you the most, it's really
the confidence that's going to
be most important when
we talk about that trust and
then allowing that
reflection to, um, to happen. So
if a combination of
non-repeating and ideally not
carrying the, the, uh,
the judgment of it too far
forward, that can be hard
to find in a work context. Um,
and I wouldn't look.
Casually, uh, it should. And it
accumulates over
time, someone you met on Virtual
Coffee two years ago
that you've been keeping up with
and have now a deeper
relationship with that could be
a thing, but of course, Virtual
Coffee isn't even that old.
Dan: More over a year though,
right?
Ray: Oh yeah. Over a year. I can
invest in somebody
Bekah: those listening, you just
got to wait literally like
another five months and then you
can have your rubber duck.
Dan: Um, you mentioned
Ray: There's also a thing.
Sorry, just one last idea.
There is such a thing called a
Mastermind, uh, which
is a, uh, structure first
introduced back in the 1930s.
It was something that Henry Ford
did, uh, that was in written
up in a book by Napoleon hill.
And it's actually pretty popular
in the startup community right
now, um, which is just in
agreement among a few people who
are all doing the same thing.
In this case, startup founders,
uh, that was
said in the room stays. And
usually they're
coming in with the biggest
business blockers.
What have you, and most of the
time it is the same kind of
phenomenon we just talked about
that applies to anything else.
So, you know, I sort of talked
about, Hey, you need to have
this depth of, you know, um,
what have you, in order to,
uh, be the basis of that trust.
But there is some indication
that you could decide to do this
with a structure and an
agreement ahead of time and a
little bit of, um, peer
pressure that says, Hey, because
we're doing this as a small.
We're all agreeing that what's
said in the
room stays in the room. So
there, I think there's,
there, there is definitely
potential for being able to
provide that kind of con uh, uh,
counsel in confidence,
not from someone wiser than you,
but at least someone
who you trust not to repeat.
Dan: Well, and I, and a group of
people. Right.
Ray: Yeah. And the small group
seems to
be where the magic of that is.
Yeah.
Dan: with, with the masterminds
concept.
Um, w in those cases, in at
least the ones you've seen
are those people who have a
history, like a relationship
already, or are they sort of
like for like minded people,
but not necessarily know each
other yet, you know,
Ray: The two that I've done have
both been in the category.
We were strangers at the
beginning of it.
Dan: Yeah,
Ray: Uh, and frankly, that was
part of the benefit, right?
That, you know, we, we had the,
um, you know, the, the false
confidence of anonymity, right.
Uh, that, Hey, we could all
leave and maybe it didn't work
out and it's not like we'll run
into those people again, because
the world is big and, you know,
no matter what your business is,
is your is probably relatively
small compared to the world. Um,
so there there's.
There's definitely an
opportunity to be starting
a little bit more for cold. I
mean, I know I said like the
whole two year thing, what have
you, but that's my experience
on the one-on-one and this
mastermind thing is something
I've only experienced much more
recently, but I think it's a
way maybe to be able to get that
jump-started, um, and
could be interesting, even at
the level of a VC initiative,
Dan: Yeah. I mean, I definitely,
like, I like the idea a
lot, you know, it's, it's an
interesting concept.
Um, and we have found in Virtual
Coffee, the like value
of small groups, you know, um,
just in general, right. And
Ray: Okay.
Dan: just being able to talk
and, you know, in small rooms
and break rooms and things like
that, um, it, it seems
like one of the highlights of.
Dunno our experience or
whatever, our, uh, mission, I
don't know, whatever, whatever
the word is, but, you know, uh,
th th this sort of intimacy of,
of, of something like that, um,
Ray: I'd use the word way.
There's a Virtual Coffee way.
Dan: the way, yes, this is the
way
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: a man, a man, sorry, I just
got sidetracked
by the Mandalorian. So,
Bekah: I have a
Dan: yeah, go.
Bekah: Okay. So if say you're
working with
a small group of people in some
capacity that we talked
about in this conversation and.
You can kind of see a path
that would, maybe you, can't
kind of like you are pretty,
have a pretty strong feeling
that you can see a path for
this person in front of you. And
you're trying to guide
them in that direction. And
maybe this is wrong.
Maybe you're like, no, you don't
try and guide anyone.
You help them get there
themselves.
But what I'm trying to get at is
like, sometimes people
just can not see that path or
they're very resistant to that
path and they refuse to try it.
So, you know, how do you, how
do you navigate that situation
where you're trying to help
somebody find the right path for
themselves or, um, you
know, the thing that, that, you
know, would be really good for.
Ray: I'm wrong more often than
I'm right.
I don't know what the right path
for them is.
Um, I think I used to give, you
know, that kind of, um,
didactic  advice more freely and
I've, uh, I've been
beaten back by that a bit. Um,
you know, I think cancer
did that a bit to me, just sort
of the experience of like, you
know, being an entrepreneur,
figuring out what works and what
doesn't has put that into me.
Um, and having, and
getting to be in groups of
people, uh, VC included,
uh, that are not like me. Right.
Has also helps with my humility
and to the extent that I can
keep building on my humility.
I think I'm going to be much
better off when I see people
in that kind of situation where
I think that they
are running into a wall. The
thing I've learned is
to don't say it, oh no, don't
run into the wall.
Actually. I just had this
conversation
with them, an entrepreneur, um,
an email back and forth what
someone who I'm invested in, um,
who by the way is, uh, at
risk of running into the wall.
Um, and I wrote this whole
note out saying, look, man,
you're running into the wall
that you're, you're, you're
going to run out of money.
This is going to be a problem.
You know, I can hear your
number to dah, dah, dah. And
then I sort of re-read it.
And, uh, and this is something
that my wife says I'm good at.
I threw away the email and I
wrote another one
and I wrote the email. That was,
why are you doing this?
What was the reason you started
down this journey?
And what's important about it.
Uh, and how can you find
what's important to be focusing
your attention
on the stuff that matters? And
not be spending on the stuff
that doesn't matter to you. And
here are like the five other
people who are really smart, who
are sitting on your board.
These are wonderful resources,
go talk to them for what's next.
Right. And they might give more
didactic advice.
But like my thing was just a,
how can I help this person
rediscover why they were there
in the first place?
And if I can do that, Then I can
put them on the tracks game.
The answers can be right for
them instead of
the particular policy. I think
might've
been right for me.
Dan: I love that. I love that
that's an experience
I have to sometimes where I
write something out sometime
I guess, I suppose most of the
time it's some sort of
snarky tweet, you know, or a
reply or something, but,
um, you know, the, initial. You
are clearly wrong, you know,
whatever, like what you're doing
would feel wrong for me, that,
that, like that idea, you know,
and not, you know, not trying
to put it on to somebody else.
Um, and just the action
of throwing away, the writing it
out, I suppose.
It's probably helpful for you,
you to reprocess, but, you know,
throwing it out and then kind of
reframing it as, uh, as a here's
some things to think about.
Right. Um, it's gotta be more
helpful most of the time, uh, to
the people.
Although, I mean, not although,
but like even if probably
sometimes people are asking
questions, so hoping for some
sort of easy answer, you know,
um, I think the, the, the
answers, the kind of answers
that you provide, that, that
you've provided to me over over
the last year, um, are, are
ultimately much more helpful
even if, no matter how much
I beg you, you won't just tell
me exactly what to do.
Uh, I just like, I love that
approach.
I appreciate it very much.
Bekah: But also sometimes it
would be nice to
know what should I do?
Dan: Okay. Uh, yeah, for our
listeners,
I be like, Ray is infinitely
patient with us, both Bekah
and I individually and probably
together have come to Ray
for advice a million times. I
don't, I don't know
how many times, and it's always
been good.
And, and this approach, I never
really put it in words, but
this is approach is exactly why.
You know, it's that, that
process of, um, reframing
things, probably just re
spitting out the things that I
said to him, you know,
but, uh, in a more connected
manner, um, I don't know.
I, I, something that I
appreciate personally very much.
Bekah: Yeah, same. And I know
Ray also has been
running two of our small groups
at Virtual Coffee, the Indie
Hackers Group and the React.
What's the full name
of the React group?
Ray: I called a group mentoring
actually, after
your idea from April.
Dan: okay.
Bekah: So the Group Mentoring.
And so I know that there've
been a lot of people who have
benefited from that, and I
always forget the day and
usually schedule something
else at the same time. So I
haven't been able to make
as much, but as I've wanted to.
But when you are moving in
these different groups or. If
you're meeting with
someone individually or you're
talking to an investor, is
there a standard approach that
you kind of take going
into those situations? Are you
really like looking at
the person in that moment every
time and trying to figure out
how you can both learn and learn
from and support that person?
Ray: So there's something that
in my own head, I called the Dr.
House Rule. Um, which is, uh,
which is after
a TV show is on decade ago. Um,
uh, where is a medical
version of Sherlock Holmes? And
the, the, the premise is
that if you've gone to the ER
and they can't figure out
what's going on and they take
you to a specialist and they
can't figure out what's going
on, they then bring you to Dr.
House, which means that every
time I'm talking with somebody.
Is actually talking with me
about their problem.
Uh, it must be not that
receptive right.
To easy answers. Right. Cause
you would have gotten them.
Um, and, and so that's the
reason, it's one of the reasons
I take the approach that I do.
Right.
Which is, um, you know, try to
discover what's going on inside.
You know, there's this idea in
systems theory, um, that,
uh, in a complex system, like an
ecological system,
um, both the problem and the
answer are inside the system.
So trying to apply resource from
outside the system is often
kind of destructive, right? So
there's like an example
of like, if you were in
Bangladesh and this time too,
and you're, you're looking at
poverty, um, there's one
theory of, well, let's go bring
a factory to town, right.
We'll be able to arbitrage the
labor.
It will, uh, we'll, we'll raise
people's living standards
and, and that'll all be good.
Um, but then when you
look there, there's like plenty
of economy down. Right.
They just don't have quite
enough, um, liquidity going on.
And so th there was a guy who I
should think won the peace
prize for this who came up with
the idea of micro loans.
Which is to create financial
opportunities, not by having
a big factory come to town.
Right.
But just to enable these people
to do transactions among each
other, and then by greasing the
gears of commerce, allow them
to make each other's, um, may
make each other wealthier and
raise the overall standards. The
answer wasn't to
come in from the outside with a
big new factory.
It was just to enable what's on
the inside.
And I think that applies in
systems as big as Bangladesh
and as small as, a human being.
Dan: I love that idea. I don't
really have anything
to add to it or, or, or to delve
in, but this
is one of those moments. We have
these in the podcast
where we, something that guests
says just kind of like Bekah
and I are, both just like
processing it, you know, uh,
galaxy brand kind of moments
that, um, that I dunno, I
don't have anything to say.
Really.
That was a very good answer.
Bekah: I would like a three hour
conversation on that.
Can we, can we schedule an
evening lecture as well
Dan: so, all right, so I'm going
to go back a little bit
to the, to the interest groups.
Um, they you've been, you know,
running, um, and I guess, I
guess my, you know, the indie
hackers group, um, is sort of a
group of like-minded people.
It's almost close to the
masterminds thing, although,
although it's not like a
specific group of people. Right.
But it's, you know, um, Um, the
people that join the meetup
are kind of all on their own
journeys of, you know, indie
hacking and stuff like that. And
we kind of all talk and
give advice and, um, and Ray
kind of moves people through
the, you know, discussions, um,
which has been cool.
Uh, the, the react group
mentoring it's, it's, it's a
little bit different, right?
This is, this is a, this is
a meetup where there's people
who are, um, learning react.
Or, or have learned it and are
working in it.
And then there's people who have
been, had some more
experience with it that hang out
a little bit together.
Um, can you talk a little bit
about like your ideas about
that group and how it's, how it
is, like, how it started,
how it's been going, you know, w
what what's been good about
it what's been, if there, if
anything bad about it.
Ray: Yeah, well, um, I would
look to the participants
to answer the question of what's
been good or bad.
Um, Luma I'm I'm, I'm running
the groups through
Luma as a platform. Um, and what
this does again,
to ask for people's feedback and
the feedback I've gotten
so far has been in the quality
of, you know, five stars and
then nothing in the comment box.
Uh, and while I appreciate the
kind stars, like knowing what
people value would help me.
Um, both get more out of it, uh,
as well as help
others get more out of it. So to
the extent that I can
be, uh, using this podcast as a
request for comment, uh, I
would, um, you know, I've been
doing this since April, once
again, I think out of what was
it called the month of
month of sharing was that was
whatever the challenge was.
That was sort of what inspired
me to start
these two little meetups. Um,
and the, the thing
I really liked about the react
meetup is the ability
to just connect people. Right.
Like, there've been a couple
of them where like, maybe for
half of them I'm talking or
something, but the best ones for
me, those are the ones
where I'm talking barely at all.
I am just keeping the
conversation, moving between
smart people, commenting
on somebody's problem. And it
can be very cool when
it's like you Dan, or it's going
to be Ryan or Kirk, you
know, uh, talking smart about a
problem that somebody has.
But the thing that is just
revelatory  to me is when
it's someone who's not one of
you who is, who is themselves
relatively junior, or perceive
themselves to be junior and
they are helping each other.
Because the problem you have
is just the problem that's
directly in front of you.
And it's strange to you, but it
might not be
strange to someone else. And
that's not a question
of being junior or senior or up
the ladder or progressive
that's just context. And when I
can have people
of different contexts come
together and make each other
smarter, and then they come out
and they are greater.
Uh, that's the mission.
Dan: Yeah, that's great. I, I've
also enjoyed
those times, you know, and I,
uh, It's funny.
I try, you know, as, as a
participant in the meetup, I do
try, like, I try to, I mean, I
love react and I love coding,
you know, and I get very excited
about all that, you know?
Uh, and so I try to, I try to,
um, get people
engaged in all that stuff. Um,
and it's just, uh, it's
always funny cause I'm sure Ray
can see me just getting
really, really antsy sometimes,
you know, Somebody asked about,
uh, you know, CSS and tailwind
and, you know, CSS and JS. And
there was, there was some really
good discussion, really, really,
really good, um, discussion. And
I was just like literally
sitting on my, on my hands.
Cause, cause it's like,
I've been doing CSS for a
million years.
Old guy opinions about it
probably.
But, uh, I mean, that's just my
personal anecdote about it.
Um, the, the, the, the meetup
has been really fun and I've
been, I've been really thinking
about different ways that it can
be, you know, if for instance,
more people start joining or,
you know, if it gets bigger, you
know, ways to, um, kind of
keep it going with the intimacy
it has, you know, so it's like
so far, it's been most of the
time, what like eight to 10.
People does that sound right
Ray: Yeah, there are 20 plus
less two of them.
Dan: Oh, okay. Nice. Well, I
missed the last one.
So, um, yeah, 20 plus is a, is
a, that's like a solid
amount of people for, for kind
of a, um, meet up like that.
And it's, you know, um, I don't
know.
It's, it's very cool. And it's a
very cool,
uh, service that you're
providing to the community
and to like the people and
honestly, the meet you.
I mean, I learned things
watching.
Um, watching other people go
through these as well.
Um, lots of times there was the,
uh, I don't know which one it
was awhile ago or somebody was
working through authentication
and, you know, react hooks. And,
um, and I think as a
group, we all just decided, like
we had run a little bit
longer on, on that problem, but
we all wanted to see, you
know, we all wanted to see the
outcome and get through it.
So we all kind of sat as a group
and cut through the whole thing,
you know, and it was great. Um,
I don't know, I just,
I just appreciated it, you know,
as, as, as a consumer,
even as a, as a group member,
um, it was, it was very cool.
Um, that's all just to say, I
appreciate the work
you've been doing on it, and I
appreciate that, that,
uh, that meetup group has been,
it's been really cool.
Ray: Well, for anyone interested
in participating they're
on the second and fourth
Wednesdays of the month at
1 PM, central as 1 PM. Eastern.
Oh, got that one wrong.
Dan: Hmm. Yes. Yes. And, uh,
the, if you're
in our slack, the help and
pairing they're usually
links are posted there too. Um,
and help and
pairing a channel. So definitely
check those out.
Uh, if you're interested in
react.
Bekah: So when you're talking
about all of these
different things that you do,
I'm trying to.
Think about it in terms of
mentorship.
And I'm wondering if you think
about it in terms of
mentorship, because it seems,
you know, uh, maybe a little
bit different than the way that
we understand or traditionally
think of mentoring.
Ray: Yeah. I think a mentorship
as
being a, um, a relatively
intense relationship.
Relatively high trust on both
sides.
That's a nontrivial time
commitment.
Um, uh, and I find that the best
model is one that actually
came from a guy named Bob Mesta.
Um, and he, he wrote about it in
the Harvard business review too.
And, um, and, and
his approach is it's. He, he, he
structured
them as 90 day programs. Um,
where he is going to
work with somebody who's, you
know, looking to make
a particular kind of change in
their life, right?
Want to move from phase to phase
B on something.
And he's there to help them make
that change.
And he's measuring himself based
on their, his success
and helping them make that. And
he measures the other
person based on their commitment
to making that
thing happen as well. It doesn't
need to be
all the work on it. Right. It's
not trying to maximize
the change is trying to move
from one state to another.
And I find that to be a sort of
a useful way of looking at
right equate to create limits.
Uh, I found that to be really
good for masterminds too. Right.
There's a, what's the
change you're looking to make in
the next quarter.
And then we're committing to
meeting weekly, right.
To be helping each other, make
that. Right.
Um, so when you have something
that's going to
be a more intensive kind of
commitment, knowing what
does success look like? And
what's that? What does the
commitment of resource? Um, I
think matters
matters quite a bit. And a lot
of, you know,
the things I tried to do here, I
try to be helpful.
Um, but again, I try to be
humble. Right?
I am learning as much, if not
more from this.
Uh, then this group is
potentially gaining from me
and I understand that that is a
value I'm receiving
and that I'm grateful for.
Dan: Yeah, that that value
proposition of being in a
community, um, is always an
interesting one to think
about too, you know, as somebody
who's, you know,
you said, and I agree that. The
Virtual Coffee has a lot of
people who are career changing,
you know, starting their
careers and things like that.
And then, um, some members
who are, are more senior, but,
you know, been around
for a while longer, um, not
changing careers, you know,
uh, and that how to provide
value as a community to
more senior members, senior
developer, IE members, um, has
been something that we've we
thought about from time to time.
Um, and that's, for me, that's
the, that's
the same answer as is. I've just
like learned, I've
learned so much from everybody,
you know, I learned about, um,
how a lot of my assumptions, you
know, can be wrong, you
know, learn about, um, how
people learn, like all the
different ways that people learn
things, you know,
in general, um, It's it's. It's
cool.
That the way you phrase it, I,
I, um, I really appreciate that.
That's cool.
Bekah: You know, I, I think, you
know, one of the things that
I would like to know about if,
if you okay, I think I asked
you about how do you evaluate
strengths and weaknesses. Right.
And I would love for you to be
able to share that too,
because I thought, you know, it
definitely goes along with
this conversation, you touched
on some of it already, but
just to be specific about that,
because I think that,
you know, that self evaluation
can be really useful in
determining where we are going.
Ray: Yeah. Um, Approach I take,
and this
again comes from Daleo is to
find, you know, believable
people, you know, who you trust
and to go ask them
about where you are strong. Um,
and then.
You know, weight, their
believability, um, based on,
well, how inclined are they to
just say nice things about you?
And a lot of this can come from
like domain expertise, right?
So like, you're trying to figure
out where your
technical skills are. You talk
to somebody who really
likes you, whose technical
skills you value, and they
rate you on your technical
skills or they comment on it.
Right. I say, rate, it's not
like it's
a formal survey or anything. Um,
and they say, well, yeah,
you're really good here. You
could use some help here
too da da da, but then I also
think you're a wonderful
leader and you have all these
other skills, like.
But that's not what you're
believable on. Right.
And what, what people often do
when they are
evaluating somebody else is they
will soften it
way by saying nice things are
outside of their door.
And the, uh, and when I'm
looking for that kind of
feedback, I'm not looking for
the, to hear a bunch
of nice things, right. I'm not
looking to get bucked
up, I'm looking for, um, the,
the advice that would
allow me to make a change.
Right? So I'm not just looking
for
the negatives I am looking for,
like, where is it that they
have the useful advice that is
believable in that domain?
So that technologist who then
proceeds to say my
leadership skills aren't there.
Maybe I'm paying
attention to that. Maybe I'm
going checking in on
my leadership skills, but I'm
not walking away with, um, a
policy prescription based on
what that person had to say,
because that's not the domain in
which they are believable.
And I know this all sounds a
little structured and what
have you, but it really does
make a difference because
then that way, like there, um,
there's this problem. Okay.
Th th th there's a, uh, an old
Dilbert, uh, where
it ends with, it was such a good
idea in my head. Right.
And lots of ideas are good in
our own head.
Uh, there's a parallel thing
that my sister and
I have two sisters who are
physicians and they both
have told me separately. There's
no such
thing as a mentor. Whenever you
have something
that's just in your head, you
can persuade yourself.
That is a good thing. Or you can
persuade yourself.
That's a bad thing. Or what have
you, it's
this a morphous bit. But when
you actually have
to use a technical term,
serialize your thoughts, right.
And move them across platforms,
one person to another who then
you have a high degree of trust
in that I found to be where
there's a lot of value to, um,
to, to bring out those thoughts,
to figure out what's real. And
what's not.
And to your point back, I figure
out where those strengths
and weaknesses really are.
Bekah: Yeah. I've also found
that there,
there are some people that are
really good at identifying
strengths and weaknesses through
conversation.
And can, can give those to you
or to talk about them.
I hear you say this. This is
what it
tells me about you. And, and in
those situations,
I find that there's like a. A
much faster degree of
trust I have in those people who
are able to, you know,
see and evaluate, but also be
honest about those,
those things that they see. And
then it allows me to
kind of think about it, reflect
on it and realize,
okay, now, now what do I do with
that information now?
Ray: Yeah, no, that's, that's a
really good point.
There is such a thing as. Um,
and you can be trained to
do this better and you can use
experience to do this better.
And I'd like to think that I've
applied a little bit of training
and probably a bit of experience
to do it better for others.
Um, but the proof of that.
Bekah: So. I was just gonna say,
like, along those lines,
are there resources that you've
also found helpful?
I mean, you've given us so many
resources here, which
we'll all go in the show notes,
but anything that you haven't
mentioned or you've personally
found like, okay, well, this
really helped me on a journey.
It helped me to fill this gap
that I wasn't able to find
through self-reflection or
working with other people.
Ray: Um, yeah, I, there there's
a whole, you know, universe of,
you know, self-help literature,
but if someone's going to
read just one, I, I strongly
recommend Covey's Seven Habits.
Um, it is, um, it is excellent,
um, as a sort of
guideposts for how to make
yourself both smarter and
kinder all at the same time. Um,
and I'd also say
that he wrote another book right
afterwards.
He called it the eighth. And you
said the eighth habit.
Cause he ends the book with this
idea of sharpening, the
saw investing in yourself. And
we talk about always
be learning, but like doing it
in a compounding way.
Um, but he said there was an
eighth habit and the eighth
habit is elevating others voices
Bekah: Hmm.
Ray: and helping them, uh, Find
their strengths and
contribute to the world. Um, and
you know, rather
than ending with the idea of
self-improvement ending with the
idea of improvement of others.
Um, and I think those in
combination, at least so far for
me right now, you know,
outside of say religious texts
um, have been the, the, the
most meaningful and immediately
helpful, um, guides, right.
To trying to, uh, be a better
person.
Dan: Oh, I love that idea. That,
and I feel like that's
part of, I hope, I hope I was
part of the Virtual Coffee, you
know, way as well, you know, as
a community, you know, doing
that for each other, um, you
know, help fill out raising.
Elevating their voices and
everything.
Um, I think that, um, yeah, I
dunno.
I was going to say, I think
that, I think that's
a great way to wrap up. I, you
know, that, that
idea of, of, of helping, uh,
helping each other, um,
together, you know, and. Did you
say that it was
a whole second book? Like he
followed that
up an entire book with the
eighth habit?
Is that what you said? I'm
sorry. That's cool too.
I'm I'm definitely. I go, I'm
going to, now that
we've, we've mentioned about
four or five non-fiction books
that I'm going to be putting on
my, on my, uh, to read shelf.
Bekah: I just want to say,
right. Thanks so much for not
only
being here and talking to us on
the podcast so we can
share this with everyone else,
but for everything that you
do in Virtual Coffee and for
everyone that you support
there, we really appreciate it.
And, um, we're very happy
to have you on here sharing.
Ray: It's a delight and I'm
grateful to both be here
and to be in the community.
Dan: All right. Well, we'll talk
to you later, Ray! Thank you.
Bekah: Bye. Thank you for
listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
Ott and Bekah Hawrot
Weigel and edited by Dan Ott. If
you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO,
or you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee's been up to on
our website at virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure
to leave us a review. Thanks for
listening.
And we'll see you next week.