Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode seven of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you. Here with me today, is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah! Today we're
joined by Mike Rogers. Mike is a
Ruby developer from the UK. And
if you're a Virtual Coffee
member
(and if you're not, you should
join), you've probably seen his
chatbots at work everyday in the
Virtual Coffee slack. Uh, which
we very much love and
appreciate. We had a really
great time
talking with Mike. Mike has had
a long and successful career.
But
at one point he realized he no
longer felt good or satisfied
with where he was as a
developer. He shared with us
what he did to
change course and how he has
learned to approach tending his
career. Almost like a garden.
Mike has a lot of insights and
we
had a blast talking to him. I
know you're going to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do in a
random check-in question.
Today's
question is you can have an
unlimited supply of one thing
for
the rest of your life, what is
it? We hope you enjoy this
episode. Hi, I'm Bekah. I'm a
front end developer from a small
town in Ohio. And if I could
have an unlimited supply of one
thing,
I'm, I'm going to say energy.
Cause I feel like there's not,
not like power for my lights,
but like for me personally,
Dan: Um, hi, I'm Dan I'm a front
end developer from Cleveland,
Ohio, and yeah. Uh, rest was the
first thing that popped into my
head. Um, I, uh, you know, I
don't know. I was just telling
Bekah before we recorded, I had
my two year old woke up maybe
four or five times in the middle
of the night, last night. Um,
and, um, just to, I just don't
have time. I don't know how time
would work. Like that was my
going to be my other answer, but
like, that doesn't...super make
sense. I don't mean
Bekah: dangerous. You're messing
with the space time continuum.
And I
Dan: I'm all right with that
though. I'm all right. Being a
time variant, you know?
Bekah: wow.
Dan: Well, like it's like almost
like a Time Turner or something,
right. Or like that, the pause
time thing. We've, we've, we've
talked about that. I feel like
before it's, it's come up a few
times. Um, but yeah, so I'm, I'm
going to stick with the rest
though, you know, um, our
energy, I suppose it's almost
the same
thing, right?
Mike: Sounds like you kind of
this pitch red bull that if I'm
honest.
Dan: Yeah, well, that's right.
Yeah. It's a slippery slope
Bekah: what we want.
Dan: But I I'm, I'm going with
rest that's that's my official
name.
Mike: Okay. well, I'm Mike
Rogers I'm a Ruby developer
originally
from the United Kingdom. I
currently live in the United
States, which is quite exciting
if I had an unlimited supply of
something, I want to say
enthusiasm. Um, because
sometimes
I go through those little down
bits where I'm like, I can't be
bothered to code and I just wish
I could turn on something and be
like, no, now I really want to
code again. This is great. Or
get
something done. That'd be me.
Dan: I liked that I was almost
going to say, like, you're just
wishing for something that you
already have, but, uh, that,
that
explanation
Mike: I want more of the thing I
already have, please.
Bekah: Mike is one of the most
enthusiastic members of Virtual
Coffee. If you are ever in a
room with him and you are
feeling
down, I don't think it's
possible to leave that room
without
feeling happy. So I hope that
you get that from this episode
too.
Mike: Always throws me off when
people say that, because
everyone
says that and I'm like,
seriously, I'm just being
myself.
Like, what do I do to people?
Bekah: It's the best you have.
You have the, the energy. So, I
guess my answer is just more
Mike Rogers in my
Dan: There you go. We just need
an unlimited supply of Mike and
we'll, we'll be in good shape.
Bekah: So we're so excited to
have you here with us on the
podcast. Thank you for being
here. And we always like to get
started with the origin story.
So tell us how you got to this
point
in your life.
Mike: say I was really dreading
this because my story is so
vanilla that I was going through
my notes and I was like, I don't
think it could be any more
boring. It was a very typical
entry in to tech. Well, I was
building websites when I was
like
little, like when I was like 12,
14, just in Dreamweaver. If you
remember that. Oh, tool from
Adobe. Oh, I loved it. I good.
And then I'd be like go to like
school and I'll show my friends
and then we'd all like start
building websites and have them
online for free. And then very
quickly I was like, Oh, I really
enjoyed this. This is really
fun. Then I went to university
and I
had some identity CS degree, but
very focused on web. And that
was, that was great fun. And
then I just ended up kind of
getting a
job, like vaguely and what I
wanted to do, like someone told
me Ruby on Rails is like quite a
fun framework. And I was like,
yeah. it does look fun. I done
some PHP, but then yeah, I think
did Ruby and it was like, oh, I
like this. This is, this is a
pretty language. So I was like,
I like you have an ice cream
Bekah: Okay.
Mike: be the best way to
describe my reaction to that.
And then,
um, to kind of fast forward to
how I got to where I am now, I
had like a few years where,
like, I was kind of quite happy
just
traveling around like the
world's kind of freelancing and
doing a
bit of work. And more recently,
like I wanted to kind of get a
bit more stability in my life
and then have like a full-time
job
where it's like, oh, I actually
get paychecks every month for
like, doing work as opposed to
not getting paid sometimes as a
freelancer, which is very scary.
Um,
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: that's rough.
Mike: That's pretty much
Bekah: So were you a digital
nomad or.
Mike: Um, that was what I was
going for for like so long. I
really enjoyed, it was like the
best few years like all my life.
I was just like, I was just
jumping between like major
cities, but like, I find the
best in that I find amazing
coworking
spaces and I'd just work and I'd
have such a good time. Um, I'm
also a quite anti-authority
person, so it's quite nice kind
of going against the grain and
finding people who are similar
to
that. So I also got featured on
a magazine as well. I think he
may
have seen the picture where I'm
just kind of sitting outside on
my laptop, just like working in
some of his like, ah, cool. I'm
going to right now to go about
you and I'm like, do it. And
Yeah. then she did,
Bekah: It's like at a top of a
very high place. And Mike is
sitting there with it.
Mike: Yeah. There was some other
shots as well. I also had a dog
with me at the time.
Bekah: Were there. Did you have
favorite places that you like to
work from or was your goal just
to go as many places as
possible?
Mike: So originally my goal was
to go see all these places like,
which I'd read about in
magazines, but very quickly I
realized the places I wanted to
go as a tourist, was different
to
where I want it to go to like
live for like a few months. So
my
favorite places, like kind of in
no particular order Berlin, like
the city in Germany, um, there's
some really nice like meetup
groups there where they're so
friendly and I'm still friends
with the people I met in those
meetup groups. One of them
tweeted me yesterday saying we
miss Mike. And I was like, oh,
That's wild. And then, um,
Prague as well, I went to a
wonderful
coworking space there. It was.
The owner was an American guy
and
he's just like, I just wanted to
make friends. So I started a
co-working space and I was like,
I like, I liked this guy's same
mindset. And then, um, I tons of
actual, like crazy places. I
really enjoy Japan. Like it's a
bit more tricky to work there.
Like I guess working remotely.
Isn't, wasn't a thing when I was
there, but I've really enjoyed
just kind of this, the Japanness
of everything.
Bekah: So where you just were
the, were you working consistent
contracts that just kind of
allowed you to go to these
different places? Or were you
trying to pick up contracts as
you're moving? That just sounds
like a lot of logistics, like,
well, I need work and I need a
place to stay any place that has
internet, you know?
Mike: Oh, luckily I was young
and happy to wing it. Um, every
time.
It was bad. In hindsight, I
think I was like a little bit
crazy. I
didn't even have like any money
at the time, but like to cover
like places to live. I would
like do pet sitting where people
would
go on holiday and that normally
I just feel so by who has the
fastest internet. And then I
just go to that person's house.
That
worked really well. Um, and then
to actually find work, I had a
few like startups, I kind of
knew about who needed work every
now
and again. And they would kind
of keep me going here and there.
And
then sometimes I'd have to like,
do some really terrible
freelance
work, which I hated doing where
it was like the stressful kind
of
you, you wouldn't pick this
project unless you were like
really styling kind of freelance
work. Um, I always had this
dream
and it was this, the worst
dream, like kind of go out with,
uh, I
was like, I'd have enough energy
to make my own startup. And I
could be the guy who's just like
sitting on a beach and ending
like that passive income. And
every time I tried, I never
quite
like finish any of the projects.
I had lots of fun.
Bekah: Yeah, that sounds
awesome. And really exciting.
And so.
Mike: to live.
Bekah: You went from being a
digital nomad to kind of
deciding
that you needed something more
stable and that, ahead. Talk
about that a little bit.
Mike: Yeah. So I started hitting
this problem and it was so it's
such an uncomfortable thing to
talk about, but when you're
freelancing, you generally are
going to stick to what you're
really good at. So with me, it
was like, okay, I'm really good
at this very small particular
thing. That's where I know I'm
definitely going to get. And I
kept doing that and doing that.
And I just felt like I wasn't
really making any progress in my
career. Like I'd hit like a, a
wall where the next place to go
was no, as like some kind of kid
who just turns up with his
laptop
every now and again. And I got
super sad because I talked to my
friends who. Work together in a
company like many years ago and
I
chat to them and then we'd be
comparing our salaries because,
you know, that's such a good
thing to do. And I was I'd come
back. And I was like, I thought
I was doing really well, but now
one of my friends is earning
twice as much as me. And he
seems
so much more like stable in his
life. And he's where everything
kind of a bit more like just,
just a couple of his like Eggs
in
a row. Is it egg ducks in a row?
That's the one not exited,
right.
That would be horrific.
Dan: eggs eggs in a basket ducks
in a row
Mike: Yeah,
Bekah: Lux have
Mike: the one.
Bekah: can be in the row with
them.
Mike: And I started kind of
thinking, right. I really need
to
solve this because if I don't
push myself, I'm going to be
that
person. And I met a few of these
were traveling where I would
chat
to them. And I just was like,
what are you doing? Like you're,
as soon as like, maybe your
technology goes, you don't have
anything to fall back on to. So
you could just wake up one day
completely unemployed and you'll
have to scramble to get work and
you don't have too much more.
And yeah, so I really. Really
struggled. So I thought the
first best thing to do is maybe
come
back to the UK, settle down a
little bit, or try and find
something a bit more stable,
which was, uh, an exciting
adventure as well. Like I
managed to find some pretty, uh,
pretty
fun startup to work for, which
was very relaxing. And, uh, they
kind of were able to change me a
little bit more. And I've really
got out of my like little quiet
shell of like, Okay. I can do
some little bits of rails, but
now. They're forcing me to kind
of learn all these other things
like server administration, how
to optimize databases, how to
really be fantastic at like
front
end. And that was, that was
quite a fun one to, uh, to
chase.
Dan: Was that a I'm sorry. I was
just going to say, was that, was
that still a contracting at that
point? Or was that like a
Mike: Oh, that was like a
full-time role. That was wild.
Um, that was like my first
full-time job. And like, I want
to say it was like three or four
years at the time. And, uh,
yeah,
it was so weird. Like every day
it's like, oh, cool. I have a
job
to go to. This is great. Um,
compared to where I'd ended up
and it was so fun, like kind of
looking back on the, kind of the
projects I had been doing, like
there's like a certain trait to
projects where they can only
hire people for like a short
amount of
time. I'm sure you everyone has
like, kind of encountered this
where if they can only have a
developer for like three. Months
in a year, they're going to
really cram in what they have to
do, and they're going to triple
it really hard to get stuff
done.
And very quickly projects become
awful to work on, like where
it's
like, instead of like a nice
logically laid out CSS file.
It's
going to be like all over the
show, possibly even one big like
cluster spaghetti mess. And so I
try, I'm very, very careful not
to make you put an explicit tag
on this podcast as the heads-up.
Dan: Yeah.
Mike: then Yeah. also some of
the products were so old. Um,
and
then being able to kind of work
in a company and be like, Hey,
if
we put some time into this, we
can, we can be way happier. And
like three weeks time, can we do
that? And then they're like,
Yeah. which was quite nice.
Bekah: So I want to back up for
a second here. So you talked
about
Mike: I've like, run through
quite quickly. I'm like,
Bekah: no, no, this is great.
Um, This, you started to feel
this
sense of there's a lack of
stability, starting to feel
stagnant, where you are. So at
what point did that happen? And
like, was it that conversation
about salary that really helped
you to understand that? Or how
did you recognize that?
Mike: It was a really difficult
thing to actually recognize. So
the conversation about like
salaries was the starting point
of like, getting that ball going
of going, oh no, I need to fix
some stuff. So as soon as I
started thinking, Okay. Actually
I've done very similar projects
and I'm not pushing myself
anymore. Like my career is like,
if you were to go look at my
work
history, it's like I was doing
the exact same job over and over
and over, like was on a, on a
treadmill almost. And for a lot
of the jobs, I was like, I can't
even remember doing half of
them.
I can see the paycheck there and
I can see the customer name, but
I couldn't tell you what was
special about that. And that
was,
that was cool. It was quite
jarring as well, like really
strange feeling. And it's like,
huh, am I unhappy? Or what's,
what's causing this unhappiness
because it's, I'm not satisfied
with the work I'm doing and not
sure how to get around it. And I
kind of jumped the Cal ended up
kind of like solving it very
quickly there. But like, as soon
as I started becoming aware that
I needed to start pushing myself
a bit more and the steps I had
to
make as well to correct that.
Was very, very difficult. Um,
but it
paid off quite quickly. Um, and
I'd love to go into some of the
things I started doing as well.
Would that be Okay.
Bekah: Oh yeah,
Mike: cause it, it wasn't like I
got depressed and then I got a
job. That was a lot of the
middle. It was like,
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. I
think, you know, once you
recognize, start to recognize
these things, like you said, it
wasn't easy. There was a. You
know, a variety of things that
had to happen. And so
recognizing is step one and then
really
diving into that middle part, I
think is important because we
often get the stories of, well,
then I decided I made this
decision and then everybody fast
forward through all of the hard
parts of things. So I would love
to hear
Mike: Yeah. Let's jump into the
hard part. So I want to say
like,
The lowest point I had was I
remember the sitting in bed one
morning and I woke up and I was
like, I don't even want to put
my
feet on the floor. I'm so
miserable and unhappy with just
the state of things. It's a
really weird feeling to be like,
oh, I'm earning quite good money
doing something. I think I quite
like, but I don't even want to
like, literally roll, put my
feet
on the, and press the power
button on my computer this
morning. Like that is too much.
that was definitely a morning. I
remember the morning really
distinctly, whereas it's like,
oh, this is, this could go
downhill really fast. And I was
even thinking, do I want to
leave tech because do I enjoy
programming for fun and actually
getting paid for it. is the
issue. And, Um, then I remember
actually I really like the
money.
That's that's, that's definitely
a good motivator. So I was like,
it's probably not that. And I
quickly made a list of all the
things I wanted to be. Very soon
on it in the future, I was like,
well, what are, what is some
small bit of all the people I
follow online or really like,
what's something small they've
done, which I really want to
copy. So one was I follow a
developer who he contributes a
lot to open source and I was
like, okay. well, I don't have
to contribute a lot. I can just
maybe contribute just a little
bit and have my little piece
there. And then I started
watching YouTube tutorials a
little bit. And there's a
particular guy that's into Chris
Oliver. I always really liked
his style where he just does a
quick
10 minute video every now and
again. And I was like, Okay. I
really like that. then the final
thing, I was like, well, all of
a
sudden. I also want to make sure
I write down the things I know
just in case I get really bored
and no one finds my videos and
then we'll find some way
principles work. So at least
maybe some of them I can at
least solve someone's problem.
If I
don't stick on with this depth
stuff. So I started like
blogging
again, and you can see it in my
blog post, by the way, you can
see like the dips as like, when
I was taking breaks and then
suddenly, like I started doing
stuff again, and then it like
quietens down a bit while I have
a job. And then it's like, ah, I
have to take it back off again.
Now I want to like do more
stuff.
But that was, that was kind of
the main things I was doing. So
I
made this list and I started
working through the list. And as
I started working through, I
started talking to my friends
about this and turns out they
were all in the same scenario
where they were all like, not
quite satisfied and they're all
working. On the little things to
try and like boost their careers
and get to that next level where
they can just do interesting,
challenging work, where they're
gonna get paid pretty well. And
I
have a really good friend called
Tom Cadwell and we, we worked
together when we were 20. We
paired every day and then we
both
went our separate ways. And then
we've texted like pretty much
once a week about what we're
doing. And. He's like, he's like
me to other how people would
describe me to other people. And
I'm like, really, Jerry he's
that for me? And it's like,
cool,
cool, nice. And we have like a
bet between us, like dollar bets
for like, who's going to get the
most followers on certain things
or he's going to get the most
views. And that was really
brilliant. Up. It's like, well,
helped me kind of keep sticking
with the things I was doing. So
like, I think Right. now we have
a bet for, who's gonna have the
base of YouTube followers by the
end of the year and he's
winning. So I really want to
work hard to
fix that. Um, but so once I kind
of side working through this
anyway, and felt more confident
to apply for those harder jobs
where maybe I might actually be
challenged a bit during the day.
And cause it's, I hate applying
for jobs. It's like the worst
experience. If you it's like,
it's almost like dating apps
where it's like, you're going to
be rejected thousands of times
and that's gonna like destroy
you, but it could be that one
thousands times actually the
perfect person for you. So you
kind of have to stick with it.
So like, I would apply for jobs
and
I'd keep upping the ante each
time and I'm like, Okay. I know
a
few of these things and I'm
going to do everything I can to
do it.
Or. Feel competent about what
I'm applying for. So that worked
quite well. And as I was doing
this, I found the best way to
find out about Joseph was
through local meetups and stuff.
So user
groups, and that was great. Um,
that was like, oh cool. By
meeting all these friends and a
little tip for everyone, um,
meetups are a great way to find
a job. It's like you meet the
people who are going to be
interviewing you beforehand. You
can figure out if they're like
nice people or not. So I highly
recommend that. Yeah. that was
kind of like what I did. And
then
eventually, like, as I was
waiting for you, the stagnation
feeling, I came out the other
side and then I was like, Okay.
I
don't feel stagnant anymore. I'm
being challenged. I'm surrounded
by really smart people. And I
felt like I've really, really
was
going, but I was back on track
where I want it to be like, when
I kind of compared myself to my
friends, I was like, cool. We
were all kind of back on the
same level. Now I managed to
very
quickly level myself up and.
That, that was a great feeling.
And it kinda made me think about
like how your career is kind of
like a garden as well. Um, who
it will be. This metaphor works
where if you kind of like,
forget about your garden and let
it grow
wild. It's going to not be a
great garden and you've got to
sit there and maintain it. And
so you can, you know, plow the
pow
pow, the grass, put it in, but
you also have to like, let it
grow as well organically like,
you can't sit there, poking the
seeds because the seeds will
never grow. You've got to like
water it and maybe brush the
soil. I don't know much about
gardening. Is that really?
Bekah: Yeah, that's a British
method that I am not aware of.
Dan: Sure, sure. Yeah.
Mike: maybe.
Dan: Get the soil brush out.
Mike: Yeah. That's this, put it
down as a British thing.
Dan: Well, it's it's that's
what's the point of the
gardening
pick? You pick that up and none
of Japan, right? I'm pretty sure
that's the Japanese soil brush.
Yeah.
Mike: Yeah. Yeah, yeah. You have
to, you have to be in your
bathroom. I said, well, you're
doing stuff. It's like, it's a
relaxing thing.
Bekah: They do in the bathroom.
Dan: that's a different,
different brush. Um, I, my guy,
I
love this metaphor. I, uh, I
was, um, I was just thinking
about
what you're talking, you know,
and, and yet, and there's a lot
of different, there's a lot of
different things you can do with
a garden. Right. And there's a
lot of different things you can
do, um, with your career, you
know, you could plant a bunch of
different things and kind of
tend them all.
Mike: Yeah.
Dan: maybe like, w were you
doing before? Like as a
freelancer or
something, right,
Mike: Yeah. Or you could focus
on like certain individual
things.
So you feel like, you know what
carrots, that's going to be. My
thing for this month, you can
agree on carrots. Or if you want
to have a big tree, which is
going to take a long time to
grow, where you put the seeds in
and you look after it, maybe you
put some like steaks in to help
it grow straight and strong. And
that's a lot like a career in a
way. And also sometimes you just
need to have people to help you
with things like doing stuff on
your own is hard. Like. It's so
much easier to have help from
other people, especially if
you're doing something big or
heavy, or even just asking
people like, Hey, how, how far
apart
should I plant these like
carrots? It's like, yeah, I
don't
know how far apart you should
put carrots. But when I have
grown
carrots, I put them too close
together and they ended up
bunching together.
Bekah: Oh, yeah. There's lots of
things like that. And even like,
if you think about weeding and
how that applies to sometimes we
pick up bad habits. Right.
Mike: Oh, yes
Bekah: we do need some help,
like taking care of that part of
it or
recognizing that like, oh wait,
that that's not a tomato plant.
That's this weed that looks
similar to a tomato plant, which
I have in my garden right now.
Right. I've got an app to
identify these things now. So
see, I found help. Um, and, and
this applies to, at so many
different stages of the career
too. I love it. Like this idea
of it can be so hard to be
patient
when you are learning something
new, but that idea, like, look,
it doesn't, these things don't
grow overnight. Put tomato
plants
in, in June. And I don't have
tomatoes that are red yet. It
just takes a while and you have
to give it nutrients. You have
to
feed it. And, and then that's
when you collect the, you know,
the things that you've worked so
hard for.
Mike: Yeah. the super nice ones.
That's super good. Yeah. Um, so
I
had something in there and then
it is wished completely out my
brain. It's like, there's no
thought.
Dan: I was going too far in the
metaphor. I was trying to figure
out how to keep, you know, how
do you keep chipmunks and
squirrels
out of your career and kind of,
I don't think I've, I haven't, I
haven't found that.
Mike: I have one good thought
though, it's like, I'm getting
rid of those bad habits as well.
Cause that's the other thing,
which is, I feel keeps so many
people back is like they develop
all these bad things. Problems
in their, like how they approach
problems or like other aspects.
So a good example is let's say
you have a developer who's very
bad at writing commit messages
or
doing pull requests. And if you
were to work with them, that
would probably rub off on you.
And then if you went to another
company, they might look at that
when they're interviewing you
and
be like, no, you're bad at this
one particular thing we really
care about. And I found the best
thing to do is like constantly.
Almost work in public, as much
as you can and ask for constant
feedback or say, I've got this
like little hot tip for anyone
who's kind of senior. Um, and is
kind of in that. position where
they're like, have I picked up
bad habits, pay with junior
devs?
They're like, they're fresh out
of like, uh, like the cancel
that
causes. You can teach them a
lot, but also you can see what
they're
doing differently to you. And
I've been pairing with my
junior.
Uh, they're not a junior
developer, they're just a
developer, but, um, they call
themselves junior and I'm like,
don't call yourself junior. I
digress. Okay. So I've been
pairing with one of my
colleagues and they're
fantastic, and they
do things a bit differently to
me. And I don't want to tell
them
that. I think they're actually
doing it a bit better.
Sometimes,
um, quietly changing a lot of my
habits now because they've
obviously found a more efficient
way because they just entered
the
industry at a different time
where like all these extra
things
I do aren't required anymore.
Like I've just picked up
something from somewhere where
it's like maybe using get
version
control where it's like, the way
I change my branch is. The worst
way possible or how I emerged
that there's like an easy way
now
there's like, and I'm just
completely wishing on it, um,
the
whole time. Um, so Yeah, that's,
that's been one of those little
hot tips, which is like
completely changed and I highly
recommend it's pairing with
anyone and anyone who will help
you
Dan: I think that's great. I
think it's great advice. I
wanted
to call out real quick. Your
piece of advice, right before
that, which was, you know,
working in public, uh, as ways
to
improve your, you know, your own
skills or whatever your habits,
every, all of that. Um, I think
that's huge. And if you, um, I
find myself lots of times I'm
writing code that I know I'm
only
going to see probably, or, you
know, most likely I'm the only
one that's ever going to look at
it lots of times. And I'll find
myself doing that, that same
thing kind of maybe, um, Not
explaining things as well, or
whatever, making commit messages
that don't actually say anything
or all of that writing, writing
issues that are just one line
instead of explaining the actual
process. And as soon as I find
myself working where I know
there's going to be other
people, whether it's work work
or where I
know there's going to be a
couple of people or open-source
stuff,
public stuff where I know like
possibly everybody could see it,
you know, Uh, almost forces you
to do it well, you know? Um, and
if you do it enough, it becomes
like you were saying, I have it,
you know, as opposed to, um, but
it kind of feels like pain. And
I
find myself personally doing
that more, even with my own
stuff,
just because it's like, oh, this
is just how I do write an issue
now, you know?
Mike: You have that feeling. I'm
going to be sitting behind you,
reading it back to you in a
snarky voice. Right? That's
that's what I do for everything
online. Now, every tweet I read,
it's like I do in my snarky
voice. Every time I write when
it's in my snarky voice. And
it's like, ah, this bug's
broken. I
can hint how you reproduce it.
It's like good. Right. There's
all these steps and as soon as
the snarky voice disappears,
it's
like, right. It's a, it's a
good, a good. issue a good pull
request
Dan: that's amazing. That's
amazing. Yeah. Somebody, um, A
Virtual Coffee a while ago.
Actually, I think it started on
the podcast, but, um, somebody,
one of the random questions was,
you know, who would you want to
have narrating your life or your
inner monologue or something
like that. And, um, somebody
mentioned
Alan Rickman and then I couldn't
just like, for the rest of the
day I had Snape like professor
Snape hanging over my head doing
the exact same thing, except in
like his like sarcastic, you
know, slow like, oh, does can't
reproduce the bug, Potter. Like
just like the sneering, you
know, at my like bad commit
messages
Mike: that's one I want Nikki T
to be like the guy Who narrates
my life, because, so I've got
such like a, like a dev crush on
him where it's like, when he
starts like working in public,
it's like, I want to do that.
That's what I want to do. Like
his confidence there is
incredible.
Dan: Yeah.
Mike: You've got me wanting to
do an Alan Rickman impression.
Okay.
Bekah: Okay. Do
Mike: it.
Dan: yes, we need it.
Mike: Ah, on the spot! Good
work, Potter. Shoot the glass. I
don't
think that's very good. Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. Oh man. He's the
best. Yeah. That the idea
though, of
just putting it in public, you
know, even if it's, um, it
doesn't seem like. Yeah. I don't
know. It doesn't like, not meant
for an audience, you know,
you're not like, uh, performing
or
whatever. Uh, I think I still
think it just helps so much. I
think that's great. Great
advice.
Mike: Yeah. And honestly all
it's the little things as well,
because if you're thinking this
is in the public, now you're not
going to do like the little
silly mistakes, like
accidentally
committing SSH keys or
something, or APA keys to
version control.
And then in a few months later,
um, when you decide, I don't
want
to do this project anymore, or
even open source of the project.
You don't find it. You go, oh
no, I have to nuke all the
history.
Um,
Dan: Right. right,
Mike: in case, um, if you look
at it, I've got two projects by
the
way, where I nuked the history,
because I did exactly that. And
I
really regretted that
afterwards. It was like, it was
like two
years of like get version
control history. And I was like,
I just,
just nuked them. Cause I
couldn't remember what was in
there, but I
wish I had done something a bit
better.
Dan: Yeah, who knows? There's
probably ways to handle that,
but
yeah, like, yeah, having that
plan in the back of your head,
maybe this eventually open
source. Yeah. I think, I think
helps helps your instincts kind
of cover that sort of thing.
Yeah, for sure.
Mike: so that one day will say,
like I was working on a project
and my friend texted me, um, my
friend Tom Familia. And he said,
by the way, you're on the front
page of Reddit. And it was on
the
front page of like one of the
small. Four bucks a subreddit.
So
it wasn't like front front page,
but someone had just found my
code base and was just sharing
it and talking about it. And I
was
like, this is wild. It was only,
I think only like 25 people
actually looked at it. Like
maybe write some comments, but
it was
like overall, everyone was
really polite and nice. And I
was like,
I didn't expect that at all. I
always assume people on the
internet, they're going to be
terrible people, but
overwhelmingly, most people are
very nice and I just very happy
to see how other people work.
I'm very happy to see something
shared.
Bekah: I'm, I'm going to back up
a little bit, because I just
wanted to highlight this point
that you see. Um, I've, I've
just
found that there are so many
people who have been developers
for a while who are also failing
like this stagnation that I
think
kind of can lead to burnout.
And, and you, you know, you even
said
like, Uh, this mean that I leave
tech, should I try something
else? And you said, you know, it
was, um, the morning that you
woke up and you're like,
dreaded, hit hitting the power
button.
Right. Like you just felt this
dread. And I think that it's, I
just want to highlight that
because I think that not enough
people recognize like, okay,
this is, this is a bad point.
Like
this is time to evaluate some
things and change some ways. So
do you think. No. How do you
think that you, can you prevent
that from happening? Um, or if
you could go back and do things
differently, is there something
that you would do to avoid that
stagnation?
Mike: Oh, it's, it's a difficult
question. Um, so when I entered
Ruby, there were two really
prominent Rubyists. So Ryan B
and
_why. And they are two
developers who kind of very
famously left
one day and never came back. And
for one of them, we were like,
is
he Okay. What's happened to this
guy. And I want to say there was
an article in the New York times
saying, like what happened to
this person who was like
everywhere? And then one day
just
disappeared. And I think they
turned out to be a manager at
Walmart in the end. And like
someone like track them down,
but
for private investigator and
that always sat in the back of
my head
going Okay. Um, so people do
leave every now and again and
just decide they want to get
away from whatever life they've
just
created, because it's just not
doing it for them. And things I
would do definitely is I wish I
had a bigger support network of
like dev people. Um, back when I
was, when I was like really
peak,
unhappy, I didn't have anyone to
talk to. Like I had like maybe
five other developers I knew,
and I wasn't that close with
them.
And I just wish I could have had
someone to be like, Hey, I'm
feeling this. Has anyone else
felt this? What did they do? And
that wasn't, it's not that it
wasn't a thing. It's just, I
hadn't found it yet. So I almost
want to like encourage everyone
to. Grow that professional
network, you know, that, that
little fish in the garden of the
professional network of people
here, like be like this, there
fee to answer some questions.
And
if you send them a private
message, there'll be like
sympathetic to be like, Okay.
cool. Now I can, I can help you
with this. And if you want to
jump on a call, so we'll go out
for coffee, then that's, that's
something that we'll do. And I
think it's easier now. Like
thanks to the global pandemic.
There's like plays a nice slack
groups and you can pick out your
individual people. You're ready.
You know, make part of your,
like, you know, inner circle of
like people you already trust.
Have you guys heard about the
thing where you only have like a
hundred and full, proper close
friends? Like that theory? Um,
Dan: Yeah, I vaguely, I
definitely am familiar with, you
know, what you're
Mike: Yeah. Like it's some kind
of human thing where you can
only
keep track of so many people
properly. And so if you've only
got like a hundred friends, some
of them are going to be family.
Some of them that'd be like old
school friends maybe. And I
think
you should probably pick like a
few key developers or people in
your field who you really like,
and let's keep them in that
light
we'll circle of a hundred people
who could sit in your phone book
or something.
Dan: I think that's great. I,
uh, having somebody who. Is in
whatever field you're in, you
know, and can understand a lot
of
the context that goes around. I,
you know, a close friend from,
from when you were young, even
somebody who you keep in touch
with, uh, but isn't it a
complete different field. Um,
when always
have the context, you know,
somebody that might be like,
well, you just, you have a good
job that pays well, why are you
unhappy? You know, something
like that. But I think that
your, your
story is going to ring true with
a lot of developers. Um, you
know, the, the, this, the, that
feeling of. Satisfaction.
Mike: there's pinpointed the
exact phrase, which made me
never
want to talk out about being
unhappy and tech as well,
because
we're a really well compensated
field. Like you tell people that
you own, like, this is how much
money you earn. Like starting.
Most people are like, oh, I just
want to do that job. And very
few
people maybe talk about, oh,
actually, There's a very unhappy
side to this where you are
sitting inside all day, typing
at
a keyboard or planning out a
database and it could all go
horribly wrong. And that feeling
is like, well, you could, yeah.
That tiny mistake, you know, is
there could just balloon into a
monster. And if you don't deal
with it, it's going to be
embarrassing. And people will
almost look at your work and
your
work always has your name next
to it as well. That's something
we've done as an industry.
Dan: Forever.
Mike: away from this. Yeah. Like
I've picked up code and I went,
who wrote this? And then I'm
like, oh, it's that guy. Okay.
He
pops up everywhere and it's
like, oh, that's an interesting
one. Or
it's like, oh wait, no, it was
me. I'm the bad guy in, in my
story. Uh, Yeah. And it's, it's
difficult to talk to people
about
this cause it's, we're in a
different world and this is why
I
really like having a few really
close developer friends who are
like, we're all kind of in the
same bubble. We know like how,
how it goes in terms of, Okay.
Yeah. You do have days where you
are just sitting at a computer
screen, looking at a black
terminal. And you'll just say, I
can't figure this out. I have.
And you Google the question and
like one guy, one person on
stack
overflow has asked to, and it's
like no answers. And it's like,
uh, how obscure is this? What am
I doing wrong? Sorry.
Bekah: Or I feel like the worst
is when you get that, but then
they respond to their posts and
they're like, I got it.
Nevermind. I'm like, well, can
Mike: Should I be what you did,
what did you do to solve it? Uh,
but has anyone come back and
found their old posts from when
they Regina to go correct them
or add more information, but
we're
just me.
Bekah: There's no way I would
ever do That
Mike: Aye. Aye.
Bekah: of where I was at that
point in my life. And I'm going
to just go with that.
Mike: I changed my username
online at some point, just to
not
fight any someone, a VC found my
OGs name, um, because I'd
written
a comment like being like nice.
And they're like, wait, hold on.
This is the same writing style
as that person. And that name is
very familiar and they figured
out it was me from like, Well,
yeah, two years ago solving That
problem and they sent me a thank
you. And I'm like, I need to go
back and work for more of these
places. Now it's the, we've got
some good detectives in the
crowd
who he know my old user name.
Dan: That that's pretty funny.
I, I, um, yeah, going back and
that's an interesting idea of
just going back and updating,
answering your own questions,
you know, uh, back in the day,
this
is what I did. I promise. I
wouldn't probably remember, you
know, any of the answers
Mike: Yeah, but you might be
able to figure it out, like go
back
and be like, this is prob this
is what I was asking. I think I
vaguely remember. What that
question could be, or at least
you can put it in the right
place or maybe archive the
question if
you were like, no, this is
garbage. I need to hide this
from
the world or something like
that, but it gets, it comes back
to the
garden again. It's like, you
know, putting up the bits in the
back, which you don't often tend
to, or like getting rid of the
bad information. Maybe if you
put out some old comments,
Dan: Right or change your use
name? Maybe just throw a tarp
Mike: no, they'll, they'll
protest
Dan: somewhere else.
Mike: every few years to start a
fresh this,
Dan: Right? Buy a new plot of
land.
Mike: yeah, I'm going to be Mike
Rodriguez. I think it's the it's
completely changed. My name grow
miss big, big bushy mustache,
like shave my mustache.
Dan: So you. Um, I, I found it
really cool and impressive, uh,
your process for when you sorry
we keep we keep going back to
that moment, but at that moment,
um, where you made that list,
um,
and, you know, found some stuff
that worked for you that wasn't
like, That wasn't like, I know
you started applying for jobs
and
stuff too, but the list of side
things like side projects or, or
other things like that. Um, and
so I guess my question with that
was, um, do, now that you were
in, um, maybe a more stable
situation, you know, how have
you found yourself? And I think
the
answer is yes, but like, have
you found yourself keeping up
with
those things that you did mostly
to get yourself moving again?
You
know, and, um, and I was
wondering if you could talk a
little bit about that.
Mike: absolutely. So this is, I
guess the other part of this,
where. When you're searching for
a job or trying to make a big
change, it's really easy to like
go out, like again, back to the
garden. Like, you know, when you
want to make it pretty, it's
like, it's easy to put the
effort in for a few weeks and
then
you've got a pretty garden, but
actually you need to maintain it
over a long period of time and
you can't go in with like
absolute, full force, full time
to make that garden pretty. You
have to do like come up with a
reason. So I've, I mean, I'm
still really bad at keeping up
to date with like keeping things
going out. But what I do is I
set myself a goal of like one
post a
month, one video a month. So,
which I think is very
achievable.
It's not, not too much work.
It's a very steady flow. And I
just
say, right, that's what I'm
going to aim for. It's I'm going
to
keep putting things out and
that's going to be what I do
like, and I've managed to do
that pretty well. So. And even
if it's
not like a really well thought
out thing, like if I've got
something on my mind, I just
want to write about it, or I
want to
make a video on something. Cause
I know I've seen people
struggling. It will happen. And
then also on the lists as well,
I
am the worst and the best. And
the greatest. There you go. I'm
the greatest for making lists,
sorry. I'm not the worst. I'm
the
best. Sorry. Completely wrong
time. I love making lists. Lists
are like I've got, I use the
Reminders app in apple where you
can have lots of little lists
broken out to categories. And I
have, I always go through them.
Curate them as well. So at the
end of the month, I remove
stuff, which actually I'm not
that
interested in doing anymore. And
then throughout the month they
keep adding stuff in. So I've
got a big list of blog posts. I
want
to write. I've got the titles
done and I've got like a link to
where I think I could take them.
Same with videos. Same with like
little things I need to do. Um,
And that has that's helped a
lot.
I, I realized I'm a very list
oriented person. Like I think
it's agile methodologies have
like ruined me. I was like
working in like, you know,
having a startup every morning.
I almost
like if I had a pet cat, me and
the cat would have a start up
every morning about what we're
going to achieve that day. And
I'll do the voice of the cat,
obviously. Um, you guys won't
know the accent. I give it, but
every day it would be slightly
different. Like I'm just
imagining that the cat is
snarky.
Uh, you can, you're gonna write
a blog post. You did that nice
one.
Bekah: I would like a whole
series of that.
Dan: Yeah. That's uh, the new,
the new Mike Rogers video series
is conversations with the cat.
We just need to, we just need to
get
you a cat first and then
Mike: It could happen soon
enough. That's there's some
floating around outside. Maybe
others feed some.
Dan: yeah. I mean, that's true.
Cats'll, cats'll learning. If
you
start feeding them, they'll
they'll learn my, um, Emily's my
wife's grandma. Uh, feeds cats
in our yard to cause they killed
the
chipmunks and squirrels, you
know, it's because she wants
them
to come, but they'll come like
they'll, they'll learn here.
They'll learn your routine and
stuff. So he could just have a
little stand up with the cat
under stoop, you know, every,
every morning I would watch
that.
Mike: I, yeah, I think we just
hit my new video series. Right.
It's like, this is what we're
going to do today. Cut. Like,
almost like, was it pinky in the
brain? What are you going to do
today? Pinky or brain. Oh, I'm
going to take over the world.
Yeah.
Bekah: but by Joe. So, you know,
one of the things like talking
through all of them, Has been
really fascinating. And I'm like
amazed by how many people that
I've talked to that have talked
about how much they love their
job. And then suddenly realized
that they hate their job. Like.
Mike: I'm suspicious of people
who say they love, love their
job
on the site. I don't think you
do. I think you're just saying
that,
Bekah: I think it's a lot of
times like putting your hand in
warm water and then slowly
boiling boiling it or frog, I
guess you don't
Mike: Yeah. That's I know the
Bekah: it with a frog either,
but
Mike: Yeah.
Bekah: You increase it, the
temperature and don't realize it
because it's just like this
slow, um, process until like
suddenly
you're boiling. And then I think
at that point you're like, oh,
Maybe, maybe I don't love this.
Maybe I did love this at one
point, but all of these things
are keep changing and I just
missed it or kept thinking that
it will get better and it just
keeps getting worse, you know?
And then we don't talk about
that
kind of stuff enough. And I
think part of it, like you said,
we
make a lot of money in tech and
you can make a lot of money and
not be happy. It's okay. To not
love to code, but there's a
difference between not loving to
code and really being unhappy
because it bleeds out into all
the other aspects of your life.
Mike: Exactly. Like if, Yeah. I
feel like unhappy at work and
you
can't quite identify, like
what's what the cause is. Or
like you're
unhappy outside of work and
you've got to bring it in. Like
it just kind of, it slows you
down in the other places and
you've got to like really. Find
the good bits. And this is why
I'm also suspicious of people
who say they've really loved
their
job. Um, sorry. I'm like, like
mumbling next to it. So I'm
like,
we aren't allowed to say we
don't like our job. It's none of
that.
It's like, no, she don't tell
people. You hate certain things
about work. It's never going to
change. You've got to like,
you've got to almost go out to
your manager or be the, be the
change you want to see in the
office. So if you want to. Do
certain processes to stop doing
them and then see if anyone will
fight you on like, not doing
them and to see what happens
like
worst case scenario. You have a
fun argument with someone and
you'll be able to find out the
benefits of something or maybe
not right.
Dan: I love it. I, this actually
that goes right into a question
I
was going to ask was, um, you
mentioned when you were talking
about, um, So your freelancing
experience, you know, before,
and
it's sort of, you said it as an
aside, but you said he sometimes
have problems with authority
and, you know, it had been one
of the
reasons why you had stuck with
the freelancing for so long.
And,
um, I was, my question was
basically just like I was
wondering you now we're working
for sort of a larger
organization. I was just
wondering, um, how that is. You
know, vis-a-vis like authority
and having bosses and, and
probably different tiers of
managers, but I'm not really
sure, but you know, that sort of
thing. I was wondering if, uh,
if
that has
Mike: It's so
Dan: any effect on you.
Mike: It's so different. I find
it almost comical every time I
have to like fill out some kind
of form and I always make sure,
like, I tell people that this is
a stupid form or like, Hey, this
is a waste of time. Like we've
just spent like three hours
planning for something like.
Yeah, well, it surprises me. So
the companies you have meetings
about when you're going to have
a
meeting about something more
frequently than you expect,
like,
I feel like when I was a
freelancer, that was like, they
would never bring a freelancer
into that kind of eating that is
like, this is what we're going
to get the freelancer to do.
Cool.
All right. We'll just give them
the work or give them the work
even. Um, yeah, I'm still. Still
terrible with authority figures
where it's like someone tells me
to do something and I'm just
like, come on, you're going to
do it. If I want to do it, that,
manage that to figure out how
you're going to motivate me to
do
this
Dan: I love that. I I, I,
Mike: send money.
Dan: yeah, I've been a
freelancer, you know, my whole
career and that's that. Um, one
of the reasons why I've almost
never really, I mean, there's
only been a couple of times
where
I've really considered, you
know, switching, uh, to say some
sort
of full-time job that the, um, I
think about the meetings and
especially if being a freelance
or not being in those meetings
is
actually like, can be really
frustrating too. Um, I found,
you
know, the, somebody just gives
you the work, but you don't have
any connection to. The inception
of the work, you know, or like
probably you might actually have
a better idea then there's, you
know, uh, I feel like that's
maybe a, a pro for getting more
involved in a, in a company, you
know, at, at a high level kind
of
thing.
Mike: Yeah. I think I've
definitely had work come in
around. I'm like, why don't we
just do the simple way? And then
I reply back and then they're
like, oh, we didn't know about
that. I mean, this had like, we
just wasted hours planning this
workout for you. And it's like,
cool. So we'll just do the easy
way then. Nice cool and those
still get paid like the same
amount. Cause that was going to
take weeks. Um,
Bekah: Uh, it should be like a
bonus for those situations.
Mike: Uh, it's, that's not how
freelancing ever has worked.
Dan: Yeah, no, that's not. Yeah,
that's it. I mean, the bonus is
that they trust you more and
they keeping paying for your
work. I
mean, that's, that's like,
that's the bonus, I suppose, as
a
freelancer, you know? Um, but
also personally, Doing things
that are stupid too. Like I've
never been, I've never been, I
know some people where, you
know, you get that same thing.
You're
like, I know that there's an
easy way to do this. That would
take
me an hour. And the way they've
asked me will take two weeks or
something, you know? And, uh, I
could just let it ride, you
know,
but I would be miserable for
those two weeks, you know? And
I'm like, let's just do the easy
way. That'd be, that'd be fine.
That'd be
Mike: Yeah, this is, this is why
I always, I think this is also
one of the things which has made
me a happier person. I always
like kind of pushing back on
everything where I can, or at
least trying to be a bit yeah.
Like confrontational, because
other you're going to be doing
that miserable work all day. And
it's like, there's no point
during the miserable work. Cause
like, it's just going to get
deleted the week after when
someone decides they want to do
it the easy way. And you just
kind of wasting your time and
your time is so precious. Like
I'm not sure. That anyone
listening to this, but like, I
I'm, I'm I feel young Right.
now, but I'm also scared that
soon I'm
going to wake up and be this
like crazy. Like my life's gone
of
like the best years have passed
or something. And I don't want
to
spend it like trying to solve
some stupid problem. Like when
there's an easy way to do it, I
to, I want to be out playing
golf
or like doing something more
interesting.
Dan: Tending tending your
garden, right?
Mike: Tending to my garden.
Yeah. that was,
Bekah: Brushing his garden.
Dan: Brushing the soil.
Mike: but yeah. Thinking about
that now, I think I'm in raking
the soils.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. That's that's
Mike: that was a hundred
percent.
Dan: That makes sense.
Mike: It took me 20 minutes to
figure That out. I'm glad we had
a meeting about that.
Dan: right? Yeah. Oh man. It's
amazing. I still do love that
metaphor though. I'm going to be
thinking about it.
Mike: I'm I feel like I want to
get like, like have you seen
when
people have like live loss live
or life, so throw those out
because those are terrible, but
change it if like, you know,
garden your career or your
career is a garden and brush it.
Dan: Okay. Brush that dirt.
Bekah: I think we have a code of
conduct. Okay.
Dan: I
Mike: Like Icarus right now.
It's like 10.
Dan: Oh man. That's amazing.
Mike: Okay.
Dan: Yeah, I'm going to make
that sign for sure. I can't,
every
Bekah: That's going to be a
sticker. We need
Dan: tell him, don't tell me,
don't tell me what to do. Sign.
Mike: My manager, but not, I
don't listen to you so like you
might manage it, but I'm
ignoring you because you're
wrong.
Bekah: Okay.
Mike: in management. You're not
a developer. Sorry.
Bekah: hot takes.
Mike: Spicy.
Dan: Well, you, you had that
lot. What was it? Uh, oh, good
luck.
Good luck managing me or
Bekah: Okay.
Dan: good luck motivated me to
do that.
Mike: Yes. That is what I want
on my laptop.
Bekah: Like, I, I we're like
almost at time and I really want
to dive into that idea of
motivation a little bit more
because something that I've been
interested in, and you're
talking
about this competition that you
have with your friend. And so,
like, obviously that's a good
motivator, but I think, I, I
don't know if we have time to
talk about this. So maybe just
some, a
Mike: should've been so quick.
Bekah: On how to motivate people
and keep them from stagnation.
Right? Cause that's part of it.
Mike: Yeah. So I've got like
one, one quick tick and it's
like, so
I have a podcast. I listen to
where. It's like a meditation
podcast and that has been so
wonderful. Um, I talk about it
in
VC, quite a lot of things called
meditation minis. They're 10
minutes. They come out like once
a week and they are just a
wonderful way of just like
before bed. I sit down and I was
very
skeptical when I first tried it,
but something about the sitting
down, down and relaxing for 10
minutes before bed has helped me
enormously. I think there's
getting a better night's sleep
and having good sleep hygiene as
well. So I feel better, like I
don't work till like three in
the morning or four in the
morning
and wake up at 7 AM and then
like rec my, uh, rec my sleep.
Which has been good. And I also
really recommend everyone. If
you're not feeling great, talk
to a therapist, it's like, it's
super easy. Now. There's like,
there's apps to do it. It's
like,
you don't have to kind of go to
a place and tap them in person.
You
could talk to someone this via
WhatsApp, and then they'll just
do the things and then you'll
be, you might feel better. Yeah.
The
reason. I also say therapist, as
well as when someone explained
the concept of therapy, I was
like, that sounds, that sounds
weird. But then they're like,
they said to me, okay, so your
parents, no one told them how to
raise you. They figured it out
and they screwed up everything
probably. So, so a therapist is
like, they iron out the bits,
your parents, like didn't like
give you the tools to like solve
in life. So like how to deal
with
like, being really unhappy or
they'll give you some techniques
to deal with it. Or if you're
feeling anxious, they.
Approaches, which no one tells
you about until you pay them the
money. And it's like a hundred
bucks and they'll pay, Okay.
Here
is the secret to like getting
rid of anxiety. If you're
feeling
anxious about something. And
then also, Yeah. a bit of
healthy
competition. Like I always, I
love to show off and like, I
love
to be competitive with my
friends. So like we always send
each other what we're up to and
try and get feedback. And
sometimes we are brutally honest
with each other saying, this is
a
terrible idea. You're going to
waste all your money here. And
then other times it's like,
they're like, no, this is an
interesting idea. You should,
you should give it a go. Um, a
really
good example of me being
completely wrong. Um, one of my
friends showed me this app ID
had where it was people watching
YouTube videos together, and
this was pre pandemic. And, you
know,
being able to write notes around
them and then have a bit of a
conversation afterwards. And I
was like, That's. a stupid idea.
That'll never take off.
Bekah: Okay.
Mike: Um, I found a app
recently, which had raised tons
of money to
do just that. And it was a
really good app. And I was like,
we were
watching, I think it was a Sandy
med store together with a bunch
of other developers. And I was
like, this is perfect. This is
what I like. And I really regret
not like encouraging my friend
now because really regret it
because he couldn't get a
millionaire. I think.
Dan: That's. Yeah, that's one of
those weird things that like the
pandemic, I feel like, uh, it,
it doesn't sound like a good
idea.
It didn't sound like a good idea
to me either that, that sort of
thing. Cause you know, and then,
well now we can't actually be in
the same room together. So, so
like,
Mike: perfect. I love it. I hate
being in the same room as
people,
Dan: yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
Mike: No, I'm just kidding.
Bekah: has been.
Mike: Yeah. It's been fantastic
Bekah: Really good podcast
episode. So thank you
Mike: to wrap up before I talk
for another two hours and we
ended up having some mega
session and it's like, the list
is like,
I think maybe we'll save like
another topic for another
podcast
season or something. I hope. Um,
yeah, if I could go out and like
one final thing Is Yeah,
obviously we talked about, if
you're feeling like stagnant in
your career, just talk, talk to
people, even if it's a private
one, you will feel better for
that. And we've all gone through
this. We all feel sad. So this
just talk, it's tell people, ask
for help. You'll feel better for
it.
Bekah: absolutely. That's a
great, great piece of advice to
end that.
Mike: my DMS are normally open,
so happy to chat to people.
Bekah: All right. Thanks, Mike.
We'll talk to
Mike: Thank
Dan: Thank you, Mike.
Bekah: Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel and edited by Dan
Ott. If you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO, or
you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, plus you
can sign up for our newsletter
to
find out what Virtual Coffee's
been up to on our website at
virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a
review. Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.