Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode eight of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you here with me today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we sat
down with Aurelie Verrot.
Aurelie
is a software engineer
originally from France, but who
now lives in
the San Francisco bay area. Like
many of us Aurelie has been
working from home since the
pandemic started. And she shared
with us, some of her
experiences, uh, going through
all that as
well as some important
approaches and habits, uh, that
allow us to
be healthy and productive.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's
question is if you could be one
kind of plant, what would it be?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Hi, I'm Bekah. I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could be any kind
of plant, I would be, I really
want to say like Sequoia because
they're really tall and cool,
but I've never seen one in real
life.
An aloe plant seems useful cause
they're healing, but like air
plants are really resilient and
they're tiny and you don't have
to do that much to take care of
it. And that, that also seems
good.
Dan: What was that? What kind of
plant is that
Bekah: An air plant.
Dan: Air plant?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: So like from a video game
or something,
Bekah: No, it's not from a video
game. It's like a real thing.
Dan: you know, aloe plants are
only healing. If you break off
the, you know, you have to
destroy the destroy, the plants,
get them, although that's a
whole different. Um, hi, I'm
Dan. I am
a front end developer from
Cleveland, Ohio. Um, if I could
be any kind of plant, I think
like, uh, like a maple tree or
something would be cool. Um, I
was really trying to think of
all
the other kinds of plants that I
know, and I can only come up
with
like three or four off the top
of my head. Uh, wouldn't want to
be
like. Yeah, I think just going
to go with maple tree cause
they're
cool. And like, plus it's on a,
that's on a whole country's
flag,
you know, so that's cool too. So
that's going to be my
Bekah: So it'd
Dan: answer.
Bekah: like, oh,
Dan: That's right.
Bekah: the flag. It's not
Dan: Exactly.
Bekah: is me.
Aurelie: Hi, my name is I am
from the San Francisco bay area
and I
am a software engineer. And, um,
if I I think I would be some
kind
of lavender. I lived
Dan: That's a good one.
Aurelie: south of France for a
while, and I had like fields of
lavender everywhere. It's just
my favorite plant, I guess.
Dan: That's a good one. I like
that one.Lavender pretty and
like, and useful, you know,
that's, that's good. It's a good
combo.
Bekah: I have three lavender
plants in my front yard for the
first time. It did not die. So I
am very excited about it. Um, so
welcome. We are very,
Dan: Good.
Bekah: to have you here on the
podcast today. Um, and we always
like to start off the podcast
with your origin story. So how
did you get to where you are as
a software developer? Okay.
Aurelie: Yeah. So, um, I'm a
recent career changer. Um, so
before I was in quality safety
and then very much management,
in
France. I moved in the US in
2015 and I couldn't work. Uh,
because
of my visa. And so I took the
time to raise my kids and make
sure the family was fully
integrating new environment, um,
when I've been able to work. Um,
one thing I knew for sure that
it
was that I didn't want to pursue
my previous career. So I try
different things. And at some
point, uh, I tried some coding
tutorials. Um, why that mostly
because my husband is an
engineer. And so I go to an easy
go-to I guess. Uh, and I liked
it, uh, but it was like kind of
hard for me to learn by myself.
So at some point I decided to
join a bootcamp. And they did
yeah, two month and a half,
three months bootcamp, and then,
um, a,
an internship for six months.
And then I found my first job
and I
started in May.
Bekah: That's awesome. That
seems like a really fast
journey. How
long did it take you? Um, from
the time you kind of started
Aurelie: I started mid 2019 with
my first. Yeah, my first
tutorials, like just learning
Ruby, running Java script. Um,
but I didn't really know what to
do with that. I mean, it was.
Kind of cool. I started to solve
some algorithm, but I couldn't
figure out how to use that, to
create like websites and
application and everything. So,
yeah. And I just tried to find
my
answers, you know, Google, like
everybody else. And there was so
many information. I couldn't
just grip breast any, so yeah,
I, at
some point just, I needed help
to, to learn, I guess, um, and
learning by myself. I know it's
not where I'm the strongest. So
yeah, I signed, I searched for
bootcamps that could allow me to
to take care of the kids and.
And also being able to travel to
San
Francisco. Um, uh, yeah, and I
found one and I applied and it
went really fast. Yeah, for
sure. Uh, in like two months it
took to
between the decision, finding
the bootcamp and passing all the
interviews for the boot gym in
two months I was enrolled. So
yeah.
Bekah: What do you think? What
was the difference in learning
experience between learning on
your own and joining up?
Aurelie: Um, the problem I found
with learning on my own was
really this fire hose of
information. And about
everything. It's you search
something and you find something
for something for JavaScript,
and you find something for 5,000
for,
and you asked for some advice
and people will give you or an
answer
with what they know. And
sometimes it's not what you are
working on. And for me, it was
just too hard to find. Really
focused on something. Um, I was
absorbing opinions from
everybody
and I just couldn't make my own
curriculum, you know, so having
something more structured and
also I think someone, um, I
could
ask all my questions. Um, it was
something I thought will help me
better. So, yeah, it was, it was
really, it was better for me.
And
also, so English is not my first
language. Um, when I started the
bootcamp, I was not super
confident with new talking
English. So I think someone will
take the time to talk with me to
understand where I don't
understand things and explain me
slowly. Um, some stuff, um, it
was really helpful. So yeah, I
really appreciated the bootcamp
for that. And I searched for
online, online bootcamp at
first. Um, but I realized that
to learn
English, it was maybe easier for
me to have the person in front
of
me and, you know, um, Reading
lips when people talk. So it
wasn't really easier for me to
have someone in front of me,
like
a real person. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. absolutely. And so
your bootcamp was it a hybrid
bootcamp? Some, some of it was
at home. Some of it was on
campus or
how was that structured?
Aurelie: So I chose an in-person
boot camp, so it was supposed to
be 12 weeks of in-person
bootcamp. And I started on
January 27th, 2020. So everybody
knows what happened in March.
So,
so I did six weeks of in-person
and six weeks of our remote
learning because of COVID
restrictions. it was really
challenging, uh, to be honest,
uh, I really liked the, the
in-person way also because it
made me, um, meet a lot of
people
that I wouldn't have met
otherwise, you know, when you're
a stay at home, mom, uh, you
meet moms and that's it. So
yeah, in
the bootcamp really. A lot of
different people and it was
really great to have like the
backgrounds, they all have
different background and it was
great. It was really, um,
helpful
for me to talk with these
people. Um, for me personally,
and also
for, um, of the tech and, uh,
switching to remote. Well, first
I had to, you know, you have to
adjust and also we didn't have
this. Um, the connection that we
had before discussions were
mostly on slack. People didn't
have time, even me to like, do
some zoom meeting after classes.
So it was really different.
Yeah.
Well, less than directions. Um,
but it went well. Uh, in the
end,
yeah, I really missed like, uh,
the social part it, which is
strange because I'm usually
someone who like, loves to live
in a cave and, uh, talk to
nobody. But I guess, I guess it
changed me. So yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I feel like a lot of
us learned some stuff about
ourselves when the, when the
pandemic started and all the
quarantine stuff happened, you
know?
Aurelie: Yeah.
Dan: You know, my, my natural
thing is like, oh, I hate
people.
I don't want to be anywhere.
know, the same thing live in a
cave, you know? And then all of
a sudden when you're forced to
not
ever see anybody, it's like, oh,
No, it turns out I actually do,
like, people might not like, you
know, lots and lots of people or
anything, but, uh, yeah. It's,
uh, I don't know. That was, that
was an experience. I'm sure it
actually had probably, uh, well,
I don't, I was going to say I'm
sure. I don't know if I'm sure,
but, um, fact that you started
your class kind of started all
together. Um, and you had six
weeks. Is that what you said
before? Uh, before, uh, you
know, the quarantine started? So
that
probably helped a little bit. I
mean, you at least knew the
teacher and you knew, um, the,
your classmates and stuff I
imagine was much harder. Um, you
know, starting from, from
scratch
in that, in that situation.
Aurelie: Yeah, for sure. I don't
think I would have, um,
succeeded. Um, yeah, maybe at
all. If it was online, heard
many. Um, people talk to me
about the same, uh, boot camp I
did,
but online, completely online.
And, um, I, I think you need
some
skills, like self skills and
everything, to really succeed
kind of online training. And
these skills, I don't have them,
I guess, or maybe not enough. I
don't know.
Dan: It's definitely
interesting. I don't know if I
would, I mean,
skills is an interesting word,
but there's everybody kind of
learns differently. Right. And
so, uh, it's, it's more. W what
were your sort of what you're
suited to? Right. And, and I
don't, I mean, I don't learn
from lectures really, or people
talking, you know, but of course
I have the same issue with video
Uh, I, I have problems. I dunno.
Um, I don't know what the right
word is, but, uh, I, I don't,
um, the information doesn't
stick in
my brain, right. until I do
things, but the self guided
stuff
only works for me personally.
Uh, when I am super into
whatever it
is, you know, I always.
Personally I'm self-taught, but
like I said, I'm self-taught, as
in like, I'd learned things but
bit at a time, you know, bits at
a time, as I things that
interest
me in college or whatever, like
w in my free time, uh, and the
idea
of trying to do that from
scratch now seems horrifying. So
I can
totally relate to like, wanting
to, um, the lesson planning and
stuff like that, that you can
kind of, kind of talked about.
And the, I would have no idea
what. To do or even, to tell
somebody what to do, you know,
if somebody is like, oh, I want
to
learn to be a developer. What
should I learn? You know, think
I
would, I'd be like, I have no
idea. know, learn stuff. It
seems
really hard to, to, to do all on
your own, like entirely on your
own. Um,
Aurelie: Yeah.
Dan: at least.
Aurelie: I'm the same, I think
also that need, like, it's not
that I need some guidance all
the way, but I think for, um, to
start, I need someone to guide
me when I start and I need to.
Maybe
show that I, I, I need to show
someone that I understood
something and to me the go to be
like maybe more confident and
then such sort by myself. But
yeah, I. I like to have like
person saying, okay, this, you
know, now you know how to do it.
You do it well. So go ahead and
do more that I need, I guess.
Bekah: Yeah. Even being in a
traditional classroom, you can,
when you see other students.
It's kind of acts as a gut
check,
right? Like if you're like, wow,
I'm really confused. Should I be
confused or other people like
you look around and you're like,
okay, that person definitely
looks confused too. So like, in
that sense, like there's a,
there's some community and that
kind of enables you to think
like, okay, well we're in this
together. We all need to figure
this out. So let's ask some
questions or, um, like, okay,
I'm not the only one that's
having
this experience right now. And
just like having that community
support, whether it's for a gut
check or to say like, yeah, this
is. It's tough, but you're doing
a good job. Just keep at it. But
sometimes that's all you need,
but when you're yourself and
there's so much information,
there's, it's oversaturated
amount of information, like you
said, some of it's good. Some of
it's not, some of it can apply
to what you're working on. Some
of
them, you don't recognize that
you can't apply it yet. Um,
because there are simple things
able to hear other people talk
about that, to ask questions and
to see, um, How, how people are
working through things can be,
um, a huge game changer for
that.
Aurelie: Yeah. And I had this
experience. We had some
exercise,
um, like we were trying to, I
don't know, create like a new
feature in class and there was
this kind of, um, algorithm to
solve for that. I know that by
myself, I wouldn't have been
able
to do it and other people, uh,
as well, but I had some, um,
understanding that helped them.
So there things as well, and
altogether, we were able to
deliver something that was
watching really well. So I think
this is important as well to
have. People around you and, um,
people you can talk to and
exchange you spend way less time
to solve problem. And, um, and
these less frustrating in the
end. So yeah, I think the
learning experience is maybe
better by the way. I mean, but
like you said, then maybe for
some people, some people are
able
to learn as well by themself and
I admire that.
Bekah: I think it's good
practice though, to be able to
learn with
other people. Because when you
go out and start working, you're
probably going to be working
with team of people. And the
more
comfortable you are
communicating about things and
asking
questions, it's going to be
overall. I think for like being
a
part of a team, especially it's
a remote team,
Aurelie: Yeah. That's something
that I wasn't used to do my
previous career. It was more
like have one task to do and you
have
to do it by yourself and the
Festus. And people were not
really, don't know, available to
help or things like that. You
didn't just. you didn't ask
actually. And so this is
something that I've learned,
with, with, coding. You have
ask,
have to ask for help. You have
to ask for people to test your
thing. You have a, yeah, you
have to ask for reviews, you
have to
ask to call So out to people and
say, Hey, uh, either someone to
review what I've done or. I
don't know what to do and I need
help
and something that I really
learned. Um, yeah. When I
started
coding, uh, it, something that
made me, a lot uncomfortable at
first, uh, to be honest, because
I like to be the person who is
expert on something. And I, I
like to be the one with the
answers. Instead of asking them,
but yeah, I changed now. I'm
asking questions all the time.
Bekah: I totally feel
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And, you know, as a
career changer too, and coming
from an
experience where I was the one
with all the answers having no
support from other people, it
definitely was a hurdle to get
through. And, you know, I taught
English for a lot of years and
would always be like, wow, I bet
you are a really good
communicator. Just a very
different role and I was not
used
to communicating in that way. So
no, I wasn't, I'm working on it
though, you know, um, it is
almost a new skillset to be able
to communicate in that way and
to ask those questions, um, I
want
to kind of the conversation a
little bit, because you talked
about, you enjoyed being
in-person for bootcamp, and now
you're working a remote
position. And so like, I'd love
to hear
your take on that transition and
in why you chose remote work
over
being in person you liked the
in-person bootcamp. So.
Aurelie: Yeah. So I discovered
that it's not really. Um, being
in an office with people that I
like, it's more, more of the
interaction interactions with
people. Um, and I think working
remote remotely is not a
barrier. I mean, a blocker for,
um, team
communication and having fun
with your team and yeah. And
having,
yeah, great exchange and. Um,
and also I'm a mom, kids, and I
need
to be available and working
remotely is the easiest for me
to
be able to continue to try them
to the doctor or to whatever
activities they have. Um, I like
to be here. When thing, when do
you come back from school? And
if they have one more. I don't
want
to just run all the time. It's
something that I did when I was
in friends. I was working full
time from eight to six, uh,
picked up the kids at the
nanny's house at six, and then
you just
had to run to run, to run. And
it's honestly, it's just not the
life. Um, and yeah, since I had
the opportunity to change my
career, Why not changing the way
I was working. And, um, so yeah,
uh, something that I decided
like early. Um, I, I, I wanted
to work
from home. Uh, that was the
easiest for me. So, yeah. And
what I experienced today in my
team, um, I mean, we have great
way to interact. Um, with each
other, we have one-on-ones we
have coffee breaks. have, um,
what we have team lunch, uh,
like
every Thursday we, we, we eat
together and, yeah, it's great.
And we have a lot of varying,
um, session if we want to. And
yeah,
so it's really not about just
being the office. It's just. How
you want to create relationship
with your teammates, you know,
and yeah. So far it's been three
months now that I'm full-time
remote and, uh, yeah, I think
I've made the choice. I really
like it.
Dan: Is everybody on your team?
Uh, full-time remote.
Aurelie: Yes. We are all four
remotes. Uh, we are all
mostly...We are all in the U S.
Um, so I'm in, I mean, the team
that is separated do teams. My
team is only in the us and the
other little team is, uh, Um, so
yeah, and it, for example, it's
another challenge. Uh, we had
like a summit for, um, our team
that is called an organization.
And, uh, we had to have
everybody
on zoom at the same time. And so
we had people during the day, we
had people during the night.
But, um, yeah, it's I, and I
think
people are willing to do that
because everything, everything
is
great and we have great
relationship between us. So,
yeah, it's, uh, it's great.
Maybe next time it will be us in
us
that will have to be up at
night. We'll see.
Bekah: Okay. I think that's such
a great point that you made
about
it's it's about the
relationships, right? It's not
necessarily about the place,
right? You are because there can
be various successful remote
teams, fully remote teams, and
there can be very successful in
person teams and, and there can
be, you know, Ones that are not
successful at all. And it just
depends on, you know, how are
you building your team? What,
how are
you creating the relationships
or the other people and like
recognizing them as, a person
and not just somebody that's got
to
get this work done. Um, and so I
think that's so important when
people say, well, you can't have
the same relationship. On remote
teams that you can in person.
And for me, I found way more
value in
the remote teams that I've been
on I ever have my in-person
teams. And I think it's just
really about, you know, what,
what is the value of that team?
Aurelie: Yeah. I never believed
in the, you know, these
companies
will have like foosball and ping
pong tables and stuff like that
to create a environment. It's
not about that. You can have
like as
many foosball table you want and
your people won't talk to each
other. So it's not something I
really believe in. And, um, I
mean, if the leadership like is
willing to show that they are,
uh, okay with being remote, that
there are, um, the way that
they're communicating with each
other is. Remotely. And
sometimes
they organize fun things. Every
people, uh, in the Yarki will do
it because we do just what the
leadership does. That's that's
the way people work. So, yeah.
And if your company is
organizing
great events, just to have
people talking to each other and
meet,
um, whatever the. Department
they are working on and
everything. I
think this is how you create
work relationship with anybody
in the
company. And for example, my
company, um, last week or two
weeks ago, I don't remember. Um,
they're organized like every
trimester, uh, what they call
table four six. So you have to
register in advance. They have
like a list of people and people
that are randomly chosen. They
create a table. So it's a zoom
room. And they give you like a
budget to, uh, order something
with door dash and you are
eating your lunch with people
you
wouldn't have worked with maybe.
So. Yeah, it's a, I think that's
the kind of evidence that needs
to happen if you want your, your
employees to just have great
relationship relationship with
it.
Dan: I think that's really cool.
I was going to ask, you had
mentioned that you got your,
your S your small team does like
every
week, right? I mean, it's kind
of eat together kind of thing.
Aurelie: Yeah.
Dan: think that's. Is there any
other, um, sort of, not like the
big summit level stuff, but, uh,
any sort of week-to-week stuff
that, um, that your team does
or, the organization does to
improve,
you know, your communications in
near relationships, um, on your
team.
Aurelie: Yeah. So, um, well, in
my team, we have like a wall to
have like least one SU meeting
altogether. So when we don't
have
any new organized, like a coffee
break or something like that,
it's short, but it's just, Hey,
what did you do this weekend?
And
blah, blah, blah. So this is
something that we do. We also
have, we also use the new
feature from slack, the slack
huddle. So
we use that mostly to talk with
all the We have, like Melbourne
or Singapore. Then, um, what
else do they do? So, yeah,
there's the
table four, six. There's a, the
end cred. Oh, okay. So
onboarding
process. Um, we are, um, in
teams during the onboarding
process.
And so we have like some
activities. I'll just call that
company and everything and they
encourage us to just stay in
contact. So like every month,
month and a half, I have this
meeting with my team that I
onboard with. And, um, so it's,
you know, it's tiny things like
that. They also organize like,
um, My company works a lot with
charities. They encourage
volunteering they encourage
people to rope together to do
some volunteering as well. So
it's all the things that they
are. I think they are trying to,
uh, find, um, ways for people
to,
um, to show their common
interest and build on that. I
think it's
yeah, it's a great idea. They
have a, yeah. And we have also,
um, like societies they call
them, that, so for example, we
have like, uh, Um, society for
women, for women in engineering,
for parents, for people from
the, uh, LGBTQA, uh, community,
it's,
uh, it it's great. And, um, To
try to yeah. To build on that
and
think this is how you make
people talk to each other. Yes.
Yeah.
Dan: I think that's really cool.
My, uh, yeah, my wife works for
Teach for America and they do,
they have a lot of stuff in it.
Similar, similar kinds of
things, you know, um, that they
do to
sort of promote, um,
interpersonal relationships, you
know, on their teams. Uh,
sometimes I think they might go
overboard. You know, they spend,
you know, a lot of time on zoom,
um, altogether, but it's, it's
cool. And, and I mean, and she
loves her team too, you know,
and they, they, they're all,
they're
all spread all over the place
and all remote and everything
too.
It's very cool. And I, I feel
like it is it's, uh, important
to
that's one of the things that
some parts of it happened
automatic or can happen
automatically when you're all in
the same you know? Uh, and
obviously there's plenty of
unhealthy in the world, but like
it's, I feel like it takes more
concerted effort. Um, When
you're, um, you know, on a
remote
team, um, to do that sort of
thing, because it's easy to into
cave, cave person mode. Right.
Um, and think the thing you said
at the beginning when I asked
this question was about how a
lot
of it comes from leadership. Um,
uh, I just want to just touch on
that again, because I feel like
that's, that's really true and
it's important, you know, if, if
leadership is like, make some
sort of rule that everybody has
to do something, but doesn't,
you
know, don't participate in it or
anything. Um, I feel like lots
of
times that ends up just causing
resentment at best and doesn't
actually promote, you know, uh,
any, any So I think that's
really
cool that the is sort of part of
this whole process. Yeah.
Aurelie: Yeah. And also we are,
um, So we have offices the
world.
We have employees all over the
world and some rules are in
place
as well to, um, to make sure
that people who are not on us
time
zones also feel part of the
company, you know? And, um, I
think that's, that's, great. We
have like all important meetings
have to be recorded. That way,
if someone is on another time
zone
and can join, or even if someone
has an emergency at home and
they
have to pick up their kids, they
can still have all the
information that has been shared
during the meeting. And I think
it's a game changer when people
do that. Remote work is really
possible. Otherwise, I, I don't
know. Yeah. If your job is only
for us market, maybe it's
easier, but as long, I mean, if
it's from
somewhere else or you have
people working from elsewhere,
you have
to implement these things in
your house, you have to force
it.
Otherwise, like you said, the
first thing people do usually is
just to KV.
Bekah: And it's nice too. When
you, when you have communities
of
belonging, where you have shared
interests, easier to learn more
about so many there. And then
also to like branch out beyond
that, because when you have an
environment that, know, feels.
One, like you're comfortable
there, there are these people
around you that you trust and,
you know, and they'll have
different overlapping
communities then you would have
to. And so
then there just becomes this,
like, know, you have these sub
communities, but then it all
works together to feel to create
something that's like this, this
nice big. Supportive community
that allows you to do, So much
more because when, when you feel
safe in a space, when you know
that you can trust those people,
then you're more likely to grow
and to take chances or risks or
be innovative, um, and and move
faster. It's funny. Yeah. That
it's not more highly valued on
teams like, oh, well, that's,
that's not, um, it's not a
valuable thing that doesn't help
us with our product, but, but it
does because of the side effects
of having a supportive place.
Um, so I know that there are
certainly lots of people out
there that. Are not interested
in
remote work, um, narrow
struggles that are associated
with it as
well. I know for me, you know,
I, I work remotely and I don't
have
an office space. So sometimes
it's like really hard for me to
stop. I'm well, the computer's
there and the kids are playing
on
the sit down and do this one
more thing. w have you found to
be
useful to kind of some of those
struggles?
Aurelie: So I have to get, we
live in a two bedroom apartment,
um, and my kids have been, uh,
at remote school, um, all year,
last
year. Uh, so. Yes, there are
struggles when you want to, to
work from home, especially
today. Um, so it's it. I mean,
you can
do just what you can do with
what you have and the time that
you
have. So instead of stressing
about having like a super
private. Room for yourself with
closed doors and just try to
make, I mean, try to use what
you have and just work on that.
I
changed my, uh, desk space like
four times last year. And I
finally find my corner, you
know, it's not, I mean, I'm, I
mean the
living room, so, um, Yeah, with
the kids. It wasn't easy. At
some
point we were four people in
your apartment having zoom
meetings at
the same time. Um, you adjusts.
I mean, especially, I think it's
even easier now before. I don't
think people were really, um,
inclined to understand that
maybe you have a dog, maybe you
have a
kid, maybe you haven't even
baby, uh, or even. And there are
only
people that you have to take
care of. Um, now the understand
better
what it is because people were
forced to work from home. And I
think this is when, if, if you
really want to work from from
home. Um, this is when you can
find your thing without really
stressing out about it. So at
first, like for example, I was
in
the middle of the living room
and I had to get. Passing behind
me
all the time. Uh, well, I can do
anything. I can, I mean, take my
kids against the wall, just for
them to not walk behind me, you
know? So yeah, just try, just to
do with what you have. Zoom can
allow you to put backgrounds,
just use that and your kids.
Well, My experience, my kids. So
they are 12 and 10. So obviously
it's easier than with little
kids. I don't really have the
experience with little kids, but
at least with my kids, uh, just
told them that what I was doing
was important and what I was
doing will maybe make us have
one day. I think it house like
with
maybe I will have my office and
they will have their own bedroom
and they won't have to run
behind me all the time. And, but
if
nobody is making any effort now,
Maybe what happened. So this is
what I try to explain them. And
they Enough to understand that.
And so we try to establish rules
and every week we weren't
changing the world because we
tried something and it was not
adapted. And so we had to change
and, uh, but yeah, it's just. At
first, I was like super stressed
and I didn't want anybody to be
on camera and everything. it was
just impossible and it made me
really nervous. And like, for
example, during the bootcamp, my
son really wanted to uh, who was
my instructor. And so it was on
the, like on the couch with me.
And it was like, Just his head.
So at first it was just the hair
and then the nose and then the
full face. And you, you can't
avoid that. Um, but yeah, so I,
I
w R reviewed the rules like
multiple times. I tried to
organize their schedule mine to
make sure that at least. Um, I
had one moment in the morning
and one moment in the afternoon
with
a quiet time where I could set
up like some zoom meetings and I
mean the most important ones,
um, a good pair of headphones. I
mean, a lot of tools exist, um,
just to, to do that better, but
yeah. I mean, unless you are
already working in a company
that
will give you a steep end to buy
a set of new monitors and
everything. Well, fine. Just do
that. But if you can't, you
just,
and also one thing that was, um,
important decide of the material
aspect and organize it or the
musician or more like aspect?
Um,
communication when I was in
projects during the bootcamps
and, uh, they wanted to, uh,
code all weekend for eight hours
a
day. Sorry, I can't, I can't,
give you three hours in the
morning and I can give you three
hours in the afternoon that's
it.
Because after that I need to
cook, I maybe I need to take
care
of my kids. Maybe I need you to
tell me also, you know, Mean,
yeah. So just being clear with
people, Maybe some people will
have some expectations from you
and you just have to be really,
um, um, I mean, just tell the
truth and say that things maybe
won't happen like that. And as
soon as you, mean, the sooner
you
that the less struggles and
blockers and frustration it
creates, so. My only, yeah, I
think my only advice is just let
it go.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's such
good advice, you know, and I
don't know if this is a mom
thing or not, but I know at
least a lot
of moms that I know now we, we
do a lot because we have to do a
lot. Right. And so. then we, we
want to continue to do things
that we enjoy doing or that
we've done before really well.
it's
really hard. Sometimes it just
doesn't happen. Or sometimes
like
we're in a different stage of
life and we need to let those
things go and it can be really
hard. To do that because you're
like, well, I enjoyed this or I
could be good at this, or I will
have enough time, I think you're
right. Saying like have clear
communication about things and
be okay with communicating that.
So,
I mean, and that's another thing
that goes. Creating trust. You
know, if you are, if you don't
just keep pushing through, just
be open to begin with and like,
I can do a little bit, but no, I
can not do that. And so.
there's, like the clear
communication
there's boundaries, your
setting, but then also talking
about being
flexible with things because you
can try it things it doesn't
work. And just having that
self-awareness I think a great.
too, to be able to work with
different groups of people and
to
with your team and, and make
sure that, everybody knows where
you're at, because that's what,
you know, that's, that's what,
creates good team.
Aurelie: Yeah, I think so. I
think so. Um, my resentfully, so
my kids find any return to
school. Uh, and so I have to
drive one, uh, in the morning
because it was cool. It was
really far away. And also, I
think he's too little to go by
himself. Um, so I ha I I've just
told my kid and my kids, my CMS,
um, yeah, starting um, August
11th, I won't be able to accept
any zoom meeting at eight. It
will be eight 30. That's it, I
mean, and nobody said, oh my
gosh, Nope. Everybody say, oh
yeah, of course. That's it's.
Yeah. So I think sometimes we
are
most stressed about saying the
thing more than really. Yeah.
too
much, I guess.
Bekah: That's for sure. Well, I
think, you know, all of these
things that you've talked about
it, think one of the benefits
of.
COVID and the pandemic and stuff
is, is that people are more open
and willing to this. And I mean,
moms have been impacted, I
think,
more than any other group or
they're very high up on the
list,
but you know, I also think that
it's good that eventually, I
think there'll be more
opportunities for moms because
things like this are regular.
Like it's okay to have. On your
screen. okay to say I have to
take my kids somewhere. And in
some sense, it's normalize this
and hopefully that's something
that we forward because remote
work is that that's what makes
things doable for me as well, to
be able to take kids the
doctor's
or to a field trip or, you know,
whatever is, something that I,
that I want to be doing. And I'm
glad that I have that ability to
do that and to, you know, be
able to. Take that time and, and
not
have to in my car for a really
long commute somewhere. I knew a
mom that was looking for work,
um, pre COVID and she was
looking
for her first job. And she said,
well, the only one that I was
offered is a two hour commute,
two hours each way gets it's not
worth it. It is not worth that
Aurelie: No.
Bekah: is not that great. And I
don't, I don't know. I feel like
it's ridiculous for anyone to
ask somebody to commute that
like,
that's a, that's a red flag in
my mouth. Like yeah. Spend all
that
time in your car
Aurelie: Well, it's a,
Bekah: could work from home.
Aurelie: yeah, it's something
that we know a lot here in the,
in the barrier, because you have
a lot of people, you know,
working for like the giants,
like Google and apple Facebook.
And,
but they can. I mean, they are
old enough to have kids and so
they can have a roommate. So
they have to live far away where
prices are I guess, to live. So
I know many people doing like
two
hours come here, morning and
afternoon. And it's, I think
it's
just crazy. And I'm glad for
them that we are in remote days
and
now they are just working from
home and everything is fine.
Dan: had, you know, when you're
talking about sort of breaking
up
your. Hours of your day or
whatever. I kind of touched on
it, but I was one I wanted, I
was wondering if you could talk
a
little bit about how you between
work and also taking care of,
you
know, your family and
everything. Um, if you ha how
you kind of,
um, build any habits or anything
for self care and, you know,
like
staying healthy and stuff like
that. Uh, if you, if you, if you
have anything, you know, any
tips or anything like that, I
could
probably use some.
Aurelie: I don't know if I have
good tips for that. But so
actually it was really funny
because when I was a stay at
home, mom, I never found time to
do anything like at all. And
since I work, I trained almost
seven hours a week. I don't
know.
Um, yeah, I don't know. It's
just a F yeah, no, I don't have
any
tips. It's just, uh, if I want,
I know that like hour I need to,
um, to go out of my desk and
just take few steps. Just
because, you
know, it's good for your eyes.
It's for your brain is good for
whatever. And so it's like, oh,
I need to the, I dunno, the
dishwashers. I will do that. And
in the meantime, I will do some
stuff and come back to my desk.
And so it's something that I
tried to do, like every hour,
um, training, uh, do I train so
much?
Um, probably because. Hey for
someone, some coaching. So it's,
it's a good motivator.
Dan: Are they scheduled? I mean,
is it, so if you're paying
somebody, so is it like it's on
the calendar
Aurelie: uh,
Dan: yeah.
Aurelie: watch, uh, they won't
check when I do they can check
if
I've done all my trainings,
every.
Dan: Okay.
Aurelie: and then it's just to
me. Um, so I try to like early
in
the morning to do my training
before working. It just doesn't
work, especially since the kids
are returning to school is just
it's too much. So I do that.
know that, uh, uh, when the kids
are
eating because we make our kids.
It's um, together. And then I,
with my husband, we eat later,
like that's weekend have a sense
of, uh, you know, of, uh, um, no
date night, just night time for
adults, you know?
Dan: Adult conversations.
Aurelie: Yeah, I don't
conversation. That's right. Uh,
so yeah, I, when they are eating
I train and so yeah, when they
are eating their rice, I'm
squatting. No, I don't. I mean,
yeah. I, I don't, I don't have
really any advice. I don't know
if you think you can do it in
the morning, just, just what's
your,
I don't know, your alarm clock
earlier or do it just no
pressure. And sometimes I don't
do it. And the next day I will
do
two trainings. That's why, I
mean,
Dan: I liked your, I liked your
approach with the concern of
getting up through that
throughout the day as well. Um,
and that like throwing in the
light. grabbing a couple of
chores, you know, or whatever in
the meantime, or, or doing that
sort of thing. I think that's
cool. I think that's a cool
approach.
Aurelie: It's really something
that I love with remote working
is being able to sprinkle the
chores. During the day like
that,
it's not just a block up. I need
to clean today. No, you, you
that
Dan: Yeah.
Aurelie: you know,
Bekah: Yeah.
Aurelie: when you think about it
and it's, it's great like that.
So sometimes I'm like, have
laundry to fold and I have my
tests running on the, on the
monitor. so while the tests are
running, I'm folding some
t-shirts.
Bekah: I think
Aurelie: That's
Dan: That's a really good idea.
Bekah: Twitter.
Aurelie: I, I just tried to be
chill and the more chill I am
and
the most I do. So I guess, eh,
maybe it's my advice. Just be
chill.
Bekah: Well, I think in the moms
in tech, um, Meet up that you a
couple of weeks ago, you were
talking about self-care and I
think this goes back to what you
were talking about earlier
today,
because a big part of that was
clear communication, too. Right.
being able to express your needs
and. And to be able to take time
for yourself or do things. And I
think that step is always just
recognizing like, okay, what is
going on with me right now?
Because I think, I don't know,
we just move so quickly that we
don't ever think that. I'll be
like laying in bed and then
like,
suddenly I'm like, oh, I
understood. I sat at my desk for
a really long time. And I felt
really grumpy. But if I had
gotten up and a walk, I probably
of chilled out and not this way
right now.
Dan: Yeah. And the, the. I think
it actually ties really well in
with the, um, having like the
happy teams and actually being
much more productive. You know,
you, you just, you said when
you're feeling chill, you
actually do more work. Right.
And. It can seem
counterintuitive, you know, like
if you think, oh, you know, if,
if I force myself to sit at my
desk, you know, and, and, and
bang on whatever I'm working on
for hours and hours and hours,
you know, it seems like that's
the only way to get things done.
It's done sometimes, you know,
but the having healthy, you
know, healthy self and healthy
teams,
uh, you might be spending time
doing things that aren't like.
Writing code or whatever, but it
turns out makes all of you, you
know, yourself and then your
team much more productive,
ultimately,
which the, like, I think studies
have shown us to be obviously
very true too, but it's, uh, it
can be hard to, um, or it can be
easy to lose sight of, of that.
I think when you're in the, I
don't
know, in the thick of it, you
know, so I think that's really,
I
think, uh, keeping a chill is
it's very good advice.
Aurelie: Yeah.
Bekah: Well, Aurelie it's been
great to have you here with us.
Um, we really appreciate you
talking about this, cause this
is
something, um, everybody is
dealing with now, uh, before we
wrap up, is one piece of advice
that you would give somebody
who's starting a remote job?
Aurelie: Um, yeah. having a
journal like every day, Taking
notes, and sometimes revisit
your notes like maybe a week
later,
two weeks later. and not
everything because you might not
know what, why you are not in
that, but, um, some point you
will discover that it's probably
a good context for something.
And
yeah, it's something that worked
well for me. Uh, sometimes it
was
like, okay. I w I need to take
that. I don't know why, but, and
it just, yeah, well, yeah, I
remember that from that day and
I
noted that, oh yeah, that's the
piece of information that I
need.
So yeah. I think the journal
helps and, um, that's it.
Dan: I love that. I think that's
great advice. It sounds, it
sounds really cool. It sounds
like a very good idea too, for
somebody new joining the team.
Bekah: All right. Well, thanks
so much Aurelie
Aurelie: thank you.
Dan: Thanks Aurelie.
Bekah: Bye! Thank you for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel and
edited by Dan Ott. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or you can
email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee's been up to on
our website at virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure to leave us
a
review. Thanks for listening.
And we'll see you next week.