Kirk: Hello, and welcome to
season three, episode nine of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
definitely Bekah.
And this is a podcast that
features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of devs at all stages of
their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their stories.
And what they've learned, we're
here to share with you.
Here with me today is my cohost,
Dan.
Dan: Um, thanks. Definitely
Bekah.
Uh, today we have, uh, a special
episode is the last
episode of season three. And so
we are here with
Kirk Shillingford one of our
community maintainers
and Bekah is actually here.
Bekah is here and fake Bekah,
all the Bekahs are here. Um, so
we have some exciting
stuff coming up where you are,
um, about to kick into some of
our Hacktoberfest preparations.
And so we thought we would talk
a little bit about Hacktoberfest
last year and what we have going
on this year, as well as just
wrap up the season our podcast.
We start every episode of the
podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee - we introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's question is if you had
to teach one class on one thing
right now, what would you teach?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Bekah: Hey. I'm Bekah, I'm a
front
end developer from a small town
in Ohio.
And if I had to teach one class
right now, like my
initial go-to is like, well,
I've taught English.
I could do that. Um, but I, I
still
don't want to, I'm still burnt
out from that.
So I would probably, I don't
know, like maybe a
kettlebell class or, um, a
patients' rights course for
navigating the medical system.
You know,
Dan: So like, that's going to be
like, a, like a
four year degree for that.
Kirk: Yeah.
Bekah: That's what you get.
Dan: Yeah. Fair enough. Um, hi,
I'm Dan I'm a front-end
developer from Cleveland, Ohio,
and a maintainer
here at Virtual Coffee. And, um,
yeah, if I had
to teach a class on one thing, I
mean, I don't know.
There's, there's some computer
stuff I could do, but I think
starting a fire would be my one.
Did we do this before?
Now that I said that.
Bekah: Yeah. Now that you said
that that was
familiar.
Dan: Oh, maybe we did it in a
coffee.
I hope we didn't do it in a
podcast. All right.
Well, I'm sticking with it. Um,
you know, if we are
repeating questions in the
podcast, please write in
and blame, um, real Bekah who
you heard at the top
of the episode, uh, or fake
Bekah just don't blame Dan.
Um, because, well, you know, I'm
blameless, I'm blameless
in pretty much all situations.
Bekah: is false.
Kirk: um, all right. This is
definitely Bekah.
Although sometimes you can call
me Kirk and, um, class.
I would teach you 100%. It would
be Sudoku I would
teach you all about Sudoku,
regular sort of who,
the different types, the
different cool techniques.
That's a joke. They're all cool
techniques.
yeah, that would, that would
totally be my thing.
And it would be lots of fun.
And, um, if we did this
question before, I didn't do
this question before, so.
Bekah: I
Dan: Fair enough. So the same.
Do you have a, I do have my
phone and I've never really like
found, uh, an app.
Kirk: I can recommend some good
apps.
Dan: Okay.
Kirk: Well, I must clear, I have
four Sudoku apps on
my phone, but each one is a
different type of
Sudoku, so it's not.
Dan: Hmm. Okay. Well, what I
like, what's the,
what's your go-to app for the
like class, like just classic
Kirk: Okay. I have one it's all
bespoke
Sudoku, none of that and machine
generated, you
know, printed press stuff, real
artisan Sudokus, I'm
not even making that up, so,
Dan: Okay. Tell us what it's
called.
Kirk: oh, I just called it WIS.
It's called it's called
classics and docu. Um, there's a
YouTube channel called
cracking the cryptic where you
can watch two, um, English
puzzle, masters solve Sudoku is
and a variety of other puzzles.
And it's just the most lovely
thing in the world to watch
a middle lake British man scoff,
a beautiful number.
So, They produce their own app
and they source it
from hustlers that we call
people who make puzzles,
puzzles in the community. And
also though, cause we're
really good an app, like helps
you if you need to.
And it gives you like smart
pins, not just
like random hints. It's great.
It's good at classics in
Dan: So,
Kirk: the cryptic
Dan: so a puzzler is someone who
creates the puzzles. Okay.
So what's what do you call
somebody who solves puzzle?
Kirk: A Solver
Bekah: That was boring.
Dan: Most boring.
Kirk: It's told you about custom
Dan: I feel like, I feel like
the Sudoku community needs to,
it needs to up their game, you
know, for making a silly, well,
not silly, but a potential names
for themselves, you know, it's
just not, it's just not there.
Kirk: therapies. We're trying to
really upset around.
Bekah: well, speaking of puzzles
and
games, Hacktoberfest sure seems
like that too.
Except we have maintainers and
contributors. See it's there.
That was a really good segue and
everybody should
acknowledge that. So last year
we did
Hacktoberfest for the first
time, and that's kind of what
stands out in my mind as, as
the, uh, When, what, when we
really kind of came into phase
two, a Virtual Coffee, um, when
we became something that wasn't
just a pandemic group of people,
what is a group of developers at
all stages of the journey
that would be around for awhile.
Um, and so, you know,
what, what we did last year, we
had an issue.
We helped, um, members get their
first contribution
for Hacktoberfest, which had
Tobar Fest.
A month long focus on open
source contributions that
sponsored by digital ocean. And,
um, once you sign up, I
think you have to have four pull
requests and then you can get a
t-shirt and stickers, but it's
really fun and kind of a great
way to build community and to
learn more about each other.
I know from my perspective, I
mean, I learned.
Organizing this working with
mentors Um, and,
and it was my first time as a
maintainer as well.
So, you know, there were so many
lessons that,
that we learned last year. Maybe
if we just talk about like
our favorite parts of year, and
then we can move into what we're
taking from that into this year,
um, which I'm really excited.
Dan: Yeah. Um, yes. So favorite
parts from last
year, um, I enjoyed, you know,
last year we decided
to use the website as one of our
repos, um, which meant
we needed to make a website. So,
um, so we did that
pretty quickly and, um,
Bekah: you mean you.
Dan: okay. The, the war, the
Royal we,
and, um, One of the things that
we pulled together was,
um, making it an, uh, an, an
issue for having people add
themselves to the, to their
members directory, um, via code.
And we created an issue and, you
know, created, you
know, set up some guidelines and
stuff like that.
And then had a kickoff meeting
altogether where w where we
could get everybody going on,
um, submitting a poll request.
In a zoom meeting and that was a
lot of fun.
It was fun. We, we got, um, I
think
everybody got it done. We had,
um, shout out to Marie.
I'm pretty sure who rescued me
at one point because somebody
was having problem with, um, git
on the command line and I don't
use git on the command don't uh,
and so I didn't know how to,
I'm a guy that I was like, I, I
mean, I, I made sure to before
the event, um, practice, you
know, the very simple things.
This was, we ran into something
that was, wasn't simple on.
I had no idea. Marie swooped
Kirk: Yeah.
Dan: with her superhero Cape
and, uh, rescued my rescued me.
Um, so shout out to Marie for
that.
But, uh, it was a lot of fun.
Um, just the event the whole
month was like that, uh, the
whole month, it was just, uh,
all members kind of ended up
being excited and, and we had
a, it was fun to have a goal,
you know, to everybody could
celebrate, you know, I dunno, it
was fun, but yeah, that,
that first meeting is the thing
that pops into my mind.
Um, when I think of Virtual
Coffee last year and
Hacktoberfest, what about you?
Oh, I was trying to think
of a Keka that's awful.
Kirk: You can just, you can just
go Kirk.
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: Um, yeah, last, last
Hacktoberfest, I mean, it
was a lot of firsts for me. I, I
like, I think a lot
of people don't know this. My
very first like open
source pull requests was just a
couple months before.
On the self-defined project run
by Tatyana Mack,
who was super amazing. But, um,
I feel like I had
spent a long time not doing like
anything coding or
tech related on the side. Just
like, especially when
I've been working by myself. Um,
and Hacktoberfest was I sort
of first opportunity to start
doing stuff with other people.
I was also my first time. Uh,
hosting an open
source project. My first time,
like teaching
other people, like formally like
Elm and getting into
functional programming. I, in a
similar fashion to Dan
may have gone a little overboard
with my, my piece of it, writing
weights and much documentation.
Um, but it, it felt really
good to kind of like, you know,
my, uh, thoughts to try and
make something good for them.
And I think it was just
really, really fun and
empowering and validating to
see so many people say like this
was my first PR Right.
And like the fact that we can
get that for some people
and they could have a good
experience with it and not a
painful experience with it. That
felt good.
And I'm super pumped for doing
that again.
Dan: Yeah, I, uh, I learned
that, Kirk, I mean, yeah,
Kirk, Kirk did a ton of work
getting our, uh, open-source
stuff set up and, uh, putting
some guidelines in place.
And I don't know, I learned a
lot, um, we're working
with Kirk on that too. really
cool.
Bekah, what about you?
Bekah: Yeah, I think, you know,
it's, it all comes
down to the people, right? It
was such a big
learning experience. I feel
like. I learned so much in the
month prep and the month of
doing it, that it, it
was like an intense amount of
learning that happened.
I was so exhausted afterwards,
but
it was so great to be able to
work with other people
and kind of learn about the
deliberate process
that goes into documenting
things and creating issues.
And the difference between
working on your.
Own open source project and then
having people work on it, it
was, you know, a lot in working
on my postpartum wellness app
with members of the community
and working through issues and
how to write issues, but then
also, know, pairing up with
them and talking through things
and hearing their stories and
their connection to, know, both
the code, but also the, um,
topic that we were working on.
It just became
something that couldn't. I would
have never imagined
that it would be that special
and meaningful to me.
So, you know, I really just love
that.
like we all just like really
close together
in that experience.
Dan: Yeah, totally. Um, I mean,
I agree.
Um, we, we talk a lot about.
That the Hacktoberfest last
year was, was sort of where
Virtual Coffee became, you
know, more of a, I dunno, I
dunno what, the more of a
thing, you know what I mean? Um,
Bekah: Like
Dan: than just, uh,
Bekah: know.
Dan: yeah, solidified I dunno,
sort of a mission or something.
I don't, I don't know, but,
yeah, know.
It was a lot of fun.
Kirk: Yeah. I think before,
virtual Coffee
was, you know, we, we definitely
sort of established the space
and, you know, we were, we were
having fun together and
we were definitely like forming
those like good and healthy
connections and relationships
feel like Hacktoberfest
was, when we sort of like the
opportunity to do a lot
of good in the tech space. Like
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: some of the big gaps And
then like, you
know, also like feeling
empowered to change them. Right.
Because if all started with that
question of, we all want
to do something for open source,
we all have this feeling like,
why does that ever feel good?
No. Why do people have so many,
so.
much trouble with this? Why
other people find
it so intimidating? we tried to
solve it.
And, you know, once we did that,
we sort of get on a
roll with the next month and the
month after that
of, let's keep trying to. Like
these things just
like together or both at the
same time in that.
Bekah: Yeah. There's so many
people
that suggest getting into open
source.
Um, if you're new or you're
getting into the industry,
and I've always found that
that's not necessarily the
best advice because open source
projects are open to
new and entry-level people, some
of them are welcoming
and some of them aren't. And so
what ends up happening
is it can be a really isolating
experience and
one that doesn't leave you.
Well, the, a good taste in
your mouth, like, oh yeah. I
want to continue to be
part of this community. Um,
because there can
be some really bad experiences
out there.
And I think, you know, that
really.
Um, stands out to me, as
everybody talked about
how great it was to be doing
this thing together.
People who had been in tech for
years, who had not done it
before doing it for the first
time, it was part of a community
and it was a sense of belonging.
And there is a greater
purpose when you're doing it
with other people that
you trust around you. it, you
know, it allows
you to grow and new ways. Um,
and so I think, you
know, bringing that into what
we're doing this year makes
it even more exciting and more
purposeful because we
know that this has happened once
before and we have
grown a ton since last year.
this year, it it's really
exciting to kind of off of what
we've done.
Dan, do you want to kind of talk
about what our
plans are heading into?
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. So
digital ocean, you know, um,
has been running Hacktoberfest
and they, so they coined
the term Preptember, right. Uh,
for September.
And the idea there for in
DigitalOcean's mind
is Preptember is for
maintainers, right?
So Preptember is get, um, get
your repositories ready.
Um, People to contribute. Right.
And they have a lot of,
they have a lot of good, uh,
resources out there for things
like, um, you know, creating
issues and adding, contributing
guides, stuff like that. And so
that was, you
know, we're, we're, we're going
to also piggyback
on that a little bit. Um, we
want to help maintainers,
um, get things ready. We, we, I
feel like we have
done a pretty good job on, in
our own internal stuff
of adding a lot of the community
health things that
you want to see a lot of the.
Some of the organizational
stuff, things that we want to
see.
Um, and so we can use that, some
of that as a guide and,
um, provide some help for both,
uh, existing maintainers
that want to sort of just make
sure they're checking all the
boxes and, uh, anybody who wants
to create a new open
source project to figure out.
You know what things to do,
what things to hit, um, when,
when you're creating a project
so that you don't end up with
the random bits of code, the
default, read me with, you know,
just a header and that's it.
Right. Um, so someone, somebody
who comes to contribute,
uh, they can help. And then the,
for us, for
Virtual Coffee, we will also
want it to have something this
month for, um, our members who
may you know, who aren't
maintainers of open-source
projects and, uh, The other
thing we thought about was
creating a, I don't know, a
challenge, you know, using our
mental challenge set
up and, um, helping people learn
how to create good
issues for repositories, because
I personally feel
like that is one of the, like,
that is actually one of the
strongest things you can do to
contribute, um, especially to
big projects, even the little
projects, uh, writing an issue.
Um, you know, I don't know if
you find something.
It he's either wrong or you'd
like to, uh, help improve
or, or everything like that.
every, almost every
maintainer will prefer you to
create an issue first. Right.
And that way the maintainers can
process them and,
you know, check and see. but
also, you know, if
you see something that's wrong,
lots of times. Okay.
So does it happen personally?
Right?
I have, I've been trying to
install a package or something.
I follow the, read me. It
doesn't work and I. Okay.
I mean, you know, whatever, I'm
busy, I'm pressed
for time or whatever. And, uh,
you know, I just
like, oh, this thing is broken.
And so I just move on, you
know, and, um, a possibly better
approach would
be to write an issue. Right. But
you can't just say
this is broken and move on.
Cause that's just as
helpful, you know, like that's
not hopefully there.
Um, so that's, that's our other,
we're doing a
two-pronged Preptember, right?
Right. Some issues for some
repositories and, uh, you know
how to do it well, How to,
you know, both, uh, set up and
create or create, um, um,
your open source project with,
with a good, you know, with a
good setup of support, um, for
maintainers.
it starts tomorrow, as of our
recording, it
starts September 1st. So, um,
which will probably be
when this comes out, actually.
Bekah: Yeah. And, you know, I
think contributors
write issues also does a really
good job of kind of showing.
What it takes to be a maintainer
or what's useful
way to approach a problem. so,
and I think it helps
to create those clear paths of
communication.
now, Kirk, I know that you did a
lot with maintainers last year.
You're working on a checklist
for maintainers this year.
What are some of the big things
that you think
maintainers should be for as
they prepare their
repositories for Hacktoberfest?
Kirk: Uh, there's part of me
wants to say
there's quite a bit. And then
another part of
me wants to say it's like less
than people think.
There are some basic like files
that we know usually helped to,
to just have like having the
good reading and like knowing
what makes a good reasoning, um,
contributing, like telling
people, Hey, here's the way you
contribute to this code
base in the way that works for
you as the maintainer, right.
Having a code of conduct. So
establishing very early
on the types of behaviors you
expect while interacting with
the code base and interacting
with other people contributing.
Um, as you said, It's all about
communication.
And I think a lot of times
maintainers it's like, we sort
of think of open source in this
very transactional way.
Like I have code base use of it
to code base.
I take something, you know,
it's, it's, it's a team, right?
It's, it's an ad hoc team. It's
a distributed team.
But while that person is trying
to work with your code, they're
kind of like your teammate. So
in the same way you would.
Keep a teammate teammate aware
of like, what's going on.
You kind of do the same thing
with, uh, with contributors.
So I usually encourage
maintainers, like, Hey, think
about the way you want to
interact with this code base.
And just like a lot of it's just
like giving folks a heads up.
I work on this, on the weekends.
So if you submit a request,
you know, expect a review by the
weekend, or like,
Hey, sometimes I slip up. So if
you notice it's been a
couple of weeks or a couple of
days with no response, me
a message on the appropriate
channel where you wish
to receive messages about your
open source code base.
if there are a lot of things
like that, but I don't feel
like we talk about a lot. We
talked about making the
issue or making the PR, I think
those subtleties.
As a maintainer find the way you
want to be interacted
with and make that super clear
for people, um,
that can be super helpful. then
for your contributors,
then they don't have that burden
of trying to decide if they're
bothering you or frustrating.
And that goes back to
what Dan said about like what's
a good issue.
You know, a good issue for a
maintainer is something they
can see like make decisions on.
I need to fix this?
Can I let this person fix it?
Um, is this a big problem that
we need to pair up more on? Can
we break this
into smaller chunks? so, you
know, it's, it's
about like building a healthy
working relationship.
And a lot of that is people
being open, honest with
like where they're at and what
they can accomplish.
Bekah: I really love that idea
of this is your team
that you're working with. And so
if you're thinking
of, okay, now you have all of
these brand new
teammates who are going to be
working on your repository.
How do you onboard them all at
once? Right.
It, it starts there, you know,
what the clear
paths of communication and do
you lay that out?
How do you demonstrate that you
are a friendly
repository for people to come
and work on things?
I talked to, um, a maintainer of
a really large
a couple of months ago. one of
the challenges that he
said was, so hard to find people
to continue being maintainers
for the project because Was
self-described as older.
And he said the other
maintainers are older and
they could really use, new
people to take it over.
it's a catch 22 almost because
so many of the maintainers
don't want to spend the time to
work with new contributors.
ultimately those would be the
perfect candidates once they
understood the repository and
how to work through
things, it over for a while. Um,
and I think.
You know, going back to what
we're doing and making
sure that we, um, work with all
of our members at all
different levels and stages.
Like that's the investment that
we put into, these repositories.
We, we make sure that
people have mentors. We make
sure that there are
repositories that are friendly
to them and that these
it's about developing the
relationships that go and create
community around your project.
So you can sustain and grow.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. And
like, that's, that's
one of the support things that
we w we try to do too.
And this stuff that we're
talking about is time consuming
from a maintainers perspective,
you know, and there are a lot
of projects out there where, um,
I feel like there are
people that would be open to
country contributions, you
know, maybe haven't spelled out
every single thing that
they could or whatever. And one
of the things that
we can do at like, that we do do
as a community is.
Is maybe provide support for our
contributors to
navigate, you know, different,
different areas of repositories
and, and what's to you. Cause
none of them are
ever going to be perfect. Right?
Uh, no, no project is going
to have everything laid out. Um,
some will get close, you
know, but, um, anyway, uh, that
that's like one of the other
things that we do once, like
once Hacktoberfest starts is.
Is provide support and
mentorship in some time, you
know, in some places for people,
uh, format for our members to
kind of work through some of the
social, you know, some of
the like social anxiety that
can, that can, that can happen.
Um, when, you know, when
contributing to open source.
Kirk: Yeah. I think you touched
on something
very important that are just
like how scary it is to offer,
to help someone on project that
like, you feel like, oh, I
don't particularly understand.
And it's all this code.
And especially if you're an
early career developer, like,
oh, I'm just, I just got here.
I'm going to mess something up.
There's so many. It's something
that we
don't really do in other
circumstances, there's a lot
of anxiety around it and sort of
anything you can do too,
as a maintainer to make people
feel more welcome is, is like
worth it, know, and getting back
to September, like you said,
like this, this year, we want it
to not just be Preptember
for maintainers, but also
Preptember for contributors,
you know, we're, we're going to
be doing, you know, a couple of
talks in a couple of seconds.
You know, to show people what
contribution looks like, but
also to let them see like not
scary it is and how approachable
it can be, you know, just
to we can do to kind of like get
through those layers of
anxiety and get to that place
where it's like, no, they,
they want me to be here. They
want me to help.
They're okay with me learning.
They're willing to sort of,
you know, guide them along. Um,
and that's when I think you
get to see people really, really
shine and like really enjoy.
Uh, making contributions to
group projects.
Dan: So you mentioned some
stuff, some, some events I
just wanted to kind of run
through a couple of the ones
that we have for September. Um,
if that's all
right, real quick. September
3rd, which is
this Friday, we, I will be doing
an event, a lunch
and learn event at noon Um, and,
and it's just an open.
So what's called the open source
project walkthrough.
And this just sort of a tour,
uh, not really a deep
dive into any con you know,
contributing, uh, any, any,
anything as far as like pull
requests or anything like that.
But, just a tour of what a, what
a repository looks like.
What are all the different
pieces that happen?
Um, looks like from the
maintainers perspective,
um, on a project and, uh, We'll
just kind of it around.
It's not going to be a, it's not
going to be super
in depth, um, but it'll be kind
of fun and we'll, know,
we'll hang out and ask some
questions and stuff like that.
Um, and so that's me, that's
Friday, September
17th is a lunch and learn, um,
how to create an open
source or a repository. And so
this is Kirk, um, at
September 17th at noon Eastern.
And this is sort of geared
towards maintainers or. People
who'd like
to be maintainers. kind of, and
this is kind
of what we touched about and
touched on a couple of times.
What kinds of things should we
look at when we're, when
we're, we're talking, thinking
about creating an open
source project, um, because it's
not just the code.
Like we've talked about a bunch
of times, right?
It's not just the code. Uh,
there's a lot of things
we can do to help, to help, uh,
contributors actually
contribute to your project. So
that is 17th.
And then am what we got the 24.
Um, which is the last Friday
I feel like probably in
September is, uh, this is
our intro to Hacktoberfest and,
um, and open-source
contributions, hosted by Bekah
but I'm pretty sure
we'll, we'll, I'll be there. Um,
and this is a general
Hacktoberfest, you know, Jumping
into everything event.
Um, I guess I should have
probably asked if Kirk, if you
had anything to say about her,
your event, uh, uh, just
realized I was about to do
either of you would
like to, you know, expand more
on what I said.
Um, but those, the events coming
up, uh, this month,
I'm excited about it.
Kirk: Um, I think he covered the
basis.
It's it's going to be much what
it says.
We're going to start from
scratch with a, Hey, I have
something locally and I want to
get it up on GitHub.
I want it to be open source and
I want to do
the necessary things that people
know that they can
come here and work here. We will
cover the required docs.
We'll, we'll get some helpful,
get up features for making that
process easier because they have
invested a lot of resources
into that type of thing. Uh,
we'll cover a few things
that GitHub doesn't really tell
you about the, you sort
of learn from our work with PC
and just all the other cool
projects in the community. So, I
mean, totally recommended
for anyone who wants to start an
open source.
Anyone who already has one and
they just want to get like a
refresher on what are the cool
things happening nowadays to
make it engaging, even if you're
a contributor where you just
want to see like, Hey, like what
actually goes into this?
I might want to do this next
year or a couple
months down the line. Um, I
think all, all three
of our events will be super
useful for anyone at any
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: part of the OSS. Uh,
Bekah: Yeah, and I always
appreciate everybody coming.
If somebody is very experienced
and has done it before and
has things to offer and can
answer questions too, you know,
it's great to have a variety of
voices from the community
who can talk about the things
and, you know, we'll start
with, you know, what is hacked
Tober Fest, um, because you
know, Plenty of people who've
been in tech for a long time
and they're not familiar with
Oktoberfest and it's okay.
It just depends on, you know,
the, the circles
that you hang around. Right. Um,
to have exposure to that.
Uh, I think I, I was just in the
like, free t-shirt.
Groups everywhere. And I was
like, you go.
so we'll get you set up, learn
how to, sign up for that.
Learn about how to find
repositories that that eligible
for Hacktoberfest and talk
through what it's like to work
your way through an issue about,
um, Creating a pull request
and, and some tips for doing
that or asking questions along
the way, but we'll definitely
prioritize answering anyone's
questions at that point. Um,
just to make sure that
everybody feels comfortable and
everyone feels comfortable
asking whatever questions they
feel like asking. Right.
It's okay to ask all of the
questions because
that's what we're here for.
We're here to answer them.
Dan: Plus, I think we all like
talking about it.
I always want people to ask
questions because it's just fun.
It's just fun to talk about all
this stuff for me, you know?
And, um, it's a. I like it can
be anxiety inducing.
It was, it was for me, uh,
certainly like getting, getting
started and, um, the, you know,
getting started with open
source, especially, especially
contributing to like, to
projects of people who you don't
know the people, right.
You don't know the maintainers
and everything.
Um, it doesn't have to be at, I
think the, me, I think
the way that you get over it.
The best way to get over
that anxiety is to, is to just
kind of get started, you
know, um, uh, ask questions, you
know, all of that stuff.
And then, and then, and then we
can kind of dive in.
And so that's why that's, that's
gonna be our process
again this year, you know? Um,
well this event
should be fun. Uh, like on the
24th, that Beck
is running and kind of hang out
and then, um, Going into October
for Virtual Coffee, you know,
we'll, we'll, we'll have some,
we'll have some more specific
events, uh, set up and some more
things kind of, kind of go in
that we'll a little bit later.
Um, in September, I guess,
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: once we figured out what
they all are.
Bekah: I think one of the cool
things too, about how
much we've grown in the last
year is that we have a lot
more maintainers with us year
than we did last year.
who have their own projects or
who have jobs at open
source, I'm working on open
source projects.
And so it's been great to kind
of see that evolution of like,
oh, look, they participated last
year and got their first PRS.
And now they're like on, on
this. Open source project
in their company. And, you know,
they're, they
bring with them that amazing
experience of like knowing
what that feels like and being
able to help new people.
And there's a lot of, um, great
projects and
also really meaningful projects
out there too.
So going to be really exciting
to see much the
variety has grown as well.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. That's a
great point. Um, and.
Well, I guess adding onto that,
one of that, another thing that
we have new this year for us is,
uh, some, some team, a team
of people that are helping out,
um, actually run the events
and, you know, run, run these
challenges and stuff like
that to our monthly challenge
team, um, especially it has
been, has been kicking butt. Uh,
I've been helping to get
this rolling in September and,
um, So I just want to shout
out to, to everybody there too.
Um, because that's
been really cool. It's been cool
to have like a
sort of a larger, um, I dunno,
group of people to generate
ideas, bounce ideas off of, and,
and you know, everything.
So that's, that's really fun.
I'm excited about that.
Bekah: year at this time, we
didn't, we hadn't
started monthly challenges that
started in November.
Um, with our blog challenge. So
it's really cool too, to
see like where we've almost made
that full circle of a
year of monthly challenges and
then next month, we're just
going to know, the last couple
of months of having other
people step up the game with
monthly challenge and, and
have things thought through has
been, you know, a really great
way to show how much support we
have from the community that
allows us to do extra things and
things that are meaningful.
And, you know, I, I got a
message from one of the members.
Wait today is still August. So
we did healthy
habits for healthy devs. And I
checked in with
one of the members to see how
they were doing.
And they said, well, this
monthly challenge is getting me
through this month because it's
requiring like, deliberately
thinking about my health and how
I can turn off work and how
I can create healthy habits. And
I just thought, you know,
what a wonderful example of how.
The work that our members
provide to support us, goes to
support everybody and
those meaningful moments make it
all worth it.
Kirk: Yeah. I think part of what
makes
this whole experience so good.
It is.
mean, it's obviously a great
thing to work with to like
provide an experience for them.
But it's also been a really
cool to see people who have not
had the experience to
maybe like provide the support
in many ways in this space,
get a chance to do that. You
know, there's, there's so
many folks now in the different
teams we have, sometimes I,
hard for me to keep track of all
the different issues we
have because we have all these
different channels where people
are doing amazing things.
everyone's saying like, oh,
this is the person that would
have done something like this.
And they're doing such amazing
jobs. And.
You know, I feel like a big, a
big part of what I like
about Virtual Coffee is that
like, this is like, this is
no one's job, but also in the
sense that for a lot of
us, it's the first time we were
trying to do something
and all we really had was the
belief that we could do it.
And like the belief that we can
get support if we needed to.
And that to me has been, you
know, super empowering.
Having a space where you can to
help other people and try
and work with other people and
try and initiative where
you can feel comfortable with
making mistakes and having to
do things over and not having to
be perfect on zoom or, you know,
just that's, that's hard to find
sometimes in real life land,
like you feel like the work you
have to do everything perfectly.
sometimes even just like
interpersonal relationships.
That feels really healthy. And
that feels almost like as
important as like who were on
the receiving it, being able
to help people on the giving end
has been really good.
And I mean, the big discovery,
which I guess isn't really
surprising in retrospect because
it like why people want to give
back, they want to help, you
know, our communities here.
Cause it's just like, oh, this
is just a nice space
where I get to help folks out.
And, um,
Dan: Yeah. I mean, I love that I
was going
to segue into some other stuff,
but do we have any final,
like Hacktoberfest thoughts? Um,
other than. We're excited.
Bekah: Well, I just want to say
too, just looking
back at how much I've grown
personally in the last year,
learning from everybody. Um, Uh,
you know, as we're
approaching this and we're doing
this event and all
of these things, think last year
I things more in black
and white, like there was
success or there was failure.
And I think this year for me,
it's, it's not ever about that.
It's about the growth. Am I
growing?
You know, what am I doing to
push myself forward and
to support the other people?
think that's just a Testament
to.
The community that's here is
supporting everyone
because it isn't, it it's not
success or failure.
We're all moving forward. We're
all growing and we're
growing together, um, and
growing in different ways.
And so I think that, I'm, I'm
very that we up August with
healthy habits for healthy devs,
because it gives a much better
perspective going into some
really, you know, event heavy.
Dan: I think that's a good
point. I think you might be sub
tweeting me right now, but I
make my own choices. Yeah.
I I'll echo that. I mean, it's,
uh, this
community is so great. And the,
the we've sort of
naturally, uh, focused on, on
mental health, I think, um,
from the beginning, you know,
without, without any, without
any sort of decision, right. It
was a natural thing
because, um, the people here.
Care.
Um, you know, and we see over
and over again, uh, everybody
knows and has experienced I'm
sure, uh, you know,
burnout and, uh, overworking and
all of that stuff.
Um, uh, the fact that our
community is a community of
people who like, who care so
much about each other, that,
you know, giving support for
that, uh, with mental
health just kind of comes
naturally for everybody.
And it, And especially, I, I w I
want to especially shout
out to Kirk here, because this
is one of the things that,
you know, that he injected into
all of our thought
processes at the beginning. Um,
this is while we were
maybe not practicing it, um,
this, you know, in this time
of year, maybe September last
year, we were pulling
together a documentation and
resources and the website
for active professed and. And
Kirk's, I just love,
I just loved Kirk's thoughts on
all of it.
And, and the, the focus on the
mental health and the
taking a break and the, you
know, all that stuff, it's,
it can be easy to get, even with
volunteer stuff, it can
be easy to get caught up. Um,
and, uh, and everything,
you know, and like Bekah said,
the black and whiteness
of everything, you know, anyway,
the mental health
focus of our, of our, um,
community is amazing.
And I, never really put it
together like that, but I think
that's a great point that August
was sort of a breather month
that, you know, in a, in a
mental health check-in month.
Um, and I don't know, it's a
good, it's a great thing to
keep in mind, moving forward,
moving forward for of us.
Even if I'm not always going to
be good at doing what's that
Kirk: Why Dan and Bekah not good
at taking breaks? No.
Who would think that.
Bekah: into this?
Kirk: You, you would identify
with this?
but don't think you're not here.
This podcast could
be called like people with
letting go issues,
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: but it's okay. That's what
we have
The community for to remind us
like it's it's okay.
Bekah: frozen soundtrack.
Kirk: Oh, I still haven't
watched it.
Bekah: you said, let it go.
Kirk: I've never seen Frozen.
Not one or two.
Heard good things. I'll wait for
the live action.
Dan: Yeah. That's all right. Um,
so.
I, um, I think I said at the top
maybe, but this is the
last episode of season three of
our podcast and we're kind
of wrapping up and things. So I
wanted to, before we end
this episode, um, I dunno, shout
out some, some different things
that have happened over either
the last, you know, during
the last season or the last, um,
year with Virtual Coffee.
Um, so I guess first the, uh,
podcast  we
passed 4,000 downloads. Um, but
you know, total for our
podcasts, uh, a little bit ago.
And I just, I think
that's amazing. And I wanted to,
say
thank you to everybody who's
been listening.
Uh, and everybody who's joined.
Bekah: on and told their story.
Dan: Yes. Uh, included Kirk is,
uh,
you know, repeat guest,  and,
um, yeah, it's really great.
It's, it's crazy that there's so
many people I've
listened to, to our podcast. I
don't know.
Um, it's hard to really
comprehend 4,000 people or
4,000, you know, listens I
guess, or whatever.
But, um, I just, I dunno, I
wanted to shout that
out and say, thank you.
Kirk: Am I the first person to
repeat on the podcast.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Yeah.
Bekah: co-host
Kirk: the Martin
Bekah: or sometimes cohost.
Kirk: the secret co-host only,
you only get access to me if
you listen to enough of it. So
if you're listening.
Dan: Um, One thing Kirk said
earlier about, um, just the
community kind of work together.
Made me think of the
coworking room as well. Um, a
co-working
room for anybody who is
listening, who doesn't
know is a, uh, a room it's a
slack channel in a room
in Virtual Coffee, psych that,
um, it's basically,
and always on zoom meeting. And
so people can join the
meeting and work together and
hang out together.
Kirk, I think, like you visit
often. Do you want to
come here?
Kirk: live in the court. Uh,
Dan: can you, can
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: about it a little bit?
Kirk: well, I mean, first I
think like the important thing
is to say, shout out to Dan for
making the coworking room.
Um, it,
Dan: I don't know. We're
shouting out other
people in this sector.
Kirk: I, yeah, but like from
the, from the slack side,
it looks like very simple. You
hit join again.
But I know like you're doing
like several magics to get
that all working smoothly. So, I
mean, you were sincerely
rewarded for your efforts. I
think the folks that use the
room really, really value it.
Um, for a lot of members, there
are a couple of our members.
Sometimes it's difficult
for them to get to regular
coffees, I've had warranty
folks say, but I know I can
always jump in coworking
and there's usually someone
there and sometimes that's my
Virtual Coffee for the week. Uh,
so that's really good.
And, you know, it's, it's just
become, it's just another
space, another platform for VC
members to interact with each
other and provide support. Uh,
sometimes people will
have questions and helping
pairing, and they're like,
Hey, you know, if no one's in
the co-working room, jump in.
Or, and then the coworking room
becomes like a little and learn
session where, know, everyone's
just like, trying to help the
person do the problem, but also
watching people kind of
pair up and go through school.
So it's, it's got a lot of
purposes, but it's, it's
definitely I know the members
really appreciate really enjoy.
Um, shout out also to Meg, who
I think also there's a lot of
work in there and, um, Yeah,
it's, I think it quickly rose up
the ranks to become like
one of the coolest parts of VC
who had coworking helping
pairing just like a, this is.
Dan: Yeah, the and I feel  like
they kind of are almost, uh,
you had to work together, right?
Help and pairing.
have a help and pairing channel,
you know, Just
very often, see somebody asks a
question and somebody
answered, Hey, I have a minute.
Let's jump into
the coworking room. Um, which is
amazing.
I, uh, we were going to add our,
like the, to our newsletter.
We're going to add the longest
meeting of the month or longest,
and not meeting with the
longest, uh, coworking session.
Right. So can last, you know,
somebody starts a session.
The session lasts until the last
person leaves. Right.
So it doesn't necessarily have
to be that person
staying on the whole time.
Right. And so.
Uh, subscribe to your newsletter
if you want to see it the
longest and August, but I, that
made me want to look it up what
the historical longest one. And
so it was, um, 789
minutes, um, on, on the, at the,
end of July, July 24th.
Um, so that, you know, I mean,
that's, whatever
it is, I did this
Kirk: No, don't go for it to
hours.
It doesn't sound as cool. Okay.
So it sounds pretty cool.
Dan: hours and, uh, yeah. Yeah.
That's, uh, it's, uh,
it, it's pretty cool. And it's
just cool that
somebody, like some of our
friends were just
hanging out for that long. You
know what I mean?
Um, I love it. We, we have, I
don't know,
almost 350 sessions have
happened since we started it.
February, maybe they're at the
beginning of the year.
Um, and, uh, it's been cool. So
if you are a member and
haven't checked it out, go ahead
and check it out.
And, uh, if you aren't a Virtual
Coffee member,
this is just one of the many
things you're missing.
Um, the, what else? We got
podcast as
room sponsorships. Bekah, do you
wanna tell
us about sponsorships?
Bekah: Sure. I'll tell you about
sponsorships.
Um, so you can sponsor Virtual
Coffee, help us keep the
coffee brewing, um, on GitHub.
I'll have a link in the show
notes for that, but if you just
go to GitHub.com/Virtual-Coffee.
There'll be a little heart
sponsor button and there's
different tiers there for
different ways that you can,
um, contribute, um, to Virtual
Coffee, to make sure that we
can cover some of the costs that
are, that, that are
incurred to run Virtual Coffee.
And I think maybe we'll.
Put something up there. We'll be
talking
more about having a
Hacktoberfest sponsor too.
So if you're listening to this
and you know, somebody who'd be
interested and sponsoring all of
our fun, please just reach out
to us at hello@virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Yep. Um, we have, we have
on our home on a, on like
on our website website. Um, we
have a section
of our sponsors too. So you can
see who has supported
us so far that we have like 26,
26 sponsors, um, and I want
to say thank you to everybody
who has sponsored us so far.
Well, um, yeah. So is there
anything else
we wanted to, we wanted to cover
before we wrap up.
Bekah: I just want to say thank
you to everybody that has
donated their time and their
effort, um, resources to making
sure that everybody has been
supported over the last year
that we've been doing this. You
know, it's still an amazing
thing in my mind that here we
are a year later, closer and
together and grown so much. And
we're able to do this again.
So you for everyone for making
sure that that
got to happen, right.
Kirk: Yeah. I think, um, I just
want to
say I, I, I still get a lot of.
I don't know.
I still, a lot of people ask me
like, Hey, you know, what
happens when VC gets too big? Or
what are we going to
do when PC gets super big? And
I'm like, well, I mean,
you know, every community has
growing pains, I think what
makes me feel really happy and,
um, really positive is no,
every, every time I come into
VC, I still see people being
really, uh, warm and caring. I
still see people
supporting each other and the
heavy channel.
I still see people supporting
each other and helping pairing.
And I think the cool thing is
there's a lot of
folks who have been here since
last Hacktoberfest.
You know, you have folks who
have been here for
over a year with us, and that's
amazing, but we also have a lot
of new folks, know, folks with
been here a month, two months,
three months, and they are.
Enjoying it, loving it and
then making new friendships and
supporting other people and
being supportive themselves. And
I don't know that just,
it just always makes me, me feel
really good every time
I see someone who hasn't been
here that long, but when we
do our Friday gratitude or
Wednesday shout outs, like,
Hey, I really liked this space.
And I really liked the people
here and I want to help out.
And, um, that makes me
think that, you know, they're
still doing that.
Dan: Yeah, I would, uh, I, I
would just echo both
what you've all said. You know,
this community is
amazing and I'm very glad and
proud to be part of it.
And the members. What makes you
know,
what make it amazing. And, um, I
don't know.
I'm looking forward to another
year.
I, I am very, very pumped about
Hacktoberfest this year.
I'm very pumped about the things
we have going on.
The people that are going to be
involved I've yet
to brew up exactly how I'm going
to, you know, try to.
Murder myself at the end of the
month, trying to redo
something, but I'm sure I'll
think of something.
And I'm pumped about that to you
honestly, because there
was a lot of fun last year. Um,
so yeah, I guess, I
guess that's pretty much it. Um,
if you want to keep up to
date with us, uh, you know,
subscribe to our newsletter,
um, follow us on Twitter at, uh,
Virtual Coffee
IO, follow us somewhere.
Bekah: To check out our site.
We've got lots of
good stuff on there.
Dan: Yeah, we have a dope
website.
It's at Virtual Coffee.io. Um,
subscribe on your podcast.
Software of choice. If you have
not done that yet,
what are you supposed to say?
Hit that something about,
Bekah: hit like, no, as for
YouTube, you can
Dan: oh
Bekah: our YouTube channel too.
Cause we've got one
Dan: Oh yeah. We have a YouTube
channel.
We have a YouTube channel. So
subscribe to that.
Bekah: on the podcast and leave
us a message.
It's always so great. When we
get messages or
reviews about our podcasts, when
they're nice.
We never got a mean one. So
don't leave a mean
one, but ones are good.
Dan: Nice. All five stars only
as Jason Concepcion would
say on his podcast. Um, yes, we
would
love to hear from you. Um, if
you have suggestions or,
um, questions, comments hit us
up on Twitter, slack, anything.
Um, and yeah, I guess we will
see you next season.
Next season will drop, uh,
beginning of October.
So we're going to take you to
take a month off podcast
and we will be back a season.
Uh, in October.
Kirk: Bye for me, definitely.
Dan: All right. Bye everyone.
Bekah: Bye. Thank you for
listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
Ott and Bekah Hawrot
Weigel and edited by Dan Ott. If
you have questions or
comments, you can hit us up on
Twitter at VirtualCoffeeIO,
or you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
plus you can sign up for our
newsletter to find out what
Virtual Coffee's been up to on
our website at virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Please subscribe to our
podcast and be sure
to leave us a review. Thanks for
listening.
And we'll see you next week.