Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode one of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. We're so
excited to be back here for
season four. I am Bekah, and
this is a podcast that features
members of the Virtual Coffee
community. Virtual Coffee is an
intimate group of developers at
all stages of their coding
journey. And they're here on
this podcast, sharing their
stories
and what they've learned, we're
here to share it with you. Here
with me today is my cohost Dan.
Dan: Um, yeah, this is going to
be a great season. Uh, we have a
bunch of really good guests
lined up. They're all Virtual
Coffee
members. We're going to hear
about entrepreneur
entrepreneurship,
entrepreneurship. That doesn't
sound right. How do you say that
word? Entrepreneurship,
Bekah: Entre entrepreneurship
Dan: entrepreneurship.
Bekah: also say Reeses and
that's not right either.
Dan: Uh, we're going to hear
about building businesses,
machine learning, uh,
accessibility, you know, civic
tech, um, and, and just a lot of
people's journeys and thoughts
on, on all this stuff. And it's
going to be a great season. Um,
in general, if you'd like to
learn more about Virtual Coffee,
um, or if you'd like to, to
support us via sponsorship, you
can find out more, you can find
out really everything you need
to
know on VirtualCoffee.io. Um, we
have now. A lot of good
resources
about joining the Virtual Coffee
about, um, you know, what we do
there, and you can subscribe to
our newsletter. You can
subscribe
to our podcast, you can get to
our Twitter, um, all of that
stuff on Virtual Coffee.io. Um,
today we're starting off season
four with Jessi Shakarian and,
um, we had a really great
conversation with her. Um, Jessi
has had. A really interesting
journey. Um, and she does, she
does UX and UI design with,
which
is a user experience and user
interface, um, design and
development, and, um, is a
really great conversation. She
talks
about how, um, she has, she has
different passions. Directly, or
at least originally weren't
directly related to work, but
how, if you're passionate about
something and you mix it into
your career path, that actually
can be a really know, a really
successful way to,
Bekah: cool way to be able to
bring energy to what you're
doing
for work, right? Like your work
does not have to be your energy,
but you can bring energy into
your work. And I thought that
was
a really fun way to think about
it because I haven't, I haven't
heard it talked about in that
way.
Dan: Yeah, exactly. Um, she has
a very unique story and, um, a
unique perspective on, on her
career. And I think on, in the
dev world in general. So, um, it
was just a really great
conversation.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think that
the rest of our episodes will
bring
something for everyone. And
we're very happy to be back for
season
four. So thanks for listening.
We start every episode of the
podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question.
Today's question is what is your
favorite
magical or mythological animal?
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Hi, I'm Bekah. I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And my favorite magical or
mythological animal is I can't
remember anything. I would like
to say unicorn, but I am not
convinced that there's no such
thing as unicorns. Um, so
Pegasus
is Pegasus a unicorn that flies.
Cause I feel
Dan: I don't think a Pegasus is
a unicorn. I think it's just a
horse that flies.
Bekah: my favorite mythological
animal is unicorn Pegasus.
That's
it.
Dan: I'm sure there's a name for
that somewhere. I'm sure
somebody
has written a name anyway. Hi,
I'm Dan. I am a front end
developer in Cleveland and, um,
Hm. Yeah, I don't have a good
answer for this. I did like, um,
I like the Griffins. Is that,
um,
is that the one in Harry Potter
with the it's like a bird with,
Bekah: Gryffendor
Dan: um,
Bekah: isn't it is that who
Dan: No, no, no. Like the birds,
they it's like a lion, you know,
body and a bird head and it has
wings. I don't know. I think
that's what it is. Uh, you know,
they, they like rescue it, you
know, it's like it like attacks
somebody and all that stuff.
Anyway. Um, I used to play Magic
The Gathering back in the day
and
there was, uh, there was a
whole, like, there's a bunch of
them in
there. You know, I had likea
whole... I was like them.
They're
cool. So that's, that's gonna be
one answer, assuming that I pick
the right name Griffin. I think
that, I think that's it.
Jessi: Hi, I'm Jessi. I'm a UX
designer in Los Angeles. And
let's see. Hmm. I feel like I'm
going to go with Pegasus just
because pegasus was always my
favorite. Like, I don't know. I
don't know if you guys remember
the, the Hercules movie, the
Disney one and pegasus was just
the best. I just loved him.
Dan: I actually have not ever
watched it. I tried watching it.
With my kids, because I want to,
you know, like, uh, and they
were, Ben was not that
interested in it at the time. So
I'm going
to give it a shot again. Cause I
was enjoying it. You know, it's
like one of those, you know, you
got four or five-year-old and
uh,
it's like, we're here mess with
whether they'll actually pay
attention to something that,
that is good. But I'm glad that
you
said that's good. Cause I'm not
trying to swing back to that
movie again. I have this whole
list of movies that like, I want
him to watch so that I can
watch.
Bekah: It's got a solid
soundtrack. I remember watching
it when I babysat in high school
and I still remember a lot of
the
soundtrack.
Jessi: It's really. Yeah. And
there's a lot of like, it's,
it's
funny for adults too. Cause I
recently rewatched it maybe a
year ago and I was like, Oh,
this movie's still hilarious.
It's
still, there's a reason why it's
still at the top of my, one of
my
favorites, Disney movies.
Dan: awesome. Um, okay. I looked
it up. Uh, it's an Alicorn.
Bekah: Yes, I looked it up too,
or Uni peg or a Pegacorn.
Dan: I also unipeg is really
awful. Yeah. That's, that's a
really bad one. Um, UniPegasus
is a very unimaginative one.
That's
showing up here too.
Bekah: Yeah,
Dan: I think Alicorn is the
right. I think that's, I like
that I think
Bekah: it needs its own name.
Cause these are really Pegasus
is
like very good name. It sounds
excellent. But all of these
sound?
Dan: Unipeg All right, Unipeg
that's Bekah's favorite animal.
Bekah: Yup.
Jessi: You heard it here first,
first?
Dan: That's right.
Bekah: Oh, Jessi. Thank you so
much for being here with us
today. Uh, we always love to get
started with your origin story.
So where have you been and how
did you get to this point in
your
career?
Jessi: Um, it's I have a very
non-traditional path into, into
tech, um, prior to. The
pandemic. I was going back to
school to be
a medical lab tech and, and
endemic cabin. And I moved home
and I needed to start over. So I
took a career assessment to see
what else I could do. And, um, I
got a 100% match with
programming, which was super
weird. And I was like,
programming. Like, I don't know.
Okay. Let's try it because I
don't have anything else going
on. So I started teaching myself
how to code and, uh, by the end
of 2020, I was freelancing. Um,
I
just, basically, it was like
HTML, CSS and JavaScript and
took
some freelancing jobs and pretty
quickly realized that I loved
everything that happened before
it was time to code. And So
that's when I sort of switched
gears into, into UX, but I still
continue to use all my
development stuff as well. Yeah,
that's kind of how I ended up
here.
Bekah: So Prior to taking that
assessment, what was your
experience with tech and
computers?
Jessi: None. All I knew about
tech is that people code like
were coders and that was it.
Bekah: that's awesome
Dan: So, did your experience
match your, you know, your, uh,
your perspective, your pre
coding perspective?
Jessi: It totally blew it away,
honestly, because I was like, oh
my God, there's a whole world.
And then I pretty soon realized
that like, oh, every company is
a tech company now. So that's
really like a game changer and
it's up to you, what you want to
make of it. And I've never seen
an industry like that before.
Bekah: That is such a good
point. I love that. And I also
came from
a very non-technical background.
I was maybe the most technical
English teacher. So I taught
people about presentations in
integrating technology, into the
classroom and nothing to do with
coding. And so it was a, there
there's a real. I think
different
perspective almost if you don't
have that background, because
there's a lot of assumptions in
what people say about
technology.
Even now that sometimes I have
to ask, like, like, I would love
to
know, know what you are talking
about, but I don't have that
experience with that. And so
there's a lot of different
conversations, but good
conversations. I think that
happened as a result of that.
Okay, so now you did this pivot
into UX UI. I think it's a
pivot, but maybe you don't. So
I'll let
you talk about that for a
second. I think that when you
first
started coming to Virtual Coffee
is when I started to hear you
talk more about that. So what
got you interested in that
aspect of
things and actually, could you
define UX and UI first?
Jessi: Uh, sure. So, so UX is
like the organization of the
site. So which pages go, where
and where does the content go?
That it makes sense. What's the
research on like, who uses this
website? The UI? is more like,
where does the button go? How
does, um, particular components
work? Like there's still visual
components in UX, but also like
how those visual components
actually work. For the user, I
guess would probably be, um, a
way to describe it actually like
it's one of those things, the UX
versus UI, like comes up all the
time in like UX circles and
it's,
it's very like, it's very
interesting. Um, so yeah, I
actually started in Virtual
Coffee around the holidays last
year, and then now I'm still
doing dev stuff and like, You
know, this community is so
great. And then I started
falling out of
love with like JavaScript pretty
quickly. 'Cause I was like, I
don't know about this stuff like
programming, that that career
assessment was wrong basically.
And then spent quite a bit of
time, basically kinda networked
my way into an apprenticeship at
a design agency, like local to
me and. And then, so once I
started
kind of getting in the groove
with that, I was like, man, like
I should come back to Virtual
Coffee. Cause it was really fun,
but then it wasn't sure it was
like, but there's so many devs
and not too many like UX people.
So would it still be okay. And
that's what I kind of started,
like messaging you bekah of
like,
can I come back you're like,
duh. Yes.
Bekah: That's not what I said
for the record.
Jessi: Okay. I put, I put an LA
twist on that.
Dan: That's really interesting
though. And that like the
separation between that is, is,
like you said, it's like really
blurry. And even between
development, you know, I would
say that, um, anybody who's
developing is probably is like
making some UX decisions. So UX
is like user experience. Right.
And, and making some decisions
whether or not, you know, so
depends on the project, I
suppose, uh, what, how much is
dictated right to the developer.
Um, but even at the lowest
level,
you're, you're still affecting,
you know, somebody's going to
use
the thing that you're making.
Right. Um, and so when you're
coding, you know, you have, uh,
an idea of what the experience
is
going to be for the user and
what the interface, right. So UI
is
user interface or what the
interface is going to look like.
And, um, last times when you're
coding, then you get stuck into,
okay, I know what I want this
thing to do. You know, and it's
like, then it, you know, it can
be hard to actually get it to do
it or whatever that is the part
maybe that you I'm putting words
in your mouth, but like that you
didn't enjoy as much, but like
actually laying out the
experience for a user and like
how things should happen and you
know, what, what people should
see, stuff like that is what
you, uh, were more interested
in. Is
that right?
Jessi: I guess it was more like,
um, okay, so. So, like I had a
freelance project where I worked
like end to end. And so I, I, I,
in my twenties I wrote a lot. So
I, I spent, I spent upselled a
little bit and was like, oh, we
can write some copies, you know,
do some content strategy work.
And so we started from beginning
to end and, um, it was more
like, oh, like, how do I, I
don't
understand a website, right? Or
an app or whatever. And how do,
how do i cat-- almost categorize
and it gets very like nerdy,
right? Like, you know, what is
the hierarchy? Like? What's the
most important thing. What's
less of a priority. Um, and
things
like that. And that helps me
sort of understand the whole
picture.
And that's when I was like, oh,
this is really interesting. And
so I thought that I was like,
yeah, okay. Like UX all in. And
then I was like, but. Yeah.
right. Like you talked about
like, it's like, it's like an
onion and the layers of like,
okay, there's UX, but then you
go deeper than that and the UX
needs
to be coded, but then the visual
design needs to play a part just
as important. And is the, is the
context, correct? Like in your,
in your content strategy, like
there's so many components that
I
feel like I never left coding in
some ways, because I'm always
still thinking about it. How
does, how do you implement a
design change on a, on a coding
level, right? Can you implement
that, you know, legacy code and
all sorts of things, you know,
if
you don't have the source code
than what you know. And so the
skills I learned as a coder
still helped me in my work today
because. I'm now have a more
holistic approach to design.
Like
if I, I can see if, if, if a
client said, oh, I really like
this on a website, but I can
tell like, oh, is that
JavaScript? Or,
oh, I think that might be React.
And so research that, you know,
and so it still provides so
much, so much value and the
skills that
I learned, the analytical skills
problem-solving skills and on a
coding level, like I've never.
anything quite like that before,
if that makes sense, like, it's
been invaluable.
Dan: Yeah, that's awesome. I can
see how that, uh, the experience
would be really helpful. Maybe
even crucial to somebody who's
going to be, um, making high
level UX decisions, you know,
uh,
for, especially for websites and
stuff, because like you said,
there's, there's so many things
that go into all of those
decisions, you know, and if you
only have one piece of the
puzzle
in your mind, Well, you'll be
limited, I suppose. Uh, you
know,
about the decisions you can make
and things like that. I think
that's really cool. Um, can you
talk, you said you, you got an
apprenticeship, um, with a
studio and could you talk a
little bit
about that experience? Um, now
I'm asking more like from not
coding or not the like UX, like
what you're actually doing, but
like how the, how did the
apprenticeship like thing work?
Because I haven't talked to very
many people. Who've actually
gone
through a formal apprenticeship
and I'm very interested. about
that, just kind of talk about.
Jessi: Yeah. So are you, um,
there's a local, I have a local
UX group and, um, so one of the
people who run that UX group,
um,
they have a design agency. And
so, um, I sort of networked my
way into that local group of,
of, I was looking for a UX job
and
there was a recruiter and he was
like, oh, Hey, you live in our
area. You should join our group.
And I was like, oh cool. I had
no
idea. There was a us group here.
And so, you know, as I was
hanging out on that group, you
know, it was like on discord.
And
I was looking up, you know, on
LinkedIn trying to find some
stuff about like, who does these
different parts of UX? And I
ended up seeing one of the
people in our group, but I was
like, oh
my God, Hey, that's that's her.
And so I messaged her and was
like, Hey, you know, I, I saw
that you do some UX stuff. Like
that's really interesting. And
so she was like, Hey, you know,
I,
I, I run the design agency and
we have this apprenticeship
program.
Um, and so why don't you fill
out an application? Um, then I
got in
and, um, yeah, so I did about
six months of apprenticeship
where we
worked on different projects. So
some were personal projects. For
anybody who doesn't know, like
I'm now obsessed with chess
because of Queen's Gambit. And
so that was one project. And
then I
had some other things like the
information architecture
conference, which I worked on,
um, last year and now I'm back
on
this year. And so I learned, uh,
I gained a lot of skills by
being
an apprentice and working on
these projects and, and sort of
getting like a, a hand, like a
more real world experience about
how to do UX. Sort of brought in
like my coding experience
because
my boss is not a coder, so she'd
be like, oh, so wait, what do
you
think about ghost? You know, and
I, I want to move all my stuff
to
ghost see that. So then we talk
about that and then, you know,
so, so yeah, and then my
apprenticeship was six months.
So
this was January when I started.
And then by June I was done like
officially, like, you know,
promoted to a UX designer. And
then by July, uh, we got a
contract. That was just a good
fit for me. So, um, I started
that and that was more about
like
incorporating some machine
learning aspects and I had
already been learning Python.
Um, and so, yeah, that's
basically
been, been my, my journey, of my
apprenticeship. And now I have
two about to be two practices of
my own as, as they are starting.
Um, there are journeys into UX,
so that's true.
Dan: that's very cool. Yeah. Um,
Bekah: that was kind of what you
needed because it sounds like
before, when you were doing web
dev kind of stuff, it was, it
wasn't a good fit. And then that
changed seems like it was what
you needed to kind of, you know,
get you excited about what you
were doing.
Jessi: Yeah. You know, that's
the funny thing is the chess
stuff is
what brought me back to coding
because like they, the. Chess
engines and like the bots and
things they're, they're very
good
at particular things, but
there's a lot of like usability
things
that I really have a problem
with. And so I was like, okay,
I'm going to learn to code
again, specifically to deal with
this.
And I need to use Python and,
you know, some understand some
components of machine learning
to do that. And so that was. I
was
really nervous about it, but,
um, it ended up being really
fun. And
partly because I already had the
experience of Java, so maybe
jumped ship. Wasn't my bag, like
my best choice of their first
language, but it helps so much
learning Python because I
already
had the, like those fundamental
skills. And so. That was really
great because I was like, oh,
this coding is really fun. So it
became like another piece.
Right. And then I'm like, okay,
so we
got the UX stuff. We were doing
coding somewhere, coding stuff,
like, okay, cool. So I can kind
of sit with this and this feels
good. Right. It's just, it's
just about like, what's the
language
that's going to click with you.
And that is something that I did
not understand when I first
started. Cause I, I really did
did not like JavaScript. It was,
it was just stress me out so
much. But I'll turn it around
back in Python. I'm like, oh,
cool. It was awesome. Should
have chosen Python first.
Bekah: I think that investment
that comes from when you're
solving a problem, that you care
about goes a really long way.
And
to allow me to become interested
in what you're working on. I
mean, for sure you could do
projects that you're not
interested in the con in the
content or, or what you're
working with, but I find like,
it gets really exciting when
you're
like, I love this thing and I
know I can make it better,
right?
Jessi: And it also becomes like,
I know I can make it better, but
also no one else is going to
make it better. At least in the
way
that, you know, you will. So
then it'd be kind of becomes
like, I
kind of have to do this. And
that's what it felt like. I was
like, okay, these chess engines
have some usability components
that I really, really don't
like. And they're clearly made
by
programmers, like for. Um, chess
players who play a lot and I'm a
beginner. So this isn't really
like beginner oriented. And that
was my sort of initial quandary,
right. Of like, okay, I have to,
how do I fix this? Okay. I got
to start, go back and learn
Python.
Okay. But Yeah, that, that
really helps, like knowing you
have
something passionate about that
you'd want to spend a hundred
hours or whatever, working on
it. Like it makes a big
difference.
When I started, I didn't know.
Cause I was just kind of feeling
around in the dirt going okay.
Where do I start? A web dev.
Okay. Let's start there. Okay.
Dan: Yeah, I think, I think the.
You know, there, there's,
there's
a bunch of different pieces
obviously to, to learning, uh,
especially when you're learning
on your own like this and, you
know, finding a language that
you're comfortable in is part of
it, for sure. But I imagine...
what I've experienced myself and
notice through other people, as,
you know, having a project that
you care about, like you're like
you guys were just saying, um,
goes such a long way, right?
Because, because then it doesn't
matter if like, it doesn't
matter as much if the syntax is
weird in
whatever language you're using
or whatever, because if you,
you,
you, you know, if you're excited
about the project, then it's
just
like smooth everything out so
much. But for me, at least, um,
it seems like maybe for you to,
um, the, the, like, I dunno,
just
the being in there, you know,
like who cares, how many hours
you're doing on it. You know
what I mean? Like that sort of
feeling
when you get in that groove,
it's really cool. It's very
exciting.
Jessi: Yeah, no, it is. And
there's something really kind of
fun about like, okay. So
everybody, like in, in the UX
world pretty much knows me as
like the chess lady. And so
there's something really fun
about like how people know me
that way. And I'm like, okay, so
personal branding check done.
Right. But also that it becomes
like, well, if people get hooked
on. You can't, you can't fake
passion. Right. And that's,
that's a driving force because
things need to get done. And if
you're passionate about it, then
it will go a long way and
everybody will notice it. And
the other people who are I've
found
her, like, I don't know anything
about chess, but like, it's
really cool watching this
journey. Right. And that just
becomes really, really fun. And
I'm like, oh, okay. So it's
motivating, right? I'm not, I'm
not, um, I'm not being boring or
whatever, you know what I mean?
Like, like, I guess it's social
media, you know, if you don't
want to follow somebody, you
don't have to, but at the same
time who, who it brings to you
who gravitates to you? That also
becomes really interesting
because it's people I probably
never would have thought to talk
to or anything like that. If
that makes sense.
Dan: Absolutely. And it's, it's
one of those things too, where
since it's very clearly a, an
organic thing for you, you know,
um, everybody can tell that, you
know, you can, everybody can
tell
you're, you're passionate as
well, but it's. You mentioned
personal branding and that's
always, you know, uh, can be a
weird place to be, but like the,
um, I think leaning into
something you're passionate
about, like, this is it's, it's
always a smart move, you know?
And it's, I don't know, I kinda
lost my point. I was going to
say something about, um, He, you
can
tell when somebody wants to
like, wants to make a personal
brand,
but they don't have a thing like
that, you know, and therefore
forcing it or whatever. Um,
yeah. Right. And, um, I don't
know.
It's, it's, it's cool. And, and
I think this is good advice for
some, for other people, you
know, it's finding something
like that
and, and finding ways to use it,
to learn more or to spread your,
you know, spread your networking
or all of that stuff, all the
stuff that you've been doing.
It's very cool. And like chess
has. Well, it just got, I don't
know, popular, not popular is
not
the right word, but like, it
just got some press, chess just
got
some press right. With the, uh,
Queens gambit, you know, so I
was
like, people are kind of like
More back into it again, you
know, um, which is, which is
always interesting to see too.
Um, so I dunno. It's, it's very
cool.
Jessi: Yeah. And I will say that
I remember talking to a hiring
manager who said that he, they
hired some developers who made a
website about sandwiches. You
know what I mean? Like okay.
Like, That dude just loved
sandwiches, but it worked
because
it showed on his, you know, on
his portfolio. And so it's like,
that's why I loved it. Like,
like before I started playing
chess, I
thought it was boring. And you
had to be like really smart to
understand it. And I was just
like, oh, I'm not that
intelligent to do it. But really
it's just about knowing what
you're yeah like, what your
passion is, but like, how do you
use that for your strengths and
your weaknesses? to show others,
to show hiring managers, what
you can do. It's just, it's just
a
vessel, right? It's and it
should be the thing that you
really
love.
Bekah: I think it's such great
advice too, because we hear a
lot
of people say like, you have to
be excited about tech. Uh, and I
think that you can be excited
about tech, but you can be
excited about something else,
and use tech to showcase that
thing.
And I think that that can be a
really great approach because
you're right. Like when you're
excited about something and
other
people get excited around you, I
don't know. It just creates this
like amazing energy. And I just
love that feeling of a really
enjoyed this. And now. Full
Bekah comes out like in those
situations where I can be
excited and passionate about
something,
we all talk about it together.
And this like very unique way
that doesn't happen when you're
kind of feeling out the industry
or the conversation or the
group. You can kind of let that
go a
little bit and just be excited
and allow everyone to be
excited.
In the conversation with you.
And that just feels great. It
feels
productive, but it feels deep
and deeper than things that I
think
we normally feel when we stick
to things that, that, you know,
maybe we don't really get
excited about, or we feel like,
well, we
should be excited about this. So
this is what we should talk
about. You know, talk about what
you want to talk about. And
that's how you find that like
really fun space.
Jessi: Yeah, Yeah. I think I
totally agree. Right? That's not
about chasing the trends because
the trends come and go. And to
me, it was, it was the
realization that like tech is so
big. And so if you make it what
you want, then you create the
space that you wish you want to
see. And other people will be
pretty happy if, you know,
there's always at least one
person who was like, oh, Hey,
you, you have just carved out
the
space of like building your own,
like Magic, The Gathering
database or cool. You know what,
I didn't like that this other
database doesn't have X, Y, and
Z. Right. So it just. It's it's
it's so framed. Right? You don't
have to fit into any particular
component. Like yeah. You could
chase chase the cloud book for
awhile. Like that's, that's a
very superficial, um, and
there's, it's definitely not
about like, that's like the tech
definitely comes second rather
than first. Right? It's about
making the thing that you want
to see, and that, that could be
the
software. Which is great, but it
could also be something else
that
everybody, any other, any like
non-tech people can use too.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. And
like, even just further on this
point,
like, if you are super into
something you don't have to, and
you were kind of saying this
too, but you don't have to make
like
the business decisions, you
know, like it doesn't have to be
some
successful product that you're
going to sell or something, you
know, uh, necessarily right. The
like sandwich website, probably
isn't making a ton of money,
but, but you know, the guy was
into it
and like had some fun and you
know, was able to learn some
stuff and probably helped him
get a job and all that stuff,
you
know, it's it's, I don't know.
It's cool. I, I do feel that
sometimes people lean too hard
on. What am I getting out of
this? Or, or what am I like,
what can I turn this into? Like
you
said, like the cloud or any, any
of the profit or any of that
stuff, you know? And when it's,
when it's something you are
just,
when you, when it's something
you just care about, like that
it's,
um, I don't know. The learning
just comes naturally. I feel
like
the benefits come, come out of,
out of that space.
Jessi: Think, oh, sorry.
Dan: No, I was done.
Jessi: Um, I was actually just
kind of thinking about how,
like,
you know, and there's a lot of
people coming out of bootcamps
and hiring managers start to see
the same projects over and over.
Right. So it's always like the
todo app and, uh, astrology app
and the, you know, tic-tac-toe
like, so. How do you stand out.
Right. And you have to be honest
with yourself. Like what's
something that I want to put in
the timeline and, and, you know,
be able to talk about with every
hire, every interview, you know,
and it should be something that
shows that, that excitement,
like
it's great to have made a
tic-tac-toe app or a, to do app,
but at the same time, like
what's a problem that we want to
solve.
That's going to help you stand
out, especially for. When you're
just trying to get your foot in
the door. Right. And you have
to,
to really be memorable, but you
have to just be yourself and you
have to show that, you know, and
that's, that can be hard for
people.
Bekah: I think that's such great
advice in, I think that. That's
that's something that you just
really have to recognize and
work
on. Like it's okay to be
different than other people. And
I think even traditional
schooling really pushes towards
the sanitisation of who you are.
Right. And like, well, what are
your achievements? Right. And so
for a lot of us, it's just
ingrained in our mindset that
the achievements are who we are.
But
that's not, it it's about, you
know, the things that we enjoy,
the things that we are
passionate about and being able
to share
those things. And, you know,
sometimes it requires
vulnerability and sometimes it
can be scary because you know,
other people are out there and
they're like, I, I built this
great thing. And then, and then
you play that comparison game.
Like, well, I did, I as my thing
as good as that, but I think
that
you're always winning if you are
working towards something that
you enjoy doing or that you're
passionate about, and it doesn't
have to be tech related. I was
talking with a couple of members
in the coworking room yesterday.
W what, what, how would we like
new members to introduce
themselves? Right? Like what,
when they introduced themselves
in the welcome channel, what
should we ask them? And what
everybody said was what's
something outside of tech that
you enjoy, right. Those are the
fun connections that you make.
And I think it was Kirk. And he
was like, well, you know, I saw
somebody said they like fishing
and then somebody else responded
about the fishing. And now
they're talking like all of this
cool and fun stuff. And you
know,
if somebody came in, actually I
could probably tell you all of
the people who said, I like
weightlifting, like, yes, me
too.
Right. But if, if you asked me
to name all of the front end
developers, I couldn't
definitely couldn't do that. You
know?
Jessi: Yeah. Yeah, no. 'Cause
we're people, right. We have
multifaceted, you know,
interests and, and that's what
makes us
unique. And so why shouldn't we
show that this is how I am
different, right. But for, for
good, not in like a, not in a
bad
way or anything like that. You
know? being different is good.
Bekah: Right. And I think that
if you find companies too, Enjoy
that, or if they mentioned that,
and that's a good indication,
like, look, this person is
interested in more than just my
tech stack. They're interested
in the person in front of them
and
that's a really good place to
start.
Jessi: Absolutely.
Dan: I was man. I had something
to say before and now it's
totally gone. It was about,
yeah, it was a total different
topic.
So if we, uh, I didn't want to,
that's why, you know, it was
Bekah: Go for it.
Dan: all right. What I was going
to ask was, oh, kind of going
back to circling all the way
back to sort of toward the
beginning
of the conversation, but w we
were talking about, um, you're
working and what you're doing
now, and so are you, you're on
your own freelance now?
Jessi: Um, so I'm doing, uh,
wrapping up a, uh, contract
project for our agency, but, um,
Yeah, so generally I'm, I'm
pretty much freelancing
otherwise.
Dan: Yeah, this is what made me,
this is how it got here. It was
was, we were talking about.
That's being yourself and, you
know, companies hiring you and
stuff like that. And I've been,
I've been independent, you know,
for my entire career. So it's
like, one of the benefits of, of
that is, um, for me, is being
able to be myself a lot more,
you know? And I was wondering if
that, if that like, had enter in
your, your thought process
about,
um, instead of, you know, like
doing contract work and stuff
like that, as opposed to trying
to get hired or excuse me,um
maybe, you're trying to get
hired. I'm not, I'm not sure,
but
like, if you've decided to stay
on the contracting route, you
know, um, whether any of that
sort of thought went into your
went into your decision making
process.
Jessi: Yeah, it did. I mean, um,
I mean, I'm interested in, in
contract work. I, I'm still kind
of, I think I'll be almost a
full
year of contracting or general
freelancing. So, um, this has
been a really different
experiences from going from
like,
pre-tech like just having like a
regular stable job. Um, and I
think some part of it is like
the freedom of contract work and
I
can pick and choose what jobs
um, I'm excited about. And that
that's really freeing, even
though it's more. Puts you more
in free fall if a job ends too
early or they don't pick you up
for the next round and things
like that. But I do find it more
rewarding to be able to pick
what I want to work on. Um, and
that,
that I think is also a part of
it of just accepting that this
is
who I am. And I kind of have a
bit of an entrepreneurial bug in
like, kind of just have to
accept that because, you know, I
don't
know how, how much like.
Full-time like, uh, you know,
regular stable job would fit my,
my, uh, like personality, I
guess. Um, and that, that
becomes really fun when people
are like,
oh, Hey, you know, I have this
thing. And I think he'd be
really
perfect to like, work on this.
And then it's like, yeah. Okay.
Like you thought I would be a
good fit, you know, instead of
having to me having to. you
know, argue for why I think I
would be
a good fit in a company
elsewhere. Um, you know, so
that,
that really becomes really
energizing because I'm now
accepting myself for my
strengths and weaknesses
career-wise um,
then that was something I always
felt like I had to find a stable
job and just do the nine to five
kind of grind, but also just
accepting that, like, maybe
that's not the right fit for me
because it's, it's quite taxing
and, you know, things like that.
So. It's much more fun to be
working in like quote-unquote
sprinting times of contract
work, if you break contract
work, but,
you know, we, I like to dig
deep, so that works really well
for me.
Um, and so, yeah, that's, I
think it's really exciting to be
like,
you know what, this is much
better for me. It's not
necessarily the status quo and
it's not quite as, um, you know,
what's the word I'm looking
for... Like it's not as. It's
not
in the norm. You know what I
Dan: I was going to say normal.
Jessi: it's not the norm, but
it's, it's okay to accept that
that's not just not gonna work
as well. That might change. And
that's the thing, right. I might
say right now, this isn't it.
But
six months from now, I might be
like, uh, you know what, I'm
tired of writing all those
proposals and then getting
rejected or not hearing from
them for three months or
whatever, you
know, I just want to clock in,
clock out. Or a year from now,
five years from now, whatever.
So that's also okay too. And
then
maybe one day you want to come
back to freelancing
Bekah: That's a good that's such
mindset.
Jessi: It's always about like,
having things open. Right. And
just seeing where things go.
That's always kind of been the
thing with tech for me is like,
okay, I'll just see what
happens.
100% massive programming, I
guess I'll try it. What's the
worst
that can happen. Right. I don't
like it.
Dan: I love that. I love the, I
love the way you said all of
that. Um, it, it lines up a lot
with the way that I fell too.
Um,
and I just, I just appreciated
that the, um, uh, man, my brain
is fried today. The, uh, yeah,
the, the freedom and the like
the, the ability to be more
individual I think is, is one of
those things. I've suggested
freelancing to people before.
And
they've like laughed at me or
scoffed at me or whatever, not
laughed at me, but you know,
like laughed at the idea. And,
um,
it's nice to hear, to hear
somebody like you that has been
successful and enjoys it. And,
you know, has the like, sort of
open-mindedness about it as
well. You know, it's, it seems
like a
healthy, a healthy mindset about
the whole thing, um, too.
Bekah: I, um, I, as soon as
they, when I was in bootcamp
before I
was. Um, maybe like in my last
three months, so it took me
about
a year. I went to this talk with
a founder of an organization and
I said, you know, I think I
would really like to freelance.
I'm a
mom. I like the flexible
schedule and, you know, to, to
not be
working 40 hours a week. And his
response to me was don't sell
yourself short and I'm like,
Hmm. I don't know that that's
accurate. Like, I don't think
I'm selling myself short. I
didn't
say that. I thought that I
couldn't do the work. I said,
this is what I'm looking for.
And there were so many people
who
said you won't be able to find a
job coming out of bootcamp as it
as a freelancer and I did. You
know, very quickly. And so it
is,
I mean, a lot of it's about
putting yourself out there, but
it's been for me a great
experience. And Jessi one of the
things that you said about, I'm
trying to think of the exact
words, but I can't, I can't
right now, something about, you
know, I
think you would be great for
this position. Right? And so
I've
interviewed for full-time work
and I've interviewed, or had
conversations for contract work.
And like one of the things I
like
about contract. So far, most of
them have started because of
conversations. It's not been
this huge interview process
where I
feel like I need to prove
myself, like you were saying of
do, do
you think that I'm good enough
No, like there's already an
established understanding and
it's come through networking
that
like, this would be a good fit.
Now let's continue this
conversation. Right. And that's
been. Huge. And, and one of the
reasons why I continue to prefer
that work because the anxiety
that comes with not only the
interview process, but all of
the. All the stuff that doesn't
make sense to me, I get like
super frustrated, like, why are
we even doing this? Like,
there's
not a point in, in doing this
portion of the interview or
doing
this portion of the application.
And that inefficiency just for
me, sends off like these red
flags in my brain where my brain
is like, Nope, not going to do
this. You know? And so it was
nice to just be able to work
together with people who are
focused on. I'm doing that, like
working together and enjoying
each other presence, you know?
Jessi: Yeah, no, I absolutely
agree. I think that the
interesting thing about, um,
like the contract job I'm on
right now
has been the, the internal team
they've asked, how can we help
you? And it's just like, Wow.
That's the first time I think
I've ever heard that, but that
doesn't mean that doesn't mean
that people don't do it, but in
terms of like, I've, you know,
done freelance work with other
freelancers, and then we just
kind of worked together, but to
have the, to have an internal
team be like, Hey, we want to
help you because you're helping
us. And, and that was really
cool and really welcoming rather
than.
I guess the stress of being like
the new person to the team and
being like, oh my God, I have to
catch up and do all this stuff.
But no, I worked, I was
completely separately from the
internal team and I just do my
thing and they just do their
thing and we would come together
when we need to, and we help
each
other, but then we still work
separately. So that's the
freedom, right? It's like, you
know, I might not know
everything. What they've done or
like what they're working on as
I
continue to work. But at the
same time, like there's a, it's
like a
different kind of camaraderie, I
guess, even though it's short
term.
Dan: Yeah, that's really cool
that that's, that's always an
interesting interface as well as
the freelance, especially with,
with, um, Uh, a company that has
developers, you know, um, so
lots
of times if you freelance,
freelance, just to somebody who
needs something, but doesn't
have any capability, you know?
Um, and
then other times it's like
you're doing now, you're helping
out a
team that has developers, you
know, and th that's, uh, in my
experience has been an
interesting. Sort of thing to
see
how it, how it all works, you
know? Um, so I mean, it sounds
like you're in a really good
spot, a really good position.
Um,
as far as communication and
contracting and stuff, uh, with
your current contract, um,
that's really cool. Have you had
any
other, I mean, you don't need to
say any like any bad
experiences,
but like has like, has that been
the norm I suppose is my
question, um, you know, with
when you're, when you're dealing
with
other teams, um, or has it been
any other interesting situations
that have come up? Um,
Jessi: Um, no, I mean, mostly
this is actually my first, like
really big, like, uh, Um, you
know, enterprise tech company.
So, um, everything I've done
prior has been like really
small,
like small-time clients and, or
like, uh, subcontracting work
for
other freelancers and just my
freelance network, um, and
things
like that. So that's why I was
like, oh, this is really cool.
We
get to come in, we get to help
people out. Um, and then. If
they
want to keep working with us.
That's great. If not, then
that's
okay. There's always other stuff
to do. Um, and that was just
kinda, kind of nice to see that
you can get like a peek into a
team and see, do I like them? Do
I not like them? Do I like this
company? Is that something I
want to keep working on? Is that
a
company that I might want to go
from contractor to, to being
pulled in house? Like you have
options and that's, that's
really
exciting. It's not just like,
oh, I interviewed at this place,
you
know, five times and they
finally, you know, want to do
it,
but the pay isn't as good. And I
don't know what I'm about to
walk
into. You know what I mean? Like
you already know at least a
little bit.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. I
mean, that's a great point too.
And that occurred like something
that you just said, I was going
to say, made me have a thought,
which is a really ridiculous
sentence, um, is, uh,
contracting, you know, affords a
company's flexibility to, right.
So when you're hiring a
contractor, I mean, contracts
differ the setup, you know, lots
of times it's there for a fixed
date or whatever, either a fixed
project or a fixed date, you
know, but, but either way, it's
like, uh, You get freedom of
both sides, right? Cause you get
the,
the, the company does like,
doesn't have to make a permanent
decision. You know, if you're
hiring somebody full-time the,
the expectation would not be for
just six months. You know what I
mean? And so, uh, like, I dunno,
I think that's another benefit
that people maybe overlooked
sometimes, um, is the benefit to
the company. So you can try
somebody out like that. Um, you
know, you can think about hiring
them or you can just, um, Keep
them contracting, um, things
like that. It's a cool way to
have new
people join your team or up, up
with your team, uh, in certain
situations, you know, uh,
without having to set aside the
budget
for a whole new, you know, an
entire employee, you know, it's
cool.
Jessi: You also get the chance
to try some new stuff and like
different industries. And that's
always really cool. Cause you're
like, oh. This one, I, I got
some, you know, some experience
like I, I, so I talked about a
little bit how I worked. I was
trying to go into medicine
before pandemic, and this is
like a
medical company. So now I get to
try putting my knowledge in a
different way that I never ever
would have thought about. And
I'm
like, do I like it? Do I not?
You know, do I still think that
this
would be a good way to use the
skills? Like the, like the
non-traditional skills I already
have in a more like traditional
tech way. Um, you know, like
that's, That's really cool. And
I, I try to tell people like,
oh, you guys should take, uh,
like
other devs who are just
studying, like take freelancing
work. And
they're like, oh, no, like it's
a scary to put yourself out
there.
And how do I figure out how much
to charge or how do I do this?
Honestly like your communication
skills that you work on your
project, like project management
skills, um, those are all really
good things to have. And when
you do decide to like, try to go
for
an interview, you already have
that skills and you can say, oh,
I worked on this client with,
you know, we did this, that and
the
other, and here's the
limitations they had and things
of that
that's really valuable,
especially if you're coming out
of a bootcamp or something like
it gives you experience that
other graduates might not have.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I think
you kind of what you've been
talking about there, this idea
of like getting energy and being
excited to try different things
is awesome. And I also love
that,
but there's maybe a fine line
between. Trying new things and
spreading yourself thin,
especially when you're looking
at
lots of different potential
projects, they do have any good
tips or advice on like how to
not do that.
Jessi: I'm still learning how to
do that. I, I am very much of
the
opinion of like, try everything.
Cause then you'll find out what
you likes and what you don't
like. But at the same time, like
when you over commit, that's
really hard to remember, like,
so
I've been trying to like write
this down, like, okay. I, I over
committed by doing this, this
and this. And I need to learn
how to
say no, but at the same time,
you're learning how to say no in
a way that helps give you depth
in other places. So it's not
that
you're rejecting everything.
It's like, you're, you're
saying,
okay, I really want to focus on
these things. And I really want
to, you know, take this
freelancing job that will help
maybe A, like, give me some
better networking skills and B,
you know, I can put this on my
portfolio about this prod, this
work project or something. Um,
and this will, this will go
farther than to say yes. And
agree to the short term thing
that maybe is more stress or,
um, things like that.
Bekah: I really love that.
Especially this idea of writing
down what you've done to get
what I've done to get myself in
this
situation. Right. I feel like
there's something that can allow
me to analyze, okay, this is not
the right decision for you right
now. It's okay to put it off
because you know, depth over
breadth a lot of the times. And
that can be really, really hard
when it's right in front of you.
And you think I might not have
this opportunity again, but you
know, like making it a
deliberate
part of your decision-making
process is huge.
Jessi: Yeah, And that's part of
it for me was just kind of, um,
understanding that like, okay,
like when I first started in
tech, right, it was good to like
try everything because you know,
this, this go to this webinar
and go to this networking
meeting and
go to, um, you know, whatever.
And then at a certain point I
realized. I'm kind of already in
tech and now I need to stop
going
to everything. Right. And then
it became like, okay, but I
don't
have to accept everything that
comes to me. I can say no. And I
can, because then it would just
sort of became like the
serotonin
boost of like, yes, I will sign
up for this webinar. Yes, I will
do this. Okay. I'll take that
contract job. Right. But at a
certain point, like I have to be
honest about how much time I.
And
that was like really weird. It
was like, oh right. I have like
a
finite amount of time and
boundaries and you know, don't
want to burn out. So, um, I
should really like try to ignore
the serotonin boost of saying
yes to things and start focusing
on
the like longer term, um, thing,
which is very difficult for me
because it's really impulsive to
be like, yes, I'll do that. Yes,
I'll do that. You know? And so
now I'm like, long-term what is,
long-term I have to think about
that now.
Bekah: Yeah, I feel that.
Dan: Yeah, for our listeners
Bekah and I are both
emphatically
nodding was just talking. Um,
it's. Yeah. It, and I'm, I'm
glad
you talked about that, Jesse,
because it's. It can be hard.
And
that, that actually can be one
of the hidden dangers of, um,
being
independent, you know, is, is
that, uh, when you make your own
decisions, you get to freedom,
but then you get the, I suppose
the danger of that too, you
know? So it seems like, uh, it
seems
like you're doing a good job of
kind of balancing everything
though.
Jessi: Thank you. I try my best.
Right. And it's it's how you,
how
you avoid burnout? Cause burnout
is prevalent everywhere, so
like,
like in tech, right. But you
know, we talk about like, oh,
you
are a person, you have a life.
Um, you know, life goes on and
you are not your tech stack or
your, you know, your job, your
title. But especially hard when
you freelance, right? Because
you're like, oh, cool. So work
hours start to blend together.
And you know Yeah. Deadlines are
deadlines and yeah. So I am,
that's hard for me. That's just
about where I am right now.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. Agreed.
Bekah: Yeah, I think it's a,
it's definitely a real challenge
for
all of us who are working
through that. Especially like
when we are
doing things that we enjoy
doing, it's really hard to stop
doing
something that you like doing.
Uh, but there is something to be
said for having boundaries for
things. And like you said, you
are not your tech stack. And I
think that that's such a good
point to me. Um, we're at about
time now, but is there any bit
of
advice whether you'd give to the
listeners or even to your past
self to say like, okay, this is,
this is how you bring the big
energy or, or find that thing
that will get you excited about
moving forward.
Jessi: I think it's mostly about
being honest with yourself. If,
if you, you know, like, okay,
maybe this to-do app that
everybody else has done is not
really like making me excited
then you should do what excites
you? Like if you have a side
project where, you know, like
that sandwich guy, like maybe
you're making the database of
all the sandwiches in every
culture
and that's what makes you
excited. You should do that. And
then talk about how excited you
are about sandwiches. Because
the
only way to know, like, who else
is also thinking you want to say
it, which is, you know, we're
just fine with this analogy now.
So even if that's it like, just,
just be honest, you know, like,
okay. So when I started with my
chess stuff, I was like, I don't
know how far this is going to
take me, but I'm really
interested in it. And I just
needed somewhere to talk about
it. And so I would just talk
about it online and I would blog
about it because I am a writer
at heart and I can't not write
about
things. So that's just, it just
needed an outlet. I just didn't
expect that it would do all
these other things that, that
have
happened since. And so, um,
yeah, there'll be afraid to be
yourself
because there's only one of you
and, you know, that's becomes
like this really, really great
thing, and it's not worth trying
to fit into the mold of, of
every other person. You know, if
you're
a bootcamp grad, don't be just
another boot camp grad. You
know,
be yourself who also happens to
be a bootcamp grad.
Bekah: Yeah, I love that. Thank
you so much. And thank you for
being here with us. We'll drop
all of your links and things in
the show notes. So listeners can
find you. Thanks again, Jesse
for
being here today.
Jessi: Thank you for having me,
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our
Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at 9
am Eastern and Thursday at
12 pm Eastern Please subscribe
to our podcast and be
sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!