Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode two of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today we're
joined by Todd Libby. Todd is a
web developer designer and
accessibility advocate. And he's
been doing it for over 20 years.
He's currently an accessibility
engineer at WebstaurantStore. And
he's also a member of the
worldwide web consortium. Also
known as W3C, doing work updating
their web content accessibility
guidelines. Todd also hosts a
podcast called the Front End
Nerdery, so once you're done
listening to this episode, head
over there and give that one a
listen. We had a great time
talking with Todd and hearing
about his long journey in tech,
how and why he developed a career
focusing on accessibility and
shared with us about what
accessibility means to him and
what kinds of things all
developers can do to ensure their
work is accessible by everyone. I
know you're going to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. Today's
question is what famous artist,
dead or alive, or you want to
paint your portrait. We hope you
enjoy this episode. name is
Bekah. I am a front end developer
from a small town in Ohio, and if
I could have one person paint my
portrait, I, when I was in
college, Georgia, there was like
big Georgia O'Keeffe paintings or
replicas in the hallways of my
department. And I always loved
them. I know that's not what she
doesn't paint people, but I think
it would be cool to see how I
would be represented by her. So
I'm going to go with Georgia
O'Keeffe
Dan: Um, hi, I'm Dan I'm a front
end developer in Cleveland, Ohio,
and, um, does it have to be
famous person?
Bekah: Did I say famous?
Dan: I, it said famous in the
question.
Bekah: I did. but now like just
take it out.
Dan: I mean, uh, Kate, one of my
good friends at Kate Brideau from
college, um, I would say that
would be the person. Um, that'd
be famous. I don't, I don't
really know a lot of famous
names. I mean, except for like
the really famous ones, you know,
and that seems like a boring
answer. Um, maybe have Raphael,
but not the, not the artist that
ninja turtle.
Bekah: Or my
Dan: Yeah. Well it's well, sure.
There's there's that too. Yeah.
Any Raphael really? I'll take,
uh, take any version. Sounds like
a good choice.
Todd: And I'm Todd Libby. I am a
front end developer and
accessibility engineer currently
in Phoenix, Arizona. And I guess
my artist would be, I dunno, he
was really unique. So I guess I
would say Salvador Dali.
Bekah: That's cool.
Dan: That'd be a good one.
Bekah: There's um, anytime
somebody is from Phoenix, I think
of a short story that I read from
Sherman Alexie. This is what it
means to say Phoenix, Arizona.
And I remember nothing about the
short story except for the title.
And it's just automatically,
that's my mind. So if you
haven't, read it, check it out
and then remind me what it was
about.
Todd: I haven't, but I will look
that up. Definitely. I'm
originally from Portland Maine.
So of course everybody knows me
because of the lobster roll
thing. So.
Bekah: Yes, Todd is all about the
lobsters and in our Virtual
Coffee Slack, he always uses the
lobster emoji to respond to
people. And so we just
automatically recognize that it's
Todd. So it's like he, he has
claimed that emoji and it's one
of the greatest things ever.
Dan: It's really cool. And it's
just like, you see the lobster
emoji pop up. You're like, oh,
cool. Todd's here.
Bekah: I just think it's it's
funny, like when, when new people
come into Virtual Coffee and then
they also click the lobster
emoji. So.
Dan: I mean I always click it. I
mean, I don't first, you know
what I mean? But like, um, it's,
it's like high five and Todd, you
know, it's like celebrating the
Toddness of it.
Todd: the virtual virtual high
five,
Dan: That's right.
Bekah: Right. And it can be about
all sorts of different things.
Like somebody could post a
question that they have, and then
like, there's a lobster emoji.
It's not about lobster. Although
if I had a question about
lobster, I would definitely ask
Todd first.
Todd: I've got a million no one
answers.
Bekah: I feel like that's a
separate podcast episode.
Todd: Yes.
Dan: Does it have to be though?
Bekah: Thank you so much for
being here with us. Todd, we
always like to start with the
origin story. How did you get to
where you are today? So if you.
want to take us through that path
would be.
Todd: Yeah. Oh boy. That's a long
one. Um, I'll give you the
abridged version. I'm nine years
old. I started on a Commodore
PET. Um, in school and then
gradually worked my way up to a
Commodore 64, where I learned
BASIC a lot of different flavors
of BASIC, um, and was just, you
know, it was just a hobby of
course at that point. But, um,
what was it about 1999? Um, I had
a. What was it? A 386 desktop,
IBM computer. And I started to
learn HTML and this was before
CSS. So that is the indication of
how old I am and JavaScript was
just kicking around. Um, I
started learning how to design
websites using Front Page Express
in Internet Explorer, three and
four. And just, it went from
there. Um, programming was cool.
I used to do, um, in BASIC on a
Commodore I would program. If
anybody remembers those, choose
your own adventure books from way
back in the day. I, I used to
program a text-based, uh, Pretty
much copied and I hope no one's
listening from that company, but,
um, I, I used to, just to just
practice, I would just. Code
those books into a, into a
text-based game on Commodore 64.
And that's really what got me
started because I was living in a
very rural area in, in New
England. And, uh, there wasn't
much to do so except for
programming at that point. So
skip ahead to today, or when I
started professionally and I was
22 years ago. And I started, um,
I read Jeffrey Zeldman his book,
Designing with Web Standards
instantly got hooked into web
standards, uh, progressive
enhancement accessibility. And it
just, you know, took off to the
point where it is today, where
I'm in the field that I enjoy
being in, and that's
accessibility.
Dan: I think that's awesome. I,
and I, I love that book too. And
Zeldman I have been, um, so 22
years ago what, 99, 2000
something like that, know? And I
think I got into, I mean, I was
starting to make something around
then and really. Got a lot more
into it a couple of years later.
Um, but was with the web
standards, you know, movement and
everything like that. And I've
been, uh, you know, and similarly
front-end focused for a long
time. And, um, one of us was just
one of the reasons I was very
excited to have you podcast and
to kind of get to get to hang out
with a little bit more. Um,
Todd: Yeah.
Dan: It's uh, so, know, on front
end and focusing on
accessibility, um, things like
that. I mean, what career
opportunities has that like
presented you from, you know,
starting, you don't need to like
list every single one or
whatever, but like run, run us
through a little bit of how
that's been being like, uh, front
end and accessibility, you know,
a specialist, um, for whatever
that means for you. Uh, you know,
run it through a little bit, like
how that's been finding, finding
work and finding people that care
about that sort of thing. Um,
Bekah: Can I just jump into, if
you can just provide some context
for what, what does accessibility
mean and how does that work as
part of a job?
Todd: Okay. Um, to address what
it's accessibility mean, uh, I'll
address that first and that is
making the web equal and
accessible for everybody. Um, it
just doesn't have to be a
disability. It can be, you know,
somebody in I'll use this example
in a very rural area who has a 3g
phone. And, you know, it's not a
very fast connection is to, you
know, what we have these days
with our shiny new iPhones and
stuff like that. Um, and then
accessibility. Somebody in
accessibility would basically,
um, not only advocate, but don't
in my daily routine of doing
auditing on websites. It's just
checking to see if, uh, Sites are
accessible if they're, you know,
if they should be failing, um,
web content, accessibility
guidelines WCAG is how I
pronounce it. There's many
different pronunciations to that,
but, um, um, the, um, you know,
and you know, there's different,
I guess. Levels of how people
will do an audit. Like, you know,
you can do, you know, a and AA as
far as the levels. So there's a
AA and AAA, a lot of people I
find don't do AAA, because it's
too stringent and it's also, you
don't have to go that far in most
cases. Um, but. It's just
auditing, making sure sites are
accessible in, um, creating a
report for a client and then
telling them here's what's wrong.
Here's how you need to fix it.
This doesn't, you know, adhere to
the guidelines and, um,
recommendations for best
practices as well. And, um, You
know, looking at code and, you
know, always looking at HTML and
CSS because CSS too has a strong
effect on accessibility and, uh,
that's what the job entails. Um,
and Dan, what was your question?
Dan: Alright, I guess my question
was, um, you know, it's, it's a
sort of. I don't know if
non-traditional is the right
word, but, you know, being a
specialist really in any regard,
um, is, uh, is a choice, you
know, and can limit your options,
but like also what you want to
do. Right. Um, and so I, my
question was more like, how has
it been, uh, on your career
journey? You know, being a
specialist, especially in the
accessibility world,
Todd: Right. Um, it's been a
challenge lately in, I would say
the past. Five, maybe 10 years.
Um, because not a lot of people,
not a lot of companies were
looking for accessibility
specialists. Um, not until I've
pretty much noticed this year. A
lot of companies are now looking
for accessibility specialists
because companies are getting
sued. And they don't want to get
sued. That's that's the bottom
line. So my professional journey
had been, I worked, uh, I
started, I did a website for
somebody I knew back in, uh, new
England, Maine. And, um, it was
just a small. And then from there
I got, you know, a few different
jobs doing websites. And then
from there I was like, well, you
know, this thing's taken off. I'm
going to do the I'm going to go
the freelance route. So that's
what I did. And. Up until 2015, I
was a freelance, uh, developer, I
guess you could say I got into
WordPress, uh, PHP development.
And then, um, I was hired by a
company to do their website and
their SAS, um, their SAS, uh,
site, I guess. It was a, a thing
where you log in and it wasn't a
public facing site. And, um, from
there it would be been about, I
don't know. I think I counted
over 2000 resumes that I had sent
out to companies in 20 years in.
One company hired me. And that
was that company that I worked
for in 2015 to, uh, just, uh,
last year as a matter of fact.
And then finally somebody took a
chance on me that would have been
Nobility. I was hired by
Nobility, uh, in March and March
or April. Geez, it's been over
six months, but, um,
Dan: What is time anyway.
Todd: well, I don't even know
anymore. I'm in a different time
zone now, so that's messed me up
too. Uh, but no ability gave me
a, you know, an opportunity and
very grateful for that
opportunity with them and, um, a
lot of great people in Nobility
that work for the company. Um,
everybody is a matter of fact and
they do some really good stuff as
far as accessibility goes. And,
um, as of October 1st, I will be,
um, on the, uh, WebstaurantStore
team as an accessibility
engineer. Uh, so I look forward
to that. Yeah.
Bekah: Can you talk a little bit
about what you'll be doing in
that role there? Maybe dive into
a little bit of detail.
Todd: Um, for right now, all I
know is it's basically doing the
same thing I do now and that's
auditing, um, their product for
their, uh, website. I know they
use, they use react and I think
it was .net. So that I'll be in
that, um, environment.
Bekah: So like when you do an
audit, where do you start with
that?
Todd: So when I do an audit, I do
automated, uh, checks and scans
first. So I use stuff like the
WAVE extension, um, the axe, I
now wait until the end to use the
axe-core extension in the
browser. Um, Things like, uh,
there's a command line called
Pa11y. So it's PA one, one Y uh,
there's that I use, um, does
Bookmarklets from Ian Lloyd and
Paul J. Adam that I use to also
do checks. Um, Let's see what
else? There's Microsoft
Accessibility Insights, which is
a great tool to use. Um, what
else? And I said, axe, color,
contrast checks. I use, um, the
Firefox accessibility dev tools,
the accessibility panels and
those, and then I move on to, um,
manual testing. So. mouse only,
um, keyboard only I will do it,
which goes back to color
contrast. I'll do the squint
test. So I'll just look at the
site while I'm squinting at it
and see if, you know, I can make
out anything cause that I was
taught not too long ago. So, um,
and uh, screen readers, I will
use screen readers. So for Mac
there's Voiceover. And it's best
to use Voiceover in Safari
because the native, you know, Mac
app and everything, um, and VDA
and Jaws on a Windows. And, um,
if, and it's very, very rare, but
if somebody says, oh, you know,
we have Linux users. So I will
test on what it's called Orca for
Linux and, um, yeah, those are
pretty much, uh, if I remember
them all correctly, um, those are
the tools I use.
Dan: That's. Yeah, that's
awesome. It's very extensive. I
was just writing all them down so
that
Bekah: So as I well, the link to
those show notes.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And so, so
like day to day, I mean, I know
you haven't started yet, but like
in your, in your role, will it be
mostly doing audits after the
fact? Or like, will you be
interfacing with, you know, I'm
not sure what they do, what they,
what, what they make or anything
like that, but you know, like
where in the process are you, are
you, uh, doing like
accessibility? Uh, you know,
helping the team with, with this
stuff, like, know, audits for me
imply, and I know this isn't
always true, but when I think of
it as something, oh, something's
done, now we do an audit on it.
You know what I mean? but I was
wondering if, and I'm sure that's
an important part. I was
wondering if there's, um, places
earlier in the process where, um,
where, you know, you're able to
interface and like, you know,
make suggestions before it, you
know, as opposed to like fixing
things, but like help build
something you know, the first
time.
Todd: Right. Yeah,
Dan: Does that make sense?
Todd: yeah, yeah. Um, I'm, I'm
sure it's going to be probably a
lot of both. Um, maybe there's
existing things on the site, uh,
that need to be checked, um,
components that may be being
worked on. We'll have to be
checked. I mean, it's that way,
pretty much with any kind of
audit. So I've had companies come
to me and say, you know, we we've
got somebody who emailed us and
said, this isn't accessible, so
we need a, an audit done and I'll
go through the site and say,
okay, I found all this. Here's
what you need to do to fix it.
They'll fix it. That'll be after
the fact of course, I've had
companies come in and ask me to
do consulting with their teams
before the project starts to make
sure that it gets done
beforehand. Because when you do
an accessibility, when you, when
you bring in accessibility from
the start of a project, it's so
much easier and there's less, a
lot less stress, doing it from
the very beginning, because when
you get to the end and you've
got, everything is as accessible
as you can. And I'll add that
nothing's a hundred percent
accessible. Um, it's, it's a lot
easier on your teams. You know,
like I said, there's a lot less
stress. You don't have to go back
and scatter around trying to fix
this, that, and the other thing
after the fact. So, um, and
that's also where my advocacy
comes in is saying, okay, if you
get this done from the start,
you're going to be, it's going to
be so much easier and it's going
to cost less money because you're
not going to. It's going to cause
a lot less stress again. And, uh,
those are the two main things.
Um, but to answer the question,
it's going to be a little bit of
both. I would think, because like
I said, it's usually that way at
the beginning, you know? Um,
Dan: Get something to a baseline
first.
Todd: Yeah. Yeah. And, and, and
it's still really early in the
process, so I'm not too sure, but
I know that there'll be a lot of,
you know, checking to make sure
everything's good. On the end of,
you know, before we put this out,
we need to make sure it's
accessible. So. yeah.
Bekah: As you've been working
through this industry, do you
think. Is there one problem that
you keep encountering over and
over, like stand out issues,
things that people can just
really look at and say, all
right, let's start here.
Todd: Well, where do I begin?
It's it's a lot, but mainly it's
color contrast. Okay. Um, that's
the biggest one. Um, and, uh,
Keyboard accessibility is another
and throwing a third one. And
that being, uh, alt text on
images, the alternative text, um,
I've had, you know, a lot of alt
text can be a tricky, um, uh, a
tricky thing because people
think, well, I have this image.
And I need to really go into
detail what that image is
conveying. If it's an informative
image and you really don't just a
short, you know, it's a purple
flower in a field, um, is fine.
You don't have to go into, I've
seen on Twitter because they give
you a thousand characters for alt
text. And I've seen this. I've
seen alt text that long before.
Bekah: I always wonder, like, I,
I don't think I've written enough
because I'm not even close to the
1000 and I have a thousand to
write.
Dan: Yeah. I always try to just
like, like, just say the joker. I
mean, usually if I'm posting an
image, it's a joke, you know, but
like the shortest version of the
joke is, you know, so I like
posted one today and it was just
like guys saying thumbs up or
something like that, that, you
know, you know what I mean? like
that seems that at least seems
like usually enough. I don't need
to give the whole,
Bekah: Sometimes I just don't
post because I don't know how to
describe it. Like, well, I'm not
really sure that I know how to
say capture what this is doing,
so we'll go, we'll go for
something else.
Todd: There's a lot of debate
around how long should it be? It
shouldn't be 180 characters.
Should it be a certain amount of
words, but just as long as it
conveys in a short succinct,
Sentence, I guess that's fine.
Um, and of course you have some
images decorative that, ya know,
it needs an empty all text. And
that's a big one because I was
just doing an audit and they had
decorative images, but no, alt,
no empty alt text, um, which is
just the alt equals, you know,
quotes and it's, the quotes are
empty in between,
Bekah: Can you explain that?
Cause that I had just recently
learned about that, but. Don't
quite understand why that's the
standard.
Todd: So there's a, it tells a
screen reader. There's an image
there, but it doesn't, it doesn't
need it's decorative basically.
So it just there's, there's no
need to, to
Dan: ha what happens in a
screenwriter? If it runs into an
image with no alt attribute at
all?
Todd: Uh, it skips over it. So
you're loo the, the user is
losing information. So if there's
something you're trying to
convey, like let's use the, um,
like, an infographic, for
example, and there's no alt text
on it. That user that's using the
screen reader is not gonna know
that it's there.
Dan: Totally. Totally. And so in
the case of a decorative image
where we don't need. It's okay.
If his screen, you know, if it's
okay, if anybody skips over it,
what do you know, what is the
tactical difference for a screen
reader for a user on a screen
reader between empty, an image
with an like with a alt property
and just an empty string and an
image with alt you know, defined
at all.
Todd: So. it's okay. Let's use a
logo. As an example, if you have
empty alt text on your logo, and
it's also linked, the screen
reader will read that link and
you don't want that to read it.
You don't want it to. It doesn't
really need to, I mean, there's
cases where somebody may say,
yeah, I want the person to know
what the logo looks like, but if
it's not really necessary, um, no
alt text, you know, it's the
screen reader. Won't read
anything and. As far as I know.
And I'll be the first to say, I'm
not an expert by any means with
screen readers, because this is a
lot of different stuff. I've been
learning lately, but to mine, to
my recollection, anyways, an
empty. So the end. So no alt
texts. Let me get this straight.
No, alt text, the URL will be
read to the image.
Dan: Okay. Yeah. That's the big
difference. All right. That's the
part, I didn't
Todd: Yes. Yup.
Dan: no alt text at all, like no,
alt property defined. When a
screen reader is reading it,
it'll come through normal texts
and then it'll just read like,
blah, blah, blah dot JPEG. Right.
Okay. That's
Todd: And then the, the empty alt
is silent. So that's.
Dan: it'll that tells it to skip
right over it, which is you want.
Sometimes like, sometimes that is
the preferred thing or like the
decorative image where it's a
background image or something
like that, or, background, but
like, you know, sometimes it's
just used for decoration. Doesn't
need to convey actually
information. and so in those
cases, putting an empty, alt like
alt equals, you know, empty
string. Is is actually very good
and much like very good for
accessibility because otherwise
they're going to see probably a
very long URL with dot JPEG,
which means nothing to them.
Right.
Todd: Yes. Exactly.
Dan: Oh, that's great. Um, that's
one of those things that. And
I've seen a lot of people. This
is a separate topic, like that,
that little, like, pick that
little bit, just, just even just
Alt getting like your head
wrapped around how to deal with
alt, alt texts. Um, like you
said, mix can make a huge
difference for accessibility
making a for your users. oh,
that's really cool.
Bekah: And you were talking about
one of the big problems being
color contrast. And that seems
like something that could be
pretty simple to identify with a
Lighthouse audit. Um, can you
explain what a Lighthouse audit
is? And if you're like, that's
not the way to go. This other
method is better. Um, I would
love to hear that.
Todd: So, I mean, I've used
Lighthouse before. I don't really
rely on lighthouse. Lighthouse
runs off of axe-core and which is
great, but I don't think it
really gets to the root of every
issue. And it really can't. Uh,
plus you have false positives,
which is, you know, something,
it, for example, I was just
talking about this on the, in
the, in the Slack, uh, Virtual
Coffee Slack. False positives for
color contrast, you know, I've
come across instances where it
will flag color, contrast errors,
but the color contrast is far
exceeds the 4.5 to one ratio. So
I don't really rely on
Lighthouse. I mean, it's a good
tool. Don't get me wrong because
there's that performance piece to
it that I really, really like,
uh, using and, um, As far as, you
know, it's a good tool, don't get
me wrong, but I use, and I used
to use it. I used to use it
myself. I mean, I used it on my
site and was like, yeah, one
hundreds. I got one hundreds
across the board and you know,
that, that virtual confetti
flying everywhere. But, um, the
tools that I use would be, um,
It's a contrast hyphen ratio.com,
which is Lea Verou, uh, color
contrast site. I also use, um,
the, let me look, I have it on my
other machine here, the color
contrast analyzer. And that is by
The Paciello Group. So Steven
Faulkner has based on the Windows
version, the Mac iOS version was
developed by somebody else. Uh, I
use that, that tool as well. Um,
and I will provide, uh, the link
to that.
Bekah: This great, I'm like
really looking forward, it could
diving into a lot of these
resources that you are dropping
right now. Cause I think
sometimes it's hard to know where
to start. And, I think that's
just a problem with teaching
developers in general. There's
not a focus on it. It's not built
into most curriculums and, um, at
all. And so there's a lack of
focus, I think, as a result of
that. And then not knowing where
to start, or if you're with a
company that doesn't look at
those things, then I think it can
be, you can find yourself a while
down the path and and not know
what you should be identifying,
how you should be approaching
this. And so the more that we
talk about it, I think the
better, um, where do you think
people could get started if they
want to learn more about
accessible?
Todd: So the w three C has a
great, um, intro to accessibility
class, which I believe is still
free. And yeah, it's an
Introduction to Web Accessibility
on edex.org. And, uh, I took that
class even. Um, and it was it's
great. Uh, you can pace yourself.
Doesn't have to be real fast is
no, you know, there's no due date
or anything. There's a free
version. If you want a
certificate, you got to pay a
certain amount. Um, it's like if
you put in four to five hours a
week, it's like for four weeks
long, uh, to do. It gives a good
overview of, excuse me,
accessibility, and you know, some
of the guidelines there's, um, a
lot of good information on the
web, uh, and, uh, even have to
pitch Nobility's website and
their blog. They go over some of
the, uh, WCAG guidelines and
accessibility is also, I want to
make this clear accessibility is
more than just WCAG guidelines.
Um, it's also about inclusive
design as well. Um, making sure,
you know, certain demographics
aren't, you know, kept out that,
that everybody's included, um,
hence the name inclusive design.
Um, but, um, Some other, um,
let's see. That's a good
question. Cause there's so much,
I mean, I guess, you know, a
search would come up with a lot
of different things. WebAIM.org
has some good stuff. As far as
accessibility, learning
accessibility, um, level access
does, uh, let's see who else.
TPGI has good stuff. So there's,
there's a lot out there that, you
know, people can find on, you
know, even there's even like
courses on, I guess Udemy and
platforms like that as well.
Bekah: So, this has kind of been
your focus the entire time you've
been working in tech. Was there a
reason that you went down this
path or, or something that kind
of inspired this journey? Or have
you just always been interested
in it?
Todd: Uh, it started when a
couple of family members, I have
like three family members that
have disabilities, um, to have
motor skill disabilities, one
visual and. Seeing the looks of
frustration on their faces when
they're trying to access
something that's inaccessible on
the web really got me motivated
in the beginning and carries me
to this day. Really. Um, I kind
of towards like 2018, 2019 was
kind of like. I guess slacking
off a little bit with my
accessibility, but I get together
with our friend, Chris DeMars in
Burlington, Vermont. There was a,
there was a conference and. You
know, he gave a great talk and
that really lit the fire again.
So there's been a really, it's
been like laser, like focus for
me as far as, since then. And,
um, just the looks of frustration
on faces of people that I've
seen, trying to access something
that's inaccessible on the web.
Yeah. It's just, it's very, um,
the word I'm looking for here,
very, uh, it hits home. It
really, you know, being that I
try to advocate for people that
don't have a voice. And, um, I
think as, as accessibility,
professional, We all, do we try
to advocate for those people? Um,
especially lately with certain, I
will use it in quotes,
accessibility, overlays, for
instance, but, um, yeah, that's
basically where it all started
was just those family members and
friends and just seeing people,
uh, yeah. Th the frustration and
the point where they're ready to
give up.
Bekah: Yeah, I, was just with
Chris last week. Um, he spoke at
KC DC. He along with Cass Ferris
and they did anaccessibility
talk. That was the first time I
got to see him speak in person.
It was really great because they
both come at it with a lot of
passion and examples. And I think
for so many of us, we have a
general sense of what
accessibility is, but we don't
have that broader sense of, uh,
you know, it might be. Um, there
might be a disability that you
can't see, or it might be a
temporary disability or a mental
health challenge that somebody is
going through and all of those
things can impact what
accessibility looks like. And if
you really look at the people
around you, you for sure know
someone that has one of those
challenges or, or you have one
yourself. And so, you know,
opening up the conversations
about this, you know, like you
have in, in like Chris and Cass
have, I think is so important to
really making change in, in tech
overall.
Todd: Yeah, I, you, know, you you
brought up invisible.
Disabilities. I have migraine
headaches. Uh, I get them when
something sets off, if there's a
website, I visit that as, you
know, animation or motion that
really it's too much. And it's
triggers a migraine. I mean,
there's all that stuff that you
mentioned and. Yeah. It's, you
know, uh, Chris is great. You
know, I, I I've seen him talk,
you know, virtually and then
before the pandemic and
everything, and we've gotten to
know each other and he, you know,
he does a great job advocating.
Bekah: yeah. I think, you know,
even so a couple of years ago I
was diagnosed with ADHD and it's
interesting how much I didn't
realize that impacts the things
that I interact with and the ways
that I interact with things.
Maybe this is just a personal
problem, but this is the
conversation between Discord and
Slack. For me, like I walk into
Discord, I don't walk in there.
Um, I open up Discord and it's
immediately just overwhelming and
I don't know where to go from
there. And then I just like
slowly back out the door, right?
Like there's too much going on
for me.
Todd: Yeah. That information
overload happens to me as well.
Um, it's like Slack and, uh,
Discord and. There's yeah, I was
on, I was watching a, uh, Twitch
stream yesterday and the chat was
going off and I was just like, I
just, I can't, I want to be able
to kind of read the chat and I
can't because you know it, yeah.
The information overload is a big
thing too.
Bekah: So I, you know, I think,
um, Your background, you talked
about your journey through this
and it seems like you've been
mostly self-taught then, is that
right?
Todd: Yeah. Um, I started, when I
picked up that Commodore 64 user
manual. And just, I love to read
and I read that I had purchased a
book. It was a Learn HTML in 21
days. And it was like a big, huge
thick phone book, like manual.
And I read through that. That's
how I actually made my first
website. Uh, not that I put it
out on the web or anything, but
then I. Um, I graduated from
there on, I went to Geo Cities
and Angel Fire and Tripod and all
those websites, if you remember
those websites
Dan: here. Yeah.
Todd: and all the great, you
know, lime green and pastel and,
you know, fluorescent colors. Um,
and then, you know, It's been a
learning process the entire time
and I love to learn. So it's one
of those things where if I can
pick up something in a Slack
group or on a Discord channel,
that's great. I've, you know, I
keep learning every day and, you
know, learning. Lately it's been
learning the intricacies of the
WCAG guidelines because there's
so much there. Um, and being able
to, and I'm grateful for this
being able to work on the next, I
guess, version, which is 3.0,
which is a few years down the
road has been a learning process
as well. And being a member of
the W3C is to, and being in those
meetings and. We're learning so
much from a great group of
people.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome. I
love that idea of just consistent
learning and being open to
learning all of the time, because
I think no matter what part of
tech or, or any industry really
that you're in the being open to
learning new things and talking
through things with other people.
and understanding is, you know,
that that's what growing is
about. That's what is important
to what you're doing.
Todd: Yeah. It's, you know, even
I've, you know, learned, I
learned on Twitter as well, you
know, I see something, a link to
an article or something and I
check it out and it's like, oh,
well, you know, Today I learned,
you know, and you know, I it's
it's, you know, there was a quote
and I'll try to find that quote
because I love the quote. Um, it
had something to do with, uh,
doing something. Yeah, right
there. Um, there are three
things. Everyone should do every
day. Number one is laugh. Number
two is think, spend some time in
thought number three, you should
have your emotions, you to tears.
If you laugh, think and cry,
that's a heck of a day. And that
was just like the best quote. I
think I've seen it in a long,
long time. I even add to that
learning one thing a day.
Bekah: Yeah. I love that so much.
I didn't think, you know,
learning things on Twitter for me
has been really big as well. Even
when somebody just has a small
portion of a tweet at, for some
reason, it sticks in my mind
better than if I read a whole
article on that thing. And I
think maybe because there's some
type of personal connection
there. Oh, I remember that person
said this one thing and it, you
know, it might be some type of
coding tip or whatever, but I
think that just be just sharing
that knowledge or, or it's Hey, I
know that I could ask that
person. That question can be
really helpful in finding the
answers to things or having more
confidence in, in being, being
able to ask questions.
Todd: Yeah. It's it's, you know,
I use Twitter as a tool to say,
you know, oh, you, you mentioned
something about the new, you
know, um, whatever coming, coming
down the line. I've got a couple
of questions for you. Um, you
know, Hey, can I, you know, DM
you, I got a question I need to
ask and it reaching out to
somebody to, or to the person
that, you know, had that tweet
it's, uh, and, and Mo you know, I
don't think I've ever had anybody
go no I don't want to tell you
the answer or anything like that.
So, um, yeah, it's, uh, it's
always been, you know, Hey, you
know, I've got this question.
People are more than, you know,
more than welcome to, to answer
those questions.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think that's
so big, especially when we're
talking about this topic. If you
don't know it is okay to ask
somebody, Or ask someone just to
direct you, you know, I'm getting
started in this. It's not been a
focus. How, how do I get started?
What do I do? And dropped a lot
of great resources here, but, you
know, I think in, in every place
and space we should, we should
know that it is okay to ask about
these things. And it's good to do
that.
Todd: Yeah, definitely. You know,
I tell people, you know, if you
have a question about
accessibility, I'll do my best to
answer. If I can't answer it, I
will find somebody that can, or I
will look it up and see if I can
get you the answer, because it's,
it's, it's that little, you know,
it's that being helpful? And
again, making, you know, making
sure that person has that
information for me anyways, is,
is big. And, you know, just
saying, you know, feeling good
about being able to help people.
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. That's so
important.
Dan: I love it.
Bekah: we have about one a time
for one more question. And, and
I'd love to hear what you have to
say about this. Cause I know that
there still are companies out
there that are, um, have some
pushback about paying for making
things accessible, or they say
like, well, that's not our focus
right now because we don't have
the time or the money to do that.
How would you that situation? Or,
you know, maybe if you were a
developer consulting on that, you
know, how would you kind of
convince them that this, this
should be a priority?
Todd: Okay. Funny. You mentioned
that. Cause I wrote a article,
uh, about that and it's on
smashing magazine. So I'll get
that. Link to you as well. It's a
very tricky slope sometimes. Um,
you know, I've heard people for
instance say, well, you don't
want to get sued. And that kind
of. Perks up stakeholders ears
and says, oh, you know, well, I
guess we're going to have to do
this me. I use real world
examples of, for instance, I ran
into a stakeholder on a project
and I said, we've got to make
sure accessibility is done from
the very beginning of the
project. He turned to me and
said, we don't have disabled
users. I in turn said to him,
you're wearing eyeglasses, that's
an assistive technology and he
kind of perked up, but I'd,
hadn't convinced him. So the, you
know, there's some people that
can be very stubborn. So I went
as far as to say, you know,
somebody's working. You know,
using your product, they can have
a broken arm, it could be a
situational disability. They
could have a broken arm. They
could be at home working with a
child on their lap. That's very
fussy. I've been there a long
time ago. I know that feeling and
I, you know, I know Bekah, you're
a parent. I don't know if you're
a parent, Dan, but.
Dan: yeah.
Todd: Yeah. Yeah. So you both
know that, you know, you have a
child on your lap and they're
fussy, you know, and you're
trying to answer an email or
something. It's very difficult.
So, you know, getting teams on
board is another thing too, where
getting somebody. A person
dedicated to doing accessibility
on the design side, on the
development side, on the
marketing side. That helps too.
But the main thing is getting
stakeholders on board. If you can
get a stakeholder on board, then
it should be much, much easier to
get the entire organization on
board.
Bekah: Yeah, that's great. I love
that. You know, it all comes down
to listening and being
open-minded right. If we work
towards understanding each other,
then we can all do a whole lot
more to improve things for
everyone.
Todd: Yeah, definitely.
Definitely. Yep. I've heard it,
I've heard it before. We don't
have the budget, you know, we'll
get to it after launch. Well,
that brings me back to. Yep. If
you do everything from the
beginning, you will have the
money for it and you know, it
will be less stressed, so, yeah.
Dan: don't need to pay for it.
Find the budget to pay for a
whole round of. You know,
auditing and stuff.
Todd: Right. Yeah. And auditing.
So I'll use an example of a
company that got sued and what
they could have. What they could
have spent just with, you know,
doing it from the beginning, they
ended up paying seven figures for
an audit. So that should tell you
something about that process.
Bekah: Right. And it shouldn't
ever have to come to that. That's
know, absolutely ridiculous,
Todd: yeah.
Bekah: But I'm so glad that you
were here today to talk us
through this and drop all of
these great resources. And I
really hope that, you know, it
helps people who are listening to
work through the stuff. And to
know that it's okay to ask
questions. And to Grow and learn
more all the time. Um, so we'll
make sure that we drop all those
links in the show notes. And
thanks so much for being here
with us today. Todd
Todd: Well, thank you.
Dan: Really appreciate it too.
Todd: Yeah. Thank you both for
having me
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: alright, bye Todd.
Todd: Bye
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please subscribe
to our podcast and be sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!