Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode three of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah! This week, we
got the chance to sit down with
Jennifer Konikowski. Jennifer has
been a software engineer for over
10 years and has worked with a
million different languages and
helped found and organize
PyLadies Boston and Boston Ruby
Women. She's currently a senior
engineer at Splice. We had a
great time chatting with
Jennifer. She talked about her
experiences building communities,
how she approached navigating
different workplaces through her
career. And she shared some hot
takes to get us through the week.
I had a great time talking with
Jennifer and I know you're going
to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. Today's
question is which vegetable is
best with cheese. We hope you
enjoy this episode. Hi, I'm
Bekah. I am a front end developer
from a small town in Ohio. The
best vegetable with cheese is
most definitely broccoli. There's
no other right answer.
Dan: Um, hi, I'm Dan. I'm a front
end developer from Cleveland,
Ohio, and yeah, I don't, this
question is bizarre. Uh, I don't,
uh, I don't really like broccoli
with cheese. Like I prefer
broccoli, just like, you know,
without cheese. If I had the
option between the two, um, I
would choose no cheese. Uh,
Bekah: rice broccoli casserole
Okay
Dan: Is potato a vegetable.
Bekah: Yes,
Jennifer: going to be my question
Dan: I don't know if it is or
not. That's going to be my answer
for sure. If
Bekah: root vegetable root
vegetable
Dan: I'll I'm stealing potato.
That's my that's my answer
Jennifer: Hi, I'm Jennifer. I am
a senior backend software
engineer at splice, um, out of
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. And I'm
also like if potatoes are
considered a vegetable, I guess
potatoes, you know, who doesn't
love some poutine, cheesy fries,
you know?
Dan: Yeah
Bekah: is a good call. I was
thinking just putting it on your
mashed potatoes
Jennifer: No, I don't. If
potatoes aren't Fried I generally
don't eat them.
Dan: I think mashed potatoes, but
again, without cheese, but like
there's a lot of fried situations
that I think cheese.
Bekah: like mashed potatoes with
cheese and bacon and why I know a
Greek yogurt
Dan: Like a big potato cheese.
Bekah: Yes Um oh welcome Jennifer
Thank you so much for being here
and tolerating my strange
question for our intro.
Jennifer: I had to miss Virtual
Coffee this week. So to be
honest, you know, this is, this
is my comeuppance.
Bekah: Oh yeah
Jennifer: I had to get at least
one weird question this week to
answer.
Bekah: Well Tuesday Tuesday was
all kinds of weirdness And at the
beginning we won't go there
because it got a little dark but
we're glad to have you here with
us today and we always like to
get started with your origin
story. So can you tell us a
little bit about how you got to
this point
Jennifer: Oh boy. Um, I, so I
grew up in Alabama. I wanted to
leave Alabama. And at the time,
my best bet to decide to start as
a biomedical engineer at Georgia
Tech. Um, after I was like, I
don't want to do that switched a
couple of times, ended on
industrial engineering, uh,
really enjoyed that actually I've
in statistics and operations
research. Super fun. Through
that, um, Georgia Tech actually
makes all their students take at
least one computing class. had
two extra as part of my program.
Um, I think that ended up putting
me in a good position because
when I was graduating, I didn't
have the highest GPA. So I was
going in the career fair to like
all the companies that had
shorter lines that like weren't
as cool. And I ended up getting a
job at Home Depot as a. Oh,
shoot. What was the, it's a weird
job title IT developer. what it
was. It was pretty similar to a
project management position. And
from there I had thought I would
be doing more development per the
job title, and there were a few
things that for me, I actually
overall I think had a pretty good
experience with Home Depot as a
company, but my particular team
was a bit of a disaster, which I
think is sort of a theme my whole
career. And at a certain point of
like, know, it's look at the
common denominator. I'm like, oh
crap. it is me. Hopefully not
though. Um, I think I'm just
really bad at where to work. I
swear, Splice is great.
Bekah: So far so good.
Jennifer: Yeah, so, so good. Um,
so I changed jobs. I joined the
deliverability team at MailChimp
for a couple of years, and then I
moved up to Boston. And at that
point, um, obviously with a job
in email delivery, there's not
that many. It's hard to find
another place where you can do
that. Uh, without against an
actual non-compete, uh, in
dealing with trade secrets. So I
was like, okay, I definitely
can't go get a job at Constant
Contact. Cause there's no way
MailChimp wouldn't go after me. I
learned, I learned some Python,
so I'm like, I guess now I can be
a developer and. I, this was,
Dan: Yeah.
Jennifer: was back when this was,
uh, October, 2012. So mostly pre
boot camps. So caveat, this is, I
feel like an origin story that is
really hard to come by these days
I got hired to be a warm body, as
a contractor, um, through like a
sort of third party TripAdvisor
and it got experience without
having to do almost anything in
the interview. And, you know,
from there, I worked at a variety
of startups, in the Boston area.
Uh, I also worked at Occupy for a
couple of years, uh, moved to
Pittsburgh uh, since then I
worked at Stitch Fix for a couple
of years, Testable for one I've
been at Splice now two over two
weeks. For no, exactly. Two
months.
Bekah: That's...
Jennifer: oh, and I've mostly
done Ruby on Rails back in, but
as I'm sure a lot of this know,
uh, it's very hard to get away
from being full stack.
Bekah: I know. So you've done a
lot of work, I think throughout
that time. With community and
building community. And I think
looking at your thinking about
your origin story and of the
different steps of your journey
to get where you were, I love to
talk a little bit about like, why
you decided to start PyLadies
when you were in Boston or like,
what was the thing that made you
think, like, I need to start
working to build community for
women and minorities and tech?
Jennifer: So, I mean, I think
mostly like, since I've started
in the workforce and had any sort
of power, I have personally
always felt the need to try and
bring people up with me. Um, and
I know, so when I was in Atlanta,
my friend, uh, Laura had started
Atlanta and we were just like a
little study group of people
trying to learn Python and that
helped me much. And that I, that
when I moved to Boston, I wanted
to do that in Boston as well,
because I saw Boston has this
really great Boston Python group.
They're wonderful. But at the
same time, the group is massive.
And I know for me, it was really
intimidating to go, especially
because it's all dudes. It didn't
matter that they were generally
like extremely kind and
welcoming. you go in a room with
like 200 people and there's
maybe. You know, 10 women, you
know, I've, even if I'm, even if
I'm generous, let's say 40 out of
those 200, know, it still feels
very overwhelming. Um, so wanted
a safe for women to come and
learn Python, maybe just
experience it. And even though I
was a Ruby developer at the time,
the reason I sort of chose Python
because as much as I love Ruby,
the community is entirely
focused, pretty much on
applications and APIs great. I
love them. That's what I do. But
I find that Python has more
applications outside of being a
software developer, uh, data
scientists use Python, academics,
use Python, There's I, I knew a
lot of linguists actually, who
were part of Boston. And I
thought that was cool. And if my
overall goal was to sort of, part
of my goal was to also more women
how to code, not even necessarily
make them software developers,
but to be like, Hey, is a thing
it's not actually that hard. you
can do it, you and it will help
you do your job faster and more
efficiently, and you don't have
to become a software developer.
You can learn this skill and it
can benefit you where you are.
Um, but obviously I also wanted
to help. If people were
interested in switch, I wanted to
do everything I could to support
them in that. And so, and I was
also as a Ruby developer. Um, my
friend, uh, Melissa Z uh, Boston,
Ruby women. And I would go to
that. I was one of the founding
members of that group and I would
help organize that. And for both
of those groups, I would host
like weekly study sessions for
Boston review women. I. I'd be
like, oh, like I'm going to be at
this. Uh, I think it was, I, I
went to area four in Kendall
Square and be like, I'm going to
be here from 12 to one during my
lunch break, come meet me. Like,
I'll answer any questions that I
can. I'll help you work through
things. I'll talk about job
applications. I'll review your
resume. Like literally whatever
you want. I'll be there. hanging
out here for you. then for
PyLadies, I'd do the same thing
on the weekend. I used to try to
do like some sort of class. And I
found that it was really hard to
get people to stick with
something at the same pace. So
having it be more open-ended I
think was better for everyone
because otherwise people would be
like, oh, I couldn't make it to
this one. So now I'm out. Which
is the thing that I, I think
maybe if I had, if I made people
pay for it, they would've stuck
with it, but at the same time,
like I wanted this to be
accessible for everyone. And I
know. I know a lot of people who
have gone to bootcamps, and I
know a lot of great developers
out of bootcamps, but I feel like
bootcamps are really expensive.
And one of the things that I saw
in Boston that I really didn't
like was that the bootcamps were,
um, themselves as the only way to
get into tech and to switch
careers. And that. I really
didn't like that because a lot of
people were switching careers
they were not in a good space
with their job and they did not,
they were not making that much
money. So to be like, oh, the
only way to switch is because you
pay us $15,000. And I'm like, no,
like, mean, you can do that. If
that's the best fit for you, you
know, maybe you need like the
extra accountability, the extra
classes. But I, one of my big
things I like the community be
able to be providing those
mentoring resources that people.
They get out of bootcamps. You
should not only be able to find
that in bootcamp, you should not
be able to only network. If you
went to a bootcamp, you you,
shouldn't be able to only like
learn in a group setting in a
bootcamp. Um, so I felt like as a
member of the community, like I
wanted to do everything that I
could, build that up. fortunately
Pittsburgh is a lot smaller, so
didn't really, I didn't really do
the same thing in Pittsburgh
because at the time maybe I would
now, but at the time we had Girl
Develop It and I felt like that
would, we weren't big enough to
really have like competing
women's development groups. of
course now girl develop it sort
of imploded, but I maybe I'll
revisit later. Cause it is
obviously a passion of mine.
Bekah: Yeah I mean, there are
Pittsburgh, surprisingly has a
lot of tech stuff already going
on, which is really nice to see.
And I think, you know, I want to
hit on this idea that you were
talking about having community as
part of the learning experience.
I think one the things about
bootcamps that is tough is it
just kind of puts you in this
place where you only talk to the
people in your bootcamp. And so
it doesn't exactly mimic the
larger experience of what being a
developer is and communicating
with other people, all different
stages in, in what you're working
on. Right? And so of have this
insulated experience, but if
you're working with a community
of people, or if you're
developing this open
conversation, allows you to
create, I think, good habits of
communication, maybe,or something
that, that could really be one of
those things that allows you to
be really successful in ways that
boot camps.
Dan: I, I, yeah, a lot of the
stuff you said. I was wondering
if you could tell me a little bit
more about like, so with groups,
you did study groups, right? Um,
so open-ended study groups. Can
you, can you just like, me
through, like, what one, like
what, what one session, what,
what would happen, you know, at a
study group? Um, you know, in
particular, like at once pick
one.
Jennifer: yeah, it would really
depend on who came. Uh, so like
one example is over a period of
weeks, this one woman, um,
regularly and was trying to find
a job. So part of what was
actually just encourage her and
tell her that, like I knew where
she was. So I'm like, I know you
have the skills to do this. Like
I think you should apply you
know, absolute worst thing is get
rejected, but I think you have a
really good chance of getting
this job. You know, I helped her
review her resume and make it pop
a little bit more. And emphasize
if she was coming from the
restaurant industry, it was
applying to a program. No, it was
project manager position at a
tech company. Um, because that's
that was a particular position
that I felt like, that she was
interested in that would take the
skills she already had
professionally and could work
them into a much higher paying
And so that was one of the things
that would happen. But then
sometimes people would come in
and be like, oh, I'm working
through. This section of this
tutorial, I don't understand for
loops and I would try to go
through it with them, give
examples, walk them through,
maybe like, cause sometimes I
think sometimes people need like
a number of different examples or
to hear things a different way.
So maybe like the first thing I
say, like doesn't make sense I
used to be like, okay, let me try
another thing. And, um, I, I give
sort of like another type of
example of how it was supposed to
work.
Dan: totally.
Jennifer: eventually like
generally, eventually they get
it. And occasionally someone
would come with some sort of like
pandas question I'm like, we can
try and struggle through this
together, but I don't know
pandas.
Dan: Yeah.
Jennifer: FYI.
Dan: That's I mean, that's, that
sounds really cool. And so like,
this was pre COVID or whatever.
Right. So, so like, would it be
people would just like, I'll
bring their laptops and sit
around a circle or, I mean, I'm
just trying to, because I'm like,
I'm used to, like, you know, I've
been to a lot of meetups that are
mostly just presentations and
hang, you know, social time
afterwards or whatever. And this
sounds a little bit more, you
know, a little different of a, of
an experience that I'm really
interested in.
Jennifer: So I feel like it was
similar to the size of like the
Virtual Coffee breakout rooms,
because the group wasn't that
neither of these groups were
huge. Well by numbers, Py Ladies
Boston is bottom was huge, but
the number of people who would
come to the actual big monthly
meetups, wasn't that big. And the
number of people that come to
these where maybe three to seven,
you know, so I'd just be hanging
out in this coffee shop and we
just sort of take over a table. I
didn't get space, but yeah, I
think that's an, another thing is
for, for me, also overall like
Boston Ruby Women. We basically
didn't even do presentations at
all. It was more, but I think
this is in a way, like more
relevant for, uh, women and
underrepresented minorities. It
really helps to have a group
where you can talk about like
what's going on at work. And the
other people in the group, like
really understand because they're
in similar situations. Um, so
Boston Ruby Women we base, it was
borderline just a Ruby Women's
Happy Hour got sponsored by
thoughtbot, know? So we just like
chill out at thoughtbot half the
time be talking about like,
what's going on at our jobs and
with PyLadies Boston, I also
didn't want it to be
presentations all the time. A.
Because it's, as an organizer,
it's really hard to actually get
a monthly presenter, like someone
who wants to present every single
month. And one of the things I
ended up doing was, uh, rotating.
So I'd have presentations one
month. talks the next a panel,
usually about work. Those were
very popular. So I'd get like six
different women. Sort of like
different stages in their career
and doing different things about
like what they do and like what
work is like, what problems they
run into. Um, what else did I do?
Oh, I started doing mob
programming, which was also fun.
It was hard to get people to want
to volunteer.
Bekah: you describe what mob
programming
Jennifer: sure. mob programming,
at least the way we did it. It's.
Uh, the whole room is looking at
the same problem. So I would,
other piece, I would usually put
myself as a Guinea pig for any of
these. Like, I always had to have
a presentation ready or some code
because if we ran out of time,
I'm like, well, got to keep it
going. And so. For example, I had
this silly Python game I had
written a while back and took it
up there and I would run people
through like the premise of what
was going on in the code and then
asked for suggestions on things
that I should consider changing
or like what they see that could
be improved, anything like that.
So, It's fun. Not a ton of places
do it at work, but occasionally
people do sort of like pairing
with a massive group. So if
you're in a good environment, it
can be really fun.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. We tried that
one. We tried it once with the
Cleveland React meetup, it was,
it was a it was interesting. I
feel like with some practice, so
yeah, you can, you can make it
like a pretty cool thing. That's
awesome. I love how the
concentration of like the small
groups and the kind of like the
less of... you said, the happy
hour, like less, less of talking
of technical issues and more of
just laying, you know, community
support and, um, like just coming
together, you know, um,
Jennifer: Yeah. Also with our,
um, with our lightening talks,
uh, one of the things I encourage
was just like, you can give a
lightning talk on anything cause
I wanted it to good place to.
Encourage women to feel
comfortable giving presentations.
so like one of our members did a
presentation that everyone loved
on birds like birdwatching, you
know, and, and getting, and there
were plenty of people who did
technical topics, I think
oftentimes, um, and I still feel
this way. I like if, when it
comes to submitting a talk to a
conference on like, I'm not an
expert on any technical topics.
So I can't give a talk on any of
those. And I know that's not
necessarily a healthy thing to
think about, but at the same
time, I know that's what a lot of
people feel. So I didn't want to
be forcing people to technical
talks and have that be the only
option I felt like you need to
build up confidence in other
ways, like be okay with public
speaking first and then deal
with.
Dan: Yeah,
Jennifer: insecurity around
getting a talk on to on something
technical.
Dan: That seems like pretty good
advice that reminds me of, um,
was that organization that, that
Gant worked with, um,
Bekah: Toastmasters
Dan: as there's like a, uh,
organization just about, you
know, public speaking and getting
good at it. And so they would do
talks all the time, but I doubt,
I doubt it. I'm some of Gant's
were technical, but I liked the
idea of, I don't know, getting
used to it without having to
like, worry about all the extra
stuff. It's like learn one thing
at a time, you know, like, you
know, yeah. No, I love that. I
love that.
Bekah: I keep wanting to do like
a lightning talk session with
Virtual Coffee. That's like five
minutes and talk about something
you're interested in. That's not
technical because I think it's
also a really fun way to learn
new things and oh, that's the
person that I can talk to about
rock climbing or, you know,
whatever Um, of the things that
this reminded me of, and I wanted
to talk to you about, so talking
about this idea of talking
speaking technically. And I think
one of the things that I was told
early in my career is not to do
community because women are often
seen as, you do community, then
people only know you for
community. And they think that
you're non-technical. So I wanted
to get your take on that and kind
of like what the balance is.
Jennifer: That's probably partly
true, but part of me is like, I
don't care because I want to help
people. And if someone thinks
that, you know, running. a user
group is, is women's work well, A
like that's, that's really
frustrating. I'm sure there are a
lot of people who think that,
that seems extremely real to me,
even though the majority of user
groups are run by men, uh, you
know, who tend to get plenty of
conference talks because they run
like a massive user group or
something. Um, And I guess on the
flip side, I think it was overall
beneficial to me. it, I don't
want to say publicity, but I feel
like it got me a lot of like sort
of tech, publicity, um, in a way
that I don't think I was
necessarily expecting. Uh, so I
would have people reach out to
me. Um, That I don't think they
would have if I wasn't so uh,
doing the work with PyLadies
Boston. So I, I think it was
overall good. I'm sure there were
some people are like, this person
spends all their actually time on
user groups gross, but if it
always feels like lose, lose,
like it's like you're supposed to
do all of this stuff. You know,
and you are supposed to network,
know, but you're also, um,
supposed to be coding like
nonstop in your free time, which
actually like that's, that's
another thing I feel like I used
to think negatively about and I
think it was PyLadies that
changed my mind. And that's
partly because I realized that.
Really, like, like real
networking is building actual,
meaningful relationships, but
they happen to be with people who
are in your, um, wow. I'm totally
forgetting a word, but sort of
like your work circle, you know,
that, and. 'Cause. 'Cause I think
sometimes people think like, oh,
I'll just out to this rando on
LinkedIn, you know, and see if
they'll refer me, that's
networking, you know, or I'll ask
this random person I met once,
know about this company and that
will matter. And I'm like, that
does not matter, you know, but if
you're actually building up
relationships like. Yeah, I I've
definitely referred like really
referred to jobs. Like there's,
there's just like posting my
referral link. I don't really
count that. in the first startup
I actually worked at, after I
left, the contractor that I was
under with TripAdvisor, uh, I
referred the woman who was
co-organizing who stepped up to
help me co organize PyLadies
Boston,because I was like, I,
this point feel really strongly
that I know her work ethic, and I
know that she would be an asset
here. And so I advocated for her,
you know, and to me, that's what,
that's what you really want out
of networking. But you only get
that if you relationships and
show people like what you're
about and. And what you, I guess,
like what you value, right. And
they're like, oh, I want that
person on my team. They're so
great. Like I want to work with
them and you don't get that from
a one-off interaction. And I
think that's one of the things I
liked about Virtual Coffee. I
like that we do the small
breakout rooms and I think it
gives us a chance to build those
meaningful connections and make
us more likely that in the we'll
be able to actually refer each
other, you know, and advocate for
each other when trying to get
people hired.
Bekah: It's
Dan: absolutely. My list of
Virtual Coffee members that I
want to work, can work with is
very long, you know? And it's,
it's all, it's all that, it's
the, it's like the longterm, you
know, connections. The networking
metaphor is interesting. You
know, it's if you meet somebody
once and then walk away, is it.
Are they really in your network,
you know, if you're like building
on purpose, you know, like that
means strong connections. And
that means, you know, actually
spending time and effort on it,
you know, um, the, the term has
gotten loaded with a lot of
negative connotations for sure.
Like, I like everything always
does after a while, but it's one
of the reasons why, like, you
know, LinkedIn is a dumpster
fire, but like the, the, the fact
that like the interesting part of
the LinkedIn model is like the
first connection, second
connection, you know, like that
sort of thing, you know, um, is
like valuable information or,
well, maybe not on LinkedIn, but
you know, be, you know, that sort
of thing. Right? have like a
strong connection with this
person. I have worked with them
or I've, you know, uh, and then
you're like, okay, well, If Bekah
recommends somebody to me that I
don't know, that person is going
to be higher on my list than
people that I don't know at all.
Right. So it's like, sorry,
there's somebody slamming doors
outside, but, yeah. So I don't
know. I, I liked the way that I
liked the way that you were, you
were thinking about that. It's
it's cool. Let's see. Interesting
stuff.
Bekah: You were saying, you made
a lot of connections through
building community for people who
reached out to you for jobs I
know been true for me. And one of
the nice parts of it is I have a
whole group of people that I can
recommend. And so I think, you
know, when you get to that point
you know people, then you make
those personal connections and
it's really great to see, you
know, how far that goes out. You
know, I recommended a person for
a job. there. And then when they
left, they recommended another
person. Right. so then this whole
cycle of, know helping us
advocate for each other.
Jennifer: a hundred percent.
Bekah: So, okay. So the second.
One of the second pieces of
advice I got after starting
Virtual Coffee. this resonated
when you were talking about not
making people pay for PyLadies
was, well, if you're going to do
community, then you, you have to
charge a membership fee, right?
Like you have to get paid for
your time. And that's something
at Virtual Coffee that we've
always had a strong stance
against. You know, we never want
to make anyone pay for access to
and the content that we produce,
because think it's important to
allow that and for everyone in
our community. So what, was what,
I guess, what are your thoughts
on that of like people have to
pay for your time?
Jennifer: Uh, if it's not clear
here I a hundred percent agree
with not so with, with things
being free. here's the thing. to
me, it depends on who it is. Like
a company is asking me for advice
or someone is basically asking me
to effectively consult their
work. Yeah. No, pay me for my
time. Like. You know, I'm doing
work to further the capitalist
machine. Like I want money,
Dan: Yeah.
Jennifer: when it comes to people
who are potentially unemployed,
you know, and are just trying to
better their own life situation,
like, no, I don't want your
money. Like, especially. I think,
especially like where, where I
was like Coffee is obviously a
little bit broader, but at the
same time, there are so many
juniors in there. I'm like, I
don't, I never felt right. my
primary audience with PyLadies
was people who are not developers
being like, yeah, I'm a developer
making, know, a good salary or.
Can you pay me to, to, to help
you get there too. I you're not
making that much money, but give
some more of your money to me.
Dan: Okay.
Jennifer: I don't know. Maybe I,
maybe this is like the socialist
in me
Bekah: Okay
Jennifer: where I was like, no, I
want to help build people up. And
I guess maybe I also like don't
necessarily. I think that highly
of myself, that, you know, by
advice is worth money. So I would
feel really bad asking someone to
pay for it. And the other thing
is I'm not necessarily creating
the content. Right. You know,
there was some times where sure.
Like the class I could have maybe
charged for that. I didn't feel
right. Doing it. But for the most
part, yeah. members are giving
presentations. Why should I be
paid for this? Like if anything,
maybe I could've been like, Hey,
yeah, I'll take donations for,
for the cost of the meetup, but
it's really like, even a meetup
is only like, I dunno, like 80
bucks every six months or
something. It's not that huge in
the scale of things, especially
if you're making a software dev
salary within the U S so I was
just like, to be honest, it's not
even worth it. Cause then I have
to think about taxes
Bekah: Okay.
Jennifer: about getting gifts and
paying, like, to me, the other
thing I'm like, it's not even
worth the potential tax headache
of creating like a business and
getting paid for this. When also
I to do this. I want to help
people, like I'm not doing this
for money, I'm doing this because
like, I think, I mean, I think
everyone should learn to code
period, I also think being a
software developers is stinking
easy job. Like it's frustrating,
but it's not that hard, you
Bekah: Yeah.
Jennifer: And I think pretty much
like anyone can do it. We paid
way too much. And there are too
many jobs. Like even now, Where
it's really hard for juniors to
find a job. I know, at the same
time, it's because companies are
like, I don't know, we can only
hire seniors. And they're an
absolutely absurd amount like
Amazon, which I'm pretty sure
they wouldn't want to hire me
anyway for a number of reasons.
Um, like they keep emailing me
and I keep like this last time, I
think I responded back with, how
do I get blocklisted by Amazon?
Like, please let me know. I want
to be on a block list. also that
is, I think proof, like, there
are a lot of people who think
like, oh, if I do like then this
massive company is never gonna
hire me. No. I have like twitter
account that how unions are, you
know, and Amazon recruiters are
so like, "Want to for Amazon?"
Bekah: Uh,
Jennifer: like, frickin' no, I
don't, you know, but, sorry, I
just
Bekah: that was fantastic. No,
no. I love that. I wish that
everybody could have watched you
give that speech there because
your body language was fantastic.
Jennifer: I'm just full of like
rants and hot takes about tech.
Bekah: my like when you're in my
breakout room, I'm like, yes.
Dan: Oh man. Yeah, I did. This
podcast needs more hot takes.
Anyway. I think, you know, if
there's one thing missing, I like
the, I mean, I I agree with
everything you said though. And.
You know, we, as, as people, like
when you're running a community
and stuff, you'll get advice or
whatever, and part of it for me,
the way I've been thinking about
it, what you know is like, it's
not a, it's not a product, right?
We don't have people, you know,
you get people that come in
sometimes to communities and
want, just want something and to,
you know, leave again, you know,
but, uh, I think. That is another
benefit of more intimate
communities, uh, you know, is, is
you get a lot less of that, you
know, if you had, if your group
was just like people coming in
and saying job, please, and then
leave, you know, like, uh, all
the time, then that's like, okay,
let's turn this into a product.
And just like charge people you
know, but it's not, um, that's
not what like most communities
are about. Uh, it's certainly
possible to turn a community into
a product and make money off of
it. uh you see lot of people
doing it, but you know, it's, I
don't know. Then it's then I
start thinking of it as a
different thing than a community
at that point, you know, you know
what I mean? It becomes... a
Jennifer: as organizers, like you
also get a ton out of it. And I
think that's the other thing that
felt weird. Cause in a way I'm
like, well, I'm probably actually
getting the most out of this.
Like not only am I getting to
constantly try to you know flex
my mentoring muscles and get
better at that. Um, because I'm
the one like making up the random
extra time, you know, I have to
give way more presentations I'm
still not the world's greatest
public speaker, but did I improve
drastically from having to give a
bunch of mediocre presentations
at PyLadies? Hell yeah, I did.
know, and I was the one there
every single month, which means
got to meet a bunch of absolutely
amazing people. So yeah, it's
like, I, I'm getting the more out
of this than anyone else. Why
should people pay
Dan: Yeah
Jennifer: also to basically just
meet me?
Bekah: And pay for your
autograph.
Jennifer: tell you right now.
Don't don't pay for that
pleasure.
Dan: When you put it that way and
that makes me want to charge
people.
Jennifer: Just charge for
autographs.
Bekah: We told you we were
charging for this podcast
episode, is one.
Dan: We'll send you, we'll send
you the bill.
Jennifer: I'll S I'll send them
the same one we can do, you know,
in, in trade it kind trade for
the pleasure of of each other's
company.
Bekah: All right, so I'm ready
for some more hot takes. So you
are, have done a lot of work to
get women and minorities into
tech. So are things that
companies are doing that exclude
women or the red flags that we
should look out for?
Jennifer: Uh, well, my favorite
is the stuff you don't get until
you're actually there. And
especially this. think it's
specififcally towards possibly
some other minorities, but I
think specifically women where
you get called, like you're more
likely to be called like cynical
or shoot. I'm trying to think of
another thing from one of my
reviews. at splice, but at a
recent company that will not be I
an article put in my review.
Again, I'm a native US English
speaker how to be more polite and
tactful in American English. You
know, so I stopped doing those
things, like, you know, think
about If you're a manager
Dan: did they think you were like
Canadian or something
Jennifer: N no, for
Dan: Sorry
Jennifer: sure. For sure. Not,
but even if, Canadians also like
really any like Um, you're a
manager listening to this
Dan: and have been
Jennifer: like, well, I got
feedback from this woman's
coworkers on how she was. So
brusque consider if that feedback
might be gendered and maybe don't
give it to him, to her and,
Bekah: Yeah.
Jennifer: tell him. The people
who gave you that feedback, but
they should probably sit with,
their, uh, preconceptions of how
a woman should speak. Um, but to
me, like the biggest struggle,
and I think why we've had so many
trouble, is often aren't ton of
glaring red flags in Um, cause
honestly, so one of. You can't
even count on diversity. One of,
one of my favorite teams that I
worked on was me and all white
dudes. But they were wonderful
Like I still talk to a lot of
these guys. They were the most
supportive, I think of almost any
other team worked on. You know,
one of them would regularly if he
was working on something
interesting. Call me over to, to
pair be like, I think this would
be really fascinating for you.
Like, um, dig into this. And this
was when I was only maybe like a
couple of years into my career.
So. Like still pretty junior,
like, you know, egging into
mid-level. I know at this point,
like people are like senior after
two years, whatever. Um, it's all
meaningless. Um, you're senior
after two years, where are you
going? Like your career is going
to be like fricking 30 years plus
years long. Um,
Bekah: burnout.
Jennifer: go at a certain point.
Um, that's another. Okay. Uh, And
versus a company that I worked at
that was extremely diverse or,
well, extremely diverse was like,
okay, on gender issues. But if we
brought up any sort of racial or
ethnicity issues, it was, it was
bad. It was, it was real bad. I
was at one point accused of anti
Southern bias. At that I am a
Southerner by the way, I grew up
in Alabama, as I mentioned, I
lived in Georgia for seven years.
I still that's still most of my
life, so I still very much
identify as a southerner. And
yeah, I was because I had
mentioned something about long
voting lines throughout the south
and I'm just like, well, hi. I
remember standing in a really
long line in Atlanta. I don't
know about you.
Bekah: yeah,
Jennifer: so. I've I've basically
found that I don't feel. And the
other thing is I've, even if
you're trying to judge based on
diversity, you might not even be
giving answers. Like when I asked
at one point in one company I
joined the interview about like,
what, uh, of like how womendo do
you have in engineering The guy
was like, oh yeah. You know,
like, I don't have the exact
numbers, but like, know, yeah. We
have like, women are in
engineering management. And then
I joined looking at the org chart
and there like three women in
engineering. Me, woman on my
team, one person in QA, there is
no one in management. I was like,
What So, so. I mean, honestly,
like, I feel like the big things
for companies I'm just like, stop
doing most of what you're doing.
Um, like it's, it's all bad. Um,
but like don't, don't lie to
people because also if someone
really cares about that, going to
be put off and they're going to
leave quickly. Um, you know, try
to be honest about where you are,
like this is for any hiring
managers. The honest about where
you are and where you actually
are trying to go. Um, and the
other thing is when people, and
people of color your company and
give you feedback on how the
process is going. I think. Don't
react negatively. Like don't get
defensive I think that's the, the
hardest thing. Cause I've been in
many places where I've tried to
be like, Hey, I think we should
consider doing this. And people
have gotten extremely defensive
and it's like, I didn't care, I
would just leave. I don't need to
stay here. Like I'm only giving
this feedback and trying to make
it better because I care about
where I am and I want, I want
this to be like a better place to
work. I want people to, to love
it, you know? And, and I think a
lot of times people miss that,
you know that if you are giving,
if you're trying to get involved
in, in, and that's, the other
thing is don't don't necessarily
make. Women and minorities do D I
efforts, but also consider
talking to least some of them if
you're consider implementing a
change, because I've seen a lot
of changes for the good of equity
and diversity rolled out that
were quite poor
Bekah: Yeah
Dan: Sure. Do you have any, do
you have any advice for for.
Somebody Who, so, so maybe went
through the interview red flags,
you know, landed in a position
like that, where they're
uncomfortable, maybe like, and I
suppose the experience is going
to be different if you're coming
in as a senior or somebody, you
know, a little more comfortable.
I mean, I don't want to speak for
you, but I would imagine you
would have no problem just
quitting a job. Right. Uh, you
know, like if you're
uncomfortable, but if you're, if
it's your first job, for
instance, a first tech job,
especially something like that,
you have any, I any
Jennifer: If first job, it's
extremely toxic. If it's
extremely toxic just start
applying You got one job. You can
probably get another don't. I
would generally not recommend
quitting before you have another
job. I've only ever done that
once. And it was a really,
really, really bad environment.
But I also talked to my husband
about it and was like, can we
afford to do this? And he was
like, because I'm tired of you
complaining this terrible place
Um he still didn't get rid of me
complaining about that for
probably like two years. Cause it
was that bad. Um, so it's, if
it's really bad start looking for
another job, like if it's
extremely toxic, it's. Just a
bunch of things where you're
like, Ugh, this is really
annoying. Try to buckle down. And
know, if it's your first job,
even getting just a year of
experience is going to make you
put you in a better position to
get a better job. And I, I
generally don't think you have to
stay out of a job for a year, but
again, when it's your first tech
job, you need experience. Um, so
being able to say just suck it
up, hopefully people with more.
Power in that particular
workplace will speak up. I don't
want to, I, the reason I try to
speak up is because I am
confident in my ability to
quickly get another job. If
things go downhill, do I want to
be fired? No. But, you know, do I
feel like it's my responsibility
for people who are coming in, who
are more junior who have less
power, like to make sure that
they're in a safe as safe a work
environment as I can make it.
Yes. But if you are that person
who is more junior, do not feel
obligated to speak up because
you're just not in the best
position to do that. Once you
start getting. Next level senior,
maybe start advocating for others
a bit more because it really is
important we all, like, I don't
think it should only be up to,
um, women and underrepresented
minorities to call out racism and
sexism in the workplace. Um, and.
It can be a little frustrating.
Um, when you know, I'm working
with, uh, a bunch of guys and
they're all, they're all really
great, but you know, they're not
really, they're not dealing with
the same crap that I am, cause
they're not putting themselves
out there and pushing back
against bad policies. So,
Dan: Yeah
Jennifer: but if you're junior,
on tight, uh, it'll get better.
Don't give up, even though tech
is mostly trash, like, our most
workplaces, you're a bunch of
people talking about quitting
tech and I'm like, nowhere's
better. Everywhere. Sucks.
Bekah: Yeah
Dan: Uh, my, my,
Bekah: academia's awful
Dan: yeah, the academia. Um, I
have no my imagi I always
imagined just going into the
woods, you know, by myself. If I,
when I imagine quitting you know
it there's no people around him.
I imagined, you know, ideal job,
trees and stuff. I don't, I don't
know what the job is
Bekah: Dan Daniel also work with
me
Dan: don't know going to oh yeah.
Well, you're fine. You know, most
times, but, uh, no
Jennifer: You can
Dan: just tech is
Jennifer: ranger.
Dan: tech. Yeah. Forest ranger. I
feel like I I
Jennifer: There's
Dan: ended up.
Jennifer: there.
Dan: Yeah. I feel like you just
ended up having to like, be
chasing kids out of the park that
had smoking weed or so they're
not, I don't know, whatever, you
know, like, you know, just being
like a security guard, almost
ranger I need something yet. I
need like a trail maintenance. I
don't know where it's somewhere
somewhere, far away so I can just
disappear for a couple of months
and then come back
Jennifer: Rural Canada.
Dan: Yeah I'll go in Algonquin.
It's something like that. Anyway.
That's
Bekah: I found one of the things
that's been helpful for me is in
having a community and then
having a network. There are
enough people that I know or
connections through people. I
know that I can ask What what is
this work environment like and
get an honest answer. And that
has been so important. So
networking is important to find a
job, but also it's very important
to find a good job. And like, I
don't mean pay, I mean, good
place to work.
Dan: And actually that just made
me think that another bonus is
having people to ask advice of
in, in, if they're in situations,
you know, where they're not sure
what to do or whatever, you know,
actually having somebody who's
been through that, uh, to, to ask
us bonus of community.
Jennifer: I think that can help.
But caveat is like one of what
was for me, like one of the jobs
I've had was that a place that
friends worked at and they loved
and other people I knew work at
in loved, but. Like I ended up
not only did I get under leveled
when I joined and that's
something that's hard to tell
because every place is leveling
is totally different, know? So I
don't know until I joined it, I'm
like, wait, what? Now I see
everyone's levels This messed up.
Um, it's also a lot of places to
really dependent on your manager.
And so the people who were. Being
like, oh, this is such a good
place. They all had a different
manager than me. I did end up
switching teams at a, at a point,
but like original manager was
really, really bad. And like
that, that's sort of the thing
with. What have you said about
like a home Depot? I had net
positive experience working
there, partly because I did
coworker and I ended up talking
to HR about situation and they
were able to remedy it for her,
but not for me because straight
up part of it, I was like, well,
I don't think this job is right
for me. Like, if I had a
different manager, um, But I
think my experience would have
been totally different and I
probably would've stayed longer
than like eight months. I'd had a
better, a better manager that I
know did exist there, you know?
So
Dan: Oh, on.
Jennifer: really, I feel like it
can help. It can potentially get
you away from like really bad
situations, but not a guarantee.
Which sucks, it did help. Like
one of, uh, one of my really good
friends works at Splice we talked
a lot before I even applied. And
she was like, oh yeah, like
here's the crappy shit that's
going on. Or that has gone on,
you know, is going on. And I was
like, oh, that all actually
sounds fine to me. none of those
are deal breakers. I'm, I'm good.
I'll apply. That sounds great.
Sounds so much better than now.
Dan: I'm trying to think. I don't
even know. Are there any other
hot buttons can push or
Jennifer: One take I'm planning
on writing on my blog is that
may, which I think getting to be
less and less of a hot take.
Good. Um, is that being a
full-stack developer is bullshit.
one, no one is truly a hundred
percent full stack because it is
fricking impossible because it is
hard enough to keep up with all
of the front end things only. And
it's hard enough to keep, uh, to
fully learn a backend language,
to get to the point where you're
end optimizing your database,
every, like it's hard enough to
really gain any sort of expertise
either side and anyone who says
they're a full-stack developer,
I'm sort of like, Hmm. But what's
your favorite because that's what
you're actually good at. And the
other thing is just the thing
you're sort of forced to do. And
you're probably not doing very
well. I say that as someone who
has been a full stack developer
and has been poorly doing HTML
and CSS forever Script probably
fine. Like I've had to do it for
long enough that I I'm fine at
it, but put me on like some real
like front end front end. And I'm
like, where's bootstrap. Oh, I
have to make a change to
bootstrap. lets not. just, let's
just make this super bootstrappy
and then we're good.
Dan: Uh, as somebody who's been
like actual front-end
concentration for a very, very
long time. I absolutely agree
with you back end stuff. is hard
to, and it's like hard. It's hard
to do it well, and there's,
there's so many I don't know I'm
with ya. I'm with you on it. If
you need a pull quote or
something
Bekah: Okay
Jennifer: maybe I'll ask for some
quotes. That'll be fun. I'll ask
all of us. That is a question.
And in Virtual Coffee, who wants
to give me their hot takes on why
being full stack is not, is real
Bekah: what I think it's so hard.
a lot of like full stack bootcamp
programs out there. then there
are people coming out of those
boot camps, looking for full
stack jobs. I just. Struggle with
that path because your learning
and just come out of a big
learning experience, but it makes
more sense to to be able to focus
on one aspect and understand the
other for sure, but to really
dive deep into that. So you can,
so you can level up and get to a
mid level position
Jennifer: Yeah, I totally agree.
And I think the. Like what's
really pushing This is companies
who want just one developer who
does their front end, their
backend and their operations. you
know, you should know
Dan: okay.
Jennifer: I'm just going to go
with, you know, rails, Ruby. Uh,
PostGrest AWS. I'm probably
probably missing a couple, you
know, probably a Reddis, you
know, gotta toss in Reddis just
for good, good measure or
something
Dan: my pet Webpack or whatever,
whatever. Well, I guess if you're
in grab, you can use whatever
ridiculous nonsense of rails
does, but, uh
Jennifer: Hotwire now
Dan: yeah. Hotwire
Bekah: no more no more React
Dan: it's so funny cause it's
like how it always used to be and
then it wasn't and then it was,
and you know, it's like, there's
this golden age where. You know
where there were really just
backing in front of developers,
you know, cause it front and got
complicated enough. Backend was
harder than that. It's just,
Jennifer: I think always been
complicated enough. I say that as
someone who was like, you know,
messing around with my angel,
FireSIGHT when I was 13 and, you
know, trying to get scrolling
text, I wasn't that great at it
then. And to be honest, I really
haven't improved that much.
Dan: yeah, no, it just keeps
getting more complicated.
Jennifer: I can get solid
scrolling text going by but
That's about it.
Dan: Dope.
Jennifer: My personal built in
Squarespace because you know
don't have time for that shit.
Dan: That's what somebody was
just asking about that on, on,
um, on Virtual Coffee, I think
Jennifer: Oh, really?
Dan: it's okay. Like their
backend developer there, it was
like a Ruby developer maybe or
something and, um, yeah. And they
were just like, is it okay if I
don't, if I use a template or
whatever, you know? Um, yeah. I
mean, my answer was emphatically
Yes. Like,
Jennifer: Yeah.
Bekah: a front end developer. I
use a template.
Dan: Yeah. I mean, whatever
Bekah: It decreases the barrier
to entry for me. Like I will sit
there and trying to design, I'm
not a designer. Right. Or like
get all of the things Right. It's
just, it's too much work to have
to think about that and, figuring
out all of the things. So
Dan: Yep.
Bekah: somebody has already done
it. They have done it well, it
cost $37
Jennifer: Yep.
Dan: hard to work on your own
stuff too spend time on it.
Bekah: Well, I think that's an
excellent hot take to end on. So
thank you so much, Jennifer, for
being here and giving us all of
your hot takes and sharing with
us, your journey. this is really
a really great and a lot of fun.
So thank you.
Jennifer: You're Welcome. I'm
always here for hot takes. Anyone
can hit me up in Virtual Coffee
for the hot take of the day.
Bekah: Oh yes. We need hot take
of day
Jennifer: We should
Dan: imagining like a lightening
talks except hot take lightening
Bekah: Oh Oh, well, if we're
going to do
Jennifer: That should be of the
weekly reminders. What's take
Dan: Ooh, I like it.
Bekah: well, we need a slack bot.
All right.
Dan: Oh man. Yes. I'll add my,
thanks to this. This was really
great. I appreciate your time and
appreciate you coming on.
Bekah: All right, we'll see you
soon. Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please subscribe
to our podcast and be sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!