Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode four of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey, and they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we got
to talk to Mark Noonan. Mark is
a
senior engineer at Cypress.io
and is a co-organizer at Code
for
Atlanta. He also works as a
program developer for People
Making Progress ,an Atlanta
based nonprofit serving adults
with
developmental disabilities at
home, work and in the community.
Um, mark shared with us how his
background in music and theater
informs his work as a developer,
which I found really
interesting.
And then we spent the rest of
the episode talking about his
experience in civic tech, how
working with local civic tech
groups can benefit your
community, uh, can benefit other
developers and, and of course
your own career as a developer.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, we do and a random
check-in question. We hope you
enjoy this episode. Today's
random check-in question. Is,
would you rather be the funniest
or the smartest person in the
room? So my name is Bekah. I am
a front end developer from a
small
town in Ohio. And I think I
would like to be the funniest
person in
the room it, because it makes it
easier to talk to people. And
you're more likable, I think.
And my grandma was funny and I
always
want to be as funny as my
grandma. So I'm going with that.
Dan: Uh, hi, I'm Dan. I am a
developer from Cleveland, Ohio.
And, um, yeah, I don't know. I
feel like lots of times the
funniest person often is pretty
smart anyway, you know, um, like
I don't want to be the person in
the room that everybody's
laughing at, you know, but, um,
right. So sure. I, I would take
a
funniest person and then. that
means you are absolutely not the
smartest person in the room, you
know? Uh, but like could still
have second place or something.
I think that's, I think that's
good.
Bekah: So now you're claiming
second place. Smartest first
Second place smart
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I mean, as long
as that's in the realm of
possibility, I'm not saying, you
know, I'm not saying that's, I'm
saying, you know, this, this
exercise, you know, if I say I'm
always the smartest or the
funniest person in the room, you
know, but it's not like saying
that means you're also the least
smart person in the room.
Bekah: No, that was not one
Dan: It's still open. Yeah.
That's what I'm saying. So it's
still, it's still possibility. I
could at least still imagine
that
I'm the second smartest person
in the room.
Bekah: right.
Dan: If I've made this choice.
Bekah: You're the funniest you
can imagine that you are the
second smartest person.
Dan: All right. That's it.
That's my answer. Yes.
Mark: All right. Um, and I'm
Mark Noonan. I am a senior
engineer at
cypress.io. Um, I live in
Atlanta, Georgia, and I'm mostly
happy just to be in the room.
That's good for me. Um, I
probably would prefer to be the
funniest person than the
smartest
person. Uh, if I had to make
that choice, but in this
specific room
with the two of you, I will take
first place, smartest person
ahead of Dan and
Dan: I mean
Bekah: Gues I'm third place
then,
Dan: somebody had do it.
Mark: if, this how the
Bekah: I'm gonna fight for
funniest. And then I'll be third
place. First smartest.
Dan: I mean, I called dibs on
second place. I don't know what
to tell you.
Bekah: I didn't even know that
was an option. wasn't an option.
You made it up.
Dan: That's it. Listen, I always
gotta call dibs when its
available.
Mark: Everbody in a room of
three it's. Okay. Everybody's
walking
away with something yet.
Bekah: I I like I have lost in
the, I got the participation
ribbon I got purple ribbon.
Welcome Mark, and is really good
to have you here with us and
being the smartest person in the
room. so we'll let you do most
of the talking today. Um, we
always
like to start off with your
origin story, how you got to
this
point of where you are in your
developer career. So you could
give us your overview, we would
love here it.
Mark: Okay. Um, I'm going to try
to remove some of the twists and
turns. Um, but the short version
is I kind of thought about doing
this job really since I was a
teenager, I started making
websites and stuff like that.
Um, but when I was like 16, 17,
yeah.
I was in Ireland where I grew up
and I was learning bits and
pieces of programming and
hitting some problems. And I
just hit a
point where I was sure this was
not for me. Like you had to be
more into maths. You have to be
smarter than I was to be good at
programming. Um, and a lot of
that had to do with what was
available to me. Education wise,
if you get stuck with a book
that
you got from the library, um,
just very hard, like back then,
this is right around the year,
2000, it's a little bit harder
to
get resources than it is today.
So I ended up going to college
for music and English and, um,
did a master's in
ethnomusicology
like That's my education
background loved all of that
stuff, but I kind of kept
getting sucked into making
websites on
the side. Um, and gradually like
found more and more things where
I'm like, oh, I wish I could do
that. So I could make this for
this reason, for this family
business or whatever. Yeah. And
eventually found myself finding
things like free code camp and
CS
50, um, using those courses to
learn more. that kind of got me
into the Atlanta Free Code Camp
Community, which got me
connected
to Code for Atlanta, which is
like civic tech code for America
non-profit work, which really
aligned with the, my day job,
which was at a nonprofit,
working with adults with
developmental
disabilities. Um, so I just kept
doing more stuff and learning
more things until like, it was
kind of obvious. I was able to
do
this for a job and it was time
to start thinking about
switching.
And so that led me to, being
developer Twitter, following
people, uh, connecting with
people there. And that kind of
introduced me to some places
where I could interview and
slowly get better at
interviewing. And then, you
know,
I found a job.
Bekah: That's awesome. I love
the non-traditional backgrounds
and I
feel like we hear a lot of
people that have come from music
backgrounds and made the
transition into dev world. And
my
background's in English too. Did
you find like you were able to
use any transferable skills or
that background helped you in
some way as you learned to code?
Mark: I I think looking back,
there are a couple of ways. Um,
is like you practice music,
you're able to get into flow as
you play. Um, and so there's
this. It happens with writing
too, where you have this
experience on your own of
working
on something and being in the
moment of like, and stuff coming
together. it can still be
challenging, but it's sort of
fun
and you don't notice the time
passing. Um, and it seems like
when we're learning development
or actually doing like the
day-to-day work, um, being able
to get into that state, um, kind
of on-demand is really useful so
that you can actually settle in
and achieve something and a few
hours. Without quite having a
full plan going in how you do
it. I think that's useful from
playing an instrument. Um, also
we used to have to read like big
symphony scores or just lots of
interconnected pieces. And
you're
supposed to be able to talk
about how they work together.
And I was
never like really that into the
theory part of what we were
doing
in college, but it did exercise
a part of my brain that was
like,
and same with plays and with,
with any kind of complicated
structures you're supposed to
get into, um, theater was a big
thing
for me in college. And so the
combination of like thinking
about a hour or two long play as
a whole script and writing some
and directing some as well as,
we have this big, complicated
thing
but we have 48 hours to build
all the sets and stand this show
up
and do it for a week. And
there's a lot of rushing around
as well
as trying to maintain this
complicated. Like, so all of
that, at least I feel like it
exercise some of the same stuff
mentally for me that I'm using
now being directly like how to
write a form in HTML or
something.
Dan: I love that. Never really
connected the flow state thing
with you. You're totally right
with me between music and, and
developing. Um, I like the, I
mean, I just really liked the
way
you described that and it is
true. Like once you said it, you
know, I thought I thought about
it and it is the exact same way.
Like, and you can feel when
you're not in it too, you know,
but you can feel when you're in
it. And that idea of like,
putting, just getting started on
something and not knowing
exactly
how it's going to turn out, but
you're, you know, and it it's
like you're driving it, but it's
still like you're in that flow,
so you're not forcing it. And at
the end, something, hopefully at
least something, something has
come out, um, I, I had never, I
never connected those, those
two, the music, like the music
flows
state and then developing flow
state before. I, I really
appreciate that. That was cool.
Bekah: Yeah, I liked that a lot.
And like, thinking about how all
of the pieces are working
together and whatever you're
doing. that sometimes we think
about transferable skills, like,
okay. And how do they exactly
match up? But you're talking
about like exercising, the same
muscles or the same part of your
brain to learn new things. And
you know, if you're breaking
down
a poem if you are matching
patterns, is. When you're
writing
or playing music, those are all
things that we're doing as
coders. It doesn't necessarily
mean that we can understand
directly how that works, but I
think it certainly helps to
build
those skills as we learn new
things.
Mark: Yeah. And I think it sort
of, when I started to listen to
specific podcasts, as
programmers were talking, this
is what kind
of helped me go from learning on
my own to being able to with
others and interact with other
developers. was like, I got
quite
far on my own, but I didn't know
how to say any of the words out
loud. So listening to podcasts,
when called Coding Blocks and
stuff like Code Newbie. And let
me hear how developers were
talking. And one concept was
like levels of abstraction. And
they're talking about not mixing
levels of abstraction, which
when
you're new that's a complicated
concept because you have, you're
not sure what levels of
extraction means. Let alone to
know if you're mixing them or
not. Um, but when I start to
think of like, yeah, you can
spend time looking at a single
line in a, in a play or
something or, uh, the
conversation or the
whole scene and zoom out further
to see how things like structure
really relate to each other. Um,
and understanding what layer of
the structure you're in, when
you're doing something. Yeah.
Like the ability to zoom in and
out to a specific layer and
understand its purpose and the
structure connected above and
below it. Um, that is hard to
like articulate, I think, in
programming because it's often
so abstract. but when you're
making
art, you have to think about
those layers all the time,
because you're working on the
details of a piece and on the
whole, the whole piece and each
script do it seamlessly without
knowing that you're zooming in
and out. Um, but I do think they
kind of relate.
Bekah: Oh, absolutely. And I
love that that's, that was such
a
great description of how you
kind of look at things together
and,
and have to break it apart at
the same time and move back at
that.
It is it's like, um, I was gonna
like, when. No, it's not coming
there. was something in there
about like being blurry and not
being blurry, but.
Mark: no, I think that you like,
especially with your background
in writing. There's a first
draft where you cannot get lost
in the
details, or you'll never finish
the first draft. Um, and that's
a
whole different layer of the
work, trying to get something
that has roughly the structure
you want. Um, and it's, uh, it's
so difficult to make progress if
you get stuck on one paragraph
or
one sentence. Um, and I actually
I'm bad at that. I don't write
and never wrote novels or
attempted to write a novel. Um,
because cannot, um, sustain that
first draft mode long enough to,
to really produce something like
that. So I ended up really
liking, working in theater,
really liking, working on poems
and songs because that lives in
the zoomed in world of a smaller
structure where I feel happy,
and I feel like it's okay to
spend
time working on sentences,
paragraphs, words, line breaks.
Okay. And uh, if I try to write
a 400 page novel like that, I
just
would never, ever get it done.
Um, so yeah, I think that that
blurry not blurry makes some
sense in that sense.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. And you know,
like when you're going there's,
your rough draft, right. For no
matter what you do, like you can
have a coding, rough draft to
where you're. Get it working.
Right. But that you can make the
code better. so I think even
like, if you break down the
process, you can pseudo code
something and then you can code
and make it work. And that's
your
second draft. And then you can
go back and do those revisions
that
really make it do what you want
it to do, but also like how you
want it to do it in the most
efficient way that you can. Um,
I
like thinking of that as part of
the process. I don't think that
I
thought about that before, but
that makes a lot of sense to me.
Mark: Yeah, lately, I've started
a routine where I will do that.
Get it working past first, even
if it's horrendous. Um, and then
I will write the tests for the
thing that I just wrote that's
working so that, um, I can go
through and refactor and try to
make it right. Code-wise and you
know, to think about reuse and
thinking about readability and
stuff. Um, and then at a certain
point, I know it's still wrong,
but I have to cut it off and
make
a pull request because there's,
there's not much value in making
it better to read or, or like
more efficient to reuse
something
because we do have to actually
complete work. Which also really
reminds me of when I used to
send poems out to magazines. I'm
like,
I know this is still terrible,
but it's time. It's time to send
it out. Um,
Bekah: I found magazine, poetry
magazine editors were the
meanest
people that I have ever met.
They would the meanest
rejections
this. You are personally
attacking me. What is, why, why
did you do that to me?
Mark: I used to, I think the,
the framing of this that I heard
was
that, um, like poems are never
finished. They're just
abandoned,
like at a certain point and you
have to move on with your life
and start writing the next one.
Um, and so there's so many even
great things that we love that
people have made that you look
back and you just see, these
are, um, you know, The things
somebody
felt anxious about and hated and
thought it was, it's still not
finished when they released it.
And like, luckily you don't get
to actually experience that when
you read the work.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I mean, I think
that's true. And I, I mean, you
were
saying this, but I think that's
true of pretty much anything you
can create. Right. I mean, you
can try to improve things
forever, you know? And, um, I've
heard that advice. You know,
from
a lot of other people too, is
especially, uh, when it comes to
maybe blogging, things like
that. Right. It's like, just get
it out
there, you know, and then you
can always improve it if you
want to
later, um, you know, Jono was on
talking about the, um, was it
the
digital garden, you know, and,
um, how you can kind of put
something out there even in a
rough draft. I mean, like it's
up
to your comfort level, but it's
okay to like put, put things out
there, you know? that aren't
completely perfect because
nothing is ever going to be
completely perfect and accepting
that it can be hard for sure.
I've found myself deep in a hole
spending half an afternoon on
something that literally like
has
no effect on the world and
nobody is ever going to notice
or care
if it's better or is, or, you
know, and I'm just like, I know
I
could do the, you know, I can
have, I know I can get better. I
know I can like whatever and, it
can be easy, be easy to step
into
that trap.
Mark: Yeah. That's all. It was
the stuff that ends up later on
getting like cut from the
roadmap.
Dan: Yeah. And then that reminds
me, that does, the other thing I
was going to say is, is getting
that poll request. So like,
there
is a, there is a, a level of
refinement that you want to wait
until other people maybe have
looked at something first to, to
confirm that it's even going to
stay, that it's even going to be
worth like the, uh, the extra
time, you know, if needed or, or
even if it's needed, you know?
Um, and most of the time, I
think
when a teammate will look at
something, they'll be like,
yeah,
This is good. You know, this is
good enough. Like let's, let's
keep moving. Cause we can put
efforts, you know, in other
places, but it can be hard to
let go sometimes.
Bekah: Yeah. And so, so we're
talking about, you know,
relating
all of these different things
from music and writing and
coding. And so you have this
non-traditional background, but
you also, um, done a lot of
work, helping other people from
non-traditional backgrounds
coming into the industry. Um,
can
you just talk a little bit
about, you know, how you've done
that
and maybe share a highlight
story?
Mark: Yeah, totally. Um, so for,
for me, Like the thing that
really helped me about this as a
job and change was starting to
go
to meetups in Atlanta. Um, and
at my first meetup, it was a, it
was
a meetup for to think that
pancakes might be about to
arrive. No, maybe yes. Unclear.
Okay. We're going to move on.
Bekah: can go check for your
pancakes.
Dan: I are there pancakes for
all of us?
Mark: Let's find out.
Bekah: I don't like pancakes.
Dan: You don't like pancakes,
Bekah: like a savory breakfast
person. I usually don't like the
sweet stuff.
Dan: but Bekah,
Bekah: Maybe crepes that are
like stuffed with cream cheese,
filling that I will take those.
Dan: I'd do a savory crepe. A
Crepe I would prefer to be
savory
then than sweet, like a, like a
crepe with like cheese and meat
or something in it, you know,
but like, Pancakes, but Pancake
you
can like a pancake on its own if
you make it, unless you're going
crazy yet. It's not very sweet.
Right. And so it's all about how
much, like stuff you put on top
of it. Right.
Bekah: it was just like boring.
I don't know.
Dan: But I'm saying mix it in
with some of your, some like
meat
and eggs and you know, and a
little bit of syrup because you
know, a little bit of sweet with
a savory, you know, like really
like helps everything kinda.
Bekah: Are you telling me to mix
up my pancakes with meat.
Dan: not mixed. I mean, I'm
saying eat them on a plate
together. Not, not mixed not
like mixed up next to each other
and
then eat them at the same time
as if it was a meal
Mark: they, they,
Dan: with multiple points. Like.
Mark: um, eitherway I have
pancakes now I'm not going to
eat
them right next to microphone
though, for, for everyone's
benefit. Um, but, uh, so get
back to this first meetup I went
to,
is, uh, like
Bekah: Thanks for bringing it
back, Mark. Cause I could've
gone.
Dan: I know I'm already
spiraling on this pancake thing.
Mark: So Yeah. So I. Part of
Free Code Camp was your
onboarding and
Free Code Camp. And they tell
you to go join the Facebook
group for
your city. Um, and if there's
not a Facebook group in your
city,
you're supposed to start it. So
it's really good. It was, that
was how it was back then, at
least. Um, I found the Facebook
group for Free Code Camp
Atlanta, and, uh, there were
meeting at a
certain coffee shop at a certain
time. So my first tech meetup, I
was pretty nervous. I didn't
know how to act at a tech
meetup. I
didn't know too many people in
Atlanta yet, or what even
happened there. So I go to the
coffee shop. And I see a group
of
like six or seven people sitting
around a table with laptops and
talking and stuff. And I'm like,
okay, this is obviously the
right
group. And so I walk up and I'm
talking to them for a few
minutes
asking people, what are they
working on? You know, just
they're like, Hey, what are you
doing? I'm learning this and
working on some Java script. And
then at some point I mentioned
Free Code Camp and they didn't
know what I was talking about.
Bekah: Yeah.
Mark: This was a group of
strangers. Who were just
tolerating me, interrupting
their meeting. And they were
just too
nice to tell me to go away. Um,
and so once we figured it out,
we
had a little bit of a laugh and
I was like, okay, well, the
worst
has happened. This the worse
thing that could possibly happen
with these meetups. So I'm
through that. Um, but what it
was
was people were from code for
Atlanta. And so they were like,
we're, we're not your meetup
that you came to, but we do run
a
different meetup and you should,
you should come to that. I was
like, there's no way I'm going
to go to that. I can't live this
moment down. Does no, just, uh,
going to stay as far away from
that as I can obviously. And,
uh, so I went over to the other
table
where there were just two people
sitting down there that was
like,
asked a crucial question. Are
you Free Code Camp meet up, um,
and
who was sitting there was
Nerando Johnson and our friend
Krista,
that's the two people that were
there. And, uh, obviously that
was a life-changing moment for
me, cause me and Nerando and
Krista had been friends ever
since, um, and help each other.
So the kindness of everybody at
that meetup and through people
showing up to just like. I
realized that week after week,
people were going there who were
not just learning, but also
people who had been through it
and people who had jobs and were
coming back just to hang out and
answer questions and support.
Um,
and so I learned so much from
those meetups, having specific
people there who could say, oh,
the problem you're having today,
the solution is not. Continue
hacking in the bad way that
you're hacking the solution is
you should learn Firebase so
that
you can users and have data
stored properly. And that will
solve like all of the pain that
you're having, trying to
something weird with cookies or
write to the server in PHP or
whatever. Um, so those moments
were really helpful for me. And
going to, when I actually did
start going to Code for Atlanta,
getting into the hackathons
there, like just improved my
confidence and improve my
skills. So having gone through
that, I
think it's nice to sort of pay
that back when are new in the
industry as well. You always
learn a lot when you're trying
to
help people. I vividly remember
the sort of embarrassment and
hesitation that you feel when
you're starting to learn and
trying to convince yourself that
it's possible to switch careers.
And, um, it seems ridiculous.
So, uh, Yeah. I like those. I
like
doing kind of portfolio reviews,
mock interviews. Um, since I've
been on the hiring type a little
bit as well, like those are
really useful. Um, and you get
to know people and, um, kinda
make
connections that stick with you.
Bekah: Yeah, That's awesome. And
I think that, like you were
saying about learning Firebase
rather than, than continuing
hacking in a way that doesn't
make sense. That's so hard to
figure out if you're learning on
your own, because it just really
depends on what resources.
You've read and how you've
understood
things. You know sometimes there
are resources, there are blog
posts out there that are not
giving you the best information.
And so recognizing that like,
Hey, there's a lot written out
there. Not everything is going
to you the right ways or the
best
practices and figuring out how
to discern between what is a
good
resource and not can be really,
really tricky. On your own. So
that's why meetups like that
are, are awesome.
Dan: Yeah, I would just, I would
also say. This is true, even if
you're not learning, you know,
uh it's you can be very
expensive,
like be developing for a long
time. Uh, but being kind of
isolated and it's possible. And
I say, this has, you know,
person
who I'm describing myself a
couple of years ago, basically.
Uh, but it's, it's like it that
exposure to other people. And
it's just, like mark said, like,
oh, just use Firebase. Like
somebody just saying that, and
it doesn't have to. Somebody
who's,
you know, a mentor or somebody
who is teaching or whatever, it
can be somebody who's also just
learning, you know what I mean?
But that, those, uh, that, that
exposure to other people who
are,
who are doing the same sorts of
things as you are, it's, it's so
important. And so, and, and
useful, uh, just even on a, on a
like tactical level, you know
what I mean? It just, it just
like makes you better. Um,
osmosis, you know, even if
you're
not like, uh, actively doing
talks or doing, you know, act
that, you know, whatever,
whatever, just like that
exposure
to people. Um,
Mark: Yeah. and you could go to
that group and just kinda hang
out, um, kind of like the
coworking room and Virtual
Coffee, where, uh, sometimes I
went to that meetup and I really
didn't say anything to anybody
because I was, um, some jobs. I
would usually get there after
work and have like some goal. I
was like, I need to do this. And
for some reason, being around
all
these people, even if they're
really busily talking. It gives
me enough energy to actually
spend two or three hours coding
do the thing I came to do. Um,
versus if I went home, I would
just be like, I'm tired after
work not have that energy from
those people.
Dan: Yeah, it totally. And the
other, the other part is, I
mean,
the other benefit of a small
group like that, especially in
person wants, which I know is
like very, very hard right now,
but, um, uh, you know, it's the
kind of thing we're trying to
recapture at least in Virtual
Coffee. Um, but. You know, you,
you can get exposure in on
Twitter, like by following a
whole bunch of people. Right.
But you never know exactly
what's
going to happen. And if you
don't know the people, then your
last
time following people that other
people, you know, based on
numbers and based on what
Twitter's algorithm kind of
pushes in front of you and you,
again, you, can't always, you
can't always know, uh, exactly
like who people are or whether
you can trust their information
and stuff like that. And, um,
when you're in a group of just
people. Uh, as a small group,
it's much more there's no, like
he can't tell how many people
follow, like follow that person.
You know, everyone's just
sitting
in a room together. There's
nobody has like a, you know,
inherent value with air quotes
is value, you know, uh, bigger
than
another person, you know, and
one person has 20 followers on
Twitter. Another has, you know,
10,000, but when they're in just
the room together, talking to
them, Sort of everybody's more
on
a similar level, um, think
improves communication. Yeah.
Mark: And I remember seeing
Krista who is fantastic and was
kind of years ahead of me in her
development and like being
along,
learning. And seeing her,
knowing that she knows more than
me and
is really good at what she does.
And when somebody would bring up
a topic that hadn't run into
yet, she would just ask the
question
and she'd be like, oh, I don't
know what that is. Tell me about
it and not feel the need to
like, um, I don't know, pretend
that,
you know, everything or like
show off people aren't going
there to
show off. People are going there
to like, Um, and so seeing
somebody that I know is better
than me still comfortable, I'm
like, oh, maybe this is why
better than me. Like, this is
how
you get good, is you keep asking
questions and you don't try to
bluff. and, and like use, use
your curiosity to drive you. Um,
so I do some of those moments
kind of stood out to me that I
think you can only witness when
you're in a group and see a
dynamic, um, and see different
people handling situations in
different ways. So Yeah. whether
it's a virtual group or not,
but,
um, it's nice that we have these
to other people.
Bekah: Yeah, I think when you
have that exposure, it allows
you
to build some sort of
relationship of trust and
understanding, and there's more
of a comfort level. So there's a
built-in credibility almost. And
so can feel free to free or to
ask questions in some situations
to not like even people that I
know from Virtual Coffee, I'm
not a big, um, YouTube tutorial
watcher, but if I know somebody
from Virtual Coffee or if I've
met them in real life, it's
easier for me to watch their
videos. I think because it's
like, okay, yeah, this is, is my
friend. And I know they know
what they're talking about or I
know
that this person talks about
this, so I'm going to go watch
their video. And so it, it
allows for that. I don't know,
like, um,
a step towards trusting that
they will be a good resource for
you.
Um, so now that experience with
Code for Atlanta was not your
last experience with them,
right?
Mark: No, no. So this is good.
This and this ties into another
thing. That I try to communicate
to new developers, um, which is
how to put things on your resume
that are like closer to
professional work. Then even
solo projects you do on your
own. And
for me, Code for Atlanta had a
headache connection for me
because they were running a
hackathon series with Marta is
Atlanta's transit agency and
working at people, making
progress, which I'm still
connected with. Uh, I was
working
as a job coach and running
supported employment programs
where people would use the, um,
Marta Mobility Service to get
from home to work. So an example
is somebody with down syndrome
who works bagging groceries, or
somebody who's working in a dish
room or something that we use to
support with schedule these
rides. The bus takes you door to
door. Um, but scheduling and
everything around scheduling was
done over the phone, which is
pretty difficult for people with
cognitive impairments or speech
impediments, like challenges
around judgment when you're
sitting in a phone queue. So I
had a lot of experience of the
pain of working with Marta and
Atlanta Code for Atlanta was
running these events. And I saw
it as my chance to like talk to
MARTA. Not on the phone, but be
in their face and say, Hey,
here's a, here's a lot of stuff
that's happening on the phone
that probably could be happening
through the website or something
like that. And the hack my
proposal for the hackathon was
here's a better way to handle
like booking and canceling rides
and keeping people informed of
when the van is coming. 'Cause
they have a 30 minute window and
sometimes it's Atlanta, there's
always traffic. Sometimes the
bus can be an hour late, be an
hour
and a half late, but if you're
waiting for it, and they come,
you only have five minutes to
get to the bus before they move
on.
So people would just stand
outside for as long as it takes
the hot and the cold and the
rain, whether they have to pee
bad situation for people to just
be waiting without knowing how
long the bus comes. And I could
get more into the weeds of that
problem, but that's the general
idea and the solution, because I
knew when I would call on behalf
of somebody and I would pick up
the phone and say, Hey, when is
Kevin's bus going to get here? I
could feel that that person was
just clicking on a computer and
reading a line off of the sheet
and telling me what the time
said
at like that field of the
estimated time of arrival, which
I could just publish that time
on the website, we could read
that
ourselves and we wouldn't have
to tie up the phones all the
time
asking about the late buses. So,
um, I went to the hackathon
there
and, uh, met some people. I
think I really wanted to go to
the
hackathon because in CS 50, they
explained what a hackathon is.
And I was like, I want to have
that 24 hour experience of like,
seeing what it's like to do it.
Um, Nerando came along for that
hackathon and we met two other
people just chatting beforehand,
who became the team. I learned
about, uh, how to turn like that
idea into a kind of app
solution. So we had somebody who
knew about
iOS. He worked on actually
building out an iOS app based on
some wire frames that we made
and some wishlists I had of what
we
would be able to do. Um, and
that a three-part event. we
actually
had two more cracks at this. We
convinced MARTA to provide some
data to us about the disability
support service they had, this
was not a part of the hackathon
dataset. This was like,
something, we were bringing in
that we wanted to work on. Um,
we
worked with them for awhile. We
made a pilot for them that they
actually used for a few weeks.
And as it turned out, they were
separately in negotiations to
buy something that did some
similar
stuff. So on the one hand it was
a bummer. We didn't get to like
really ship our code. We were
able to get into meetings with
the third party provider who
they were using to provide this
service and give them early
feedback on what their product
did or didn't do that would be
useful for the population we
wanted it to help. So, um, it
got us like in the room for
those
types of conversations and it,
let me put MARTA on my resume as
like I did a project with MARTA.
not saying it was a paid
project.
Not saying I was a consultant or
anything, but here's a project
with an organization that you've
heard of in your city, um, that
is different to my calculator
that's on code pen. is homework
from Free Code Camp and like
using civic tech to connect with
nonprofits or other
organizations that you can do
work for so that
you have something people have
heard of on your resume that
you've contributed to. Maybe you
had requirements, you worked
with
a team, all this like benefits
of adding to your resume beyond
a
project you came up with on your
own, really strengthened that.
And let me talk about something
different in interviews. So I
really believe like my purpose
is Code for Atlanta now is not
so
much to support any specific
project, but to like support
people, building their resumes,
who are new to the industry and
have worked for them to do, uh,
that's kind of what motivates me
to stay involved and spend some
time like helping to organize
things I'm able to do that.
Bekah: I love that. And I think,
you know, we hear a lot of
advice
to early career folks to, you
know, get into open source and
that's a good way to build your
resume, I liked this idea of
civic tech. Because it seems
like be a more intimate group of
people communicating together.
Whereas you almost feel a lot of
open source contributions. Like
you're an outsider coming in and
if you need help, it's harder.
Ask because there's not clear
paths of communication or, or
whatever, but you're working on
something that's mission driven
and that has a team of people
that need to communicate, those
are certainly all skills that
can
be utilizing and kind of
building your own team. Right.
So if
you're involved in a community
like code camp or code for
Atlanta Virtual Coffee or
whatever, You can turn to people
and say like, look, there's a
nonprofit in my hometown. And
they could really use some help.
I'd love to. Ask them, if I
could
work on a project for them, but
I could use some support, is
anybody else interested? And I
think that's a really great way
to show, like, look, you are
taking initiative, you are
working on a project and that is
not a calculator or, you know, a
to-do list app and really,
really kind of own the project
yourself
is, is a great way to showcase
you can do to learn a lot pretty
quickly. Um, and yeah, to have
something on your resume.
Mark: Yeah, and Nerando will be
annoyed if I don't mention this.
Cause I do sometimes forget to
mention this, that project
extended into a different, uh,
event. That was a civic tech
challenge. That was run by GE
and AT&T. And so our team kind
of re
rebuilt the project, added some
smart city integration because
it
was a smart city thing. Um, and
we won a $40,000 prize, Uh,
which
we didn't expect to win. So we
had all signed in advance that
we
agreed to donate this to charity
because we thought maybe we
would
come in third or whatever. So
like, um, it's. uh, I think it's
a better story that we gave away
when we were all broke. This is
the thing, like we were not, we
didn't have jobs yet as
developers. Um, but we agreed
that so many people had
contributed to this, that it
would be kind of unfair for just
the, the six people on the team
at the time of that competition
to walk away with the money, um,
because it was a long project.
30 people who did something on
it. Um, so we all felt good
about
that. And we thought maybe we
would come in third, which was
like five grand, not too much.
Um, but you get involved in
stuff
like this, it does have
potential. This won't happen to
everybody. It has potential to
snowball into a weird side
effect
of like donating more to
charity. Then you make it a
year. So, uh,
uh, that was good. That was a
good thing that we did and I
still stand by it. But, um,
Yeah. I, I also was wierd if I
forget
to finish the story with that
detail.
Dan: Yeah, no, he was, he, uh,
he might've mentioned that when
he
was on the podcast as well. I
think he pretty much felt the
same way as you like. Well, I'm
glad we did it... but also...
Mark: Well, the thing, the thing
I like about it is when that's
the outcome of a project, it
doesn't matter that like MARTA
didn't use our prototype. We got
money to charities that serve
people with disabilities, which
enables them to increase their
mission and have impact. And
like I, because I worked at one
of
those charities, I know what
that money is spent on. So
through the
channel of civic tech, if you
are able to enter and win prizes
and
donate prizes, have this other
way of making impact. That's
actually probably a little bit
more effective than on any
single
project to really take off and
be implemented. It's like a lot
of
the work in civic tech. If it's
not tightly integrated with an
actual organization or a
nonprofit is more like proof of
concepts. Here's how you could
do your government. Here's how
you
could do your MARTA mobility
service. And it shows the way to
something, but it might not be,
um, it might not be the
technical
solution that actually gets
implemented, but if it gets the
conversation going or you raise
some money with it, like that's
a
valuable output, or if it helps
someone get a job, that's a
valuable output for um, the
activity of civic tech that can
sometimes seem like it goes
nowhere.
Dan: Yeah, I love that, you
know, and it's is, uh, Like
Bekah was
saying. Yeah. Some people, you
know, it's a little easier to
conceive of going into, trying
to contribute to open source,
um,
stuff like that, but that it's
civic tech is it's a little
more,
um, so what I was gonna say was
it is a little more, um,
nebulous
in my mind, if you, excuse me,
if you were, if a developer was
like
one or two, start getting
involved in this in maybe they
don't live in Atlanta, uh, like
where, where would I look like
if
I want to. Maybe, you know, try
to get involved in civic tech a
little bit more in Cleveland.
Um, for instance, like, should I
just
Google civic tech, Cleveland and
see what comes up or is there
other like specific places, you
know, that you might look first?
Like what, what can we do to,
you know, if somebody wants to
do
this.
Mark: Within the US, there's
definitely Code for America is
like the umbrella organization.
And Code for America itself is a
nonprofit that, um, specific
projects and has employees and
often works with local
governments and organizations
like that, but it also supports
the brigade network, which is,
um, all around the U S there's
there's many Brigades, I forget
how many, but most states have
at least one. Um, you can find
your
local project from there. And
there are, there are also civic
tech communities around the
world. Um, so I guess I'll have
to look up the address for that
and we can it somewhere. Um,
yeah, but I know there are
communities in Ireland, there
are
communities, um, kind of all
around that are United by the
sort of social good impact tech
work. Um, people consider the
actual details of what's
important to focus on
differently
in those communities, depending
on kind of what their mission
is.
Um, obviously my point of view
is like helping people get
exposure.
Um, very much I'm focused on the
non-profit side of things, not
as
much on the interfacing with
government entities. but so
there
are different roles. You can see
a typical civic tech
organization
having, um, but it's, uh, it's
really nice when. Most of the
time, there is plenty of people
to do the work. And there's also
plenty of projects happening at
once. So you can come in and
find
something where you can either
learn or you can participate.
Um,
and the kind of people who do
these things tend to be of the
helpful variety. Like whoever's
giving up a Tuesday night to go
and work for free for a
nonprofit they never heard of.
They're
probably nice enough to help you
set up git do things like.
Dan: Yeah.
Mark: This is where I learned
how to use git properly. It's
where I
learned how to install packages.
Like just real basic stuff. Came
from Code for Atlanta people
helping me there.
Bekah: I just want to follow
that up and say that when you're
working on you don't have to
work on a time intensive
project.
Right. So I know, you know,
there are people that are
learning who
have jobs and kids or other
responsibilities, and they might
say like, wow, that's just not
doable. But I think that, you
know, there are so many
different options out there and,
know, one,
if you're working on a three-day
project. are going to learn so
much in those three days it
might be more than weeks worth
of work
that you were learning by
yourself. And so, ya know, kind
of thinking about the benefits
or, you know, look at a longer
project, start something
yourself with other people and
say like,
we're going to do this over a
period of six weeks and then
evaluate where we are and it's
going to be five hours a week or
whatever, you know, it doesn't
it work for you, but those
experiences are invaluable as
you're making your way into the
tech industry.
Mark: Totally. And I agree it
can be slow. Our, um, our MARTA
thing
went on for about a year, maybe
more. Um, a lot of it is really
incremental. Some of the
projects I worked on only did
anything
twice a month at the civic hack
night. So I would work really
hard to prepare for a civic hack
night because I would have
people
who wanted to come and work on
something like Free Live
Transcript.com that you guys
have seen. Um, so a lot of the
work
that's on that now came from a
civic hack night where I have
like two hours of people I'm
going to try to explain how the
whole project works in the first
few minutes and then figure out
what everybody's good at and
what they want to do. And come
up with
tasks and get them assigned out
and like check on them. And
sometimes that works beautifully
and sometimes it's hard to get
people going because the, the
code is pretty ugly in there.
And, uh, you need a certain
level of experience to, uh, undo
what I
did when I wrote that project.
But like, uh, sometimes it is
effective and you can get eight
hours of work done by four
people
in a two hour period, which
really moves the project
forward.
Um, and now four people know how
to work on it. And one of them
might have like a bee in their
bonnet and want to come back and
fix it the next time. Or
sometimes they just drift off.
It
doesn't matter. They
contributed, they got something
out of it. Um,
I kind of liken it to being an a
band in college where sometimes
most people would show up to
practice. And like you're
relying
on volunteers. Your expectations
should be that things are going
to be slow and every now and
then a hackathon will come and
they'll
be really fast for a few days,
but mostly you will try to set
up
your tickets and try to set up
your list of tasks to be like,
anybody can pick this up. And
nothing's too big or too small
for someone to take a crack at
it at a hack night. And even the
smallest ticket is really
meaningful. If it's someone's
first pull request, um, that
they've made to an open source
project or something like that.
So fixing a spelling mistake or
whatever, um, can be like, Hey,
so my first time forking a repo
and contributing to open source,
just like we're doing what heck
over Fest at this moment in
time. Uh, those do that does
kind of
the mystery of how to do that.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I think
that any step forward the
momentum. Right? And so if you a
typo or something small, then
it's still moving you forward
and getting you ready for the
next
time you create a pull request
and feeling a little bit more
confident as you do that. So I
don't think that we should
diminish any contributions. It's
good to get started and to get
in
there.
Dan: Yeah, and I mean, this is
something we talk about a lot
with Virtual Coffee. It is hard
to get into opensource. You
know,
it's, there's a lot of, uh, uh,
and this is true. I'm sure of
civic tech just opens doors in
general. Right? There's, there's
a bunch of things to learn, you
know? And so honestly, if you're
doing something that is maybe a
small contribution to the code
itself, like fixing the, a typo,
um, then it frees you up to
actually just concert and
learning about, get or learning
about pull requests, learning
about, uh, that process, uh,
without trying to learn a
mountain of coding stuff at the
same time. Right. And, you know,
it's a great way to, I like,
it's
a, I think that's the best way
to get started in, um, you know,
and
get in contribute and, you know,
open source, things like that
is,
is do, uh, you know, small,
small contributions where you're
not
overshooting, you know, you're
not biting off a big chunk of
something um, code-wise to start
because then you can just
concentrate on the one thing,
learning one thing at a time.
Mark: I'm really struck by how,
working in the industry for,
four
or five years now or whatever it
is. Um, you're only using a tiny
slice of your programming
knowledge at a time. Um, to all
that you have learned already,
you're still on using a tiny
amount of that. And relative to
all the stuff you could learn,
that's so scary when you're
getting started, you're like
using a little dot of knowledge.
like, I work in a Vue code base
and I use Tailwind for CSS and I
do certain things that like, um,
are their own little bubble and
have their own documentation. it
doesn't matter that I even know
PHP from before. Um, I'm not
using it. I guess I learned
something from learning that,
but
like, When you actually see
projects and action and talk to
the people they're like, Hey,
you can contribute. And here's
the
tiny area that you need to know
about. Like, you need to know
how
to, how to, how to extract this
thing from a loop and JavaScript
and make it more efficient. And
here's the tiny piece of
documentation that will help you
do that. And then ask me if you
need help, like that reveals
that we're still focused on just
like
really small areas of the
overall practice of programming,
um, at
any given moment on any given
ticket, we're not using the a
hundred things that we could
know about.
Dan: Yeah. I, I mean, absolutely
agree with that. And I think
that's actually another benefit
of getting involved in a
project,
like a civic hacking project
where somebody else, you know,
if
somebody, if you have somebody
like Mark who was sort of
running
the project, right. And you
join, um, as, uh, somebody who
is
learning, um, you know, you can
be provided. One of the
challenges of learning when
you're learning is that cloud of
there's a huge amount of things
that you could learn, right? So
if you go to something like
this, I want to contribute like
you
now, now you have, um, the thing
to do set in front of you, and
maybe you can just concentrate
on learning just that one thing,
you
know, and it removes the choice,
uh, which, and then maybe you'll
find it they'll figure out,
well, I hate this. I don't like
JavaScript or something, or I
don't like something and you can
move on, you know, it, um, but
the. That's just another,
another
benefit of get involved with
groups like this, especially a
civic hacking group that is
going to have projects like it's
going
to have work to do, you know,
and, and, and help, um, doing
it.
Uh, that's my, like my, my go-to
advice for learning is just
like,
make, do a project, just do
something, you know, and
Obviously better, but it can't
be bad advice. Cause like, well,
what do I do then, Dan? And then
I'm like, well, I don't know
that
this is like something that
provides that,
Mark: And I'll say as well, it,
it provided me with leadership
experience. I did not go in
wanting to run the project. I
was
like, so if I have an idea, Do I
also have to run it and they're
like, Yeah, you have to do, if
its your idea, you pitch it and
you own it. will get join your
team. Um, I was like, okay,
I'll,
I'll learn how to pitch a
project. And I would be very
nervous at first. And, um, I got
feedback one night from somebody
who was like part of the local
Toastmasters or something,
happened to be there.
Bekah: it's a recurring theme
here, toastmasters.
Dan: Yeah, it was, was it Gant?
Mark: I don't know, but it was
just like, uh, he, offered take
notes on me pitching and give me
like he had three or four
points.
He's like, you move way too
much. Your, your idea is good
and your
communications clear, but you
speak too softly and you're
swaying and it's distracting,
but here's the good things, you
know,
and that was a, you don't have
to remember much advice to be
like,
okay, I'm going to move less.
Um, and try to slow down a
little.
Uh, uh, just from being at a
hack night happening to run into
people who are experienced,
looking at how you're doing when
you speak. Um, so a lot of
benefits for me, random
unpredictable benefits from
being involved in Code for
Atlanta.
Bekah: When I want to follow up
on that too, and say that that's
a skillset, right. That you're
learning. Not everybody can
pitch. It's not a natural thing.
I, well, maybe for some people
it's a natural thing that you're
born with, but a lot of us, it's
a skill that we need to work on
and get evaluation. And mean, it
goes right along with
interviewing, right? Because you
are essentially pitching
yourself and if you're using the
wrong
tone, I will never forget. I
think I was 11 years old. It was
my first science fair project.
And the highest you could get
was
a superior. I got an excellent
and I was like very upset with
my
excellent and the feedback I got
was, um, inappropriate
inflection
at the end of sentences. Right.
So what that means is when I
talked, I would talk and, and
like, it was a question than
actually saying what. Actually
knew about the project, And so
there, you lose credibility. And
I worked very hard to not do
that
anymore, but that feedback has
allowed me to grow as a speaker
and be more deliberate and think
through how I'm doing things
and.
So maybe your tone is wrong when
you're interviewing and you're
not coming off as credible, or
maybe you're not completing your
sentences. There there've been
times in my life where would
just
start a sentence and then would
get overwhelmed with people
looking at me and I would just
stop. There was no end to that
sentence. And usually I ended it
with, so, and that was to me.
didn't know where go from there.
It's something that I have to
think about still even, you
know, if I'm in a situation
where I
suddenly get uncomfortable, like
don't end your sentence with, so
it's a complete
Mark: implies that you're going
to keep speaking. So it actually
makes it take even longer for
people to realize that you've
stopped.
Bekah: Just like once someone to
pick it up for me. So who
Dan: I've never done anything
like that, except for every
single podcast episode.
Mark: Oh yeah. But But's another
one. Sometimes I'll be like, so
yeah, that's it. But, uh,
Bekah: Yes. Yes. 100% do that.
Dan: Well, you probably looked
through the transcripts and
just,
just see all the times I've done
that. even on the podcast.
Mark: I'm very self-conscious
about how much I may have done
that in the last hour.
Dan: Oh,
Mark: We'll find out.
Dan: Yeah, we have a, um, we're
using, uh, what's it called, uh,
Descript now for, uh, podcast
editing, which is a really cool
tool. But one of the things it
does is highlights, filler
words.
And like, I don't like there, we
could just remove them all or
something, you know? I mean, I,
I know that there, I'm sure
there's
some podcasts that will do that
or whatever. Um, I don't do that
both because it is
time-consuming, but also I, you
know, is pretty, it's a pretty
chill, you know, podcasts in
general, but it does highlight
all of them. And I can see them
in my, you know, in the
transcripts for my, uh,
paragraphs of talking it's.
Mark: Published a stats Dan.
Don't keep this from the people.
Dan: I don't think I'm going to
do that. It'd be too
embarrassing, but I'll do it
for, maybe I'll do it for just
this
episode.
Bekah: But we have transcripts
available for every episode. So
if somebody would like to just
go do a control, find, you will
know
how many ums we have had in
every episode, you can publish
it for
us. Well, I think we're about at
time Mark. This was really great
to hear about civic tech. I
actually am really excited to go
find some civic tech projects
and think about how I can
involved in
this more, is there any last
piece of advice you have for
listeners?
Mark: Em, I think that it's.
It's natural to not be sure if
we're
talking to listeners
specifically who are learning
development,
which is not everybody like in
the Virtual Coffee Community.
Um,
but like I remember so much
hesitation and, and not being
sure that this was the right
thing or it was gonna work out,
um, that does not mean that it's
not the right thing or it's not
going to work out. So I would
suggest people find some way to
live with that feeling. It may
well be there for many years
into
your career for a lot of us.
and, uh, it's just not a very
useful
feeling. So, uh, I would
encourage people to let it be
and, uh, keep working regardless
and don't pay any mind to the
part of you that's saying that,
uh, cause it's not going to help
you learn and, uh, Obviously
from the amount of people who
have
come through the same journey,
these people that are going on,
uh, it doesn't, uh, hold you
back.
Bekah: Yeah, that's so great.
thanks so much for being here
with us today. And we will talk
to you soon.
Mark: I'm waving. goodbye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our
Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please
subscribe to our podcast and be
sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!