Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode five of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you here with me today, is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we sat
down with Suze Shardlow. Suze is
an award winning community
manager, coder, tech writer and
tech event MC and she currently
leads the developer community at
Redis. We had a really
interesting conversation with
Suze. She's done a million
different things throughout her
life and her career and she
shared with us how her
experiences have informed her
time as a software developer and
a community leader.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We
hope
you enjoy this episode. Today's
random question is if you could
pick a fictional world to live
in, what would it be? So I am
Bekah, I'm a front end developer
from a small town in Ohio, and
there are so many cool fictional
worlds that it's hard, like do
do
you want to totally go fantasy
and a different world? Want in
space? I definitely don't want
to live underwater. Um, so where
do
I want to live? Now I can't now
I can't even think of a
fictional
world that I want to live in.
Dan: Do you get to choose who to
be in the place that you live?
You know,
Bekah: I you're going to be
yourself. I think that's the
rules.
Dan: But I mean, like you said
Harry Potter, like, you know,
Hogwarts or something, but just
Bekah: You're just Dan at
Hogwarts.
Dan: Just a muggle. A muggle
Dan, you know, like that would
be
worse.
Bekah: Yeah. I, um, I'm just
going to go. I, you know, I
really liked the world of X-Men.
So, I I'm going to go live with
the X-Men in that world. Um,
because I have always enjoyed.
Dan: A friend, a friend to the
mutants
Bekah: I will be, I will be an
ally to the mutants I draw.
Dan: Where you could be a, a
mutant advocate or would that
be.
Like a like dev you got like a
big Twitter account and stuff.
Suze: Mutant community engineer.
Bekah: Yeah.
Suze: nice.
Dan: Um, hi, I'm, I'm Dan. I,
uh, do web stuff. I live in
Cleveland. Um, my fictional
world. I was like, I wanna go
somewhere where it's a little
less. Maybe where there's no
computers, honestly. Uh, you
know, all the ones that I keep
thinking of, there's like a lot
of strife and that didn't,
wouldn't be fun. You know, I
want to go somewhere relaxing.
Maybe
just like the, it called
Hobbiton? Is
Bekah: Yeah, that's a really
good one
Dan: Without all the bad stuff
that's happening, um, to feel
like they had some good times
there too, you know, so just
like
some chill, more chill and,
Bekah: or Rivendale, that would
be sweet too.
Dan: Wait what's.
Bekah: Where the Elves live.
Dan: Oh, yeah, that seems cool.
But they seem like pretty
serious, you know, the hobbits
like have like taverns and, you
know, you know what I mean?
Like, I don't think they drink
any, any
beer. elves don't drink, you
Bekah: I was don't. drink beer.
Oh, we need a fact check on
that.
Okay.
Dan: obviously Kirk is probably
Bekah: Kirk
Dan: out loud at us. I'm sure a
bunch of different things.
Suze: It wasn't me Kirk, it
wasn't me.
Dan: Uh, I'm going with, I'm
sticking with Hobbiton though.
I,
I liked the houses in the hill
too, you know, like there, the
whole vibe.
Suze: Cozy.
Dan: Yeah.
Suze: Nice. Well, my name's Suze
Shardlow. wear so many hats, I
don't even know where to start.
I'm a software engineer, coding
instructor, published tech
author, and a developer
community
manager based in London,
England, in case you couldn't
tell from
the funny accent, and if that
wasn't enough of a fantasy world
to be living. Uh, this question
is really hard. I don't know. I,
I'm not really into fantasy
books, but worlds that you
escape
to when you go to the movies and
say, the first thing that came
into my head was The Truman
Show. Because one of my favorite
things
is to look at the sky,
especially like on a day this,
we do
actually have blue sky today is
quite cold. There's a few clouds
and I look, and I the end. Yeah.
Uh, he went to the edge didn't
he
went to the sky and there was a
of steps on the door. I often
kind of think, you know, We're
quite insignificant in the grand
scheme of things and we are all
just kind of on the stage.
aren't
we? Um, so yeah, I feel like
going on the Truman Show would
be, uh, would be a good place to
live.
Bekah: That's fascinating. I
love The Truman Show it's right
up
there...
Suze: I need watch that again.
Yeah.
Bekah: Ever like big fish. I
don't know if you've, what's a
movie and a play and a book. Um,
but it's, it's a journey. So
they're going to different
places that would be cool too.
Dan: Do you say Reel big Fish?
Bekah: big fish.
Dan: They're a ska band
Bekah: No, there's there's no
real in and fact check for you
Legolas' people in particular
traded wines from the south
quite
often, so
Dan: Did drink them though? Or
did, just like, you know,
profiting
Bekah: I believe that they are.
Um, let's see. Are there
Dan: Yeah. If you said like,
they like sip fancy wines, you
know,
like, you know, believe that.
Bekah: Which one of the
characters in Lord of the rings
can't get drunk? That's one of
the characters, right? Is that.
is that one of the elves? All
right, sorry. I'm going, going
down the.
Dan: Isn't that Wolverine
somebody, the healing, somebody
with a healing thing can't get
drunk.
Suze: We already in the rabbit
hole. Well, that must be a
record.
Dan: Honestly, Kirk was poking
at us a couple of episodes ago.
And
so now it just like.
Bekah: yeah.
Dan: We'll just have a little
Kirk segment where we really
make
him mad and then, uh,
Suze: Poor old Kirk
...provoking. It's not nice.
Bekah: Um, well, thanks so much
for being here with us today.
Um,
there's so many different ways
that we can approach this
conversation, because like you
said, in the intro, you do all
of
the things, but let's just start
with how you got to this point
in
your career.
Suze: Okay, I'll give you the
short version. Cause, uh, it's
like two decades long, so, well,
two decades along since I left
university. And then another two
decades before that. So yeah,
then my whole coding journey
started when I was a small child
in the 1980s. And I don't really
remember where this computer
appeared from, but my dad
must've liked gone out and
bought it and
brought it home one day. So we
had a BBC micro, which is a. Uh,
computer that was actually
developed and made in the UK.
And
it was sponsored by the BBC,
which I think a lot of folks
around the world have heard of.
Um, and it was accompanied by a
TV show that they showed on the
BBC. And in those days we didn't
have the internet. So you kind
of had to watch the TV and write
down the code and type it into
your computer. And or use a book
or use magazines and things like
that. But the, um, so I was
probably about five when I got
that computer. And then I
programmed that like, well into
my teens and stuff into the
1990s. Um, and then there came a
point at school where you have
to
decide what you want to do, but
the UK education system. And I
don't think the UK is unique in
this. Um, doesn't know what to
do
with girls that like computers.
And it still doesn't know what
to
do with girls that like
computers. So when we had
careers
days and things like that at
school, I was never actually
shown anybody that was doing
programming for living man or
woman or, or gender. So, um,
yeah, we were just shown like
lawyers and doctors and vets and
things like that. And nobody
ever
sort of said, you can do this as
a living. So, um, and also at
school they didn't offer
computing subjects. Um, they
didn't offer any computing
classes, but we did have a
computing club, which I was very
heavily involved with, but, but
for some reason they didn't
offer any actual classes. Um, so
then,
so therefore my path to taking a
degree in it, wasn't really that
clear and it didn't occur to me
that maybe you can go do the
degree without taking it at
school and stuff. Cause again,
had no role role models. None of
the teachers were interested in
it. So I went to university and
took the most versatile degree
that I could think of, which was
business. 'cause I thought,
yeah,
that probably lends itself to a
few things. Still don't really
know what I wanna do, but, um,
one of my ambitions when I was
younger was I really wanted to
be a radio presenter. So I
thought,
okay, if I take do marketing or
something like that, it's quite
close to media. So that's what
they've specialized in marketing
and then came out of university
and just kind of got my first
marketing job and then just
stayed in marketing for quite a
long time, but it was always
still interested in technology
and try to get sort of
technology, adjacent marketing
roles. So one of the roles that
I did was marketing manager for
an
IT company. And then when I got
made redundant from that. When I
joined, um, the police here in
London as a communications
manager, so supporting
technology rollouts with
communications
campaigns, um, we've had about
50,000 users at the time, police
officers and police staff. And
if you think about, you know,
this
at the time, there were about
30,000 police officers in London
and every single one of those
officers was using a radio when
they went out. So we, then we
upgraded all the radios I put
together campaigns to support
those type of tech rollouts. But
then I was at the police for
quite a long time and still kind
of thought this isn't really
what I want to be doing forever,
but
what do I really want to do? So
I did quite a lot of reading to
figure out what I wanted to do.
And one of the pieces of advice
that I kept coming across was
think about what you enjoy doing
when you were younger. And I
thought, oh yeah, actually I
enjoy coding when I was younger.
So I, uh, I decided to go back
and do that. But I think, cause
well, I forgot to mention was
when I was doing the marketing
roles, I was still like making
websites and things like that.
So I was still really interested
in
still trying to do things, but
just didn't see a path to
actually get to do this
professionally. Meanwhile,
sitting there with dev teams
that were full of men. Um, but
yeah,
it just didn't seem to be a
clear route for me. So I did a
bit of
research after about... maybe 10
years in the police. Now
probably
about 10 years. I was there for
12 years all together. And a
couple of years before I left it
sort of research that to do it.
And around that time was when,
um, bootcamps were springing up
everywhere. And I thought, yeah,
actually this looks like a nice
defined route. And also I'm the
type of learner who likes to
turn
up to a class and sit down and
learn and then go home. I'm not
really that good at the whole
distance learning thing, self
learning. So I decided to enroll
on a big cap, which happily
coincided with the fact that the
police were looking to lay
people
off in my team or lay some of
the roles off. And they were
very
kind about actually, they said,
you know, if you want to go
then,
um, then that's fine. You can
go. And because the police has
quite
a nice defined plan for if
they're laying people off,
because I've been there for 12
years, then I got quite a nice
severance, which I was very
lucky to have, which then gave
me a bit
of a cushion to decide what I
wanted to do next. So after I
did
the big cabin and left the
police, I kind of thought
actually, I don't really want to
be a coder full time. I just
want
to take my time and see what's
out there. So while I've been
researching and around the time
that I kind of got into the, um,
bootcamp, I was getting more
involved in local meetups. And
at
the time there weren't that
many, so that was probably
around 2014,
2015 ish. Um, so yeah, there
weren't that many boot camps
around that time. Sorry, there
weren't too many meetups around
that time. So I joined the ones
that I could find. I just kind
of
met people there because I had a
marketing background eventually
started to help to organize one,
which kind of took me back to my
roots of organizing the computer
club at school. And also when I
was at the police, um,
organizing the association for
senior women
in a police as well. So kind of
always had that community
interest. And, um, so yeah. Then
when I left the police and I had
that little sort of cushion and
a little bit of time to think
about
what I wanted to do. Just sort
of continued with the whole
community building piece, um,
blogging. Um, just, just bits
and
pieces of different freelance
stuff that seemed to come my way
up. I think I've been quite
lucky in that respect, um, that
people
have seen what I can do. And
they've approached me most of
the
time to say you will you do this
for us? And then, um, so I
currently work at Redis their
developer community manager. And
they actually had hunted me they
could see what I was doing. And
they said, um, you know, we've
got this open role come and
apply
for it. We really want you to
apply. So I applied for that.
And
of course, like, you know, there
were other folks there in the
mix
as well, who had also applied,
yeah, it made it all the way
through the recruitment process
and got offered job at the end.
So there for about two months
now. Um, so yeah, it's been
quite
nice because it's a good combo
of what I started off doing in
my
career, which was the marketing
communications. And also,
combines in all the experience
that I got with organizing the
communities and stuff, but also
with like the software thing as
well. So it feels like it's a
really good combo of all the
things that I because any job
that you get, you're not going
to
enjoy all of it. So it feels
like I've taken all the bits of
all
the jobs that I've had, that I
enjoyed and fit them together to
create this job. yeah, that's
how I got to where I am
currently.
Bekah: Oh, so awesome. I love
that this feels like such a good
fit for you. It's I mean, it
definitely sounds like it. And
as
I was going through and kind of
preparing for today's podcast. I
was trying to think of this word
and it's somebody that does a
lot
of things and is talented at all
of those things. Right. And so I
didn't find the right word, but
I did find there's this word
polymath, means having learned
much. A person whose expertise
spans a significant number of
different subject areas. I was
like, okay. Yeah, that that's
exactly who you are. And I think
even if you go on to your blog
and check it out, there are so
many things, you know, you're
cooking, you're sewing, you're
writing about code. You're
talking, writing about giving
talks. So I especially feel like
that's refreshing because so
many
people are the personal branding
is a big thing right now. Right?
And so much a personal branding
is an over-simplification of who
you are, and it allows you to
have one focus about the things
that you want to talk about. and
it doesn't allow us to kind of
present our full selves in the
conversation. And so just really
love that you present all of the
things that you're interested in
talking about and, and pursuing,
and, you know, I I'd love to
know, you know, your take on
personal branding or like what
kind of makes you feel like,
yeah, I'm just going to talk
about all the things I like.
Suze: Yeah, that's an
interesting question. And you,
you do hear a
lot about personal branding,
especially if you are in tech
and
especially if you're on tech,
Twitter, um, It's really hard. I
think being in the tech industry
is hard anyway, without this
added thing of like, you've got
to make a personal brand. And I
remember when I was coming out
of bootcamp, the, um, the
careers
coach did say you need to have
consistent branding, but what
she
meant there was visual. So, you
know, make a business card, make
your CV, make your website and
make sure that the branding is
consistent and then sits there.
You know, they took more about
personal branding. And I think
that you can only really have. A
good personal brand, if you do
include all those other things,
because if you don't, if you
just say right, I'm a, I don't
know,
I'm a JavaScript developer.
That's not really a personal
brand, is it because what makes
you unique? All of those things
that you said, like, you know,
do you like sewing? Do you like
cooking? Do you like running? Do
you like cats? That's what makes
you, you isn't it. And that's
your personal brand. And you
know, this is how you write,
this is how you speak or maybe
you
choose not to blog. Maybe choose
not to speak. Um, but yeah, I
think that there is a lot of
pressure around making sure that
you've got a personal brand. I
dunno. I don't think that I
necessarily curated mine. Like
you say, I try to be quite
authentic and you know, if
people don't like my hobbies,
then I
don't really care because they
can get their own hobbies
company. Um, but yeah, I think
it's, it's just interesting to
read about other people as well
as see what makes them tick. So,
yeah, we're all different. And I
think it's up to you as to how
much of yourself you put out
there. And that's the other side
of personal branding, isn't it?
That there is a lot of pressure
to put yourself out there. And I
always say to people. You know,
they come to me and they say,
oh, you know, you did a lot of
public
speaking do this and that. Like,
I, I, don't know if it's for me.
And I'm like, well, you know,
don't feel the pressure to do
it,
because for some people, like
I've seen them physically
shaking
when they had to get up and do a
talk and I'm like, you know,
find
something that you feel
comfortable doing. Don't feel
like you have to go and do talks
and stuff because everyone else
is doing it. There's got to be
other ways of showing what you
can do. Like maybe you can write
something or can just build
something you don't, maybe don't
even have to write and speak.
Maybe you can just build
something and show your talents
through that. Um, so yeah, I
dunno, it's a big topic and, uh,
I'm not really too sure the
answer is. I often wonder if the
people with the big personal
brands are truly happy and how
much time they spend on, uh, on
nurturing that brand and keeping
it up because does feel like
some of these folks are on
Twitter all
day, every day. And it's like
how, I can't think of that many
things to tweet. have you got
time to do your day job? It's
really weird.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I have that same thing too.
I'm lucky if I get one or two
tweets. you know what it also
happened. I'll try, I think of
something and then edit it over
and over again.
Suze: Oh, yeah.
Dan: and then just close the
window
Suze: Yeah, exactly. If you
overthink it, you buy, I do that
all the time. Yeah.
Dan: are never, yeah. The ones
that go through that process are
never a good, good anyway, but
yeah, that's um, actually,
honestly, I was coming in the
office this morning and thinking
almost that exact same advice
about. There is a lot of
pressure
to do, um, a lot of this stuff
or, you know, anything, even
the,
the there's the, the build in
public, you know, movement. And
there's a, all, all my, um,
asking me almost always good
intentions behind all of the
advice. You know, people are
pretty much talking about what
worked for them But I love that
you said like, please, like
don't, you know, if likes public
speaking is very, very hard for
you or horrible, you know, just
don't like find, you can find
something else. There's lots of
other things to do.
Suze: Yeah. Yeah.
Dan: I appreciate like that
advice people can use to hear
that that's good stuff.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think we're
looking at your career too,
you've tried a lot of different
things. Um, have a lot of
different interests. Oh, my gosh
interest is I need more coffee,
I
guess, but one of the things I
see consistently is your work
with communities. And you first
started coming to Virtual
Coffee,
you became a breakout room
leader really quickly. Um, it's
just
because I wasn't in your room.
think I've only been in your
room
once because you became a room
leader so quickly and I'm most
often a room leader, but it was
it's consistently, um, commented
on what a great room leader you
are. And in everyone's always
like, oh, if I could be in a
room, I would be in her room.
And
so, you know, you've been an
emcee for events and other
things. And I just wanted to
see, like, is there an approach
that
you have as you go into this and
you lead these small group
conversations, or maybe you can
just kind of like walk us
through
your thought process as you're a
breakout room or being an MC for
an event that helps people feel
welcome.
Suze: Yeah. Yeah, no, that's a
really great question. And, um,
yeah, it's true. I did become a
room leader very early on and I
thank Dan for that. Actually,
Dan invited me to, because I
remember
the turning point. Do you
remember that?
Dan: I am almost interjected to
steal credit for that, because I
don't remember what we talked
about. You and I had a
one-on-one
conversation or something. And
then I was like, oh, we just
need
to get in here. Which is,
Suze: Yeah. Yeah. What it was
was you were room-leading that
day,
but I think you had a really bad
night and yeah. You were
properly
struggling. And I was like, oh,
okay. So I didn't, I don't think
I consciously led the room, but
yeah. I was like, oh, I thought
I
had dan looks like. We're going
to fall asleep. So let's see if
we can take the pressure off.
Yeah, it was, yeah, it was, it
was you weren't well that day at
all, but, uh, that's the thing.
We often commit to do something
and, uh, and then find out that
actually today's not the day.
So, uh, yeah, so also that we
were
like, okay, let's, let's do this
thing. So, um, yeah, I think it
all comes down to. Empathy and
knowing your audience. And this
is something that I learned like
really early on doing marketing,
because if you want to do
marketing, you have to know your
audience. Otherwise you're not
going to be very good at
marketing. And so being in
Virtual Coffee, I think I
probably maybe came to four,
three or four before I became a
room leader. And so it was very
fresh in my mind, what it felt
like to be new to Virtual
Coffee. So I tried to kind of
incorporate
that in, um, And so something
that I always ask when I get
into
the room and I'm rim leading is,
do I have anyone new to Virtual
Coffee here with me today? And
then I'm like, look, don't be
scared. Like just put your hands
up. It's fine. We're not all
going to judge you. I just want
to make sure that I'm not
missing
out any information that, you
know, I need to know. And then I
might go over a few bits that
you've already gone through in
the big breakout room in the
main room. But I feel like in
the main
room, sometimes there's just so
much going on that maybe they're
not taking it all in. So it's
just easier in a smaller group.
And then just put them at ease
because they're gonna have to
introduce themselves anyway. So,
you know, so they can kind of be
in the spotlight.
Bekah: Yeah.
Suze: Um, and then I also try to
make sure that there's a balance
of topics and also balance of
people speaking. So I always,
um,
asked for all the topics
upfront. And then say, right,
I'm going to
try and split the time equally
between all of these topics so
that folks can all kind of get
their questions answered and
stuff like that. And then I'm
not afraid to call it, say,
we've
done 20 minutes on the topic.
I'm not afraid to say right. I'm
just
going to take the last point
here from Dan. And then we're
going to
move on to the next topic,
because I've already said at the
beginning, we've got these
three, so everybody knows we're
going to
have to move on at some point.
So they can, they can't be too
upset
when we actually do move on.
Whereas I guess if he didn't do
that, and then we pivoted
somebody might be like, oh, hang
on a minute. I didn't quite
finish what I wanted to say. Um,
and then, um, when people speak,
I do a lot of active listening
as
well and make sure that I kind
of highlight back to everybody,
the
bits that kind of resonated with
me, which are going to be
different for everyone, but at
least I think it's important to
people to feel heard, isn't it.
So what better way of making
them
feel heard than repeating back
what you heard? So, and that
also
gives people a chance to then
think, oh yeah, actually, you
know, I've thought of something
else or whatever, it kind of
stimulates conversation, but
sometimes. If you feel like, um,
it's kind of dying off a bit,
just doing that little summary
piece gets people thinking, and
it gives them a bit of time to
think about, what comes next and
stuff. Um, yeah, so those are
the
main things I just try and
include people really...um, I
think that's the main thing,
because being an introvert
myself, know that when I'm in a
group, especially when I don't
know people, it can be really
hard to get a word in edgewise.
Yeah. um, oh, and the other
thing I always do is I make sure
that
we use raise hands in all of my
rooms. I don't, I don't allow
anyone to just unmute and, uh,
and speak because the people who
do that are going to be the ones
that are confident to do that.
And the people that don't do
that, aren't going to be the
ones
that aren't confident to do
that. And then you won't ever
hear from
them. So I always say, please
use the raise hand function. And
then
that helps me to see like how
many people are in the queue.
And
I've got five minutes left until
I need to pivot. So. Ask them to
be brief and stuff. It just kind
of helps me with the whole
management of the room. So yeah,
I do try and build in a few
different things to help the
more introverted people, because
I
know what that's like and you
kind of feel like, I can't get a
word and then you just give up
and I don't really want people
to
do that because there's a reason
why they came and the reason why
they came wasn't really to sit
there, listening to everybody
else, but really they wanted to
speak didn't they, and either
they didn't manage it this time
and that's really what I want to
avoid.
Dan: I love all of that. I love
hearing about it, your process,
you know, it's something that
I've personally just really
started thinking about since
Virtual, you know, over the last
year or so. Somebody with your
experience, you know, with the
community building and, um, you
know, things like that. It's
really nice to hear that I like
the active listening, active
listening, you know, I'm glad,
I'm glad that I can ask you this
question because it's is a cool,
um, is as cool as see how much
actually goes into being a room
leader. When, when you know room
leader, most of the time isn't
going to be talking it, like
isn't talking that much through,
through, through an hour long
conversation. Um, but still. Uh,
doing a lot. I like how you
illustrate it, like how much,
uh, you know, so that somebody
can
improve, help, improve a room
and, and help people get hurt,
you know? And that's that, was
the other part of what I liked
was the, how the active
listening is, you know, is a
form of
managing the conversation, but
also like acknowledging that a
person got heard, you know,
that's phrased was not put that
together very well, that
sentence, but, you know, th that
was the, you ended with like,
that's why people are coming is
to maybe to, you know, connect
and, and part of connecting is
actually being heard as far as
well as, uh, you know,
listening,
I suppose, that makes any sense
at all.
Suze: Definitely. It's
definitely a conversation is
always a
two-way thing. Is there
communication's a two-way
process. So, um, yeah, it's not
just about talking at somebody
at
all. So yeah, I do try and get a
bit of a, a bit of a balance in
there, but you know, that's not
to say, you know, I know there's
a lot of folks who've tried the
room leading and then you were
it
and there is a lot to remember.
So just don't feel any pressure
to do all of those things, but
just be conscious that you're
not
just sitting there to be a
person that's calling out names
I
guess... maybe, um and we were
just trying to incorporate one
or
two little tactics in there, but
at the end of the day, we're
just
grateful for anyone who steps up
to do that role, because it's
not
an easy one is it?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Uh, it's, are so many
little things like you were
saying, and we want everybody to
be comfortable and feel welcome.
Right? And so allowing space for
them to do that and creating
different pathways for them to
communicate by giving time with
the hand raise function, or
allowing a little bit of silence
for someone to jump in or to use
the chat and bring that forward
is, you know, really important
to forming those relationships.
And
I think. Active listening is, is
a skill that can be that's
learned really, I think because
we all like to talk about things
that we're excited about and,
you know, sometimes it's hard,
sometimes room leaders continue
to talk about things. You know,
I've been known to go on a hot
take rant every once in a while.
Um, but by keeping those things
in mind and recognizing, okay,
I've been talking for awhile. I
need to figure out how to bring
other people into this
conversation. If there aren't
any
hand raises or this person in my
room was very excited, but
they've been talking for five
minutes straight without taking
a
breath. I need to make sure that
there's space for everybody to
be
part of the conversation. And
that's why we keep the. Small
like between eight and 10
people, ideally, because it does
allow
room for that. And I think that
are lots of helpful tips for
people who are room leaders, but
also for people who are, are in
the room or in a group
conversation, or, know, sitting
at a conference table with a
bunch of people you don't know
can be a challenge. But I think
that, know, it's all towards
building an inclusive community
by keeping those things in mind.
Suze: Yeah, definitely.
Definitely.
Dan: I'm glad we got into this
too, because I, you know, I
don't
know how many listeners we have
that are not Virtual Coffee
members. Um, but you know, this
is like one of the main things
that we do in Virtual Coffee and
all of our room leaders are all,
you know, sort of volunteers
that we, either volunteer to, or
we
pulled into helping manage these
rooms. And, um, I just wanted to
like take a quick moment to
shout out everybody. mean, Suze
and
everybody else, because I don't
know how many people are. In
that
we, you know, we have a group of
people that we pull from, but,
uh, they're all awesome. And
they're all volunteers and it's,
it's like, this is a good
illustration of like that th
that
it takes work and it takes
effort, you know, just, just to
do those. And we, you know, we
appreciate everybody
appreciates.
It these rooms B uh, B
Suze: Sometimes it takes getting
over a bit of fear as well. I
know there's some people that
have tried to do it and they've
really kind of had to psych
themselves up to do it. So not
everybody can just jump in and
do it. And I really take my hat
off
to them as well.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: absolutely. It is. It's a
process and it's not for
everybody, but also something
that you can work on and we try
and provide support for a new
room leaders and, um, to
transition into. Full-time room
leaders. I don't know what to
call they want to, but you know,
like you said, there can be a
lot
of challenges along the way.
Yeah. that that's one of the
things that I think is really
interesting about your story
too.
Like you, I think are
consistently taking on new
challenges. It feels like, you
know, you're, changing career
paths or you're writing a book
or you're streaming on Twitch.
so
you're consistently pursuing all
of these new and challenging
things. And I just want, why.
Suze: I don't know. Um, it's
funny. Yeah. Why? Well, um, that
is, that is the big question. I
don't know. And I'm really glad
you said that. So thank you for
saying that because I think it's
really hard. And actually like,
especially through the pandemic,
I've really kind of struggled
with my mental health quite a
lot. And there have been points
where I'm just kind of thinking
like, You know, my achievements
aren't really anything and what
am I doing? And you know, what
do I do next type thing. So it's
really nice for you to
acknowledge that. And it does
make me feel a bit better than
that. I actually, uh, I am
actually doing something even
when it feels like I'm not, but,
um, yeah, I guess. I dunno, I
guess I'm just curious about
stuff. I just see people doing
it like this Twitch thing, and
I'm
like, oh, what's that all about
then? How does that work? And
then what can you do with it?
And I think I also like to be
different as well. So I want to
try something that other people
aren't trying or other dev teams
aren't trying, or maybe the same
thing, but in a different way.
Um, or just try, try something
for the first time somewhere. I
don't know, or just take a
different slump on it, but I try
to do things in an organized way
as well, because I'm always
thinking about why am I doing
this? Like, what's the point of
doing it? And I think that helps
quite a lot. I'm not really a
random person. I don't I don't
really like random. I like to do
things in quite a strategic and
planned way. So yeah, while it
might seem like I do a lot of
different things, I probably did
over think all of those things a
lot before I actually jumped in.
Um, so, uh, yeah. Yeah, I think
that's, I think that's what it
is, the curiosity and the
wanting
to do something different and
you know, what tools can I use
to do
that?
Dan: So you're streaming on
Twitch, you know, sort of
recently is that that's for
work, right? Um, is that true?
All
right. Um, um, not totally
remembering, but.
Suze: Yeah. So yeah, the
streaming or Twitch is very
recent. And like the other thing
about me is like, I kind of go
big or go home. So I think they
think gradually I don't do a
small thing. I'll be like,
right, I'm going to go on
Twitch. So
this month is the first time
I've ever twitched. And by the
end of
October, I will have done nine
at least. There's nine in the
diary.
Yeah. So I, so, okay. So when I
decided I was going to apply for
this job during the recruitment
process, I said to my boss, you,
they hear some projects that I
would really love to do if I get
the job. And one of them was,
they Redis, we have, um, Redis
university got eight free
training courses. And I said,
right. Okay. Lets o RU 101 I'll
take RU101 as part of my
onboarding and I'll learn in
public. Um, so I'll stream that.
And so I'm streaming that with
one of my colleagues who works
in
the Redis university world and
the we're going through all the
different classes together and
stuff like that. And he's
teaching me, so that's my
regular one every week. And the
other
project that I pitched to my.
Um, at the time, hopefully
potential
boss, but now he's, my boss was
hacktoberfest. So, um, yeah,
Redis has got its roots in open
source and I thought, you know,
this is a really good fit and
Redis, hasn't done hacktoberfest
before. So let's look at putting
some of our stuff out for folks
to get involved with and
contribute to because you know,
I've Participated in
Hacktoberfest before for the
benefit of everybody listening,
I'm just holding up my t-shirt
that I'm wearing. And this poor
t-shirt is stretched. Cause I
keep holding it up on the, on
the strings. Um, so yeah, I was
like,
let's do Hacktoberfest. Like how
hard can it be? Really? And
actually it wasn't that hard,
like, cause I was really
organized about it and um,
talked to a few people across
the
business about, you know which
we realistically include here?
issues can we put out? And we've
had a really good response. So.
With that. What I did was also
the docs team at work. We're
really lucky. We've got docs T
in the Dev rel team with us. So
it's
all like this nice place where
we can just go directly to them.
I
don't have to go into another
unit and ask and stuff. I said
to
them, documentation is often
cited as a way for folks to get
their feet wet with openings
source. And all hacktoberfest So
let's live streams is where we
demystify technical writing and
documentation for people that
will want to get involved in
that. You know, there's a lot of
coders that want to get into
technical writing. There's a lot
of people that don't code, but
they're interested in writing
who were interested in doing
technical writing cause they
don't want to code, which is
fine. Um, Th those people on my
teams, who've got three
technical
writers. One of them was a
coder, one of them wasn't. So
that was
really good. So, um, I've done a
panel, um, chat with them last
Friday. So that's on YouTube now
and next week hunting one to one
file size for each one of them.
So that's another three streams.
Um, and this morning, yeah, this
morning, me and the dev rel
manager, the developer advocacy
manager a live stream at 9:00 AM
this morning, which was fun
actually, because we both in the
UK. Normally we do it at 5:00 PM
because that's the time that
hits
like Pacific, Eastern and a lot
of other places, but we thought,
okay, let's do the 9:00 AM slot
and just see what happens. Um,
so
we went through, um, you know,
let's have a look at the issues
that we've put out and let's
have a look at the PRs. We've
got
back. Cause some of them were
really amazing. And like I said,
at the beginning, didn't know
what we were going to get back.
Like we put out a load of
issues. We didn't know how well
they were
going to be received. You know,
how hard can it be? But we got
so
many great contributions from
people. Some of whom had never
used the product before. And
this was really kind of a
Testament to
how good the readmes were that
people had put on the repose.
But
back when they created the
projects, not even just for
hacktoberfest. We were really
like thinking like everybody,
everbody's past selves for being
kind to us there. And, um, so
yeah, this is, this is how I
kind of got into streaming. I'm
not
sure whether it's my favorite
thing to do. I think it's a
really hard grind actually. And
it depends why you want to do
it.
If you're doing it to get
followers, you probably going to
do be doing it for a while.
Maybe just doing it because you
like
streaming then fine. But I think
there's always a part of you
that
wants somebody to be watching
because otherwise, why would you
sit there doing it?
Bekah: It's less scary. If
there's nobody watching, then
you
can say, well, I tried it, you
know,
Suze: Nobody came so I'm not
gonna do it anymore, but yeah,
we
recording all ours and putting
them on YouTube and we getting a
decent, uh, views of the
recording. So that's something.
Bekah: Are those all in the
Redis lab twitch account?
Suze: Yes. Yeah. I can give you
the link. Yeah.
Bekah: Got it. It'll be in the
show notes.
Suze: Yeah.
Dan: That's fun. Yeah. And the,
the, the fact that it's easy to
put those recordings on YouTube
is as fun it's, it's becomes
like, even if you, and if you
just keep going you'll end up
with followers, I think, you
know, but like on Twitch, but,
um, it's a nice way to record,
um, with some lower
expectations,
you know, so if you drop onto a
YouTube link that says, here's
the stream recording from
whatever, then people are going
to expect a stream level. You
know, like not highly edited,
not
like highly produced, but a nice
stream. And you know, so that
the
expectations are like set, you
know what I mean? And so that's
one reason. That's one, one side
of that. I like streaming, you
know, for coding stuff, because
if I made a typo, you know,
whatever I had to hit delete
and, you know, whatever in a, in
a
recorded video that I was like
producing, I would have to edit
it out and do a scene or
whatever rerecord it. But if
it's not a
stream, like, you know,
everybody makes typos, it's not
a big deal,
you know? So, um, That's like
the Twitch to YouTube pipeline
aspect
of it. I, I feel like is, uh, is
nice. I don't know.
Suze: Yeah, no, you're
definitely right about that
authenticity
thing. If people want to see
what you're really like, they'll
either they need to watch you on
a live stream and they get the
warts and all don't. They like
the first livestream that I did
accidentally expose my password,
which is like a bit of a Rite of
passage for any new streamers.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. That'll happen.
Suze: Um,
Dan: like watching a recording
of a, of a concert or something
as
opposed to a music video, you
know, it's like,
Bekah: And it's the same thing I
think that goes for, there are
so
many online conferences, right.
And everybody complains. It's
not
the same energy, but that's
because they're not creating a
new space for that thing. So
many of them are prerecorded and
you
don't get energy from that. At
least I don't. It sucks. It
sucks
the energy out of me because I
know I can, Yeah. I can edit
that
thing or I have to nail it
because it's, recorded and
that's
an expectation, but if you're at
a conference and you're giving a
live talk, you're not, that's a
totally different energy. And I
think. You know, maybe there's a
middle ground between just going
into a livestream without any
preparation and having a
produced
YouTube video and that's where
the online conference space
should live. Like be able to
give your talk, um, while
livestreamed
and. Um, it's harder because you
can't see people, but when
you're
navigating the chat that goes on
a Twitch stream or whatever,
that
becomes part of the interaction
and there shouldn't be that
expectation that this is going
to be like an in-person
conference
talk because it's not an
in-person conference talk,
right.
There should be a shift in how
we find our energy online.
Suze: Yeah. Yeah. And that whole
finding your energy online thing
is the age old question. Isn't
it? We kind of rapidly had to
desperately find some energy
from somewhere when everything
went
online and some conferences are
better than others. I definitely
like the ones where they have
like networking and stuff, and
that can be scary for people.
Um, but yeah, those ones are the
ones
that I probably enjoy the most.
And like you say, the ones that
I
enjoyed the least were the ones
where they were prerecorded and
like for the past sort of 18 to
24 months, I've done a mixture
of
both. So I've spoken at
conferences, online conferences
live and online conferences
where it's been pre recorded.
And yet
pre recordings are energy
sucking aren't they?
Dan: Yeah, it's hard to, it's
hard to, and I agree. reason
that
it's happening right, is
everyone just tried to do
straight, you
know, live ones when it all
started. And that's really hard
too. And there's so many
technical challenges that can
come up, you know? And so I
think there was a whole year or
a few,
like half a year of conferences
that were all. Parts got messed
up and the organizers are like,
we're not doing this again, you
know? Uh, because they just
tried to do the same thing
except on
zoom, you know? And so swung way
around to the other side of
where
you're, you know, now you're
like a lot of prerecorded talks,
but
Suze: Yeah.
Dan: I think everybody agrees
that, um, Codeland did an
interesting thing where they had
a bunch of prerecorded recorded
talks, but they had like they,
there was like a of time of like
four talks It was just like,
they were just like streaming
the
recordings, you know? And so the
MCs would like drop in in
between, but, they also released
on demand links. And so you
could
just like shut off the stream
and go watch them or something
if you
wanted, or, you know, like that.
Um, which was like kind of
interesting. Uh, you know, I
don't think it totally solved
the
problem, but
Suze: No, I don't think there,
there is an answer. Cause some
people don't even like in person
ones. So for some people they
really love the online. So yeah,
definitely can't please
everyone.
Dan: Well, yeah, that's, that's
all, that's always true.
Suze: Yeah.
Bekah: I think people too don't
realize how much speakers
prepare
for their talks and. When you go
to a conference, a lot of times
they'll pay for your travel or
they'll pay for your hotel stay
and you'll get, you know, some
kind of gift as part of that,
which is like a nice
recognition. You, you put a lot
of time into
this and we appreciate that. And
I think that there wasn't as
much
of that with online conferences,
because one, they didn't have
funding or sponsorships and two,
they were trying to figure out
how are they going to run three
tracks of this conference online
and in a lot of instances, the
speakers kind of got lost along
the way, in terms of just, just
simple thank yous is even, and,
and I, I understand it is hard
to organize events and make
changes
and stuff like that, it just
goes back to that. You know,
earlier
talking about those, there's a
lot of work and effort put into
a
lot of the things that we do
that are, um, audience facing
things.
Suze: Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Cause people are quick to tell
you what they didn't like, but a
lot of the time they don't speak
a couple of say what they did
like do they, um, and also even
if you ask people some times,
like you did a survey,
historically I was in marketing
for ages. And I think the survey
completion rate was somewhere
between. Um, 5 and 15%, but
normally around the 5% mark and
it still, it's no different
today, really, unless you kind
of offer a nice incentive for
somebody to fill that in. So
yeah, even when you directly ask
people what they want, they
don't necessarily tell you. And
yes,
organizing an online event is it
is a different set of skills and
knowledge. Uh, than, uh,
organizing an in-person one. And
like you say it in in-person
ones kind of a bit easier, cause
you're dealing with physical
rooms, aren't you? And you know,
if you've got three tracks,
you've got like that room one is
track, one room two is track two
and room three's track three
easy. Just tell everyone which
room they've got to go to, but
if
you're using a technology
solution to manage your tracks,
that can become a bit of a
nightmare very quickly. I think
you probably need more staffing.
To manage something like that,
but then you the safety issue.
Yeah.
Bekah: Well, w when you're in a
room with somebody, can say, the
speaker is not here. You can
physically find them. If
somebody
is not online at the right time,
more difficult.
Dan: Yeah. And you're, you're
much more like at the whims of
their local, you know, their own
computer and their own internet
connection, all that stuff to
which, which causes problems
Suze: Yeah.
Dan: can cause some problems
Suze: Yeah. Where do
Dan: there was a, there was
some, there was some good, the
keynotes
were live, so the keynotes were
live. And then there was other
talks that were recorded, which
hybrid hybrid combo,
Suze: Hmm. Yeah, sometimes they
do, um, prerecorded talks and
then live Q and a that's quite
nice.
Dan: Yeah,
Suze: You can see that the
speakers have tried to do the
continuity thing by wearing the
same clothes that they wore in
the recording for the Q and a.
But I did notice, like somebody
would rearrange their room in
the few weeks in between. I was
like,
oh, okay. Yeah, you didn't think
of that. Did you eat the plants?
Moved, walked across the room?
Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: Well, and so, you know,
we've talked about all of these
different things that you've
done. Well, a lot of them, but
we
haven't really hit on your book.
So I would love to hear about
like, you know, this is another
thing you took on. Why did you
decide to write a book? And what
was that process in reception?
Like.
Suze: Well, this book is not
something I actually made the
decision to do per se. I didn't
sit down. I didn't wake up one
day and say, right, I want to
write a book, it was something
that I wanted to do. When I was
a child, I always thought, yeah,
I'm going to write book at some
point, but I always thought it
was going to be fiction because
I think a lots of kids like
writing
stories, don't they? Um, but
yeah, I kind of didn't really
think about it too much. And
then, um, always been interested
in writing and that was what I
was mostly interested in when I
was doing the marketing stuff,
like, uh, communications and
things like that. So yeah,
somebody actually reached out to
me on Twitter and said, they've
got this project. Um, And would
I
like to contribute to it? the
series is called 32nd and, um,
The books that existed before my
one. So my one's 32nd coding
where things like 32nd
architecture, 32nd biology, 32nd
chemistry, you know, all these
32nd history, things like that.
And, um, the objective is to get
across like 50 different topics
within that whole theme within
that book within about 170
words.
So they, I think they said to
me, oh, I saw your blog. And I
think
you would be really good for
this project. And also what's
interesting actually is that
these, uh, the publishers
published the book in like, I
think 30 or 50 different
languages or something like
that. So I might actually come
across
this book in a different country
with a, B you would recognize
the
branding, which is funny. So
even though you do what you
didn't
understand what the words on the
front side, you know, from the
picture. So, um, so yeah, so he
said to me, you know, I'd really
like you to contribute to this
book. So yeah, in the end there
for some of the books, 15
contributors, but on this one,
there's only three. So I got to
write quite a nice chunk of this
book. Um, so yeah, to have sort
of, uh, like variables, how do
you explain what a variable is
in like 174 words? It's quite
hard
Bekah: Yep.
Suze: and, um, you know, arrays
and functions and loops and all
of that
Dan: you have your, can you, can
you just do your, can you do the
variable one? Do you have it
somewhere?
Suze: I've got my book in front
of me. I can read out to you
Dan: yeah. Yeah. Just, just,
just do it or pick one, pick
one. It
doesn't have to be the variable
one, but that,
Suze: Right. Let's do variables
cause like that. You didn't say
to me, just tell me what a
variable is in 170 words because
I, yeah, it's not the sort of
thing you can remember. We'll be
able to articulate, but right.
Okay. So variables, we use
variables in programming to give
us an easy way of labeling and
therefore recalling and
manipulating memory locations in
which we store pieces of
information. For example, our
program might ask the user for
their name and location. When
the
user submits these pieces of
information, we can assign these
values to name variables,
current years Suze" and current
user
location equals Europe. I
deliberately said Europe because
the UK left the EU, but we're
still in Europe. So holding on
to
that, that's just a note, that's
a footnote, but no one we're
still in Europe. Please
understand that the computer is
still with these values and the
memory locations associated with
each variable. This allows us to
greet the user by name with a
salutation appropriate to the
time of day where they are. When
declaring a variable, we can
decide whether or not its value
can be modified. We also need to
decide the scope of the
variable,
where it can be seen in use in
the program. Some variables have
a global scope so they can be
used anywhere in the code.
Others
have a scope that is limited to
a specific code block. For
example,
current time may only exist in a
function where you are
determining whether it's morning
or evening in the user's time
zone. In addition to a name and
value, variables in most
programming languages also have
types. For example, a variable
whose type is integer can hold
whole number values. There you
go.
Dan: Nice.
Suze: 170 words on variables.
Dan: I think that's great. And
variables. Yeah. I mean, I
that's
why specifically? I said, can
you read it to me? Cause I was
trying
to figure out how to, you know,
the thought process about like
distilling something down to.
You know, to a simple language
like
that. Um, and that quickly is,
that's takes a lot of skill and,
um, thought and that was really
Suze: Yeah. I feel like, cause
you know, Bekah said earlier,
I've tried so many different
things. I feel like. Um, and
also
it goes back to, you know,
wanting to do that different
thing or be unique. I always
seem to go for the hard way of
doing
stuff. So it is much harder to
write something short than it is
to write something longer.
Dan: absolutely.
Suze: So yeah, definitely got
Bekah: 100%. I'm trying to...
Dan: yeah, mean, you could see
an entire book written on the
topic.
I mean, you know, I can, I'm
sure that I'm sure there are
entire
books written on the topic, so
that's yeah.
Bekah: I'm trying to write a
proposal for a lightning talk
right now. And it's, it's five
to seven minutes. you tell me 45
to
60 minutes, no problem. I can
give you quite a few different
talks, I having such a hard time
figuring out how I will talk
about. Anything for, just five
to seven minutes, it's more
overwhelming to have less time
than it is to have that whole
hour.
Suze: Yeah, I think in a five to
seven minute talk, you probably
only want one argument. Don't
you because you only have time
for
one there's, you can't really do
three takeaways. You need to one
argument and really argue the
heck out of the argument. I
think, and it goes really fast.
I remember at school, one of the
things they made us do every
year, which was really evil.
Cause I went to an all girl
school. So you can imagine that
was like, Horrible in itself.
But every year they made us
stand up
in front of the entire class a
speech that we had prepared. And
yeah, that has served me well in
adult life, but it was quite
traumatic way of, of getting the
skills. and yeah, so I think we
had to do, was it a two minute
talk or five minutes? It was
really sure, but it felt like it
was going to be forever, but now
yeah, 20 minutes is too short
for me, I think.
Bekah: uh, we're just about at
time here. And so one more
question, and maybe you don't
have a straight answer for this,
but of all of the things that
you've done, what has been your
favorite challenge?
Suze: My favorite challenge.
Yeah, that is a good question.
Hm. Okay. I've got two from I'll
choose two from this year
because
I'm struggling to remember
anything pre pandemic.
Dan: as are we all, Yeah.
Suze: I I'll say, two from this
year, which again are really
different things that I had
never done before. So the book
definitely, which I actually
started last year, but that,
that
whole process is long. Uh, but
that got published. The book got
published at the beginning of
October. 2021. For any of you
good folks of the future who are
listening to this podcast? Um,
on
the same day as Dave Grohl's
book. I don't know. I
Bekah: You were retweeted,
Suze: I know. Yeah. Yeah. So
Dave Grohl is my best friend. I
tweeted about my book and said,
It's been published on the same
day as Dave Grohl from the Foo
Fighters and the Foo Fighters
tweeted me back and said
Congrats... oh my God. Holding
the book in my hand was
something. And then I got that
tweet. I was like, oh, I don't
even need this book now I've got
a tweet from the Foo Fighters.
Like really? Um, and then last
weekend I actually went into a
physical book shop for the first
time, probably since pre
pandemic. And I found my book in
there and I was like, yeah, that
was so weird because yeah,
because I was like, hang on a
minute. This is a copy of the
book that I don't own. And it's
going to be in somebody else's
house. This is just so wild to
me that my name is going to be
in a
thing in somebody's house is
just really well. yeah, the
book, um,
because that is just something
that just kind of, I don't know,
I always wanted to do, but I
never seriously thought that I
would do it and I haven't
actually made a plan to do it.
So, yeah, that's a big
achievement for me. also earlier
this year, right at the
beginning of the year, I
actually did a six
hour live stream conference type
thing. So I don't know if any
you
have heard of global diversity
CFP day. It is a, um, it's an
annual event. And this year it
was online for obvious reasons
where we encourage people from
underrepresented groups to
submit
proposals to CFP so that we can
get more diversity on the tech
conference stages. And so I was
given the brief of.... Um,
organized a six hour live stream
find speakers for it and things
like that. So I found some
speakers. I did some firesides
did a bit of slight karaoke. I
am seated all. I produced it
all.
yeah. Now if you said to me do a
five-hour one, it'd be like
nothing. Cause I've already done
a six hour one. So yeah, I'm
really proud of that because at
one point, um, probably towards
the end, I did a shout out and
said, look, you know, Post in
the
chat. If you've been with me for
the whole six hours I was here
people had, and one of them
actually said I hadn't planned
to, but it was so good I stayed.
So, uh, yeah. So, know, people
are choosing to spend six hours
of their life on a, uh, on a
Saturday with you then, um,
you're doing something right
aren't you. uh, yeah, those are
my two big things that I'm proud
of this year.
Dan: that's awesome.
Bekah: Yeah, great. And I love
that. if someone asks me to do a
five-hour one, I, we easy, cause
I've done a six hour one. I
think
that's a fun way to approach
doing anything.
Suze: Yeah. Yeah. Five, 5 hours
and 59 minutes. No problem.
Bekah: I got this. Well, Thanks
so much for being here with us
today. This has been great to
follow along the things that
you've done and to hear all of
your tips. So, thank you. And
we'll talk to you soon.
Suze: Thanks. Thanks. for
inviting me. It's been a
pleasure.
Dan: right, bye.
Suze: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io.