Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode six of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah.
And this is a podcast that
features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here on this
podcast, sharing their stories
and what they've learned. And we
are here to share
it with you here with me. Today
is my cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah! Today, we
talked
with Bryan Healey. Along with
being one of
the original members of Virtual
Coffee, Bryan
is an entrepreneur, tech leader,
data scientist,
machine learning engineer, and
business developer.
He's helped create or grow
several startups, raised money
and built managed teams of
varying sizes, small to large.
And he's currently CTO of a
FinTech company.
He co-founded called Aiera.
Bryan has had a long
and interesting career, and he's
been in a lot
of different roles. He's being
hired as an engineer,
hiring and managing others and
founding entirely new companies.
His experiences have given him a
unique approach to
decision-making that he was kind
enough to sit
down and share with us
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast.
Like we start every Virtual
Coffee.
We introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're
from, what we do and a random
check-in question.
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Today's random check-in
question is if it were possible,
would you live on the moon?
I'm Bekah, I'm a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio, and not live on the moon.
I feel like there are plenty
of spaces in the Earth that we
have not explored yet.
And so I would like to start
there.
Dan: Um, like what.
Bekah: The deep sea.
Dan: Bottom of the ocean. Okay.
Bekah: Where the aliens live.
Dan: Uh, hi, I'm Dan. I live in
Cleveland.
I do development of many kinds,
I suppose.
And, uh, yeah, I don't like the
moon as it exists right now
seems pretty, you know, boring
and empty and all that stuff.
Right. But I've read like a
number
of different books that are set
sort of in the
future where the moon is... you
know, populated to different
levels or whatever, you know? So
I would consider it in, in
those cases, it depends on, you
know, like what they got going
on there, you know, do they have
like movie, if they have
like movie theaters and, you
know, uh, restaurants and stuff,
you know, if it's like that kind
of thing, uh, then yeah.
But if it's just like all just
like tents and science
people, and then it's less
interesting to me, to you,
you know, but I do like
exploring like, you know, new
areas and hiking and stuff, so
that, that could be cool.
Plus the jumping always looks
always looks fun. Yeah.
Bekah: vertical would increase.
I really think so.
Dan: I would hope
Bryan: Quite
Dan: Yeah.
Bryan: Yeah. Go, uh, I'm Bryan
Healey.
I'm a entrepreneur in Boston,
mass.
Um, and I currently am a
co-founder and CTO at
a company called Aiera. And per
the moon, I'm going
to go with probably no. Um, I'm
in the same camp as
Dan, like, if, if, if it's built
out, like we're talking
future moon with like colonies
and like tons of stuff then
okay, maybe, but even then I
feel like I have my option, I
prefer like Mars over the moon.
Bekah: Mars. Okay.
Bryan: yeah,
Bekah: So maybe the question
should have
been like outer space. somewhere
Bryan: Absolutely. Yeah,
Bekah: cowboy.
Bryan: we're going somewhere
Dan: Why? Why is the Mar why is
Mars better than the moon?
Bryan: Uh, just slightly more
stuff.
Like it's like probably had
water at one point.
They'll be more to investigate.
It's got a little
Dan: Uh,
Bryan: uh, you know, it's got
mountains and glaciers and,
you know, whereas the moments
like once you've seen 100
square feet you're just looking
at different types of rocks.
Dan: Just different craters.
Yeah, that makes sense.
That makes sense.
Bekah: Yeah. Um, welcome Bryan.
We're really, really excited to
have you on the podcast today.
For those of you who don't
know Bryan, he is one of the
first people to ever
come to Virtual Coffee. And so
has been around a
really long time because of
Bryan, we have a slack.
Um, so you, you all owe that to
Bryan.
Um, this is long overdue. I feel
like.
So thanks for being here.
Bryan: yeah, happy to..
Bekah: so we always start off
with kind of your origin story,
your background, and a little
bit about what got you to this
place where you are today.
Bryan: Just generally like my
career?
Um, you know, I probably had one
of the more straightforward
career paths in tech. You know,
I, I went to
college for computer science
right out of high school.
I went to Northeastern
University, uh, here in Boston.
Um, studied Computer Science and
jumped right into,
you know, working at a startup
while I was there.
I actually, so the, the actual
path of my career, uh, was I.
Northeastern has this sort of
five-year program where
you, you actually do work
interspersed with academics.
So you six months in school, six
months on an actual,
like, uh, like industry job.
Dan: That's cool.
Bryan: Yeah. it was pretty cool.
I didn't even realize how
cool it was at the time. I
thought it was just like,
ah, money, you know, as, as, as
a older adult, I'm
like, damn, that was a, a big
leg up in terms of like
how the future progressed. Um,
but so I did a,
I did two, like more traditional
internships.
Six-month internships. Um,
Goldman Sachs and WR Grace.
So fairly large large-ish
companies.
Um, then, uh, in the intervening
period before my third one,
I actually started a small, uh,
startup, uh, in my dorm.
Um, ironically, it was of a
silly thing.
It was a notetaking shareable
notetaking social network for
like other college students. I
was trying to actually
pitch it Facebook style to like
the university would
sponsor it and to cover fees and
everyone's sort of
joined in, uh, it did okay. It
was sort of making a little
money, um, but ultimately I
actually kind of got
Acqui-hired into my, uh, uh,
second role, which is
working at another startup in
Boston called Garment Valet,
which was sort of the, luxury
delivery, uh, laundry service.
Uh, and so they had this pitch
where they were trying to create
like a national brand out of it,
and they were going to
create like a central tech hub
that sorta managed, uh, almost
like Uber style, like drivers
across the country would,
would work for different shops.
And it would sort of.
You know, work somewhat
independently, but
centrally managed. Uh, and so I
joined them as
my third before graduation. and
they ended up staying there.
So I was there for like three
and a half years building out
their platform scales from like
three people to 25 people.
Um, Yeah. And so, I mean, can
obviously
keep going for forever. I don't
know how far
you want me to take my
Bekah: Well, I just like want to
pause for a second.
Cause you're like, oh, I have a
traditional path
into where I am today. And you
were like, I started
this startup in my dorm room and
then I worked at another
startup that was acquired. And
I'm not sure that
that's the traditional path. And
I think that's the
very Bryan Healey path of doing
all of these things
and just like, all right, going
to keep going with it.
Bryan: Fair fair. Yeah. Maybe
traditional
is the wrong word. I should've
said more like
I didn't career transition.
Bekah: Yeah,
Bryan: I was just like straight
into tech, like ran out of the
Dan: did.
Bryan: Yeah, it definitely,
probably not truly traditional
from like what most people
experience, which is just like,
get a degree, get the first job
and sort of March from there.
Bekah: Well, and so you've
always been involved in
the startup life then. So it's
been startup
after startup. And then, so at
some point
you transitioned from somebody
else's startup
to your own startup. So where's
that happening.
Bryan: Yeah. I mean, I I'll
quickly caveat
that by saying that I didn't
realize this was potentially
unusual until I was older, but
I've always had that bug in me.
I think I was starting
businesses when I
was eight years old. Like I was
always
been  doing thing.
Bekah: Eight year Bryan's
business.
Thats what I want to know.
Bryan: Yeah. So, well, like for
instance,
like random, uh, story in that
vein, but I'll
only tell one of them. So when I
was.
10 years old, I started a lawn
care service in the
neighborhood, but I hired all of
the neighborhood
kids to work for me.
Dan: amazing.
Bryan: and essentially got about
30 houses in the neighborhood.
Just sort of sign up for this
like kids lawn service.
And, uh, and I would take cuts
at everybody doing care for
Dan: That's awesome. What, what,
like, where
did you learn to do that? Or
think that
way, you know, that early.
Bryan: the weird thing. I just
sort of like.
I mean, I, I, I must've learned
from somewhere, I guess, but
I don't have a clear vision in
my head of where, I mean,
I'd probably just observed
Dan: Um,
Bekah: Twain.
Bryan: yeah, yeah. Just think
observed other
people doing things and you're
like, I could do that.
Um, so yeah, that's my random
aside. So.
So the progression from how I
got to college
to my own startup. Um, I, I
won't tell the whole
story cause I I've had a lot of
gigs in my career, I think
not eight, eight gigs in total.
Um, but the gist of it is
that I've I've sort of to the
startup space in general,
at the very least sort of like
innovation space.
I I've had a couple of tiny
stints at bigger companies,
but usually it was in a very
specific capacity.
So like I did a stint at Amazon
in 2013 to 2016.
Um, uh, but I joined
specifically to work on
the, uh, Echo Alexa project.
Cause it was like an,
it was a brand new division in
the business.
I was one of the first 50 hires.
I got to sort of like
play entrepreneur inside of a
big beast.
Uh, and that was its own kind of
fun other than like
random deviations like that.
I've mostly been around
startups, either help try to
find them or
just join very early. like from,
from the startup,
I joined in college art LA um, I
jumped to another startup
as the hire, called shape up,
um, and was there from six
people to, I think about 75
people, something like that.
Um, jumped from there to another
startup, uh, Uh, sort of a later
stage startup, I think I was
like the 52nd higher, but it
was another like, um, that vein,
they were like four years old.
Um, whose name actually escapes
me now.
They were up in Waltham. Um, and
then from there, I,
actually tried to start a
startup of my own, a company
called JoinVester essentially
early days of like crowdfunding.
I was trying to start up sort of
like a republic.co style
company, trying to get people to
sell their startup shares
on an exchange using, um, very
new regulation called, oh no.
What was it called? oh, that's
going to bug me
is actually a name for it. It's
kind of a cool name,
but it's just been so long. It's
like out of my head now.
Yeah, I ended up bringing on two
co-founders while I was
doing that, we a little bit of
seed money and we sort of were
talking to investors and sort of
try and get things going.
We never quite got it up to like
launch.
There was all kinds of questions
around the regulation.
Is this going to last there's a
lot of opposition to it.
Is it worth investing in
companies to sign
up was a challenge. Anyone who
is a really
high value would of course just
go range, venture
raise venture dollars. And so it
was like
getting quality deals. Do you
have the platform was
that was a bit of a stretch. So
that for about two years,
but never really took off. Um,
and it was from there
that I, uh, Jumped to another
startup called name May Media
in other ones that like late
stage startup, I think I was
like the 60th employee they were
like four years old.
It was like pre IPO. and I was
there through
them getting acquired. And then
from there
I jumped to Amazon. And so
that's sort of
where the next piece of it sort
of takes off.
So while I was at Amazon, I
ended up getting recruited
into being the AI director at a
company called Lola.
Which is, uh, if you know
anything about kayak.com
was founded by this guy, Paul
English, um, he's
a big name in Boston. I'm not
sure how, how far his
sort of like presence reaches in
the wider US tech community,
but he's a big deal here. um, so
he co-founded Kayak after
he sold Kayak to Priceline. He
started Lola as
I, this new venture
conversational, um, base.
So like, it's sort of like an
automated travel agent
was the original pitch. So you
can. I have the experience
of personalized travel agency
without having to
physically go anywhere, even
talk to a real human, you
could just do it through, this
digital experience.
Um, and so I joined there
through that whole experience.
I got connected with my current
co-founder Ken Sena.
He was, uh, a senior at a
company called Evercore.
Uh, and then later Wells Fargo.
As an analyst, which basically
he's sort of a financial pro.
He, he, um, advises
big funds and firms on how to
invest in money.
Um, and through connecting with
him, uh, we ended up
co-founding Aiera, which was
sort of like this, um,
AI enabled platform to help
analysts do their job better.
Make smarter decisions. days of
Aiera, it was
actually literally making
predictions, trying to sort
of like do the analyst job of
writing research and sort
of making recommendations. and
it has evolved more into
like, um, a pro's, uh, Suite of
services to help them do
the job on the edges better. We,
including the big
centerpiece of ours is events.
So we connect to calls,
conferences, things that
investors care about
and pay attention to and make
decisions on.
And we them and analyze them and
make it easier
for investors sort of like
handle that workflow.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome. So
all of this experience,
it sounds like you've got to
play a lot of different
roles, which seems really. Fun.
I'd love to know maybe like
your best experience was or, or
what made you, what
were you most excited about
doing throughout this period?
Bryan: really hard to pick a
favorite experience.
Cause it's, it's more like
there's been a suite of
things that have all just been
different in different ways.
And I have highlights from all
of them.
So I get sort of give some of
those top line highlights.
I mean, like for instance, uh,
joining Shape Up, was,
was a specific experience. So
prior to Shapeup I had
been in this other startup, but
that other, it was more
of a grind, you know, like I
joined as the third employee,
it took three and a half years
to get up to 27 employees.
And then the, you know, 2008
recession the business.
and so it was just like slow
grinding process of
like building a business a much
more like ground level,
like functional business. They
actually had like trucks
and drivers and felt more like
real world, if that makes sense.
To join ShapeUp was the, my
first experience
on like a rocket ship. Like I
joined a company
that sold digital products. So
there was, it was just
an office and servers. I joined
as the third
employee and in a year we hired
50 people and then
was just like this curve. And
while I was there,
we raised a ton of money. Um,
and we hired a new CEO, a
new CTO, and like, it was just.
It was a firehose of crazy
every single day for the whole
time I was there.
Um, and even after I left, I got
to watch them.
I stayed in touch with people
and they just kept rocketing.
And eventually they got acquired
for big dollars by Virgin Group.
So that experience, think
colored a lot of the rest
of my career of like, oh, this
is what I like.
This is fun. I enjoy the
intensity of it.
know, even things that might not
even seem fun in the moment.
Like we had a couple of
stretches where we had product
launches with deadlines and I'm
literally sleeping at the
office for 24 hours a day for
like four or five days in a row.
And it's like at the, in the
moment I might've hated that.
in hindsight, it's like, that's
an experience that
like is hard to reproduce in a
successful way.
Um, and so sort of colored my
realization that.
Me being around startups. Wasn't
just a convenience.
This is where I like to thrive
this, you know, I've
done the biggest, bigger company
thing and internships,
and like, this is the fun. Um,
and then, oh, go ahead.
Bekah: I was just gonna say, it
seems like so many
different personality types.
There's there's a fit for that.
Right? So there are people that
would thrive in
that startup atmosphere. There
are people that will
thrive something that's more
like a nine to five, and this
is the same things that we do
pretty much every day.
So it's really dependent on like
who you are as a person.
Bryan: Yeah, exactly. Right.
And, and if I, if it's
possible, my advice to younger
engineers is almost
always to do a stint at each
Bekah: Um,
Bryan: sort of get that
experience level.
people just know themselves well
enough, and that is that's Okay.
you truly are like, now I know I
would hate that nine to five,
like clock-in, clock-out do my
job kind of thing or vice versa
that that's good to know that,
but if you have any sort of
questioning tech is, is somewhat
unique in the world of work.
And that is very common and not
at all judged to do like
year or two years stints. So you
can sort of do some
stuff first and sort of build up
a bit of a resume and build
up a bit of an experience cash
and be like, okay, I,
now I kind of know what I like
and saying, then you Target.
Yeah.
Bekah: thought about that. That
idea that it's normal to
move from place place after
Bryan: Yeah, especially. Yeah.
You know, once you get
to really senior level, just
start rising to like
director VP C-suite stuff. Now
it becomes more like, well,
we expect you to be stable.
You're here as a leader, but
when you're in the junior C made
an even early senior
levels, it's sort of like,
you're just a gun for hire
in most of these places. So it's
not judged
during usual if you're sort of
jumping around.
Um, you know, I think the only
mark I ever see is sometimes
people like I'd like to see at
least a year, you know,
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: so they can at least
stick around for a couple
of projects and, you know, see
some things through to
production before they move on.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. So,
okay.
So kind of like along those
lines, do you ever hit
that burnout point though? Like,
I feel like
there's gotta be a point. It may
be, it's not hour
spent, but the just not there.
And you're like, why am
I doing this anymore? Or have
you just always
found that like, okay, I've got
momentum, that's
carrying me forward. And I'm
excited about this.
Bryan: Yeah. don't know if this
is
unusual, my suspicion as it is,
but for some reason
I do have like bottomless energy
and always have, so
I've never really experienced
burnout in the classic way.
People describe burnout. I will
say I've experienced
things, similar burnout, and
it's almost always oriented
around how excited I am when
things are going on.
know, we've talked about this in
other forums.
I'm a, I'm a ADHD even diagnosed
as a child.
And so I have that sort of like
dopamine fixation of like,
I need something to me in. If
you can latch that,
then I'll go 24, 7, 365 at full
speed all the time.
And I, and I can just. Sustain
that energy.
Uh, as soon as I start to lose
that though, I start to
lose the ability to sort of
maintain that just because.
Connection problem, my brain.
And so most times when I've
experienced it, it usually just
means I'm ready to move on.
Like the company I'm at is no
longer at a place where
it's really engaging me. And I'm
sort of starting to
work on side projects more than
I'm working on my main project.
And, um, and, uh, and I'm ready
for the next big challenge.
So it's, it hasn't happened to
me much in my career with
a few times it's happened.
That's been the result.
It's like, okay, it's time for a
next big thing
that's going to excite me.
Dan: When you're, you know, um,
I have similar, you know, like
a, a similar situation going on.
Yeah.
Um, but the, my question was,
um, you know, knowing that about
yourself, did that enter in the,
your decision making process
about starting a company now? So
now you're like, you know,
a co-founder of a company and
maybe it feels like you might
be a little less like able to.
Hop out, uh, you know,
you know what I mean? And I was
wondering if I was
wondering if that entered in
when you're thinking about it.
And also like, now that you're,
how long has, how long, I'm
sorry, how long has, uh,
Bryan: uh,
Dan: and
Bryan: at Aiera uh, we're about
three half years
Dan: three interviews? Yeah. So
like two parts of
that question, I guess, you
know, before, when
you're thinking about it. And
then now, you know, now
does that thought ever like
creep up or, you know, like
how would you like approach that
in this situation?
Cause you're not any more a gun
for hire or whatever.
Bryan: yeah, for sure. It
definitely changes that
capacity too, if I ever did feel
so to like the urge to
like move on, it would be
considerably harder, but th
there's sort of a caveat to that
is which is, this is my thing.
And so like, I can kind of the
direction, um, and you know,
It's, it allows me to be more
flexible than I'd be able to
be in more traditional roles.
And so there are still
of course, boundaries
self-imposed boundaries for
like what the business is. We
can't pivot all the time and
we have investors and you have
to make good smart decisions
about how to run the business.
Um, but you know, My
ability to contribute to the
business has been able to
be as flexible as necessary,
both for my own ability to
contribute and my ability to
sort of empower the team
to, to what they need to do. And
so, know, my
role has shifted over time from
being like.
Primary full-time ML engineer
working on a prediction product
being mostly a sales tool and
business developer to moving
back into like where the R and D
style role working on, uh,
NL projects that are on the, on
the front burner of demand,
but are important for like
long-term value generation.
And so being able to sort of
like set my own vision and sort
of work with the team, opposed
to like, here's your project,
you're working on X and. As well
as sort of influenced,
I think that balance a little
bit, all that being
said is worth caveating. That,
and this is somewhat
funny to admit, almost all of my
career from college
to now has had a remarkably
small amount of planning.
It's mostly just been like, Hey,
that's exciting.
Hey, that's interesting. And
just sort of
like moving w where
Bekah: We're all method, right?
Bryan: exactly.
Dan: That also sounds very
familiar to me.
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: For sure. And so I, I
confess to say
that I think very little of that
was pre thought like,
oh, I should be careful here.
This is a start up.
You know, it was just more like
Dan: Totally.
Bryan: this now. This is
exciting.
Dan: Yeah. no, I there's a lot
in like,
you know, I I've, I don't, it
start-ups, but I've been
just independent, you know, my,
my whole career as well,
you know, and I think that I
find that a lot of people, um,
especially people with ADHD that
are been in the industry
for a long time, I, I think are
gravitate towards these sort
of situations where there's
yeah, in control a little
bit more of their own, uh, their
own destiny, you know?
Bryan: Yeah, A little more, you
just a little
bit more in control of how you
can direct your injury.
Dan: absolutely. I think that's
right.
It's really important cool.
Bekah: Oh, sorry. I, So did you
decide, like
you were ready to start your own
thing or was that, I
mean, I imagine that can't be
really impulsive, right?
There's gotta be some thought
process.
You on a co-founder.
Dan: Yeah.
Bryan: well, th a there's,
there's genuinely kind of
two answers to that actually.
Um, the process by how moved
into and out of startups of my
own creation, I've,
I've, I've attempted or
successfully created my own
startup, like four times. Um,
uh, I'd say two
of those were genuine successes
of some capacity.
Every one of them kind of evolve
the same way, including
Aiera which is that I've never
really been anywhere.
That wasn't my company where I
wasn't working
on lots of side projects. I
just, I'm the type that
can't really sit still. So when
I'm, when I'm done
the work for the day and I'm
home and I'm working on
something else and scaling
effect is when is sort of in
my mind, when am I spending.
When  am I almost doing two
jobs?
Like when does it move from like
a 10 hour a week?
Like having fun side project to
like, this is a thing, and
it's really showing traction and
there's excitement around it.
You know, um, building Aiera um,
there was a good
six month period where I was
still in my other job.
but Aiera was consuming a lot of
time.
Like I was doing like sales runs
and going to
New York and pitching. And like,
it was, it was a
meaningful thing that I had
built entirely on the side.
Uh, and so there is, there is a
decision point
where you're like, I could
probably just do this now.
Um, but that does genuinely just
kind of appear like
the, for me, it's always been
just like, there's literally
a day where I'm like, I should
just be doing this.
This is really what I'm enjoying
doing the rest of
the thing, you just paying bills
and adding stuff to
the bottom, bottom line. And so
it's time to shift with
the process of getting there is
very organic for me, at
least like I've just always got
another thing going that
I'm excited about and want to
see if it goes somewhere.
And most of them, peter out,
most of them don't go anywhere,
but you just keep trying stuff
and number I've probablty
started projects of some kind
that I thought might go
somewhere 20 twenty-five times.
And most of them don't
know where they just, they just
sort of languish.
And then I closed them down
after awhile, but
Dan: Um, do you have any. About,
like how to, how
to consider those projects that,
uh, you know,
that don't go anywhere. I I've,
I've heard and also
experienced, you know, some like
people expressing, you know,
shame or whatever about, you
know, some side project they
wouldn't know, or, you know,
it's, it's still there and it's,
you know, like that sort of
thing, you know, like, and, and
you seem, I'm asking because you
seem like very comfortable
and, and, you know, feel good
about it, about the situation.
You know what I mean? I was
like, wondering
how you approach that, like, uh,
like the.
Um, you know, I think people
sometimes avoid starting
side projects because they don't
want to make something
that is going to fail or, you
know, for instance,
Bryan: I mean, The, the, the
unfortunate
answer is some of it. I don't
know how to, to
answer other than just like,
don't be shameful.
I know that it's a terrible
thing to say.
It's like telling somebody don't
be sad, you know, but
like, this is an element of that
where I've just never
really felt a problem with that.
I liked to do stuff.
And when things don't work out,
I'm very failure comfortable, I
guess is the way I describe it.
Like
Dan: Yeah.
Bryan: things don't, I, in fact,
I almost have this, um,
it might be almost a negative. I
haven't quite decided,
uh, in my own self analysis, but
like when things
don't work out, I'm really
comfortable going like, okay.
And then never think about it
it's like, I can just
completely move on once. I've
decided that something's
not going to work and like right
up until that point,
I will be doing like 110% to try
to make something work.
And it's like this weird thing I
can do where I'm
just like, okay, I've decided it
won't work.
And I move on,
Dan: that.
Bryan: in terms of like, but
other than that potentially.
Uh, advice, uh, the, the more
practical advice that.
we give is really just around
like perception thing.
Um, the only reason I could
imagine to feel a problem
with it is you're fearful of
like outside perception.
Like, does it look like I'm a
failure?
I guess it could be internal
Dan: Oh yeah, that's
Bryan: but I, now I'm kind of
projecting a
Bekah: me out on that. Bryan. I
feel like personally
attacked right now. No, I don't
feel like that. it.
Bryan: So it's like, so if it's
an external validation
concern, uh, and I dunno if this
is helpful or not,
but in general, I would say
nobody's going to judge you
for that a hundred percent. And
anyone, anyone who might
is somebody who's weirdly
thinking about things in
a way I can't wrap my head
around, I don't monitor,
people's GitHub accounts.
They're like, oh, they
deleted Something's weird going
on there.
Like nobody cares. This is not a
thing. So like, you
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: from, from a hire, from
like an employer perspective,
I like seeing people that are
tinkering and toying and
creative, like ultimately we're
in a field that is a
very mental, creative field. I
want to see people
who are sort of like. Out there
willing to take
chances willing to experiment.
You know, it's a fundamental
basis of experimentation is lots
of your experiments,
prove your hypothesis wrong.
Like that's what
you're looking for. They all
just proved them. Right.
Then they wouldn't, you know,
something's not right there. So
Bekah: I love that. And I want
to
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: a minute just to make
sure that we emphasize that.
So, you know, that idea of loss
projects can be
where you can testify. Like,
look, I am
trying new things. I am getting
creative.
I want to push myself beyond
these things.
And I know when it's time to
stop and move
on to the next thing. And that's
a great way to
reframe those experiences.
Bryan: it's also worth saying
that like, there's also nothing
wrong with, with having ideas.
That linger, like if you're
working on something, but it
doesn't yet have sort
of like a clear niche and you're
not taking off, but
you're not ready to call it.
That's fine too.
Can just exist out there. I've
done a small
handful of those. I got, I'll
give you a silly one.
out there anymore, but I, uh,
years and years and years
ago back in 2007, eight God,
long time ago at this point.
Back in my PhD days, I wrote a
framework and PHP called helium.
Uh, you know, mean, I'm
egotistical uh, it was, it
was just the standard MVC style
framework, but I spent
a ton of time, like just sort of
like pouring  in there.
Um, I had no idea what it was
for.
I just like did it to do it. Um,
and so I put a website up
with it, through up a GitHub and
I was, uh, I might not
have been GitHub back then. It
was SourceForge
SourceForge and, uh, And it was
just sort of like, Okay.
here's, here's the thing I
built. Maybe it'll be
something interesting. Um, back
then there were
companies that were sort of
cropping up that was just
selling like frameworks as back
in the very early Django days.
Um, you know, the early, um, oh,
what was that PHP site anyway?
Um, but I didn't know what I was
gonna do with it.
So like for, for a solid like
five, six years, it was just
a thing that existed that update
a year when I got the
motivation and then finally. I
think I'm the only one
that's ever used this. This it's
just my
thing basically. And I just
didn't feel
like maintaining it as I took it
down.
And that that's fine. It's just
a, it was a
toy that I was wanting to see if
it went somewhere.
It didn't and that's okay.
Bekah: Yeah, I really love that.
I think so this, this is going
to be a little bit of a tangent,
but, um, there was, uh, when
I was first starting learning
how to code, I went to this,
um, conference online and one of
the talks was about how to
monetize your kids hobbeys. And
I was like super kind
of grossed out by that. Like,
Hey, why don't we
just let kids have fun? But then
as we move into
adulthood, like that mentality,
I think that that
exemplifies what the mentality
of adulthood is, right?
Like if you have a hobby, you
better be
making money off of it. Right.
And like, why not just try some
things out and see what happens
with it, or have fun with it
and not put all this pressure on
yourself to be founder or to
build the new and best thing.
Like you don't have do that
thing in all of your projects.
Like sometimes it's just
worth pursuing to see like what
comes out of it,
Bryan: It's sort of, it's sort
of weird, like, In my
experience, this is just
anecdotal, but in my experience,
the vast majority of successful
founders, really aren't people
that set out to be founders.
They're just people
that do stuff. It just like a do
stuff.
Just constantly doing stuff.
Bekah: The ADHD people. people
Bryan: all the ADHD people. And
it's just like, I
just need, I need, I need
something in front of my face.
That's taking up my, you know,
my attention and,
uh, and they just end up, like I
said, they fall into
something lucrative, like. This
is a thing.
We have a lot of users. Now,
this is, this is cool.
And you can sort of lean into it
and sort, it takes off.
Um, and that's Okay. Like, it's,
I agree with you.
Like, it doesn't have to be
like, oh, how can I make money?
Bekah: Okay.
Bryan: I, you know, like, how
can I make money right now?
What can I do to convert this? I
mean, obviously money's
important part of life and your
job and all that,
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: you're, you're focusing
really just being
more on doing things and, and I
think it can be...
even that's a little bit, want
to make sure I'm
not being disingenuous. Cause
like I'm always
wanting to found a company. I'm
an entrepreneur mindset.
It's more just like, how do
those two mix together?
My mindset is that, yes. I like
being entrepreneurial
and I wanna, I wanna take things
somewhere, but it's
like, I'm not going to a legal
pad and going like,
okay, my next business idea. You
know, it's just, more
like in the back of my head, I
know that's where I might
take everything eventually. Like
that's what I'm tinkering.
But in the moment I'm just
tinkering and then
we'll see what lands
Bekah: I've talked to a number
of people who are in like the
more senior portion of their
career in the past couple
of months have just felt. You
know, they've hit what
we often refer to as burnout.
And I've, I've said like,
you know, I think your bored,
like this was interesting
when you got started and I see
it all the time.
Like it is interesting and you
push forward and
you do these new things. And
then at some point.
You stopped doing all of the new
things, right.
It gets a little bit slower and
you're working
on the same things. then it
just, it becomes hard
like in, in honestly, like it's,
it's a place where a lot
of people experienced mental
health issues where they start
to become depressed because they
don't have that same
like or like that momentum for
that keeps them going.
And then it just kind of like.
Oh, that thing that you've
invested so much time in, that's
given you energy.
It's not like sucking all of
that energy out and like,
Hey, it's time to move on. Like,
whether you don't have to
find the perfect project, but
find something that's better
than what you're doing.
Bryan: Totally. Yeah. And, and
you can, you know,
I always feel like a little bit,
I, I'm not calling anyone
specifically, but I hear a lot
of things when I, when I
go to younger engineer forums
and discussion points of like,
there's a lot of focus on.
Trying to plan your career.
That makes sense. It's like,
what's the
next thing I should do. I'm
looking at all this options,
you know, and if that's your
personality type, that's great.
I'm not gonna discourage anyone
to do what works for them.
But in general, I'd say that
there's nothing wrong too,
with quite literally being just
like a rock in a pond, like.
If you see something cool, go
for it. Like this.
There's really no like, oh, is
this a bad career decision?
I don't know, do it anyway.
know, if you're, if you're
working at a company it's not,
not making you
thrilled and you hear what a
startup that just doing
something that intrigued you.
Pursue it, maybe it
doesn't go anywhere. Maybe you
don't get the job.
Maybe you get an offer. It's not
good enough, but
always be willing to take
chances and just yourself out
there and dive into things. I
think that's the only way
to, like you said, avoid that
burnout where you don't feel
like you're stuck to a thing.
You can always move
anytime you need to.
Bekah: Do you ever find that? I
mean, maybe personally, and
as a person that like hires
people for the company that
you have someone on the team, or
you've been in a situation
where it's very exciting
initially, then very quickly
they hit that like, oh actually,
maybe this is not for me.
and then what, what do you do in
that situation?
Or, or what advice would you
give.
Bryan: um, well, so there's
probably, there's probably two
answers to that, what advice
would I give as the employer
trying to retain my talent? I
would, I would probably
encourage them to pick up new
projects internally that they
might find more exciting. You
know, what things can,
can we put them on that gets if
the motor moving.
From a mentor perspective, not
outside there.
I'd say that there's nothing
wrong with making
that realization quick and
starting to look right away.
done that before. I've had, I
have at
least one, maybe two. I'm trying
to really think
through my career now, but I
know I had at least one like
six months didn't I'm like
resume where I was like nah
this isn't, I'm not enjoying
this at all it's time to move.
And I just really looked around
and there's
nothing wrong with that. I think
if you did that
repeatedly, like four or five,
six times in a row after a
while, it starts to look funny,
but one or two or even three in
a career happens it's normal.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean, that's such
good advice.
Like, oh, we find so many people
in that position all
of the time trying to figure out
what they're doing.
And it's a lot of, it's the hang
up on what it's
gonna look like a resume.
Bryan: Yeah. And, and, and like,
anything
else I'd say that it's sort of,
it's sort of shitty to make
this kind of advice, but like,
there does come a point where
things like that get weird.
Like, like I said,
if it was six of
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: as an, employer I might
go, oh, they haven't
a one, one year stint in the
last, you know, six jobs.
That's a little weird, but like
there's no magic number where
it's like, oh, four is too much.
Like, it's, it's really just.
It's really just an eyeball test
of like, how does it look?
And in general, I'd say a few of
those is not a problem that they
were bothered me as an employer.
If I see like one or two
of those, um, I might ask a
question in the interview, just
be like, Hey, I noticed, you
know, you had a, you know, six
months didn't, you know, what
happened there all I'm ever
looking for is just like, Yeah.
it just wasn't, you know,
it wasn't the right fit. The
projects weren't as
exciting as I thought. And we
parted ways,
amicably that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
It was like, as long as they
don't get the, oh yeah, I hated
my boss kind of answer then.
Bekah: What if they do hate
their boss, what does they have?
A terrible boss.
Bryan: Well, has nothing to do
what we've been talking about,
Bekah: Okay.
Bryan: like random career
advice. Never say that even if
it's
true, cause nobody cares and
all, it just makes it look
like the wrong answer, even if
it was the right answer.
And I can't verify it as an
employer, so it's always
like, oh, to hear that one. just
lie to me as an employer.
Just, say it was of,
Bekah: What if you don't have a
good lying face?
Bryan: Well, I guess that's
tougher.
Bekah: Turn camera off. I'm
sorry. I'm having issues
with my camera. it was totally
fine.
Bryan: I'll answer this
question.
Bekah: I feel like you have a
really good gut
instinct for things. Do you,
would you
agree with that?
Bryan: I like to think I do Who
knows how true that is,
but, um, yeah, I think so.
Bekah: And what do you think. I
feel like this is
a silly question. Can you
develop a gut instinct?
Bryan: Um, I actually think,
yes. Um, I, I just don't
know how to teach it. I
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: that you can, you can
develop something you kinda
have to develop on your own it's
cause it kind of also
depends what we're talking about
by gut instincts.
So there's sort of a couple of
different
things that play in that. So
like I have a pretty good
read for people in general. I
think, um, and that's,
that's, it comes with extreme
risk for bias.
So I always try to
Bekah: Yeah,
Bryan: it by looping and lots of
other people.
I'm never the final arbiter of
this kind of stuff, unless
it's universally a positive,
like sometimes I'll I have in
the past taking a unilateral,
like positive decision, like
I'm going to hire this person
because I think they're great.
Um, I, I very rarely, almost
never have taken unilateral.
I'm not hiring this person
because I don't like them.
Like, I always try to make sure
that I'm mixing in
people to sort of check me on
those kinds of things.
Um, but separating that, that
acknowledged concern for bias.
I do think I have a generally a
good impression of people
and sort of what I think they
can do or, or excited to do.
You know how they'll fit in
certain roles.
Um, there's also like gut
feeling for just general
things like career things. Does
this company look exciting?
Do I think that the leadership
that I am talking to actually
sounds good or bad, and guess it
has a little bit fits into
the people analysis, but, um,
it's like parallel versus
directly in the same line. Um,
and so a lot of that I think
just comes from experience. Like
you can have a decent,
like, general intuition for it,
but most of it you just learned.
I've talked to 20 companies in
my career, and these are
the things I keep seeing in
companies that burn out later.
And these are the companies that
keep seeing in
companies who I remember and
have good relationships
with the founders with. And you
sort of like start
to develop that checklist of
like what you're looking
for when you're talking to
potential employers or you're
talking to potential employees.
Dan: No.
Bekah: is that, that Bryan
Healey book coming
out that specific one.
Bryan: Yeah. So ironically, um,
it, it probably needs
massively updating. So I
actually, I wrote like
I self published it kind of
silly but it was basically
just the collection of old
essays on this, these kinds of
topics, like years ago, that was
like the kind of crap I
see in startups repeatedly. And
I find interesting.
Um, and I I've always wanted to
do one.
on like people too, but that
one's also a little bit.
Riskier.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: No, we got to come up with
a pseudonym for you for
publishing. So that'll be a
Right. Ryan, Ryan feely.
Bryan: feely.
Dan: I don't know.
Bryan: It's a name. It's not a
football player.
Oh man. He's like my, uh,
ultimate ego.
Dan: I'm still thinking about
the helium named
for that PHP thing is amazing.
Bryan: as I ran through, that
was my nickname.
All through grade school was
always Yeah.
That's where it came from.
Bekah: That was fantastic. Um,
okay.
So, so through all of this and
what you're working on
at Aiera, you're doing a lot of
machine learning stuff.
And so you know, there's been a
lot of advancements,
I guess, over the past, even
couple of years.
And like, how does that, you
think that like, that's part
of what's kept you interested?
Like it keeps growing,
it keeps changing. It's a fun
field to be in.
And like, but also it's
overwhelming.
Cause there's so many changes.
So how do you balance that?
Like, this is cool versus like
a, I don't even
know where to start.
Bryan: So machine learning is my
favorite field of any
career I've ever been near
specifically because it's just.
Lunatically fast-paced like tech
in general is fast paced.
Machine learning is insane. I
can't even, actually,
uh, I had the, um, a friend of
mine talk about it.
Like we shouldn't talk about
machine learning
engineers, like wine vintages,
like, oh, that's a 2007
machine learning engineer. know,
you know,
Keras and because. Rapidly you
lose your,
you lose yourself. Like, oh, I
haven't worked
in, in Keras in five years.
What's it  working on? Oh my
God.
Look at all this stuff. You
know, they come with all
these prebuilt models now. Like
everything's just always
moving at such a pace that yes,
it keeps it super exciting.
a little stressful, like always
think trying to stay
on the cutting edge and learning
new things and
keeping up on what's new. Yeah.
But I think, I think you're
right in that it, it hits that
side of the brain.
That's like, I'm never bored.
There's always something kind
of neat going on in this space.
Um, and yeah, so I'd say that's,
that's pretty much the gist of
there and it's sort of funny.
It also fits into the same
medium that tech in general
kind of fits for me, is, um, I'm
trying think how to phrase
this, but like learning makes me
feel this especially, but really
all of tech is that it's not
really an industry in a classic
Bekah: Hmm
Bryan: It's like it's just there
in everything, you
know, there's, there's
healthcare tech, there's legal
tech, there's finance tech,
there's, it just, it fits into
every vertical pretty much. And
so not like I just sit
and code for the sake of code.
I'm always serving an
industry of some kind. Uh, and
I, so I can go into
any of these and sort of play,
you know, I, in my career, I
have worked in health tech. I've
worked in consumer tech,
I've worked in retail, I've
worked in voice assistance.
I've worked in FinTech and I've
worked in travel and, and
actually more and more, like,
you just always get to sort of
play in these different spaces.
And so both tech and machine
learning, especially allow you
to sort of like never get
bored in a single space where
you just like, I just know
this head to toe and it's not
driving the excitement anymore.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. You
know, I've always
felt the same way. It's, you
know, it's another,
another bonus of either moving,
moving jobs or, you know, being
independent or all that stuff is
like you get into a different
job and all of a sudden it's a
whole new domain to learn.
Right. And you don't have to,
like, I don't know.
I, we, we work on, um, I don't
know, gas pressure valve, a
company that makes those right.
But I'm like writing
JavaScript and stuff, you know,
but at the same time,
I know a whole lot about gas
pressure that I didn't before.
And that sounds like I wouldn't
like say I'm going to, I'm
going to do like chain. Yeah,
exactly.
Like, that's what I mean. It's
like you get to
nerd out about, um, about
something new all the time.
Uh, aside from the technology
that you're
actually like building.
Bryan: And to your point,
without having to make
the commitment being
Dan: Right, right.
Bryan: I have to change careers
to learn
Dan: Right, right, right,
Bryan: you
Dan: right. Yeah. No, no. I'm
not going back to school and
becoming, you know, some sort of
mechanical engineer and learning
about gas lines and stuff. It,
you know, but there is a
certain amount of it that I have
to learn just to do a good job,
you know, and same, I'm sure at
the same as with every single
industry that you're in, it's
like, it's just a new, a new
puzzle to like, learn about.
Bekah: Well, I think it's
interesting too, because a
lot of early career people or
people who are coming into
tech, the thing that you hear
is, well, do you enjoy front
end or do you enjoy backend?
Which is really hard to tell
because you've been working on
these very basic understandings
of all of the things. And so I
don't think
it gives a really good. Um,
amount of experience,
but you might really enjoy
front-end dev in one
portion of an industry. Like
maybe you love end dev
in healthcare stuff, you hate
front dev in another
sector of the industry. And when
I.
I've never really thought about
it broken down, but I
think like, even going back to
Jessi's podcasts from
the beginning of the season
where she talked about that
guy who was talking about the
sandwich shop or deli, right.
Like he was interested in the
deli.
And so he built something, Jessi
was interested in chess.
And so she framed everything
along those lines.
And so in the same way, if. you
feel bored in whatever
industry you're working in, but
you like front-end
dev or you want to give it a
try, then maybe just
try a different industry. And
that might be
more exciting to you.
Bryan: For sure. absolutely. I
mean, I think there's
a lot of, try to think how to
phrase this.
Like, I feel like. I, I want to
say this
for career changes. This is
probably even
true for just young people,
people in college.
There's a, there's like a lot of
this, I think,
pressure to understand what you
want to do and sort of
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: into it. And so there's
like this of like
evaluating things like, oh, do I
like front end or like back end?
Do I like machine learning to
like, to.
And my, my generalized advice in
my career as it's progressed
has always been like, do that.
Just kind of do stuff I know
that sounds so weird, but like,
Bekah: Yes, sir.
Bryan: one of the few industries
where you can do that.
for the first several years of
my career, I
was a front end engineer. Anyone
who's seen things.
I created know that that was a
bad decision.
Dan: Um,
Bryan: front end skills
whatsoever.
I can't design anything. And yet
there are three ish
websites world that I designed.
God help them.
Uh, you can still find them on
archive.org if you want to.
it's like, that's okay. Like I
fiddled in a space.
I even got to get paid for it.
And then I was like, this
is really not going to work real
for me in the
long-term it should, I should do
something else.
And I would experiment with data
science.
Uh, I would experiment with
backend projects and
server infrastructure and. Doing
things.
Uh, it's a big reason why I'm a
big fan of early engineers
being full stack, just do stuff
like willing to make APIs and
front end designs and play, you
know, an API development
and database architecture. And,
you know, it's also why
I kind of advocate for young
people, try a start up or
two, because you're going to be
in a space where that
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: as a forcing function,
like you're one of five people
you're going to do everything.
just have to.
Dan: Yeah, I totally agree with
that.
And like, I'm glad you said that
because it's.
It's the kind of advice I've
wanted to give as well.
And I struggled giving it, I
took it like putting it
into, into like phrasing it.
Well, you know, but that like
just stop worrying and just,
just do the thing or whatever,
you know, like, uh, you know,
jump in and, and build.
Bryan: And I mean, I'll also,
I'll even admit, I mean,
just for the sake of devil's
advocate and B can be, you know,
admitting to the, the risks
there's downsides to that too.
There's not a lot of like, um,
there's not a
lot of good mentorship in tech
either because
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: Like, there's, there's
not a lot of like, um, what's
the word I'm looking for? Um,
There's not a lot of
like apprenticeship paths in
tech where you can,
like, want to try this. I'm
gonna spend two
years working with people and
learning.
It's more like, here's the
thing. Good luck. You know,
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: a lot of that in tech and
that can be a negative,
but I, you know, just because of
my nature, I like to spin
that as a positive and be like,
yes, that can be stressful
and it can have its downsides,
but it also means that.
And have the flexibility to
learn at your pace, to learn on
your own, which is always fun.
And it's rewarding when
you pull things off and it means
that you are never get
yourself stuck in a path. You're
like, crap, I've spent
five years on this thing. I
don't like now, what do I do?
I can't just pivot now. Yeah.
You can just keep moving
until you find things you like
and as an industry
that uniquely affords that
without much downside risk.
Okay.
Dan: Yeah, all of that. It, and
it's, it's so true.
And I wanted to call it that
advice of, um, that
you dropped a minute ago. Having
a, when you're early
career like joining a small
team, you know, where you're
going to get that, there's
probably going to be a little
more pressure on you and maybe a
little less, you know,
structure, uh, to support you,
maybe, you know, but the, but
the, the, the bonuses of it are
so are so large, right?
And then you get the exposure
across like a whole, a whole,
like a large amount of space.
Right.
And you're going to end up,
like, maybe you're gonna end
up doing some database work and
also some front end,
you know, react to worker. PHP
or whatever it is, you know,
like whatever they need, right.
Because that's what they need.
And, um, if you, at least, if
you can trust the organization
to be okay with you learning on
the job, you know, then
like that's the best way to,
that's the best way to
get all of the experiences. I
think that's great advice.
Bryan: And it's sort of like,
there's sort of an interesting
identity to that that has an
element of risk to it.
I'll admit like, obviously it
sucks when you fail and
that happens sometimes and I'll
always coach people
to be like, that's okay. It
really is. I promise, know,
you used to learn. The same
token by taking the
risk where you might fail those
times where you do get thrown in
the deep end, thrash around and
learn to swim, feel like heaven.
It's like, I conquered this.
This is my thing.
Look what I just did. That's
that's a great feeling.
And there's not many places
where you get to
experience that so often.
Dan: I love that. And yeah, that
is the thing that
happens all the time in tech.
It, it, you know, it's small
ways in big ways, you know? Even
just squashing that bug
that was driving you crazy for a
hours or whatever, a couple
of days, you know, that feeling,
uh, vanquishing
it, you know, it's like such a,
such a good feeling.
And, uh, you know, that can
scale all the way up to career
challenges and all that stuff. I
love that.
Bryan: Yup. For sure.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think that's
one
of the biggest takeaways that,
that anybody can have
from what they're doing,
especially early career people.
There's just this, focus on
failure for whatever
reason, you know? Really
flipping it on its head.
It's not a failure. So what is
it like, how else can
you reframe how you're thinking
about this job experience?
What have you gained from this?
And really like, kind of
addressing like, okay, well, you
know, like maybe it's just,
I learned where my limits are. I
learned that I will not let
treat me like this in a job
situation, it's I learned that
should ask for help sooner. Or,
you know, anything, you
know, I I've, but thinking about
what you've learned in
doing that self evaluation is
not something that we talk
about often, but I think that it
can help combat a lot of
the problems that we see with
early career people who leave
the field, even people who are
interviewing, right, because.
It's really hard to interview.
If you are interviewing
for junior level position,
there's a lot of people
interviewing for junior level
positions right now.
And to get turned down, it's not
a failure.
about what you've learned, about
how you can take that
moving forward and, keep using
that, you know, build on that.
Well, this has been a really
great conversation, Bryan.
Um, but we are just about out of
time.
So is there any last tips that
you have for our listeners,
about career or startup life?
Bryan: Oh, boy. I mean, that's
dangerous.
I could probably talk forever. I
mean, I guess the last tip
I'll sort of piggyback on
something you were just saying.
I think it's worth addressing,
I've said it before in different
contexts, but I'll say it again,
which is like, especially
with things like interviewing.
Remember that that's
its own skill. And, and, and to
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: that a little further,
most of the things in this
space are their own skills. And
it's almost a problem that
we'd lump them in with the word
tech it's like saying medicine.
Like a surgeon is very different
from nurses, very different.
Like th there's a series of
skills in this space.
And so to your point, struggling
with any one of those at any one
time, even, you know, getting
better at it than struggling.
Again, none of this really means
anything about you as a
person doesn't mean anything
about your career path.
It just it's its own skill that
might need, um, a little
workout once in awhile, like
interviewing is its own skill.
It's a hard skill. You might get
good at it.
And then it might go five, six
years before
you're interviewing again. And
now you're rusty.
Like that's also fine.
Bekah: Yeah.
Bryan: just always give yourself
grace in this space
of being like, not failing.
You're just sort of like
working muscles as you go. And
sometimes those muscles
take longer to develop. you
develop them and
let them atrophy. That's also
fine.
You can redevelop them, like
just let yourself grow
at your own pace and just be
willing to, your point.
Just take lessons from things
that don't work
out and keep moving.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome. And
for those of you
who don't know, Bryan is very,
very strong as well.
so I'm going to keep going with
this, this analogy here, because
I think like there's some days
you go to the gym, right.
And you can lift that heavy
weight.
And two days later you go back
there and you
can't lift it, you know, what,
what has happened. Right.
Bryan: yeah.
Bekah: know, A number of
conditions that can happen that
you just can't, you can't hit it
that day, even though it
was easy two days ago, that's
like, it's exactly what you're
saying about interviewing.
Bryan: Totally. And I mean, I'll
even
extend that further to
something, which I really.
I I've, intense ADHD. So my
focus is all
over the place. There are some
days where
I'm walked in and I'm writing
code and working
and managing, and everything is
sort of running smooth.
And then I'll have, I'll have
two week long stretches where
I'm just kind of like feel a
little bit, you know, and
Bekah: the listeners, Bryan,
Bryan is sitting
there with his hand
Bryan: just
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: in his hand, just living
around.
Bryan: sort of like looking into
space and it's like, and it's.
I don't know why I have always
been able to all the
way back to school days I'm
always been able to just
be comfortable with that.
Everyone else I've had
this very sort of, um, be a
little vulgar for a moment.
I always, I always joke that I
have a very Boston  f
you attitude about life. Like
worry about my thing.
You worry about your thing.
We're all gonna be fine.
You know? And so I've always
been very comfortable with the
fact that like, that's, that
happens to me sometimes.
And it's like, well, the next
two weeks are going to be
some   and I'm just going
to drink some coffee
and, and try to muddle through.
But I know a lot of
people struggle with that. And
so like my advice generally,
Try as best you can, whether
that's through your own self
coaching, whether that's to
outside mentorship or even
therapy or whatever things
needed to get you there to
like, be comfortable with your
own unique way of managing
yourself and your life. Not
everybody is going
to be in the same boat um, and
that's okay.
And you just sort of like learn
strategies and learn methods
to sort of do your own thing.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely such
great advice, Bryan, this has
been a great conversation. And
anyone has not met Bryan,
you're missing out because Bryan
always has advice
and hot takes for days. So, very
much have
enjoyed this conversation. Thank
you so much for
being here with us today.
Dan: Bryan
Bryan: It was a lot of fun.
Bekah: All right, well, we'll
talk to you soon. Bye.
Bryan: Sounds good. Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by
Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot Weigel,
and was edited by Andy Bonjour
at GoodDay Communications. If
you have questions
or comments, you can hit us up
on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
sign up for our newsletter,
check out any of our other
resources on our website
at virtualcoffee.io. And of
course join us for our
Virtual Coffee Chats every
Tuesday at 9: 00 am Eastern and
Thursday at 12:00 pm Eastern
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure
to leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and
we'll see you next week!