Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season four, episode seven of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you here with me today, is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today, we had
a great time hanging out with
Jessica Wilkins. Jessica is a
self-taught developer and staff
author for the freeCodeCamp news
publication. Jessica talked about
how to get started with tech
writing, how to differentiate
between constructive criticism
and negative feedback. And how to
avoid things like gatekeeping in
your tech writing by eliminating
assumptions about your audience.
And avoiding terms. Uh, like
"it's so easy" and "just do
this." Uh, she gave some tips,
like adding a prerequisites to
your posts or, uh, other
resources. Um, Basically, um,
Outlined her entire process for
all of her tech writing that she
does. And, uh, she does a lot of
it and it's all pretty awesome.
Um it was a really great
conversation and i know you were
going to enjoy it
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We hope
you enjoy this episode. My name
is Bekah. I am a front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio, and my favorite childhood
movie was Beauty and the Beast.
Dan: That's a good one. Hi, my
name is Dan. I am a front end
developer from Cleveland, Ohio.
And, um, yeah, my, my favorite
movie is Star Wars. Um, I think
if I had to pick one, it would,
it would be Return of the Jedi.
Um, yeah. As, as a child, I
watched that. just, just a lot.
So it's easy choice for me.
Bekah: The solid choice.
Jessica: Sounds pretty good. Hi,
I am Jessica Wilkins and I am a
musician learning how to code. I
am also a technical writer for
freeCodeCamp News. my favorite
movie was actually the Toy Story
movies. And so the original one,
but all four of them are amazing.
Dan: Those are on big rotation at
our house with, with our kids.
Uh, we also enjoy them. They're
solid.
Jessica: I totally cried. When
Andy went to college, I bawled
like a little baby. I was like,
oh my gosh, he can't leave. And
then he was giving his toys to
the little girl. I'm like, I
mean, teary-eyed now.
Dan: Yes.
Jessica: ya know?
Dan: I actually tried to
discourage that. That's I started
three. I tried to actually
discourage Toy Story 3 just
because it. It's very good. It's
about it is emotionally, uh,
affecting
Jessica: Right,
Dan: absolutely.
Bekah: my oldest is 12 and he'll
look at me and be like, are you
crying? yes.
Jessica: It's very sad. We grew
up with Andy.
Dan: Dude, I entertainment. Like
it takes on a whole new slant
when, especially when you have
kids. Cause like I just find
myself being, you know, uh,
affected by this stuff in
different ways, you know? And
it's like, I don't it's matter.
It's cool.
Bekah: It's been wild rereading
novels. I read. As like a young
adult to my kids. I, because I
always young adult fiction and I
always loved the young adult
character. Right. And now as a
parent, when I read it, I with
the parents and the novels and
I'm like, oh, they don't
understand what they're doing to
their parents. So, yeah, it's
very different, lots of crying
and young adult novel reading.
Dan: Yeah. at some point I
realized it with Calvin and
Hobbes. I was a big Calvin and
Hobbes fan Growing up and found
myself recently, you know,
identifying much more with
parents.
Bekah: Um, welcome. Jessica is so
great to have you here with us
today, because we did a lunch and
learn recently with Jessica and
we'll put the link to that in the
show notes. And she did such a
good job about talking us through
writing and writing career. And
it is our monthly challenge this
month, every month we hold a
monthly challenge, in the
community is welcome to do it.
And this is. The one-year
anniversary of when we started
monthly challenges. And so it's
one of my favorites. It's the
blog writing challenge and it's
based off of NaNoWriMo national
novel writing month. And so
Jessica is just an amazing
writer. And we kicked off the
blogging challenge and our goal
was hit 50,000 words. That's
what, uh, as a community, that's
what it was last year. We didn't
quite make it. We almost made it,
this year the, today is Tuesday,
November 9th. We have already
have we, where are we at? We're
past halfway.
Jessica: I think we're at 27,000,
I think. Yeah.
Bekah: and largely in part due to
Jessica
Dan: Yep. Over well, over 28,000.
Yeah.
Jessica: Oh, cool.
Bekah: So extra happy to have you
here to talk about this challenge
with us. But before we jump into
that, we always like to get your
origin story and you have a
awesome one. So tell us a little
bit about how you got to this
point your career.
Jessica: Yeah. it's definitely
unique there. So I grew up in
Southern California. I grew up in
a town called Palm Springs, which
is like two hours south of Los
Angeles in California there. And,
uh, grew up with a single mom who
was a teacher. And so. Uh, I got
into a music pretty early at
seven, and then just kind of
stuck with it. And it pretty
early on, I decided I'm going to
be a professional musician. Uh,
and so I started with piano and
then I at 11 started learning the
oboe, which is like a woodwind
instrument. And I. At first
didn't really like it. Cause I
didn't sound that good at it,
Dan: Yeah.
Jessica: then I started to kind
of get into it. I was like, okay,
cool. So then I started doing
like festivals and private
lessons and all that fun stuff.
And I decided like 15, I'm going
to go, try to go to music school
or conservatory. And go down that
route and be a classical
professional musician. so, uh,
when I graduated from college or
from high school, I went on to
Eastman School of Music, which is
in Rochester, New York, uh, and
study there for four years on
oboe performance. And then I
graduated and went on to a
Master's at University of
Michigan, which is in Ann Arbor.
and then after that, I decided to
Southern California because the
cold was just not agreeing with
me. So after six years of really
cold weather, I was like, no hard
pass. Let's go back to Southern
California. So I came back and
decided that I wanted to start my
own sheet music company and run
that. And then also, uh, perform
and freelance and so. Uh, from
2015 to 2020, uh, all I did was
perform and record and run my
sheet music company and teach.
And so I was kind of busy with
all that fun stuff. And then 2020
happened and everything changed.
So for everybody, but me, it was
just okay, go home. And there's
no work for you. and I'm like
Great. So what am I supposed to
do now? So I just worked on the
business and try to keep that
going and afloat and changing
there, for a few months. But then
in June of 2020, um, you know, US
was going through a lot with
COVID and then race relations
with the George Floyd murder And
so a lot of people were talking
about diversity issues within
many industries, including
myself, right? My industry with
the classical world of operas and
orchestras, cause there's a huge
diversity problem, with, uh, with
black representation, especially.
And so people were asking me.
Yeah. Can you give me information
about composers I can learn about
so we can start to change. And I
decided there should be a
website. Like there should just
be one place where people can
find all this stuff. I, I was
like, well, maybe could build it.
I've never built anything. I've
never coded before, but Hey,
we've got all this time, so maybe
we'll learn and see what happens.
So that's how I got into
programming and been doing this
for about a year and a half now.
Yeah, so that's kind of my origin
story and how I got into, where
I'm at now.
Bekah: awesome. Does that site
still exist out there?
Jessica: So I created, um,
version one about six months into
my learning and it's called the
Black Excellence Music Project.
And I built that with HTML, CSS,
and Vanilla JavaScript. and then
I revisited it a few months ago,
um, over the summer of 2021
create a version two, which was
built with React and Tailwind
CSS, and has more artists and
more games and all of this fun
stuff. yeah, so this was always
like a passion project. And so I
got into tech I wanted to switch
careers. I thought initially in
June I was like, oh, this thing
will just blow over eventually.
And I go back to my old life and
yeah. Obviously not what
happened. I wildly miss,
understood how COVID works. I
totally thought this was just
going to be like a couple of
months and I was completely
wrong. So, but, and then I ended
up starting to get developer
work, uh, and that was kinda
cool. And then I started writing
for freeCodeCamp, which was also
kind of cool. and I was like,
well, maybe I could have a career
there. So yeah.
Bekah: That is so awesome. So,
um, that project is an open
source project, right?
Jessica: Yes. Yeah. Yeah. And so
it's available on my personal
GitHub, but it's completely open
source. It's a, anybody could
like in there and if they want to
contribute there, I'm pretty open
to that. So, yeah.
Bekah: Right. It is really
awesome. And again, those links
will be in the show notes I just
think seem like. Uh, so driven
and motivated from everything
that you've talked about your
career as a musician, you know,
at 15 years old, you decided that
you were going to do this thing,
and that's not an easy thing. So
you have this, um, I don't know,
Tenacity or, or something. How
would you kind of describe that,
that that's allowed you to go
through these different things
and accomplish so much.
Jessica: I think that's in large
part to both my mom and my
grandmother. And so both of them
were single parents. And so one
was by choice. my mom, uh, worked
as a teacher for many years and
then in her forties decided that
she wanted to adopt and have a
child. Um, and so, uh, she had me
when she was like 44 or 45. And
then with my grandmother, uh, she
was married, but it was
unfortunately an abusive
situation. So she had to get out
and get to safety and raise two
kids by herself and was also a
teacher. but then went on to, um,
you know, own land in certain
parts of California and just be
fiercely independent. so I just
kind of picked up on that, where
if they decided they were going
to do something, they just went
for it. Growing up with that type
of mindset and energy, it's like,
well, I guess That's just what we
do here. If you just want to go
do something. so when I
discovered my love for operas and
orchestra and this weird,
beautiful instrument of the oboe,
I was like, I want to go do that
I want to go achieve that. And so
I just went for it definitely
didn't think I was going to get
in to. The conservatory I was, it
ended up working out thankfully,
but leading up to it cause I got
four rejections and then the last
one was an exception into my
dream schools. So at first I was
like, well maybe I'll just start
going to college. I have four
rejections from other schools.
But then at the very end I was
accepted, uh, to Eastman. And
that was the last school I heard
back from. And I was like, okay,
cool. I guess we're going. And
we're going to my dream school.
So that worked out.
Dan: awesome. Oh, um, the oboe is
an interesting choice. What, uh,
w w do you have any reason why,
like, what made you like lean
towards the oboe, I know from,
you know, I, I know it's very
hard to learn and all of that
stuff. I was just curious about
that.
Jessica: so I didn't actually
choose it. Um,
Dan: Sure.
Jessica: I didn't choose it.
Yeah. um, I was learning piano in
elementary school, and then I
tried to pick up trumpet. That
definitely was not the right fit
for me. I couldn't really make
any type of sounds, but I wanted
to be in band because all my
friends were in band and I loved
music. so I asked the, uh, band
director at the middle school and
I told him, I said, Hey, I'm
really passionate. I want to
learn something. his answer was,
you should learn the oboe. And
I'm like, Okay. what is that? He
was like here. And so he got out
and oboe and he got out of reed
he put it together for me and put
it, he said, okay, this is. You
know, blow and just how you make
an abasured. And I did that and
it squeaked, he's like perfect.
You should be our new oboe
player. I was like, Okay, cool.
And I'm like 11 years old, so
I've just game for anything. And
he probably totally planned that.
Like, yes, we got another one
because oboe's so rare in
schools, along with like basoon.
So that's when he heard that I
was, I just wanted to join and
he's like, cool. Let's just talk
her into playing this thing. And
we're all taken care of, but I
guess I have to thank him for it
because I ended up falling in
love with it. So.
Dan: Yeah, that's awesome. Yeah,
I imagine there was, there was no
oboe player, you know, before he
started.
Jessica: Yeah, there was actually
just one, but then he was like,
we really need one other one. And
so it was easy to talk at 11 year
old, because at that age, you're
just like, I just want to do
anything and you're not going to
like fight it there, so.
Bekah: Oldest is learning their
trombone because someone gave us
a free trombone.
Jessica: see, there you go. Yeah,
exactly. That's how, like most
kids fall into it. They're like,
I don't know. Just give me an
instrument. I'll figure it out.
Bekah: Yeah, that is awesome. And
so it's great to hear to your
you've had this history of
teaching in your family, it
sounds like you also taught
music, but you're also teaching
now through what you're doing.
You know, you did the lunch and
learn for us and taught us all
about writing, but also as you're
writing, you're teaching. So, how
much of that do you think that,
you're able to lean on. What
you've learned from your mom and
your grandmother, um, or is it
something that you thought you
really had to work hard to
acquire that skill?
Jessica: Yeah, I you know what I
was teaching beginners, there's a
lot of patience required when
you're teaching beginner
students, especially beginner
oboist, because it's like a
really weird instrument and
there's not a little. Unnatural
things with it. And so it
requires a lot of patience and
just saying, okay, let's just
take it one step at a time. And
so I think that translates a lot
into the articles I write. Now I
write a lot of beginner articles
on HTML and CSS and JavaScript
and tutorials and all that fun
stuff. And so I know what it's
like. First start out in
programming. And I think a lot of
writers just skip over stuff and
they'll skip like 20 steps where
they're writing about something
and they'll go, oh yeah, first
you do this. And then when you
log in, just take care of this
and then go over here and I'm
like, wait, wait, wait a minute.
Like, how is a beginner supposed
to kind of fill in those gaps?
And so I really try to be
conscious about explaining
things, not assuming anything,
being patient there, I think that
goes into my writing. Um, cause I
just want to help people as best
as I can.
Bekah: That's so important
because the, it. It really helps
to create a more welcoming and
inclusive space in tech to have.
Tutorials or guides or articles
that don't make assumptions about
the people who are reading them.
I can't tell you how many times I
started reading something and got
very frustrated because I was
following the steps. But it
wasn't working and I didn't know
what to do or what to look for.
And that can be really hard to
navigate through, especially
you're self-taught or you don't
have a good support system. So I
really appreciate hearing you
talk about making sure that
that's part of your process.
Jessica: Yeah. Yeah. Cause it's
just like the person came to
learn. And so when you're just
skipping steps or saying, oh,
what are the things too? That's a
pet peeve is when people say, oh,
it's so easy. You just do this.
You can't say that. Like a lot of
people do this when they're
setting up, like get hub for the
first time and they'll say, oh
yeah, This up and you just run
these commands, just open up
your, your. terminal. It's
totally fine. And, and there you
go. And it's like, no, it's not
totally fine. This is brand new
for a lot of people. So you've
got to walk through those steps
and throw in some screenshots
make sure that people can follow
along. Cause it might be easy for
somebody that's been doing it for
many, many years, but when you're
first learning it, you're going,
wait, where's my terminal.
Where's my command prompt. How do
I type, do I type this in first
and then do this? Or this is very
confusing. So.
Bekah: Yeah, I'll never forget.
It's one of the first times I
paired with somebody is somebody
that I really like admired in the
industry. And I was terrified
because I didn't know. And at
that point I hadn't really been
using. Uh, VS Code or, or
anything like that. And so okay,
um, can you open up a text
editor? And I had no idea what
that word meant. And so I opened
up Google docs and, they like, of
went with it. And then eventually
they were like, do you have
something like VS Code or Atom.
oh, a text editor. like, Things
like that, you know, I didn't
know.
Jessica: Right.
Bekah: I hadn't seen it written
before and I was using built-in,
things with the lessons that I
was learning. I remember just
that sense of shame that didn't
belong there. Right. I shouldn't
be ashamed in that moment, but
when you feel like there are
assumptions like, oh, I should
have known that. And it's not
true. So to have people breaking
things down to avoid, that makes
it much easier for people to keep
learning.
Jessica: Yeah, exactly. Cause I
mean, people want to learn and,
and I think writing is just such
an important skill. I think
everybody should write and work
on writing. And I think there's
just two levels. There's writing
technical articles and then
there's also writing about your
personal story. And so the cool
thing about this monthly
challenge is I get to do both is
I get to focus on some technical
stuff and then I get to talk
about, some weird stories I have
some fun articles coming up there
and just kind of sharing my story
there.
Dan: Yeah, I think that's
awesome. That balance of, of, you
know, not making assumptions
about your audience and, um, but
also still kind of getting your
point across for the thing you're
trying to learn is, is a, is a
hard balance to strike and I
think you do it well. there, is
there anything. If somebody was
starting a technical article, you
know, I mean, w what advice would
you give? Like, you know, say the
thing that I wanted to learn or
that I wanted to, you know,
teach, uh, required to GitHub,
you know, required you to check
out a repository and all of that
stuff. you say, like, would you
suggest putting all that stuff
step-by-step in or linking to.
Articles about, you know, about
how to do that and that kind of
thing. Like what, what kind of
approach, you know, generally
would you would you suggest?
Jessica: Yeah. So I think it's
fine if they're. Uh, if you want
to Link an article, or if you
want to have a right at the very
top of your articles, just say,
prerequisites must be familiar
with and GitHub. Um, I mean, I
just wrote an article about, uh,
how to work with Node and
NodeMailer for emails. And so I
had a prerequisite say, okay, I'm
not going to cover basic
JavaScript. So it's important.
That you understand some of the
basic concepts and the basics
behind nodes. So we can dive
straight into this. And there was
one section there's a different
setup with how to do Google with
NodeMailer and set up all the,
off the authentication there. And
so I did link to another
freeCodeCamp article and say,
okay, here's a detailed
step-by-step process. If you're
going to use google with
NodeMailer, otherwise you could
walk through the steps that I'm
going to show you here. So I
think that's completely fine.
There were, if you feel like you
could write through. Um, all of
those steps in the article, I
think either approach works
there. Um, but I, I think it's
healthy to have like a
prerequisites if necessary, just
to let everybody know, Hey, if
you don't have these
prerequisites, that is going to
be kind of hard to follow,
especially for some of the
tutorials, because I see a lot of
people have freeCodeCamp, go
through a lot of our Python
tutorials, which assume you have
some basic knowledge, but they're
not acknowledging that you have,
uh, that basic knowledge. And so
they'll come to the forum and
they'll go, how do I do this? Or
why does it say I have an
indentation error? And so we'll
tell them, like, you're doing
crazy things with your
indentation. You can't do that in
Python, but they won't know that
because they just started coding
Python like two days ago. And
they're trying to build like a
Discord bot. And so just a
properly communicating. Like,
this is not necessarily a
beginner or if it is like, some
walkthrough steps that you can go
through. Here's a great article
that lays it out. so I, I think
that's completely fine there.
Dan: Ah, I love that, that, um,
prerequisites, you know, is, I
think that's a great, a great way
to set expectations for the, you
know, for the article. Right. And
then you don't get down three
paragraphs in and. Um, assuming
you read prerequisites, you know?
Jessica: Yeah. Yeah. I try to
make it obviously, you know? a
headache, like here you go.
Dan: Right, right.
Jessica: So if someone misses it,
it's like, okay, well, I did try
to warn you.
Dan: Yeah, exactly. I think
that's great advice. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah, I think too, it's
almost a really good convention
to build into something so I
could see, um, Like software that
hosts tech blogging, like, uh,
tech blogging platforms. be
really nice if that was built in.
what are the prerequisites? And
then you can click the thing or
you can add the thing then that
way it already, everybody knows
where they should look Okay. This
is what I need to know. I don't
know those things. And it also
puts it in the writer's mind that
it makes it obvious to them to
think about. It makes it a
deliberate decision to recognize
who their audience is what they
should already know coming into
this. So I think like from both
perspectives, it would be really
useful in helping us to have
these conversations about, what
content is usable, usable for
different audiences.
Jessica: Right. And then there's
some tutorials where people label
it beginner, but it's clearly
isn't beginner. I'm like, I don't
think beginners or I wasn't doing
that. I was first starting out.
And so sometimes people really
mislabel, which hurts beginners,
and then they're going through
it. They're like, well, how do I
do this? I was like, well, maybe
we start off with something a
little bit easier if that's okay.
So yeah, so sometimes people, I
think a lot of it has to do with,
they forget what it's like to be
a beginner
Dan: Yes.
Jessica: or they rewrite history
and they're like, oh, I was
totally doing this when I was
first learning in six months or a
year. And it's like, no, you
probably weren't. You probably
just forgot you weren't doing
those types of things. Cause I
think the first few months. Going
through a freeCodeCamp and going
through the certifications, but I
didn't understand how HTML CSS
and JavaScript work together. I
was just like, okay, there's
these things like arrays and
objects, but how do I make a
webpage? So I just didn't
understand how everything
connected. and so beginners,
it's, it's a lot of information
and it's just like fire hose. And
so you just have to make sure
that you're not making
assumptions going, oh yeah, you
could totally do this with your
beginner. And it's like, no. you
gotta break that down there.
That's definitely not a beginner
tutorial. Let's label it
intermediate at best there.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And you
know, to your point. People could
forget, um, you know, the, what
it feels like to be a beginner at
it from experience. It's very
easy to forget that, you know, it
takes effort to that in practice.
I'm sure. You know, it becomes,
easier. but, um, yeah, it's, it's
hard to, it's hard sometimes to
put yourself back in. know, once
you're a few years into a career,
uh, to put yourself back into
spot, you know, the like total
utter confusion,
Jessica: Right. Exactly.
Dan: like, I, I can remember it,
you know, if I, if I make my,
like, if I think about it, I can
remember it, you know? And I was
at the same boat. I'm like, well,
I'm writing, you see him out
here. I'm like, and I was writing
like PHP at the same time. Like I
was like learning it all at the
same time and understand how they
all connected. And, you know,
somebody sent me a CSS file. He's
like instead of using whatever
use this. And I'm like, well,
here's a bunch of black magic.
I'm just going to drop into my
like... into my program.
apparently it works, you know, it
it's, uh, yeah, it can be a, a
hard thing to, to remember, but
an important thing for sure.
Bekah: So I want to back up a
little bit because I feel like we
miss this very impart important
part of the story of. You started
learning to code and suddenly
you're writing for freeCodeCamp.
Like that's not something little
right.
Jessica: totally glossed over
that. Yeah.
Bekah: accomplishment. So I don't
want to lose that. so tell us,
how did that happen?
Jessica: Yes, it's a crazy story,
but that's kind of my life. But
what ends up happening is around
October of 2020, or actually
September of 2020, I decided to
join the freeCodeCamp forum
because like a lot of self-taught
developers, you kind of bounce
around different. Uh, resources,
and then you try to find one that
works. And so I did a few
different things before
freeCodeCamp, but then I landed
on freeCodeCamp. I was like, I
kinda like this. Okay, cool. So I
started going through, the first
certification, which is on HTML
and CSS and responsive design.
And so I decided to just sign up
for the forum. I was like, maybe
I could connect with some
beginners that be kind of cool.
And some other developers just
talk with them. As I originally,
I just thought I would just kind
of hang in the background and
maybe jump in once in a while,
but I ended up jumping in a lot
more and answering questions or
just giving my perspective and
sharing my story. And so after
about a month of being on the
forum, Quincy reached out to me
and he was like, Hey, you're
super active and what's your
story? Let's talk. And so we set
up a Google Meet we talked for
about like 45 minutes, and we
just talked about his background
coming from a teacher into tech
and then my background with
music. And he decided, he said,
well, you should join our forum
moderator team and start writing
for freeCodeCamp is a volunteer.
Okay. I don't know what to write
about. Cause I've just been doing
this for like two seconds and he
said, just share your story. And
I'm like, oh, I could do that.
That sounds fun. So I decided to
just write a few posts about my
story so I wrote one, my first
one was about what I enjoyed
about being a beginner. I wrote
one article about the parallels
between music and. Uh, uh,
blending code and programming.
And then that was noticed by
Gatsby and they were like, Hey,
we have this blog and do you want
to write it? We'll pay you. I was
like, yeah, that sounds fun to
me. So that I wrote about
imposter syndrome and how I dealt
with it as a musician and how.
Yeah, it goes in with
programming. so now all of a
sudden I start writing articles
and just sharing my story. And
after a few months of doing that,
Quincy comes back to me and says,
well, I've got another
proposition for you. Um, do you
want to start writing technical
articles and we'll pay you per
article? And I was like, ah, I
don't think I could do that. So
originally I actually said no
very politely, because I just
didn't think I could do that.
Cause at this point this was like
six months in and we're at the
same time I had started my first
developer job, but I was still
kind of overwhelmed with that. I
was working part-time at this
small company. And so I was like,
I don't know if I'm qualified to
write technical articles, like
who is going to believe me. I, I
don't know what I'm doing. And.
He said, well, I, I think you
can, I think you really good at
just breaking down concepts and
could pick articles you feel
comfortable with. And so he had
this whole Trello board uh,
topics and I could just choose
which ones I felt comfortable
with. So I picked all the HTML,
CSS, wines, I think maybe a
couple of JavaScript ones, um,
and just started from there. And
so a few months of just writing
and getting paid per article on
my own schedule and, uh, around
July. Uh, it was interesting
because I was deciding if I
actually wanted this to be a
full-time career or not. And, um,
an opportunity came up with
Disney for a music job, but I
ended up turning that down to
pursue software
Dan: Wow.
Jessica: Yeah. Which is a whole
other story in of itself, which
we could cover. But, uh, but
yeah, so then I was like, okay, I
guess we're going into software
now I turned down that job and
then Quincy reached out again,
said, Hey, I've got a job for
you. I want you to join my team
officially you know, be, uh,
writing all the time. I was like,
okay, cool. So it's funny how
life works out, where one door
closes and then another one opens
around. Uh, I started officially
in August of 2021. Writing
articles and being part of the
author team. And so there's a
total of four of us. And we all
come from very diverse
backgrounds and we're located all
around the world. but he'll now
assign us articles. And so he'll
send us like 10 or 12 different
headlines a time. And then. we
just write. basically we research
and write. Uh, so right now I
have a whole bunch of SQL
articles and I've been learning
about that and just writing about
SQL basically as Well, as a few
more JavaScript articles that I
have leftover that you get to
write about. But Yeah. that's,
that's kinda my story. How I,
weird story, how I wound up at
freeCodeCamp.
Dan: Oh, Thats great. Yeah. And
you actually answered it at the
end of a question I was going to
ask was, um, you know, how to
balance, like, if you're, if
writing is, you know, your main
job, um, how to balance actually
learning, you know, whilst
writing, but it sounds like kind
of built into the job, right?
Jessica: Exactly.
Dan: very cool.
Jessica: Cause there's times
where I'll get assigned articles
Dan: Yeah.
Jessica: and I'm like, okay, I
feel comfortable about this. And
then there's times where I'm
like, I've never really worked
with this. So I guess I'll have
to learn it because I have to
write about it and convince
people that I know what I'm
talking about there, but it's
really great because I get to, we
all have that, where we are. One
of the authors was asked to learn
some PHP and writes a PHP
articles. Another one was asked
to write C, uh, C++, and learn
that. we're all down for just
learning, whatever we need to
learn and get the job done there.
Bekah: I love that much.
Dan: That's
Bekah: Sorry, go ahead.
Dan: That was my whole thing.
That was awesome. That sounds
awesome.
Bekah: I just kind of want to sum
up your whole timeline here of
everything that's happened
before. I think that for a lot of
people that we talked to,
especially people who are trying
to transition into a tech career,
it's where to get start. And
first of all, like get
comfortable with being
uncomfortable, but also. You
finding that spot, you had this
opportunity because you
participated on freeCodeCamp
because they reached out to you
because they saw like, look,
Jessica is awesome and she's here
and she's contributing. that just
progressively led to more and
bigger and better things. And so,
you know, start with telling your
story and, writing those words
and this. You know, that's
largely been my blogging
experience. I rarely write very
technical things because just
want to get the words out on
paper, or it's not on paper, but
put, put it out there into the
world and that's a good place to
start.
Jessica: Yeah. I mean, there's,
everybody has a story and
everybody has something to talk
about and share. And so just,
just share with people and you'd
be surprised who reaches out. I
mean, that's how I got my first
developer job is I wasn't looking
for a job. I didn't think I was
anywhere close to being ready,
but this guy found me on the
forum. He's like, Hey, I'm
looking for a junior. Yeah. Uh,
junior and what,
Dan: Um,
Jessica: you want me to write
code for you? And so he's like,
yeah. And, I still work with him
to this day and it's been an
incredible learning experience,
but that came out of just being
active on the forum and just,
know, writing and talking about
my story there.
Bekah: Sorry. I was like, my
brain is split in two different
directions of where to go here.
Um, I'm a, Dan is you want to add
something before I take us off on
a tangent?
Dan: Nope. I would say pick the
left one.
Bekah: The left one. Okay. My
left one was, um, thinking about
your, and literally in my mind,
it was, it was on the left. your
career goals. I don't know if you
have career goals, but does, is
writing something that you want
to continue to do? Do you want to
pursue, the writing aspect of
coding or, or find yourself
somewhere in the middle or just
see this as of a tangent of your
journey?
Jessica: Yeah. Yeah. I would like
to have at one point a, a
traditional, like full-time
developer job, but I definitely
still want to keep writing. And
so if there's any way I can still
be involved, especially with
freeCodeCamp, it's still write
articles for them in some sort of
capacity. Cause I just, I, I love
to write it. I love. Teach people
and help out wherever I can. but
they think the bigger career goal
too, is I have all these ideas
for music related, uh, tech that
I want to build. And some of them
are crazy ideas. And I mean, I
guess all my ideas are crazy, but
Bekah: are my favorite.
Jessica: I guess That's the
entrepreneurship maybe where it's
like, oh, my ideas are insane,
but I just don't want to let them
go.
Dan: Those are
Jessica: the best ones And so.
Exactly. So, yeah, so that's like
the long-term goal is to start
slowly tackling some of these
ideas and just kind of go from
there and work a regular
developer job, but then also keep
writing and have fun with it.
Bekah: Yeah, that gives me an
idea for a monthly challenge, I
think we have a big energy
channel in slack. And a lot of it
is just GIF's, um, to bring us
big energy. But I really think
that so many of us have these big
ideas that we think are
unattainable, or this is too big,
or this is too out there. Right.
Or there's just too many of them
like on one. if there was a big
idea month, right? Like we all
write down all of our big ideas
that we want to share. And work
together to kind of give feedback
on those big ideas and figure out
like where to focus or how to
break things down. And then, you
know, that way, like together, we
have that support, but we're,
we're making progress on the
things that we really enjoy doing
it.
Jessica: Exactly. I mean, I think
ideas are fun and playing around
with them and then trying to
implement them. And sometimes
people will call you crazy. I
mean, people thought I was nuts
to try to do a publishing
company. I remember I went to an
alumni event. And I was just
started with the business and I,
you know, you go around and does
events and you talk to small
groups of people, and it was some
sort of administrator with the
university of Rochester. And she
was asking me what my next plans
were. I said, well, you know, I
just moved here to LA and looking
for freelance work, but I also
have this sheet music business
that he just got started and she
was. Y I'm like, oh, okay. Well,
let me tell you why that was a
little taken aback. I was like,
okay, great. Well, this
conversation won't last long, uh,
so I had a few people. They're
just like, why would you, why
would you do that? But I just had
a very specific. Vision of what I
wanted with my sheet music
business. And then people were
surprised that it actually turned
into a business. I'm like, well,
yeah, I told her I was going to
do that. You didn't believe me.
And so, yeah, I think sometimes
people will just reject it and
then once they see it come true
and they're like, oh, okay. I see
it there. I mean, the same thing
happened with, with Disney where
people thought he was nuts to
build a park in Anaheim where all
these orange trees were and then.
Obviously that worked out for
him, but initially people thought
he was just completely nuts. Like
who's going to go to this park
and where is Anaheim and Well,
people were wrong then.
Bekah: Well, I love that
confidence that you talk It with
too. You're like, yeah, I'm going
to do this thing because I want
to do it. And it's a good idea.
And at some point, people start
to buy into that idea because of
how you present it and the
confidence that you use. And, oh,
you're just like, love how chill
you are when you talk about
things. I'm like, oh yeah, yeah.
I would definitely work with
Jessica on that, you know?
Jessica: I just like going for
things cause it's like, Yeah, it
either works out or it does it.
And if it doesn't work out, I
learned something. I had plenty
of things that didn't work out,
I'm glad I tried it. So I could
at least learn along the way, but
sometimes you just gotta go for
it. You can't really play safe
and, and um, you know what to do
too risky. You don't want to go
like bankrupt or anything crazy,
but like, you know, you just want
to. If you have an idea and you
feel really confident about it,
just, just go for it and take it
one step at a time. There.
Dan: Yeah, it's a theme. That's
come up a few times on the
podcast that, you know, it makes
me think of a Structured YOLO.
Uh, Nick Taylor, um, which is a
phrase he, he coined, you know,
but it's the same sort of idea,
right? It's is. You know, I mean,
don't want to do YOLO, right. But
the
Jessica: Exactly.
Dan: structured YOLO. Yeah,
Jessica: the way out there. I
Dan: yeah,
Jessica: my
Bekah: little bit of YOLO.
Dan: yeah,
Jessica: my business, I wasn't
like, okay, cool. Let's just
raise all this money. No, that
would have been crazy. Cause I
was like young, 20 something year
old had didn't know what they
were doing. Excited to take small
little steps to get there. I
couldn't go that big and do some
crazy fundraising goal or
whatever when I had no clue what
I was doing. So.
Dan: Absolutely. But the, know,
the willingness to have an idea
that is not what a normal, I
guess, whenever, you know, idea
that you might run into that
conversation with somebody like,
well, why, why are you doing
that? You know, but the
willingness to, um, jump into it,
you know, and, and push through,
I think is, uh, a, know, a
valuable, valuable trait to have,
you know, and obviously it's
served use or do.
Bekah: So sometimes, um, it can
be really challenging to write.
Blog posts to get started and to
receive feedback on blog posts.
You know, whether that's from an
editor or somebody who has
commented on your posts in a way
that is not, um, kind So how do
you navigate those challenging
situations while you're writing?
Jessica: Yeah, It's feedback is
always interesting, especially in
the world of the internet because
people can just hide behind their
computers and save virtually
anything to you that they
probably wouldn't say if you
guys, if you were face-to-face
with them, but I try to just
separate them between actual,
constructive feedback versus.
this is not helpful. I'm just
going to move on. And so I've
had, uh, some constructive
feedback, like, oh, this is
really good. could you like, uh,
you know, expand on this part or
could you talk more about this?
And I'm like, okay. Yeah, that
makes sense. And then there's
been times where it's like, well,
I think it would be better if you
went into this. I mean, that's
what real developers do or
whatever. So I've got like those
comments I'm like, okay, well
you're an obviously not helpful.
And so I just learned that, uh,
when I was running my business,
There's just those comments that,
that people just have to, you
know, just write things and
you're just like, okay, I'm just
not going to waste my energy on
that. It's a, luckily I haven't
had too many just absolutely
horrific things. Uh, at least
with my programming writing,
there was only one incident, um,
that I had when I was running my
sheet music company, where there
was this guy that went out of his
way. To make accounts and post
race, racist memes and stuff on
my page and on my YouTube
channel. And I, of course I had
to block all that, but he would
keep creating new accounts of
like, you're that threatened what
I'm doing, that you have to spend
time. And so there are people out
there that just are that hateful
that you just exist because of
your race or your gender. And
it's just like, okay, you know,
it's a it's, it's okay to be
human. Yeah. Uh, you know, feel
that and go, well, come on. Yeah.
But at the end of the day, you
just have to remember like that's
their issue, right. They they're
just a hateful person. Is he just
trying to block them and move on?
Um, and, and just focus on the
helpful, constructive feedback as
well as the positive feedback to,
to know that you're on the right
track, you're doing the right
thing.
Bekah: Yeah, I really liked that.
And that's for a long time, I
stayed away from blogging on any
platform except my own blog,
because I didn't have comments
enabled. I couldn't see how many
people liked it, And I still
frequently think about going back
to that rather than cross posting
other places that, that have
those built-in things, because
sometimes it can just, it can be
hard or you put a lot of time and
effort into something maybe two
people like it versus the thing
that I, I YOLO'd on a Saturday
night. And then there's all of
these hits and like, what, what
is this.
Jessica: Yeah. I I've been there
so many times both with like
writing technical articles then
with sheet music where I'll
release a new product I'll be
like, oh, this is good. Totally
sell through. This is gonna be a
hit. And then. The sales are like
nothing. I'm like, okay, wildly
misjudge that. And then I'll
release another product then
like, okay, this will do okay.
And then it ends up being a
breakout. I'm like, what
happened? What did I misjudged?
That it's the same thing with
writing where there'll be some
articles. Actually, this just
happened with the CodePen and
Replit articles, because I
decided to write those because
free cookie up uses both of those
tools, um, in their
certifications. There really
should be a guide to help them
since it's based on the course.
And I just thought, okay, well,
few people write these. Hopefully
they'll just refer to them. But
then both of them were retweeted
by the co-founders and the CEO.
And I'm like, okay, that was
unexpected, but that's kind of
cool.
Dan: Do you ever um, like doing
tech support comments, you know,
sections when you're writing
technical articles,
Jessica: I do. Yeah. Yeah.
Sometimes someone's like, oh, I
tried this example from your
article. It's not working. And
I'm like, oh, could you write the
code? It's sometimes it's hard.
Cause like Twitter and stuff,
it's not really good for writing
code, but I'm like, I don't know,
just try your best or take a
picture or something. then I'll
say, oh, you have this syntax
error right here. If you clean
that up, that you should be good
to go. It's a. Sometimes just
kind of, uh, or actually this
just happened to, with, uh, the
NodeMailer article where they're
like, oh, could you put this up
on, GitHub repos so we could
study it? And I was like, oh
yeah, I should totally do that.
Cause I had just posted the final
code in the article. and without
thinking, like people would want
to study it and uh, you know,
fork it and all this fun stuff. I
was like, oh yeah, we should
probably do that. So I created a
GitHub repository and then, uh,
just shared it with that. But
sometimes I'll kind of
troubleshoot with them as best as
possible. My questions are vague.
I'm like, I'm not really sure
what you're working with unless
we like together on some sort of
zoom meet, but I don't know how
feasible that is, but
Bekah: yeah. that doesn't scale.
Well, I think.
Dan: Uh, what about, so you
mentioned like code stuff like
that. kind of, um, I dunno
process, or I guess I'm looking
for advice generally. if, you if
if your, uh,article Involves a
lot of code and stuff like that.
Do you try to, um, like things up
into little bits or make a link
to Like, you know, like you
mentioned, uh, what, what kind
of, of approaches do you take
with, uh, w with technical
articles and with
Jessica: Yeah. So for some of the
examples they're really small,
like I just wrote one about, um,
JavaScript contains or includes
method. Um, and so those were
like really, really small, um,
uh, code examples in there. But
then one of my other articles was
on the MVC pattern. And so I kind
of had to struggle with how much
code am I going to include in
this? Cause I built an app
specifically to talk about that
pattern. But I thought, okay, is
this going to be a full
walkthrough tutorial, or am I
just going to give out chunks of
it? So it ended up working where
I said, okay, it's fine. If they
do. Work with that particular
stack that I was working with and
I was working with the burn
stack, but if I could just talk
about the concepts and just have
a few snippets of code and say,
this is what this code does. Even
if you're not a JavaScript
developer, at least they can,
there's some context. And I had
the final, project there that
they could look at and say, oh,
okay, that's what she's doing
here. And so sometimes you'll you
just want to have like these
small little code examples
sometimes it's totally fine to
just link to a repository if it's
super super long. cause then
there's that battle between
length and it's like, how much
are people really gonna read? If
it's super, super long, there's
not too many, really long
articles on freeCodeCamp. There's
a few that are like at 7,000 plus
words. I personally haven't
written any of those. but I think
my longest is 20 I think my
longest was 3000, but that ended
up just listing off all the types
of like free courses you could
take. but, uh, yeah, I try to hit
that magic mark of like 1500, a
thousand words or less. I mean,
if there's only so much, you
could write about some of these
methods where it's like, I can't
write 1500 words on the includes
method for JavaScript. There's
only so much you could do there
that.
Dan: Oh, a good note. I mean, and
that's also an interesting thing
to like of, you know, um,
writing, you. If you could feel
yourself getting like too long,
you know, it, do you try to cut
down or do you about splitting it
up, but, you I suppose it depends
on what platform you're on or
Code Camp or not, or, you know,
but generally
Jessica: right. Cause
Dan: you know,
Jessica: I just joined dev.to,
week ago and, or I think I joined
a while for Nick's VS Code tips,
and then just hadn't used it for
awhile then, like rejoined, I
guess. uh, for the NodeMailer
article, I was like, oh, Well, I
have these ideas about how to
style the emails and how to, uh,
actually, uh, you know, deploy it
to Heroku. But maybe we could
just break that up. That could be
a separate article. And I like
how in-depth too, you can link to
like, create your own little
series and it will link all the
articles together. so sometimes
when you're writing something,
you're like, huh, I have these
other ideas. Maybe it could be
like, this is part one. And then
this is part two and stick around
for part three or something.
think that's totally fine. Just
so it doesn't become this monster
article. It's like, ah,
Everybody. It's the same thing
with videos. I think some of the
videos are super long and some of
these channels
Dan: Yeah.
Jessica: where like, if
somebody's going to sit through
17 hours or is that one of those
things where you just got to
break it up into smaller bite
size videos. but I guess
everybody has their own learning
methods. So maybe there are
people that will go through a 17
hour video or, you know, 7,000.
Bekah: My husband used to
livestream for freeCodeCamp. And
sometimes he would do it for
hours and people would stay the
whole time.
Jessica: Oh, yeah. Yeah. There's
some like, yeah. I'm just like,
wow, how
Bekah: I just live stream for an
hour for the first time ever,
probably by myself. I was tired
of hearing myself talk, like, I
can't imagine how everybody else
was feeling. You
Jessica: right.
Bekah: my attention span to die.
And then I, then I start YOLOing
things and it's, it's not, not
the place I want to be
Jessica: Right. Right. You know,
actually that reminds me, Danny
Thompson is one where he has
these really long Twitter spaces,
but they're really good. So
that's why he kind of is able to
get away with it because for most
people. They would kind of die
off after like at 45 minutes or
an hour, sometimes he'll go for
like three hours or longer. And
then there's still like hundreds
of people and I'm just like, wow,
that's kudos to him then.
Bekah: I feel like you need voice
training for some or something,
you know, like even talking, even
when I used to teach night
classes, like three hours of
having conversation and by the
end, My throat hurts, you know,
and like I am done, I, I did know
a teacher who was taking classes
for that reason, because they
were saying, it's, it's how
you're using your voice and you
have to do it in this different
way. And then you'll be fine. And
exercise your muscle. Like, ah, I
know that's a lot. I mean, I
think it's the same thing for
writing too. It's it's a muscle
that you have to exercise. So I
imagine, I mean, you're writing
on a lot of new topics all the
time and learning things, but has
the writing process gotten
easier?
Jessica: Yeah. Yeah. I now have
more of like a game plan on how
I'm going to enter into an
article. And so I usually like to
start off with just a little
introductory paragraph, knowing
I'm probably going to edit it
later on, but I just throw
something up and then I get into
the meat of the article and kind
of flesh it out. Um, and then
once I clean up the actual main
part, then I can go through and
come up with a really good
introductory paragraph and a
conclusion there I try to focus
all my intention, uh, you know,
just writing the main parts. And
sometimes I just do like a free
write. Throw words on the page
and of them make it some of them,
I cut out sections. I'm like, I
don't know what this was. I mean,
that just happened with the
article a few weeks ago on how to
create tables and SQL. And some
of those sections of like, why
this doesn't make any sense. I
don't know why this, I thought
this was relevant, but I was just
throwing words on the page. I'm
like, oh, I should talk about
this. And then I read it back.
No, I shouldn't have talked about
that, but that's an easier? for
us to kind of cut things out
there and then just reshape it
into something acceptable that I
could send to the editor. she
doesn't have to look at it and
go, what is this?
Dan: There's one of the benefits
of the medium, right? Is do you
have the, it easier to go back
and things out that don't make
sense,
Jessica: Exactly. Yeah.
Dan: as opposed to maybe a live
streamer, something things to get
out there?
Bekah: the expectation of live
streaming, so
Dan: for sure.
Bekah: acceptable thing. Um, I
can't remember what to say. Oh, I
know what I was gonna say. Um,
Rough drafts are so important. I,
and I think that it's worth it to
point out that there's a process
that you get better at that
process. And you have a rough
draft. No, nobody puts out a
perfect rough draft, a perfect
draft. The first time it is a
process and it does take time.
You know, just listening to you
talk about tech, Jessica, you
communicate it so well. it's
really, I feel like I learned a
lot just hearing you talk about
these things. And so you can
really appreciate that process of
learning and then, and how it
impacts the way that you talk
about things. And I imagine it,
that goes into interviewing and
stuff like that. Because you talk
with credibility, then people are
more likely to. Um, see you as a
credible person.
Jessica: Yeah, Yeah. And that's
the thing is that want to come
across as, how can I add value to
the company or organization if
you come across as I just really
need a job? Well, the company's
not really hiring you because you
need a job. Like they're hiring
you because they need people to
join their team and add value. if
you come in and say, here's how I
can add value to you, then
they'll listen. And I think
that's just coming in with a
little bit of confidence. Will go
a long way there.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. So we're
at about time here, but are there
any last tips that you have for
our listeners about getting,
started with writing?
Jessica: Um, I think just the
best tip is just, get started. I
think a lot of people
procrastinate because they're
like, I don't know what to write
about. I don't know what to do. I
don't know how to get started.
get started and just start
working from there. And you can
always ask for feedback within
your community and say, Hey, I'm
writing this article. I dunno how
it really works it yet, or it
needs some help, but, uh, don't
wait for the perfect. To get
started writing? to just start
writing, to start throwing some
words on the page, start creating
an outline, then you can shape it
and edit it down from there.
Bekah: Awesome. you so much for
being here with us today. This is
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: to hear you talk about
this and your journey. You have
so many fascinating things, and
I'm really glad that we got to
hear them today.
Jessica: Yeah. Well, Thank you,
so much for having me.
Dan: Yeah. Thank you, Jessica. I
appreciate it.
Bekah: Okay, bye.
Jessica: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please subscribe
to our podcast and be sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!