Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode eight of
the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you. Here with me today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah. Today is the
penultimate episode of season
four and we're ending on a
really good one. We sat down
with Dr.
Maeling Murphy, a software
engineer who recently
transitioned into tech after an
eight plus year journey as a PhD
research scientist in material
science and engineering, and
also
creating her own digital content
creation business. Maeling
shared
with us, her approach to finding
employers with the right culture
for you, some ideas on how
contributing to open-source
projects can help prepare you
for your first job. And the
value of
developing the connection to
community and being able to grow
alongside others. We also talked
at length about her habit of
taking notes as she works. And
she was patient enough to answer
all of our questions about
finding the right approach.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We
hope
you enjoy this episode. Our
random question today is if you
could have someone follow you
around all the time, like a
personal assistant, what would
you have them do?
Maeling: oh man.
Bekah: Thinking about that. My
name is Bekah. front end
developer from a small town in
Ohio. And I, there are like
little things that I don't like
to do that I would like them to
do, or like to remember for me,
like, tomorrow your kid has, has
silly hat day. Like I never
remember that it's silly hat day
until the morning. So they'll
make sure that the silly hat is
put out in that I've turned off
the stove that I have all my
Christmas presents, that kind of
stuff. And calling insurance
companies. Yeah, they would
definitely make all of the
insurance company phone calls
because that was the worst.
Dan: Yeah, that's a good one.
Um, hi, I'm Dan. I'm a developer
from
Cleveland, Ohio. And, um, yeah,
I mean, don't know one answer is
what would I not have them do?
Uh, but then I was thinking
about
it a little bit in the first
thing that really popped to my
mind would be, you know, to
remind me of what I went into a
room to do or remind me of, you
know, like I go down to the
basement get something from
pantry. but just like I'm on
autopilot and I go and open the
frigerator that's down there.
And
then I'm just staring at the
frigerator wondering. I'm doing
when I
Bekah: I've done that before. I
was like looking for my keys and
I was like, wait a minute. Our
keys are
Dan: so just like somebody that
could be like, Hey, yo, you're
supposed to get the cereal for
down here.
Maeling: and whispering just
like
Dan: right. They can do it in a
way that wouldn't let anyone
else
know that I, uh, yeah, I forgot.
That would be the, that'd be,
yeah, that'd be a high value, a
high value, uh, uh, itself. But
that's what I'm going to go
with.
Maeling: My name is Maeling. I'm
a software engineer based out of
Atlanta, Georgia. I would have
to say the first thing that came
to
my mind was meal planning,
everything surrounding meal
planning. I would just pass off
on to them because I feel like
so
much of my time is dedicated
towards answering the question.
are we going to eat today for
breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
And
so of that pass to them. If they
want to order things, actually
do
the meal prep too. That's fine
by.
Bekah: Oh, I love that this, I
had really busy October and so
like, I don't don't have the
brain power for this. So we
started getting Hungryroot. we
are not sponsored by Hungryroot,
but I am open to a Hungryroot
sponsorships. So if anybody
knows
how to do that, send me food as
payment, but it's really nice.
Cause it was like healthy food a
lot of different varieties for
all of the meals. And and it was
good. It didn't like taste
terrible. It was super easy
through most of it in the air
fryer and call it a day. And
that was, I felt like a game
changer.
Maeling: Yeah, that sounds
incredibly useful.
Bekah: Yeah, so welcome Maeling.
We are very, very happy to have
you here with us, um, on this
fourth season of Virtual Coffee
Podcasts, and we always get
started with origin story, and I
know yours is think it's super
interesting. So I'm really
excited to hear you tell more
about how you got to this point
in your.
Maeling: Sure. Um, so I will try
to make this as linear as
possible. Um, where should I
start? So my background is in
material science and
engineering. It's what I did for
undergrad,
but I did my PhD in. But during
my graduate school experience,
that's kind of where I started
delving into the world of tech.
So while I was in grad school, I
kind of started experimenting
with websites and blogging. I
don't know if you remember the
platform blogger, but I started
blogging there and then switched
over to WordPress and ended up
building this like lifestyle
brand that turned into a company
that I ran for about eight
years.
And in the course of running
that business, I started doing
work
with other businesses and
helping them with their social
media
presence and also doing a few
website development projects on
the side. And the deeper I got
into that work. I enjoyed the
development side, um, more than
I did the marketing and the
social
media aspect necessarily. And so
I started having like these
great
ideas for different clients
websites, and I quickly realized
that my vision of what I wanted
to achieve did not match my
level
of programming. Because at the
time, you know, I'd been
tinkering with HTML CSS, I
started wanting to build full
fledged backend stuff. And it's
like, you know what, let me,
I've
been playing around with this
for awhile and you know, I'd
done
some classes in high school,
HTML, CSS. I was like, you know,
I really want to explore path of
actual programming and just see
where it leads me. Like, I, I,
when I started. More folk, like
my more focused journey into
tech started the end of 2019.
and I
started reaching out to the tech
community on Twitter found a lot
of resources just to explore the
path towards becoming a software
engineer. And since 2019, I just
went on the self-directed
journey. Definitely. I wouldn't
say self-taught because there's
just been so many people and
communities and resources. I
have
been so integral to my journey.
I did not do it alone. Um,
that's
how I, um, here, and I guess
kind of like my short version.
Bekah: All right. I need to dive
into this a little bit more
because you have a PhD in
Material Science and
Engineering.
And you you've gone to all of
these different, very exciting
places. So, how do you go to
school for that long and, and of
decide to do your own thing?
That's a hard decision for a lot
of people.
Maeling: you know, I understand
that. I think part of it is just
my personality. like to try a
lot of different things. Um, I
have a
lot of different interests and.
There's never really a time. I'm
just focused in on like one
avenue. And so, you know, while
I
was in grad school, I was doing
all of digital marketing, social
media stuff. Um, what really
helped me crystallize my
decision
to make a full transition into
tech was the fact that I wanted
to design my lifestyle in a way
that allowed me more
flexibility,
since, you know, I had just
given birth to my son, uh, like
I was
pregnant with him, like, see
right when I was doing my
dissertation and like I
defendant and gave... Yeah. Once
I
graduated and, you know, I had
my son, I really started
exploring
more flexible career
opportunities. And he said,
excuse me. And I, um, just
evaluated my interest in said,
you know, let me at least give
this programming a shot. You
know, it's something that I'm
interested in. Let's see. If I
can make a career out of this,
because I really felt, from what
I was reading and this was, you
know, before, um, the pandemic.
So remote jobs weren't as big as
they are now, but I still felt
like I could potentially have
more flexibility, and being able
to work from home, down the
road. and. Pursue something I
was
passionate about. I love the
problem solving that programming
affords me. I mean, of, uh, the
skills that I developed as an
engineer in the material science
world directly translate to
programming as well as a
software engineer. So Yeah,
that's, That's
kind of how I transition.
Bekah: That's awesome. And I
think, you know, so many,
there's
so many moms out there that I
hear talk about wanting
flexibility, but in wanting to
be engaged, um, intellectually
and
what they're doing. And I,
that's the same thing that I
really love
about coding too, is that I can
do that. You know, I can have
the
time to work part time and, and
do the mom thinks that I want to
be able to do, also. Even if my
house is destroyed at the end of
the day, usually I have
accomplished something with my
code. Now that doesn't happen
all the time, but it's nice to
feel
engaged in that way. And I
definitely definitely understand
that. So when you pretty early
on in Virtual Coffee, I think it
was
early on for you. I was early on
from what I remember you, you
built this homeschool app that
was gorgeous. And we were doing
a
demo days, monthly challenge.
And you were, you were up for
it. You
were like, yeah, I'm going to do
this. And I was like, this is
awesome. And you presented it
and. I mean, it is very, very
beautiful. I'll have the link to
it in the show notes, but can
you
talk to us about how you went
about developing that and like
getting the courage to present
it to all of these people?
Maeling: Oh man. Okay. So to
start that story, it goes back
to. Me starting to take the CS50
Harvard Introduction to Computer
Science course. And a part of
that course at the end, you have
to build, you know, this kind of
capstone project, integrating
all
of the skills that you've
learned and for my project, Um,
it was,
you know, based in like Flask
using Python, hadn't really
delved into the world of
JavaScript too much. And
initially, you know, the, the
requirements for the project
were
not. Very the scope was not very
large, the idea that I had I
quickly realized was way beyond
what the course had taught me.
And so. You know, I tried to
think of a project. First of
all,
that was something that I knew I
was going to be interested in.
And for me, being able to keep
track of my homeschooling
activities for my child was
something I knew that was going
to motivate me to continue
working on the project. I didn't
want to start it in abandoned
that I really wanted to see it
through. And so as I started
working on the project and
started exhausting, what I had,
you know, Been able to apply for
my CS 50 course, I turn to
Twitter and, long story short, I
got involved in the 100 Days of
Code Challenge And in the midst
of that, I was always finding
resources that would help me
with
different parts of the project.
And as I would successfully
implement certain things. The
ideas just kept pouring. And I
was like, Oh, maybe I can add
this now, maybe I can add this.
And, um, I started talking with
people, who I think could
potentially use the site and got
their feedback as well. And so
by
the time I came to Virtual
Coffee, I'd already been in the
state of, you know, being
comfortable sharing my work
because I quickly realized the
more I shared, the more I could
learn, from the community and
it, it just really helped to,
Just
cement, my understanding, being
able to talk about what I was
working on, even I would run
into issues, learning how to
phrase
those questions, to be able to
get meaningful assistance, like
all of that was so helpful. And
so, I was really excited about,
uh, that challenge, that Virtual
Coffee hosted because it was
formal way for me to do what I
had been doing on Twitter. and
so
I'm really grateful, you know,
for community like Virtual
Coffee
and the challenges that, uh, The
community offers because they're
just so beneficial for your
development as a developer.
Bekah: Oh, thanks.
Dan: Yeah, that, uh, the, I
mean, I was, I was just kind of
cruising around on the, on the
school journal app and it it's
really cool. And, you know, when
I was kind of looking around, I
saw the, um, the learning log
and I assume that's part of the
a
Hundred Days of, of Code, um,
you know, thing, which I've, I
know a
lot of people that have very
excited about that. I haven't
done it, but I was, you know, I,
I found it very interested in
seeing the sort of daily
progress and, and you logged it
and. And
we'll, we can put a link to this
in the show notes too. Right.
But
you have this a one document.
Right? All of these, all of
these, uh, all of your days sort
of day's progress. And then
days,
you know, I know you have where
you have to like some thoughts
or
like, you know, links to stuff.
And, um, and it's very cool.
It's
really cool to see that all kind
of put together in one place. So
that's the times I think people,
I don't, I don't know what the.
or whatever of a Hundred Days of
Code are, but, uh, I see them on
Twitter and stuff like that a
lot, you know, and it's, and
it's
always cool to see people's like
work, but, um, it all, uh, in
one
place, you know, one project.
Right. Uh, it's very cool. As I
was kind of wondering if you
wanted to talk a little bit more
about, um, like that specific to
this app, you know, or to this
project, you know, how. I don't
know. I like how that helped
you,
how you, you know, the things
you got value out of it, was it
like
a chore? Was it, you know I
mean? Like I just thought I'd
talk a
little bit about that experience
because it's really cool.
Maeling: I'm really glad you
brought that up because, um, my
motivation, so the, the name of
the repo is called My Learning
Path. And early on in my
journey, I was looking at a lot
of
inspirational blog posts of
people who succeeded, excuse me,
successfully transitioned tech.
And I came across. This one blog
posts. I wish I could remember
his name, he linked to this
template. I, I borrowed that
template from him and it was
just
so fascinating to see his
journey from not knowing a line
of
JavaScript to, you know, a year
and a half later, having this.
Professional, uh, role in
programming. And I knew from
that
moment that I wanted to record
every moment of my path. So I
could always look back and see
how I progressed one then two
serve as just a resource I could
share with other people. So they
could see what resources that I
encountered along my way, could
potentially be helpful for them
and in being encouraging in
their
own journeys. And so. For me
having that, uh, that repo where
I would, you know, update daily
for the most part, was very
encouraging. It was my
motivating, one of my motivating
forces, uh, And that kept me
excited during this, you know,
self-directed path because I can
always look back you know, see
what I'd accomplished or things
that I had questions about. And
it would be a great way for me
to be able to reach out and just
not
lose track of what I was
learning and what I needed
assistance
with. And so, for the project
itself, it was just a natural
progression to include all of
the updates for that as well.
Definitely helped when it came
time to troubleshoot different,
uh, aspects. And then also
helped me just remember the
amount of
work I put into certain
features. So when it was time to
talk about
my project with two employers,
um, it was very easy for me to
remember the work that I'd put
into it.
Dan: Yeah, I think that's great.
I love this and it's one of
those
things that always seems very
valuable to me. And I don't, I
have trouble with getting myself
to do, know, things like this.
Uh, you know, you mentioned the
template and the template is, is
literally. Uh, the date. so
it's, today's progress,
thoughts, link
to work and resources and that's
it. Right. So each day is just,
it's just that. So, um, uh,
simple, very simple format and a
very, you know, it turns out to
be a very, I think, valuable
tool. Um, so do you, like, I
know that I'm sure it's not the
same
every day, obviously, but like
it, did you work into like, was
this part of your routine of
sort of ending the day or, uh,
Like,
when do you write these
summaries? This is the kind of
thing. I also like pick people's
brains that successfully do
these
things, because I, you know, I'm
always trying to like figure out
how to, how to do it. You know
what I mean? I feel like I'm out
the door every day, so
Maeling: yeah. for me, what
worked best was to do it. Just
as
I was doing the work. So for
instance, um, like if I was
troubleshooting, um, a specific
feature or if I was learning
something new in a language, I
would just copy those links and
just drop them in the document.
And then if I had thoughts about
it later, once I'd had time to
digest, I would throw those
thoughts in there or. Thoughts
in the moment, even if I was
unclear
about something. So for me, it
wasn't a really defined
structure. It was just as I
worked, if something stood out
to
me that I should throw it in
there, I would just pop it in
there. And so what really helped
was having my, uh, vs code for
that repo open at all times on
my desktop and just made for
easy
transfer of resources.
Dan: And that's a great, uh,
that's such a great habit. I
feel
like that to do, you know, I
could see how that could be so
useful, you know, is like, this
makes me think back to our
random
question. I could also, you
know, it's the same thing of,
um, You
know, walking down to the
basement and forgetting about a
thing, you know, thinking about
something else. And I do that
same thing to myself, even when
I'm writing code. Right. Or I
have a question I'm like, oh,
that'd be cool. Or I wonder how
this works. And I'm like, well,
let's fix this other thing, you
know, and then forget about it.
Uh, so, you know, um, if you can
get yourself to take those notes
as you work, I think that's, I
think that's very cool.
Maeling: Yeah, it's really
helpful for me now, even in my
role, don't do a repo for it,
but I have, you know, a notion
doc
that has different notebooks. So
as I run into issues and I
resolve them, I quickly update
that as I'm working, because.
Inevitably, sometimes you run
into the same issue and you're
like, wait, how did I figure
this out again? And so it's,
there's
like a great resource, uh, you
know, troubleshooting and just,
you know, learning the different
parts of the code base and
things
like that. So that's just me. I
have to take notes. Um, just how
my brain operates.
Bekah: I really love that. So I
am trying to like Notion and I
continually don't. So is there a
template that you've used that
works for you? I think it's just
overwhelming. There's so much.
Maeling: oh, I totally get it. I
will have to share the link with
you because I did find this
template basically set up, um,
notebooks on one page. And so
I'll have a notebook. For, you
know, different repos and the
code base or for different
technologies. And so it's very,
very easy to stay organized for
me that way. And so, yeah, I'll
have to share that link with you
cause it's, it's been great.
Cause Yeah, when I first started
using notion and just saw that
blank page, like, well, where do
I start here? How do I, you
know, make this effective? So
Bekah: and there's so much you
can do with it. And if you're
sharing it with other people,
then it's just a whole can of
worms that you have to, like,
all using it in their own ways.
And
like.
Maeling: I got it. I will say
though, like. um, when I did
start using Notion, um, during
the job search as well, and
there's a great template that
someone from VC shared for the
job
Bekah: Karen I think.
Maeling: yeah its so great. but
in addition to that, um, using
tables and notion, I don't know
if you've ever tried it, but
when, because I was on Twitter
all the time and you know,
you'll
see all these tweets with like,
all of the amazing resources
that
you should check out all the
time. And I was quickly
overwhelmed with the amount of
bookmarks that I had on Twitter.
And so tables and notion, you
can tag them, you can create
your own
database in Notion I would like
sh uh, save my different links
and then tag them with like, oh,
this is for JavaScript, or this
is for AWS. Or, you know, this
is for doing databases. And so
when
I'd go back and wanting to,
study a certain topic, I could
just
search my tags and quickly see
all of the links for that
resource. Instead of trying to
come through Twitter bookmarks.
Bekah: That's useful. I keep
thinking about what, how to do
something like that for Virtual
Coffee, because we have so many
people contributing to coffee
chats. Every week we get so many
great resources. I want to have
a repository where we can just
send
people. These, these are things
that our members have
recommended, but I really do
like the idea of having tags
there. I
think that makes it, um, easier
and more organized to use and
other things I've explored.
Dan: Yeah, for sure. I, I use,
uh, he's an app called Pinboard
that's very old school, uh,
bookmarking app that has
somewhere else survived. Uh,
it's, and it just bookmarks and
Antech. I think I can add notes
to things, but, um, I don't
usually, but I have found that
when I can remember to get them
in there, you know, it's like
the habit for me is the, is the
hard
part. And
Bekah: Pinboard is on your site,
right?
Dan: Uh, is it,
Bekah: I think it is because I
believe that I have gone there a
couple of times. Cause I'm like,
I know Dan talked about this
resource. Somebody go check his
Pinboard.
Dan: Um,
Bekah: using Dan's pinboard.
Dan: that's cool. Yeah, no,
every once in a while I share it
links
to it, but like, I, I forget
about it sometimes. And other
than that, you know, but it's,
I, I'm always so thankful for
when I
have remembered and then go
back, you know what I mean? And,
and,
you know, grab a grip link from
whatever random, you know, CSS
or
note or whatever um, feel like
that. Um, yeah, the Twitter
bookmarks is, is hard to, I, it
works better for me as, as an
inbox of things to process, you
know, and then stick somewhere
else. I think if it's going to,
if you're going to try to, um,
use it for resources. No. I love
the idea of creating your own
like database to like that.
That's
Bekah: There is I,
Dan: that's cool.
Bekah: yeah, sorry. I
Dan: like a notion. Sorry.
Bekah: There's one thing in
notion that I do like, and I'll
include a link in the show
notes, but it's the front end
developer
learning guide. And it's, it's
one page and it has a checklist.
And I really like checklists and
it has resources with tags. Now
that you say that it reminded me
like different sections. And so
it's different than the roadmap,
but I like it because. just
really breaks down different
things to learn and provides
resources for that. So I have
not vetted this and I'm not sure
how
old it is, but I really do
appreciate how it's organized
and
how there's, there's a journey
through that, thing that I can
understand. Um, so the, the
other thing too, I think re we
frequently get the question or
people wanting to talk in
Virtual
Coffee about note taking and how
people keep up with this stuff.
So just love this part of the
conversation, but have you been
able to take into your job that
you're doing now? Are you still
taking notes or do you still
find that useful.
Maeling: Oh, absolutely. So I've
gotten a lot of great advice
from
those VC chats about note taking
I take notes, um, in notion
primarily, and then also just in
a regular notebook, because I
feel like in meetings it's
quicker for me to just jot down
things and then be able to flesh
it out in notion later. But like
on the spot, definitely my paper
note taking, um, And then for,
you know, like I mentioned, like
taking notes when I'm working on
a ticket, I have like notebooks
for different tickets. Just so I
can keep track of, you know, the
issues that. I'm working through
and techniques that I'm learning
and you know, uh, parts of the
code base and the foundational
knowledge that I'm ramping up
on.
Cause there's just, you know,
always so much to, to pick up
on.
So Yeah. I'm, I'm definitely
still note-taking for.
Bekah: Yeah. And so as part of
that process, is that something
that you take in to maybe
one-on-ones with you or, you
know, what, if somebody was
asking, should I, is it
important
that I invest in starting to do
note taking as part of my
developer journey? I you would
say yes. But you talk, like,
what
would you tell them?
Maeling: I would say to give it
a try and try not to
overcomplicate
it, it's just starting small,
you know, jotting down ideas or
questions. But, I will say that
the benefits are worth the time
invested. Um, I know for me
personally, like in my
one-on-one
meetings with my manager, like I
have a template for those
meetings as well. So those are
another place where we're kind
of
taking notes for like, I have
for him or next steps. then he
actually initiated something for
the team where we have our
weekly
highlights and lowlights. And so
that's another form of kind of
like note taking. So during the
week, as I, you know, come
across
things that I feel like worthy
of that document, I'll just
include
that as well. And so, I, for me,
it just really helps. There's
just so much information to
process all the time. And for
me,
it helps if I can dump that out
of my head, to somewhere else
that is easily searchable
reference and easily sharable as
well.
Bekah: I love that. I think
really breaking down those, what
you're working on too helps to
solidify those ideas in your
head. Or I know like sometimes
I'll be writing something that
doesn't click, because I want to
ask you a question about it and
then suddenly like, oh wait a
minute.
Maeling: Yup.
Bekah: I know what I should be
doing here. Or I know what I
missed. And so having that as I,
I don't do a good job of note
taking while I am working, but
it's something that I am working
towards. so maybe if you share
that notion doc, I will do a
better job of it.
Dan: Do you end up, um, you
know, an Oracle or, or another
places,
you know, you talked about
sharing stuff that I was just
curious about. Do you, do you
share, like, through notion, you
know, directly, know, do you use
like tools, like sharing views
through notion or are you of use
notion as your own, um, like
collection and then, you know,
some other document to share?
Um,
That makes sense.
Maeling: In notion that's great.
You know, you can have, I feel
like this is turning into a
notion,
Bekah: was just thinking I'm
like, this is going to be our
Notion episode.
Maeling: But I, I love, I love
note taking, um, you know, and
it
probably makes sense because,
you know, in my, uh, graduate
school,
Working in the lab, we had to
keep a research lab notebook. So
I had to document everything
every day for all of the
experiments, because when it was
time to write our papers, you
had
to be able to reference those
details. So now I'm of making
that connection. That's probably
why I'm a little bit obsessive
notes. Um, but Yeah. back to
notion you can have, you know,
private notes and public notes
all in the same, uh, profile. So
it's easy to, you know, make a
public note and just pull
certain
things that you'd want to share
from your private notes and put
it there. So you don't have to
share your entire private, you
know, notebook. For instance,
that answers your question.
Dan: totally. Yeah. I was just
like, you know, so for example,
you, you had, um, a section for
your one-on-ones with your
manager or whatever, and I was
just like, oh, what does demand,
you know, is that like you guys
can, you know, collaborating in
notion or is it more just, you
know, you're collecting your own
stuff and then basically reading
from it to, you know, when you,
when you, when you talk
Maeling: right. Yeah. I
definitely have a mix, a mix of
private and public.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. That's, that's
awesome. Another, another nice
thing about notion. I, I keep
wanting, when I do notes, I keep
them just in notebook, on my, on
my, on my Mac. And it's very,
you
know, very simple and it works,
you know, but it's, it's not, it
doesn't have like all that nice,
you know, those nice tools like
that. So that's cool.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and
no taking is so personal too, so
everybody will find something
and it's, it's like one of those
almost controversial topics. I
feel like because people like
love their note taking software
so much that there will be like
arguments over, you know,
whether or not that is the right
one to
use. There's not the right one.
There's whatever works for you.
And it's great that you found
process through that you've
done.
And you're still able to carry
that with you and see that work
as a software developer software
engineer. Um, and so, okay. So
you've done all of this stuff
and you seem very organized to
me you
also have a kid at home. And so
what was that transition like
going from learning as a mom to
working as a mom? It sounds like
you've kind of been that your
whole career, but can be a big
change when you're diving into a
new profession.
Maeling: Absolutely. So, you
know, when I was learning. I
just
had to schedule around my child.
And, and so there were many, you
know, days where I would be
programming mostly at night or
early in the morning before he
was up. But you know, now that
I'm working in my professional
role, like I just have to like
give a huge shout out to my
husband because I could not do
this without him. You know,
especially because it's a little
bit more of a formal. Um,
structure. It's not like, you
know, be at your desk nine to
five, there's flexible, flexible
working hours, but you know, to
be really in the zone, you need,
at least I need long stretches
of time, like uninterrupted time
to
really like get in there and
resolve issues. so me, it's,
it's
great that I, you know, I'm able
to work from home and still be
able to spend time with my
child. But like my husband is
also
there. You know, being active
with him as well. And so I don't
feel guilty for working because
I know he's taken care of as
well,
because me and I, we talked
about this, like in a VC, um,
meeting
in the past, but I when I was
looking in, like, when I
actually
started looking into software
engineering as a career, I was
very hesitant to start searching
for jobs. because I just wasn't
sure if it was going to fit my
lifestyle, you know, after
working for eight years, running
my own business and setting my
own schedule, it was hard for me
to wrap my mind around making
that transition because I just
enjoyed the freedom that I had.
And it wasn't until I spoke with
a friend who was also a software
engineer and also a mom told me
was like, no, you know, they're
remote work opportunities that
have flexible working hours and
accommodate parents. like, what
I did not know that this was
possible, you know, and the
opportunities increased in the
remote you know, following the
pandemic. I just was not aware
of. All of the different company
cultures. I, I just had in my
mind, a stereotypical, you know,
you work at a startup or
whatever. Like you're going to
be working early mornings, late
nights every day, all day, all
week. And when I finally
actually
started the job search process,
I quickly realized that
companies
have different cultures and
possible to find one that fits
your lifestyle. And so, yeah,
it's, it's been a great
transition. I felt, I feel like
I've had a lot of. From the
family side and also on, um, my
job site, like I have a really
supportive team, really
supportive manager, and it's
just
made this transition or really
exciting one.
Dan: That's very cool. you were,
when you were searching for. May
not.. Maybe not when you began
the job search, but when you you
know, learning about these
different cultures things like
that, what were there, how did
you find, like, how did you find
the jobs that like had the, sort
of the flexibility or the
cultures that you were looking
for? I mean, what they show up
in
searches or was it more once you
were in, you know, once he began
dialogue, then it became clear,
you know,
Maeling: Yeah, that's a, that's
a great question. So I have to
shut
out this site that I found
during my job search called
keyvalues.io. Um, but they have
a section on their site called
culture queries. And you can
basically go through this like
tag cloud and select the
qualities that are most
important
to you. So if you value pair
programming, if you value
flexible work hours, and so on.
And so I kind of used that as
springboard to start seeing what
companies were out there that
shared the same values that. And
so that's how I found, some of
these companies and then just
being active on Twitter. I'd
always see, you know, tweets
about different companies and
their culture. And so I just
kept a running list of
companies, uh,
again, in a notion doc, come
running list of current. That I
wanted to investigate. And, um,
I had no problem reaching out to
employees on LinkedIn of those
companies to like, get a more
accurate you know, quotes, uh,
pulse of like what the culture
is
actually like. uh, that's kind
of how I, I try to gauge, uh,
you
know, the outside, looking in
what, uh, a company was actually
about.
Dan: Well, that's very cool. I
hadn't, that sounds like a great
tool. but now, now I want to
know, I want to know more about
your experience of, of reaching
out to people, you know, current
employees, uh, as a prospective
employee, you know, um, find
people in generally receptive to
that sort of thing? Uh, it's
kind
of like a cold call situation,
right? I
Maeling: it was, yes, it was
exactly a cold call situation.
And, um, surprisingly, I wasn't
nervous about it. Just my whole
attitude in approaching software
engineering as a potential
career, I was just kind of. You
know, I'm just going to see
where
this goes. If it doesn't end up
there, like I'm just going to
enjoy the process. I enjoy the
coding. And so that's how I
approached like every step of
process and like securing a
role.
And so when I was reaching out
to people, was friendly, it was
like, you know, um, Hey, I'm
interested more about your
company. If you have 15 minutes
to spare, would you mind hopping
on a quick chat chat call with
me to just discuss. What you
enjoy
about working at such and such.
there were so many people who
responded back and gave like
really great advice and feedback
for my job search and even
referrals and like not even
asking for them. And so I, I was
pleasantly surprised to see. How
generous the people, um, were
when I reached out to them. And
like it extended to what I'd
seen within the tech, uh,
community on
Twitter as well. I I've found
people to be very generous and
supportive. so to see that, you
know, off off of Twitter and in
other spaces like LinkedIn and,
you know, all of the developer
communities as well, it was just
very encouraging to see amount
of
support, who's just trying to
transition into space.
Dan: That's very cool. It's cool
that it was a pretty positive
experience here, you know? Um,
yeah, I suppose you never know
when you. You know, when you
reach out to somebody that you
don't know. Um, um, and that's,
that's great. They had a
generally positive experience.
It makes me wonder if you ever
had
anybody that was just like run
away. You don't
Bekah: I have had those
Dan: but that's just.
Bekah: Somebody, uh, on Twitter
saw I was going, that wasn't
applying for a company, but
somebody else I knew was. And so
I had posted about it and a DM
and they said, this is the most
toxic place I have ever worked.
And I'm afraid to say anything
out loud, because I think that
the retaliation would be so bad
that I might never have a career
in tech again, like, that is
horrifying. And it's hard cause
you just don't know it. What to
do with that information. At
least I didn't know what to do
with that information other than
to pass it along. Um, you know,
also one person's experience
might not be everybody else's.
So
it's really trying to figure
out, I think, how to ask the
right
questions too.
Maeling: Absolutely. Um, that's
such a great point because, uh,
like you said, it could
experience could even differ
from
team to team within an
organization. So someone just
saying they had a negative
experience working at XYZ, it
may
have been because of the
specific team and may have been
because of
a specific manager, like you
never know. So ask all the
questions is my, my advice and
connect with as many people, you
know, working at the companies
that you're interested in just
to
help you get more. A better
sense of what it would be like
work
there. And of course you never
really know the full story until
you're actually working there.
But if you can clear as
information as possible to, to
help you make your decision, go
for it.
Bekah: Absolutely. I always take
down names of people and then I
check them out on social media.
I see what they're tweeting
about.
I talked to somebody once and I
was talking about, well, you
know, I'll think about the, the
opportunity and then I'll get
back to you. I want to do some
more research and they're like,
okay, well I just posted a
tweet. I just tweeted. And I
tagged
everyone in my team. So if
you're interested in knowing
more about
the team, then everybody is
right there. Like, well, that
makes it
easy. But, but I think that can
say like, even looking at their
interactions, I know this might
sound weird. It might sound
creepy, but I like to see how
people interact with each other.
And sometimes that's the only
glimpse that you get of it is
through social media, to be able
to see that. So I don't know.
It,
it peels back the curtain a
little bit. I think that's not,
if you don't peel back, the
curtain pulls back like.
Dan: Mixing metaphors
Bekah: I am. I think I did it
earlier in Virtual Coffee too. I
was talking about peeling
things. I'm on appealing today.
That
should have been our intro
question. Would you eat your
apple peeled or not peeled?
Dan: who its...
Bekah: a good one.
Maeling: I liked our question. I
liked our initial question.
Bekah: Peeled potatoes or not
peeled potatoes. Now I'm on a
kick. I should stop going with
this. Okay. Need to redirect my
brain. sorry. Um, this is what
happens to me at three o'clock
every day. My brain just starts
to lose it a little bit.
Dan: I feel like we made it 40
minutes before a full-on
sidetrack, you know, so
Maeling: That's pretty good.
Dan: it's pretty good for us.
Bekah: Um, okay, so now you, you
are at this job now and what
been
the biggest, I guess maybe
what's been most surprising
about this
job or the things that you've
been happily surprised by since
starting.
Maeling: Oh man. Great question.
So I would have to save the
biggest thing that stood out to
me when starting my job is just
making that transition from
working on personal projects to
production level projects, with
massive code bases. Um, I
remember when I, when I first
looked at the. Hundreds of repos
I was a little overwhelmed and
wondered, like, how do you
approach this? Like during my
journey, I never saw a blog post
on to learn a massive code base
and start contributing to it
within a month. So I would say
that was definitely, something
that surprised me because I just
not, I had not seen that, level
of. Breadth in a code base
before at the production level.
Um, and
on the other hand, what I was
pleasantly surprised with, uh,
was just the amount of, uh,
support across the organization,
not just within my team. Um, I
am really grateful at my job.
They
have a very great onboarding
process. So when you come in,
you're matched with a new hire
buddy and that's someone who is
there for all of your initial
questions for like the first
several months that you're on
the job. And so when I had
feelings
like, whoa, this is massive code
base, where do I even begin? I
already had someone I could just
reach out to without feeling any
shame or anything. And, you
know, just connect on that level
and
then have them be able to
connect me with other people
within the
organization to help. So was
really surprising to me to just
have that kind of, uh, that
level of support just early on,
um,
just a very welcoming, um,
environment. And I'm grateful
for
that. That's, that's really
helped with me making this
transition.
Dan: So other than having
somebody that you can talk to
you
to help, do you have any tips?
You know, now that you've got
your feet under you about diving
into a large code bases, you
know, for the first time.
Maeling: oh man. Yes. So I would
say one thing I, I would have
would recommend is. Contributing
to open source projects and
finding some that have large
code bases and digging into
those
issues because uh, if you can
find one issue to work on within
a massive code base that will
give you an entry point into
learning how the different
pieces connect, especially if
they're
using, you know, other services,
cloud services that like, for
me,
I was not familiar with, um, a
lot of the cloud services and
how
that integrates um, into the
architecture. And so if you can
find pro open source projects
like that, you know, if you're
learning right now start diving
to those issues, to just learn
how all of the pieces connect, I
feel like that will prepare you
immensely for, you know, moving
into a role where you have to do
that on the production level.
Dan: Great advice. I love that
advice very much. Um, that. That
not specifically open source.
That is usually my advice. When
the next question comes up is,
is find something small, you
know,
in the code base, whatever, you
know, if it's the new code base
you're working in or, um,
whatever, find something small
and try to fit, just, you know,
start there and fix it. And
you'll start just to make the,
they make the connections. But,
um, I had never really connected
that. I mean, The practice of
contributing open source and
finding big projects, especially
to get used to this. Right.
Cause it's, it is like almost
everything. Um, a thing that
we're we're practice makes, uh,
well, just helps you improve.
Right. And so, you know, having
been a developer for a while,
you know, I don't have like a
lot of
anxiety jumping into a new code
base and that's not to say I
jumped into it. Know anything
it. Right. but I have the con,
like,
I just have the experience of
having done it. A lot of times,
I
just kind of, can I just trust
that I will be able to do it
because I've just done it, you
know? And yet you using an open
source for that and to prepare
yourself before you jump, like
before you get to your first job
where you know, you're going to
be, you know, dumped into a huge
code base because anybody that's
hiring, probably most people
that are hiring already have
something, you know what I mean?
And it's probably already a
giant... Well, I say giant mess
or... That'll depend, you know,
about how long, how long the
thing's been going on, but, you
know, there's a lot of giant
messes out there and that
doesn't
mean they're bad. Uh, but they
can be very overwhelming, you
know? Um, I love that. I love
that advice about using open
source to like practice just
that specifically, you know,
Bekah: And I would add to that.
It can be challenging to get
into
open source and finding issues
when you're starting out, but
people in your communities, like
in Virtual Coffee, Is there
anybody here that's running an
open source project. And if I
take an issue, will you help me
or Hey, I really want to, I want
to contribute to open source,
but I'm afraid to, would anybody
be
there to pair up with me if I
get stuck and that can, or even
just
to find the issues that can.
Reduce those barriers to entry
because you have that support
and you can talk to people who
maybe
have been in the code base or
who are used to diving into
large
code bases and, and, and allow
them to, you know, kind of
mentor
you through that, but to also
have the chance to communicate
with someone else, because
the... circling back to what you
talked
about in the beginning. Like
being able to talk about what
you're doing is so hugely
important. And so if you think
you, well, I don't need help
diving into this code base. You
need practice talking about it
if you haven't, because that's,
that's a skill that a lot of us
don't get to develop when we're
learning mostly own.
Dan: I just, yeah, I just to add
to that, there's a lot of
awesome
people in the developer
community that. Either for work
or for
their own projects, you know,
maintain opensource projects
like
this. Nick Taylor comes to mind
with Forem, which is a
commercial
product, but it's open source.
And, um, he has, I mean, I've
watched him do it a million
times. He is always happy to
like
help people and, and jump into
issues, you know, with the forum
code base. And I think any, any.
And that, and that's another
good
example of a large scale, you
know, codebase, right. It's not
a
simple app at all. Um, and he's,
you know, he's always very
generous with his time. And, um,
there's a lot of people like
with
projects like that, that are
worth contributing to, you know,
there's almost always people
that maintainers or, or, or, or
advocates or whoever, you know,
um, that I think, uh, reaching
out to you and would be excited,
you know, to, to help somebody
learn, you know, help somebody
to contribute to that, to that.
I
think. Um, what I was kind of
pushing open source here,
Virtual
Coffee so if it fits in with the
theme.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. Nick
just came to my live stream that
I did before this and as doing
TensorFlow JS stuff and I
couldn't even get it running and
he's, he's there debugging it.
He
does. He's not done TensorFlow
JS before, but you know, he, he
is
there to be supportive and to
help work through things that,
uh, I don't even know where to
start right now because I, that
error. Is, means nothing,
nothing to me. So, you know,
it's just
nice to have people there and to
build that community because you
can be part of the community
building aspect of things. Um,
so
as you kind of look forward into
your future, do you think that
you'll continue to value? Or are
there lessons that you've
learned
over the last you know, year or
so you're hoping to take with
you
or to grow with.
Maeling: Awesome question. At
the top of my mind, I feel like
one
of the things I want to continue
developing is just that
connection to community. Um,
it's just so integral to
development,
no matter what industry you're
in it just makes life more
meaningful as well. I, I value,
you know, genuine personal
connections and being able to
grow alongside others who have
similar goals and visions is
priceless to me. So that's,
that's something I highly value
and will always striving to do
develop more. And as far as like
looking into the future, I, I
want to, at some point be more
active in sharing more of the
knowledge that I'm learning, um,
to just help others, because
that
was so priceless to me on the
other side, when I was learning
from others. And so I want to be
able to give back in that way, I
feel like I still need to get
this work-life balance situation
together before I start pouring
energy into that. But that's
definitely the horizon and
something that I would be
passionate about contributing
towards.
Bekah: well, you got the notes,
so always
Maeling: the notes are there.
Bekah: They're there. Well,
thank you Maeling so much for
being
here with us today. This was
very awesome. And I have learned
a
lot. And so, yeah, thanks so
much.
Maeling: Um, my pleasure really
enjoyed chatting with you all.
Dan: Yeah, thanks. Maeling all
right. We will, uh, yeah, I
guess
we'll talk to you. I don't know
where the sentence is going. I'm
sorry. I totally lost the whole
thing, man. I made it almost the
whole way without totally
imploding. Bekah you say by,
this
is the part, this is the part
where
Bekah: We're not good at saying
goodbye. So you
Dan: Every, every time.
Bekah: we usually stare at
eachother awkwardly or
something.
So thanks Maeling, bye.
Dan: Oh man. Thank you for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and was
edited by Andy Bonjour at
GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our
Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please
subscribe to our podcast and be
sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!