Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season four, episode nine of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. they're here on
this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you. with me today, is my cohost,
Dan.
Dan: Thanks Bekah, this is the
final episode of season four. So
as is traditional, now we have
with us Kirk TK Shillingford
himself. Um, and you know, you
all know Kirk, he's a maintainer
of Virtual Coffee and a long time
member and, uh, obviously a great
person and, uh, we're we're gonna
kind of today. Talk a little bit
about the last year, but, um,
what we've done, a Virtual
Coffee, we just wrapped up
Hacktoberfest and we are into
our, uh, November monthly
challenge, which we'll talk about
a little bit. And, um, what kind
of just, I don't know, hang out
and chat for awhile. It's a
little bit different format than
usual, but, um, it's kind of a
fun way to wrap up the season
and, uh, yeah,
Bekah: So we're going to start
this episode of the podcast. Like
we start every Virtual Coffee
with our name, where we're from
what we do and a random check-in
question. We hope you enjoy this
episode. Today's random check-in
question. Is, would you rather be
able to run at 100 miles per hour
or fly at 10 miles per hour? So
I'm Bekah. a front end developer
from a small town in Ohio and to
fly at 10 miles per hour would be
cool, but I'm like terrified of
flying. I don't like it at all. I
think I'm going to stay on the
ground and I'm going to run a
hundred miles per.
Dan: All right. All right. Um, I
am Dan, I do computer stuff from
Cleveland and, uh, yeah. Um, I
don't know. I, you know, you get
into these questions and then you
start, like, I need to know a
little more details. You know,
the running a hundred miles per
hour sort of situation is like,
okay. So like, if you ran a
hundred per, like right now, one
of us just started running a
hundred miles per hour, your
shoes would explode instantly,
you know, would your feet
Bekah: they, is that true? Has
that been tested
Dan: I don't know about
instantly, but like they would,
well, I mean, I guess if you only
ran for 30 seconds or something,
then maybe that's fine, you know,
but if you ran a hundred miles in
your shoes at one time, maybe
they'd be fine. They're not going
to be able to do it twice shoes
aren't built like that, you know?
So you'd have to get some special
Bekah: Bare feet. This is what
I'm talking
Dan: Bare feet. All right.
Bekah: In your bare feet. some
calluses, your a hundred miles an
hour.
Dan: I think I'm still gonna
choose flying at 10 miles an
hour. Uh, you know, that's a
faster pace than, uh, you know, a
general run. I mean, it's not
faster pace than like a
professional sprinter, but it is
a faster pace than any, you know,
sort of running in general. And,
uh, so plus flying, you know, you
can cut corners, obviously you
can go, but you don't have to
stick to, you know,
Bekah: Go over mountains.
Dan: right. Over mountains, over
houses, over traffic jams, et
cetera. So I'm doing fine. Plus I
actually like heights and I like
being able to see stuff and even
just being able to like go
straight up into the air and like
look around and then come back
down. That that'd be my jam. So
I'm choosing the flying option.
Bekah: Alright Kirk, What doyou
have?
Kirk: Oh it's my turn. Um, all
right. My name's Kirk, um,
software developer from the
Caribbean. Uh, this is not, there
was no question here. It's a
hundred percent fly. There was
no, other option is silly.
Bekah: Everyone picks on me on
these questions. I need to find
better questions. I think.
Kirk: The average human running
speed is 10 to 15 miles per hour.
So I could just fly as fast as I
run now. And everywhere where I
live is like Hills, right? It's
always a hill. So if I had to
run, just like zigzagging all the
way down the mountain, whereas I
could just fly down. You know,
you can do a just flight, you
know, it's flight,
Dan: I'm with you. It's like, if
you.
Kirk: You can take like, groups
and stuff,
Dan: Look at any map directions
and the route to anywhere you go
is all sorts of zig zags and
curves and all that stuff. Even
on an interstate. But if you're
flying, you don't have to worry
about any of that.
Bekah: Well, I mean like
rollercoasters are fun, Right.
Cause you go very fast up and
down Hills,
Dan: But you could still go on
coasters.
Kirk: That's the biggest roller
coaster I've ever heard.
Bekah: All right. I feel like I
lost. And this is an introduction
question. Well, I suppose I'm
going to try harder the rest of
this podcast episode.
Kirk: Flying and like a pigeon
just like smacks me and Dan in
the face feel a lot better. Like
we'll really eat our words, you
know?
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I'll just, I'll, I'll run
to you as quickly as possible. So
can take the emergency room.
Dan: Yeah. But you can't run to
Kirk cause he's on an island, but
we could fly.
Bekah: If you're running a
hundred miles an hour, you can
just run on water that
scientifically proven.
Dan: And you,
Kirk: I mean,
Dan: is that the, is that the,
that's the speed at which you
just stay on top of the water?
suppose you got, uh,
Bekah: 100... 99 I think maybe.
So I've got
Dan: If you could run a hundred
miles per hour, probably you
could like, hang your feet over a
boat and then you know, like,
well, this is like in, um, in
Incredibles, right? So it's like,
uh,
Bekah: leg
Dan: there. Yeah.
Bekah: that's what it's about
Dan: And he did skim across at
least a small pond. So,
Kirk: No. They're like you pick
this running it, but won't help
you with your favorite thing,
which is box jumps
Bekah: Well, it, it will not help
me to jump higher. guess if you
get a good running start, then
maybe
Dan: Then you'll just crash into
the box though. The, your Crash
Kirk: the box??
Bekah: why am I going, to crash
into the box?
Dan: Your momentum will be going
forward. Well, then you'll fly
over the box. And I suppose
Bekah: So then I'm flying at 12
miles an hour And I beat be you.
Kirk: Uh,
Bekah: Welcome to all our new
listeners out there. It's just a
podcast about developer
communities.
Dan: And goodbye to all of our
oldest.
Kirk: Now they know what they're
in there for
Dan: Yeah, that's true.
Bekah: Um,
Dan: I was honestly hoping for
some sort of fantasy or, you
know, comic book related
questions so we can try to make
Kirk cry on air.
Kirk: You know, No, Bryan was
here the last time and you didn't
mention these like the biggest
Lord of the Rings, Like nerd-fan.
You could have totally, you know,
Dan: That's true. I forgot about
that. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I could have really poked at
him for two.
Bekah: I think Bryan, Bryan, um,
can, uh, get out of control
pretty easily though. So we were
trying make this in the PG range.
Dan: That's true.
Kirk: And
Dan: That's
Kirk: He did really well.
Dan: I only had to edit out like
three curse words. I think the
first time we had to do that.
Bekah: We had decisions about
what was appropriate to stay.
Kirk: I found out that PG 13, you
get one F-bomb.
Bekah: Yes you do do but there
are certain contexts you may not
use it in. So how you use it also
impacts whether or not you get
that one. The more, you know,
Dan: Valuable information.
Bekah: Uh, okay. So I thought
today it would be good to when we
have Virtual Coffee every Tuesday
and Thursday, do, um, everybody
comes into the big Zoom room and
then we go into breakout rooms
and we usually have eight to 10
people in the breakout rooms with
a room leader note taker. And we
always have a back pocket topic.
And we do that to make sure that
if nobody has something they want
to talk about or bring up that
we, go ahead and have something
prepared. And so I pulled from
our back pocket topics for this
episode, because I think it makes
sense in the context of what we
have been doing over the past
couple of months. And so the, our
back pocket topic that we have
talked about before in Virtual
Coffee with open source software,
We talked about the most painful
barriers to entry for open source
contributions, how to reduce
those barriers favorite open
source repos to contribute to.
since we just wrapped, wrapped up
Hacktoberfest, I thought it would
be good to, jump into this and
see what we've learned. Uh, two
years of doing Hacktoberfest
initiatives with a community. If
we've learned anything more about
this or what we think. So who
wants to get the conversation
started?
Dan: Um, I'll go, uh, you know,
I, I think my, my biggest lesson
and it was a lesson that I, it
took me a bit to learn the first
time. Right. And it really
solidified this last time is
that, um, open source is, you
know, you, you use the phrase
painful barriers to entry, right?
And that, that like that barrier
to entry exists for everybody
that hasn't done it yet. And not
just, um, not just new
developers, uh, experienced
developers, you know, people
who've been writing code,
writing, building websites, doing
all this stuff for years and
years and years, if they haven't,
uh, you know, up until they do it
for the first time, uh, they,
there is there's this barrier,
you know, and there's a whole
world of, um, you know, Unknowns
and that that's like, that's
been, the biggest thing for me
is, is the unknowns and, and
providing support for that right.
Is, is kind of whatever, what
I've, you know, what we've made
our goal. Um, there's technical
things to know, you know, um,
there's all the Git stuff and
merging and all that stuff. And
then there's Git Hub technical
stuff on top of that, right? How
pull requests actually work and
forking, which is a huge, you
know, a ball of stuff to figure
out. Um, but then there's the
social aspect of it, which I, you
know, which I found personally,
like that was my biggest barrier,
you know, getting into open
source, uh, in the first place
was the sort of anxiety around,
um, you know, jumping into this
thing with people you don't know
on, um, Even if I feel confident
in my ability to write a piece of
code or whatever it is, you know,
for the task, like, like there's
still a large space of
possibility to embarrass myself,
you know, for one, for one thing.
Uh, right. And you know how like
so-so figuring out how to, um,
how to find ways to contribute
and how to be more comfortable
with it. And it's honestly that
there's, uh, there's we can write
and talk about all the different,
like possibilities and different
things to look into, but let's
like, get just diving in is
really, it's like breaking the
seal kind of right. It's like,
you know, once you start getting
doing it a little bit, it becomes
much easier every, every time.
Uh, so that's, that's been my,
like, that's been my big. Lesson
is, is like remembering that this
is hard and it's hard for
anybody, uh, who hasn't done it
before. It's hard for, I mean,
it's still hard, even if you have
done it before it, you know, if
you're, if you're trying to join
a new project or whatever for the
first time. Um, but that's, I
don't know. That's been the thing
that's been the back of my mind
for all, all of our stuff that
we've, that we've been doing. Um,
I feel like we've helped, but you
know, that's anyway, that's,
that's my main, that's my main,
uh, I don't know, lesson, I guess
that I think about it.
Bekah: Yeah. And I, when I saw
those barriers too, with some of
my mentees, both of them I think
were first-time contributors.
And, one of them picked up a
first timer, an issue for a first
timer it didn't. Go into the
issue and describe the whole
process that was required even
commit or to run the project. So
she had to learn about Docker.
She had to learn about test
writing there were all of these
things that I'm like, I, I am
going to do my best to help you,
but I've never done any of these
things and it's not spelled out
in the issue either. And she, she
really pushed through it and did
an amazing job and reached out to
this, their Discord community to
get some help. But I just
thought, wow, that's really
overwhelming to jump into it.
And, the way that it was, um,
phrased seemed like it would be a
fairly simple issue. And it
turned out to be really in depth
and required a lot of different
pieces that weren't laid out in
the issue. And so like that, like
those kinds of things are always
something that. I am surprised
by, especially for, um, w and
repositories that have a lot of
people contributing, not having
clearly written documentation. It
continually surprises me.
Kirk: Um, I'm not sure. I mean, I
do wish that there was a
standardization of the language,
but I feel like part of it is,
you know, even with we're doing
reviews for like PRS and issues
coming in, but then there's that
question of, you know, like who
reviews the review? So it's,
it's, you know, if you're a
person submitting a pull request,
then someone will take a look at
it and get feedback and give
comments. But if you're the
person writing the issue, you
know, do you get that same
treatment? And I think I can
really highlights even. you know,
like we discovered that when
contributing as a solo endeavor,
it's just like way, way harder
for all these reasons. Right. But
when maintaining as a solo
endeavor, it's also super
difficult. Cause you, you know,
it's not like someone's born. If
I can intimate knowledge about
how to present issues for people
to fix. And if you don't have a
support structure or you don't
have people who can review your
work, I feel like it's just so
much more likely that these
things happen and a maintainer
might not even know. They're
like, oh, you know, this is
enough context to solve this
problem. And it might take us on
us, but like it's enough context
given. And then there's a list of
givens. it. And this person
understands Docker, given this
person understands, get this
person understands our code base.
And there's like a whole, know,
Um, yeah, I think like my, my big
takeaway was just that, um,
community helps with community
helps with like every stage, you
know, and we did encounter a lot
of maintainers who were like, I
don't even know if my project is
inviting. Is this welcoming or
not? You know, what should I be
doing? Um, even internally in VC,
you know, it's, you always feel
better. Um, if at least one other
person has a chance to just, even
if you think like, well, I know
what I'm doing, it's just good to
get some lift. Yeah. That looks
good. Or I think that's a good
idea. Or maybe tweak this. Like,
it just, it helps so much. So I
feel like that was the big
takeaway. And last year we were
like, oh, it takes a lot of work
to do this. And like this year
it's still like, oh, it does.
Like, I don't know. It's and this
year was amazing. But it just
sort of like reinforced how much
effort is required. And like, I
think a DigitalOcean, know, put
in a lot of work, they updated
the site, you know, they took
some feedback from last year,
they made changes. They had a
fact like they, you know, they
went all in, but there were still
gaps and that's not like a, they
didn't do lot. It's like, there's
still just so much here because
ultimately we're telling people,
Hey, you should try to contribute
to a project in the tech space.
And the tech space is massive and
it's almost impossible to find
somebody has exactly the right
set of tools to completely help
you through something. So it's
this weird mismatch of
documentation, support, and
spawns time from the maintainers
access to resources. And
hopefully it all comes together
in a way that someone can make a
contribution and feel like
they've, they've done some good
quality work, but it's so easy
for one of those at least one to
be missing. then, you know, that,
that resistance that Dan
describes just like, then it's
like, I just, if I'm not sure I
can do a good job on this, you
know, am I getting paid for this?
Like, I'm not making mistakes for
free. So I think that's like my,
uh, my take.
Dan: Yeah, I would, I mean, I
would say that's my other main,
the main thing, especially that
solidified this, this year also
was the, the, the other side of
it, you know what I mean? Like
coming from the maintainers
perspective and, um, you know,
part of it is what I was saying
was like, you know, learning that
all of this stuff is hard and
trying to make your repository,
um, uh, open and available and
welcoming for an entire audience
of, you know, entire spectrum of,
uh, technical level and, you
know, experience and all that
stuff, uh, is, is really a really
hard, it's a hard balance to
strike. And, you know, do you, if
you're a maintainer of a project,
you know, Take on the
responsibility of teaching every
single potential contributor, how
to use Git, you know, for
instance, um, or how to use
anything, how to use Docker, you
know what I mean? Like the, like
you would like, I, I, the bare
minimum on honestly, would be
whatever command, you know, like
I imagined Bekah, the one that
you, the project you were talking
about, like had some, just like
go install Docker, and then run
this command, you know, and then
move on. Right. Like that would
be, um, and that, like, that
assumes, uh, assumes some amount
of knowledge and ability to
download things and configure
things, and also assumes that you
remembered all of the stuff you
did when you set up the project.
Right. Which is like very hard to
do. And then I think, correct.
What you said was what, like you
run into, uh, as a maintainer,
you know, lots of times somebody
might try to contribute, have a
problem, not be able to find an
answer and give up, you'll never
know, Right. Yeah. You'll never
know about it. And so that is
like one of the reasons why we
wanted to try to provide support
for maintainers, you know, and we
did that last year and this year,
you know, um, and is, is helping
maintainers, um, you know,
provide, you know, provide
information for the repositories
and get some extra sets of eyes
just on. Okay. Like what, what,
what does a person actually have
to do to install this, you know,
on their computer? What happens
if they're on windows? You know,
like all, all of this stuff and
maintainers don't have time. Most
of maintainers don't have time
for any of that stuff, you know,
it's, it's so hard to do. Um, and
so that's the other side of it
and it's like, I, I would
honestly. I've been thinking
recently in, in, you know, in my
own retrospective about
Hacktoberfest about whether we
should maybe have a maintainer,
like an OSS maintainer thing.
That's not Hacktoberfest, you
know? Cause it's so hard for us
to, um, you know, we have all, we
have lots of, lots of people that
were excited about contributing
and it was amazing, you know? And
I, I feel like we in preparing
for all of that, you know, could
have, I mean, we could spend a
whole month just on helping
people,
Bekah: I mean, we kind do, you
know?
Dan: Well, yeah,
Bekah: With preptember, we have a
whole list, but mean, I'm right.
there with you. I think, know,
providing that, providing very
active support to maintainers.
Cause I think that, especially if
you're a first time maintainer
it's, you don't realize the
amount of work that goes into
writing a good issue or having
the documentation or the labels
and stuff that you need. And then
there's not clear instructions
for what that looks like either.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And it
it'll look different depending on
your project. And, you know, if
it's like, Kirk has the Cordo
game, right. And so that's like
its own sort of, uh, it's a game.
Right. You know, so you can
download it, install it and run
it and all that stuff. And, but
some people have, um, projects
that are packages, you know, that
are dependencies for other
things, you know? And, uh, so
that like how much, like if you
make it React component, for
instance, as an open source
thing. Um, and there's a million
examples of that out there. You
know, how much like teaching
about React? Do you put into your
documentation for your thing? You
know, it reminds me of, um, we,
we talked with Jessica, I guess
this will be a couple of weeks
ago when this one comes out and,
um, you know, she does... a
really good job writing articles.
And we talked a lot about, um,
how to, how to like set that
level of, um, expectations for
when you're reading which in her
case it was tutorials and things
like tech tech articles, but it
applies, I think, to
documentation too, you know? And
so one of the things she tries to
do is, um, as either, if she's
not going to deep dive into
everything, you know, she'll,
she'll add some steps of a
prerequisite she calls them at
the, at the beginning of the
article and I think that's a
great, like a great resource, uh,
you know, to do. And I, and I've
been thinking about it a lot at
applying to documentation as
well. Right. So prerequisites for
this package, you know, um, read
about React or whatever, you
know, uh, uh, this package, it
depends on the useEffect hook.
Here's like three blog posts
about it or something like that,
you know, for example, you
Bekah: yeah, I feel I mean, you
can even make that an issue for
somebody, To add that to your
documentation. How does somebody
get here from different levels or
what are the resources people
could use?
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And we
say, you know, lots of times
it's, uh, one of those, like, I
don't know, tricky teachery
answers, but you know, oh, like I
couldn't figure out how this
project works and then I figured
it out. And so, so somebody will
just say, okay, we'll make, make
a pull request and fix the docs.
You know what I mean? And it's
like, I dunno, I always feel
snarky, you know, um, saying that
to somebody who's, who's still
learning and new to this, but
improving documentation is one of
those things that, um,
maintainers, I think will almost
always welcome, you know, at at
least welcome to the discussion
and, um, I don't know.
Bekah: I added a number of
issues, I think, to repos this
year for that documentation issue
and told other people to do it
too, And said, you know, you are
stuck on this. So somebody else
who wants to contribute will be
stuck on it as well. If you raise
an issue on somebody takes on the
documentation, you're helping
next people that are coming
towards coming to work on this
project and enriching the
community. And, know, I just hope
that those kinds of things get
raised too. And recognizing you
can add an issue having to do the
PR yourself.
Dan: on yes
Bekah: But just making people
aware. Cause sometimes if you've
been in it for so long, it's hard
to remember that you have to go
through all of these steps.
Dan: How were those received,
where those on those were other
than other people's projects?
Bekah: Yeah. So I got a couple of
messages just asking for a little
bit more clear. Some of them were
just like, I need to put this
down. I was doing them from my
phone, which makes it a little
bit more difficult, but I do use
the Git Hub app a lot. Um, and
so, you know, talking through,
okay, well these are the things
like, and in some were as simple
as it would be really. helpful if
you had a form for, um, issues.
So you can select the different
type of issue just to make it
clearer, to add labeling, really
click quickly and for people to
look through things. And so,
know, some were receptive, some
didn't respond and you know, I
just, my best to improve
documentation this year.
Dan: well, there's only so much
you can do as a, as a individual
contributor. And, you know, we've
all said it, but it's a lot of
work as a maintainer. And so if
you make a issue or make a pull
request and it doesn't, I don't
know, it just gets ignored or
whatever. I just gotta remember
that there's people on the other
end then. Um, I don't know. It's
hard lots of times,
Kirk: Yeah, I think, well, the
context of, um, this is people
donating their free time, but
attempting to help people
donating their free time, and
like, if it works ways. Um, it's
sort of like, it's good to keep
empathy when you're dealing with
someone who is maybe like
confused or as like a lot of
questions. Cause like, Hey, this
person is like literally trying
to help me for free. Um, it works
the other way. Cause sometimes,
you know, I will send a message
to a repo maintainer and they
won't respond and then I'll
eventually be, and I'm like, you
know, also this is like not their
job and it's also not my job, you
know? Like we're all we give it a
shot. And then like ultimately,
which, which is, I think why it's
such a valuable thing for
developers at all levels, you
know, it's, it's a very low
stakes way to do something good.
To get more experience, to build
community, to, you know, explore
spaces you'd like to try before,
like, and you know, like that's
like, that's our motivation. We,
we genuinely think. Contributing,
oh, sources of good thing to do,
or at least to try. Um, there's
many things. Like I would not
have the opportunity necessarily
to have done in like workplaces,
but that's okay because I can do
it in an open source environment.
I can still get that practice and
that experience, but, you know,
that's the key thing is like, you
know, we're, we're trying to do
our best, everyone's trying, so
like, you know, if people can't
or they have to take as long as,
as long as like being a jerk,
don't be a jerk. If you're
listening out there, don't be a
jerk. know, not you, you, um, but
it's also okay to say, um, I have
a lot on my plate right now, or
this is a little overwhelming or
I don't have the bandwidth for
it. Uh, a couple of my mentees
were like, Hey, this is actually
a super busy month for me. I'm
like, that's, it's okay. You
know, like these repos will be
around after hacktberfest. I'll
be around after Hacktoberfest,
you know, like, uh, PR is just as
good in month, know, this month
is like, it, it gets the
community going, but know, like
people have in Virtual Coffee is
going to be like, ask me next
year. You know? So I think like
that, it's also like important
to, I especially say that as
somebody who spent a lot of time
this month, like I didn't get to
submit many things to other
repos, not as much as I wanted
to, but.
Dan: Yeah, no, it is okay. And
it's like, yeah, we, I mean, we
make this push based on
Hacktoberfest and DigitalOcean
cause they do this thing and it's
very fun, you know? And it's,
it's cool to get the challenge
completed if you want. But, uh,
it's also. Like we've said on
both sides of the, you know, uh,
on both sides of it. It's people
spending their free time working
on other things for free. So it's
all good, you know? Um,
Bekah: probably do one in, too.
Dan: uh, July, hacktober. Well,
we'd have to come up with a
different name,
Bekah: Yeah. I'm sure,
Kirk: Jul-Ober
Bekah: this is why, so it's so,
because, so it's so popular now.
It can be really hard to find
good issues because they just get
taken so quickly. that's one of
the biggest frustrations I see
with a lot of people who are new
to open source. mean, we need
somebody who will, will back the
t-shirts and the sticker packs
and mail them because we all know
that I will not mail them and
forbidden for mailing things,
Then then there's less of a, I
don't, maybe there's just
different months for
Hacktoberfest, right? This month
is devoted to contributors or
first-time contributors. And this
month is devoted for someone who
has been a developer for a while,
hasn't contributed before. I
don't know, like breaking it
down. So it seems less of like a
race to get things done because I
felt the same, Kirk. I really
wanted to make some, what I felt
were meaningful contributions and
didn't get there and I still want
to, but it was just, you know,
trying to support other people.
And then I think I spent an hour
and a half, one day looking at
issues. I'm like, okay. I just, I
don't, I don't have time an app
to look for an issue for an hour
and a half.
Kirk: Yeah, I think that's, you
know, it in the, in the vein of
takeaways, that is the thing that
I think as a community, as a tech
community, we underestimate it's
again, just find an issue and
grab it. That's not, that's a
non-trivial process, you know,
unless. You are fortunate to have
not to like, know someone was
like, Hey, here's a great issue.
And they like, you know, hand it
to you, but even then you still
have to familiarize yourself.
Like it's still an entire
software project. And if it's
open source, it's like you know,
like a meaningful software
project, like it's doing a real
thing, but you have to
familiarize yourself with it's
someone else's work and no matter
how much we say you do want to do
a good job. So, you know, and
that just takes And I think it
takes time in a way that, like, I
feel like it's very difficult to
say, okay, I'm going to work on
this PR and I'm going to do 10
minutes every day. Like, it's not
like meditation. Like you
probably, you know, it's like, is
going to take me a couple of
hours to sit with this problem
and then some time to make the
solution and then to get the PR.
Um, and I don't know if there's a
good solution for that. I think
in our community. We did a lot of
consolidation, which I liked a
lot of people are like, Hey, this
Repo seems to have some good
resources and we would get that
all in a central place. Um, and
then of course, you know, like
we, are people in the
organization who have
repositories and, you know, can
like, keep, you can say like,
Hey, do you have an issue? And we
can make sure you get, I'll make
sure there's one for you. And
that's, that's a nice way to, but
I don't know if that is scalable
to the larger OSS initiative. Um,
we still run to run into the
issues of what does newbie mean?
Is it just to open source? Is it
new to programming? Is it to the
Git commit to PR life cycle? And
where does that fall? Uh, so
yeah, it's, it's, complex and
it's, it's hard and everyone is
trying, but I do. And do you
think that maybe trying to do of
that in the 30 days is it's a
challenge. Um, and I, you know,
I'm even thinking it's like
September for, for Hacktoberfest,
like maybe where, there's like a
bunch of different preps. I would
almost want to do the maintainer
stuff like a month or two, even
before that, you know, like a,
Hey, do you want to be a
maintainer for project? And we
just spend a month getting people
like set up there and we talk
about like healthy patterns and
schedules the docs up to date.
And because I could spend a month
just working on good issues. And
I think that's what I maybe
wanted, like next time. And next
time I need to take an entire
month with my projects. Like my
job is just every few days or
once a week. write some more
fluid issues, because I think for
the maintainer, that is probably
the largest time sink. It's just
having the good issues available.
And then you can spend the actual
month kind of focused on getting
people over the finish line, but
you have enough time to get
reviews and ask for help and get
some feedback. So, you know,
like, Hey, I'm, I'm ready to go.
Bekah: Yeah, it does seem like
having a whole open source
quarter of the year would make
sense to develop those skills. I
like it.
Kirk: hack order year. No, we can
workshop that.
Bekah: If anybody has
suggestions, you can email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: Yeah. I mean, writing issues
takes forever. That's the other,
I mean, it is the other problem.
I spent hours writing issues for,
just for our site. And I think
over the two months, you know, I
probably wrote 20 issues and they
all took a long time. They all
got done or, you know, or in the
process of being done. Uh, but
that's still just 20, you know,
and we had, I mean, we had lots
of people wanting to involved
in...
Bekah: What are the stats?
Dan: Oh, well, so I was, I was,
yeah, I know. W w we, uh, I
thought about that. We didn't,
but then, um, might as well, I
mean, like I have this, I have
this pulled up, so now it would
be a good time we could do a
little Hacktoberfest, uh,
results. So we, so for Virtual
Coffee members, right, we had a
hundred members sign up, um,
including contributors and, um,
mentors and maintainers. And of
those a hundred, at least 66
members had merged at least one
pull request, uh, in October and
collectively, uh, merged 336 pull
requests across 129 different
repositories in the month of
October. And that's just our
members, um, which is just
incredible. I am like still
astounded by it. Um, and you
know, some of those, like, I
didn't, this is not checking
against Hacktoberfest, you know,
rules or whatever. And, you know,
I know. There are some that can
be, you know, probably emerged in
November with still counting and
all that stuff. So there's
probably even more, um, as to
say, um, on, on the Virtual
Coffee IO site, which is an
open-source project. And, you
know, I, I was sort of leading,
maintaining this month. Uh, well,
in October, um, we had 81 poll
requests merged, uh, in the month
of October. And so 50 of those
are, um, you know, we had our new
like member profiles set up. And
so members could either add or
update them their, you know,
their information on our sites.
So 50 of those or those, and then
we have 31, um, pull requests
that were, uh, not that new
features or fixes and all of that
stuff. And, uh, that also is just
a enormous number and it's, it's
really cool. Uh, very, very cool.
Um, a you had, so you had like
four, I think four different
issues merged or pull requests
merged in, um, October. She did
some really good accessibility
work. Todd Libby also did some
good accessibility features. So
our site is, uh, I don't know, it
has vastly improved accessibility
features now, um, which is
awesome. Um, Abbey hit did a
really cool style update that
I've been wanting to do for a
very long time. And I very
appreciate that. Uh, Matt McInnis
actually did. Good, uh, tooling
updates for us added prettier,
which I've been also wanting to
do for a long time. Um, and that
was a huge pull request cause he
basically formatted the entire,
every file in the whole site.
And, uh, he worked with like, we
worked together for a long time
and he was very patient with me
cause I get picky with some
things and uh, and it was great
and he added some, uh, some
other, some BS code stuff, uh,
which was really cool. Um, and
yeah, and we had, we had a bunch
of other different, um, kind of
features and fixes and
documentation updates and you
know, our content, a lot of our
content is in Git Hub. So there
was, uh, people doing writing for
us or, you know, updating
documentation. Um, that was
really cool. So, you know, I feel
like we succeeded both as a
community for the, you know,
general Virtual Coffee, uh,
Hacktoberfest initiative. Uh, and
also as, you know, as a, as a
maintainer of this project, you
know, it, it, we. made a lot of
progress and it was really cool.
So I was excited about that. This
is a fun month. It's a lot of
work. Uh that's 81 pull requests
that, you know, we had merged and
all that stuff. So it's good
stuff. So that was our sort of
high-level summary.
Kirk: Yeah. And I think in
addition, uh, this month was just
really awesome in terms of the
community I've been supporting
each other. We got heavy use of
Hacktoberfest coworking room.
Heavy use out of Help and Pairing
just a lot of people being
willing to help each other out on
set ups and installs had a lot of
good questions are being answered
by people in the community. It
was just like very, just all
around a team effort, I think
really good to see. So, you know,
was, that was great. If we could
just do that in tech everywhere,
you know, It'd be kinda cool.
Dan: I mean, agreed. It's it does
bring into focus, all this stuff
we've been talking about, you
know, how, how much kind of
support can be needed, you know,
especially to get started, but
it's good stuff. It was a good,
it was a good month. It
Kirk: As we do hacked order,
there'll be even cooler.
Dan: Hack Fest Corder. Um, Bekah,
do you want to talk a little bit
about what we're doing this
month?
Bekah: Yeah, sure. So this is
this marks one year of monthly
challenges. So November, we came
off a Hacktoberfest and we were
like, let's start doing monthly
challenges have lightning talks,
was an ex. We were very exhausted
after that month. So this, this
year, you're not doing lightning
talks in November, but we are
continuing with monthly
challenges and we're doing the
same one that we started off with
last year, which is national
novel writing month. We talked
about this and Jessica's episode,
but all working together to where
our goal was 50,000 words to
write in our tech blogs and hit
50,000 words. we are past that
point today is November 15th.
we're halfway through the month
and we have surpassed our goal.
And so we upped it to, I think, a
hundred thousand now right?
Dan: Yeah, it's the first that's
strech goal one 50, a a hundred
thousand. So. We, yeah, we hit
our challenge, I think on the
12th or the 13th, something like
that. We had, we had,
Bekah: According to Friday, we
hadn't hit it yet. Cause I posted
in slack and I said, who who's
writing? Can we get to 50,000 by
Monday? And it was before, before
today that we hit it, but it's
just been so fun to watch the
monthly challenges. Some of them
have worked out really well and
been great. Others have not. Um,
but the nice thing is, you know,
some of those monthly challenges.
We're scrambling at the end of
the month, last year to try and
get something together. Cause it
was new to us and we were trying
to figure out how can we make
something that everyone can
participate in at any stage of
their tech journey. And so trying
to make it open to everybody and
have folks be interested. Um,
sometimes it just difficult to
do, but now we have a solid set
of challenges that we'll go ahead
and repeat, and we're working on
this cycle of what that should
look like. So I'm really excited
to see how these play out in the
next year as we go through 11
more challenges and see how we
can get the community involved
and get them excited. Obviously
they're excited about this one.
They were excited last month we
did use Hacktoberfest as our
monthly challenge. and so we're
going on a string of a lot of
people being really excited about
the things that we're doing. And,
you know, Kirk, you you've been,
you've put a ton of time and
effort into the monthly
challenges too. So are you
excited about?
Kirk: So many beings, uh, it's
just nice to be, I think in it's
nice to have the comparison data.
I feel like 2020 was a lot of
what guests were doing this, you
know?
Bekah: Structured yellow.
Kirk: Yeah. Sort of like, uh, I
guess I'm a member of this
community. Oh no. Am I a
maintainer? Well
Bekah: Just kept pulling you in
for more.
Kirk: also, yeah, like this time
when you're like, Hey, should we
do the lightning talks again
after Hacktoberfest? And we were
like, no, no, we should not
because we have learned lessons
from the last time.
Bekah: Yup. We learned them.
Kirk: Um, yeah. So, you know, I,
it's nice to have like a year
feedback. Right. We have a year
of challenge feedback. Um, you
know, we have a cast of VC
members who are now also
supporting us on these. Right.
Um, and know, I'm looking forward
to, we get, as we get towards the
end of the year and just, you
know, just like going back and
appreciating all the stuff that
we've done, because I think we've
done a lot and I think that you
know like the real spirit kind of
like started all this is still
here and still strong Um but also
a good chance to you know like
take stock and go okay like what
did work and why what didn't work
and why and you can maybe you
know like let's we can get better
at things And I think that's what
I'm excited about You know like
even with this time Hacktoberfest
it's like okay well we know what
went right The last time we said
Hey what went right Let's do more
of that You know And we were like
Hey what was a little wonkie It's
like well let's see if we can
shore that up And then it gets to
that again So each time we get
sort of like better and better
and know we spend most of our
time going ah this is tomorrow Ah
and all the time know going ah
what are we going to do in three
months Ah it's the same energy
just like a different a different
timeframe And so hopefully by the
end of it you know we're just
like flying at 10 miles an hour
instead of like frantically
running at a hundred miles an
hour, you know, just the
Dan: It's obviously the better,
yeah. The better situation to be,
Kirk: way better.
Bekah: Maybe, maybe captures
something deeper.
Dan: uh, real quick. I just
wanted to shout out, you know,
Kirk mentioned having help with
monthly challenges and, uh, two
of our members Aurelie and um,
Andrew had been leading, so we
created a month of challenge team
and, um, they've been doing a lot
of work helping the same with
the, with the same thing,
helping, uh, plan and, uh, and
execute these challenges for the
last I don't, I don't know how
long, a few months, at least, uh,
and it's been, it has been, it's
been really awesome to have, um,
community members, you know,
excited about. Creating, you
know, helping create these and
brainstorm and do all the work
that goes involved. You know,
like all the work that's involved
with, uh, putting these together
and, you know, it's been neat. So
I just wanted to say, thanks real
quick
Kirk: Yeah. I mean, even kind of
beyond the challenges, just
having. This expanded group. I
think of community members who I
can, like we can rely on for
feedback, for support and
encouragement for just like
really solid insights, you know?
Um, I know for all of us, there's
a people just like, oh, you know,
I need to talk to I ain't talk to
that person. They're always like
there and they always have great
advice And, you know, I feel like
even where the community is now
is as much a result. Uh, you
know, those people as it is like,
you know, like we're just, job is
to just like, get the good advice
and, you know, maybe like
condense it and maybe make some
priorities, but, uh, that's been
a big help. And I think like a
big relief, I, I, none of this
would be happening. I think if I
didn't know, like, oh, I can turn
to, to these folks and really...
be with a group of people who
have the same interests that I
do, which is just like making
this community as awesome, a
place as possible. So this also
feels like the year that more
than before. And it's awesome.
Bekah: Yeah. And going along with
what both of, you said, Kirk, you
were talking about feedback
earlier and you know, we've,
we've been working on feedback,
but it's one of those things that
I know that I have to I have to
deliberately make time for it
because feels like I like moving
forward quickly and sometimes
stopping to do retros. Like that
can be hard because it doesn't
feel like. Moving forward and
taking the time to do that really
ensures that you have the energy
to continue moving and helps you
focus on the other people who are
on your team and thinking about
like, okay, well, you know, how
can I better support people to
doing more of these things or to
contribute in ways that are
meaningful to them? And so, you
know, moving forward over the
next, you know, 11 or 12 months,
just really trying to make sure
that, I take the time to do that
something that I don't know that
I would say I'm excited for it,
but I am, I am happy to be
building that into part of my own
process, you know, to make sure
that we continue to support the
people who have supported us.
Dan: For sure.
Kirk: I am very proud to say that
a significant portion of the
people who like plan these events
and help out in this community
have ADHD or, you know, like
there's a, we're a big narrative
first group, I think. And, and we
make it work and we, you know,
try and focus on our strengths
and we encourage each other when
we're having like the not great
brain days. So. Yeah, we should
write a book about no, we should
not. We are not qualified.
Dan: Don't say that. she can hear
that.
Bekah: It's NaNoWriMo. We've got
two weeks left.
Kirk: Listen,
Bekah: can all together. We've
got this. Everybody could just
write a hundred words
Dan: yeah, it's a lightning talk
book
Bekah: we can inspired by Ray's
morning pages. If everybody
writes morning pages
Dan: Bekah. Bekah making, you're
a lightning talk book. This is
what you're doing.
Kirk: yeah
Dan: we agreed. not to do this
November.
Bekah: No
Kirk: a really passive aggresive.
Bekah: We agreed not to do
Lightning talks. We didn't agree
not to write a lightning talk
book.
Dan: tryin to work her way around
rules You write the first half,
I'll write the other half C no, I
shouldn't even say that. then
Brian healing thing, everything
is a challenge. I was going to
say what we should be really
passive, aggressive. Like when
wikipedia was doing like their
funding drive, where it's like,
do you know, you could just give
me $3, like, you've been using
this thing for like a decade. If
you just give me $3. You garbage,
you know, well, you write 140
characters, you know, like 10
times a day in your tweets, you
can give me a hundred words. be
like that. And then no one would
talk to us. Don't say that was a,
that was an example of what not
to do
Bekah: Going to use that.
Dan: Um,
Bekah: Oh,
Dan: good
Kirk: For those listening. We
wonder what our planning meetings
are like, can we usually schedule
an hour? And it takes about 20
minutes to get this out.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I feel like we've gotten
better at it. Or at least one
person will always be okay. You
know, actually we haven't had a
planning meeting in a while.
that's why.
Kirk: It's only because like at
least one person has like a
followup meeting.
Dan: We've all just gotten busier
as I think the problem is. So
there's more deadlines.
Bekah: Well, I mean, we do a
really good job of async
communication for the most part.
And so we're all, um, we have
pretty good processes and
structures that are in place to
allow us to do that and to know
like somebody's care of that or
somebody else's on top of this
other thing. And, um, so it's,
we, we are very good at being a
remote and async team like to put
that out there.
Kirk: We do not have a choice
though. I mean, and this year has
been, I mean, first of all, as
one of my coworkers said, the
last two years have been weird.
Um, but it has been a pretty big
year of change for the community.
So many people transitioning to
new roles in their life,
professional and otherwise, and
it really has like a lot of
people who've been in. New
ventures. Um, and we've all like
tried and not just the
maintainers, but like everyone is
sort of like try to be present
and still be supportive, even
through all these things
happening, which, you know, we
also do appreciate, you know, a
lot of members have been, you
know, they'll reach out and like,
Hey, I haven't been around a
while. It's not because I've
forgotten. I've just been doing
this. I'm like, it's okay. You
know, you should, um, settle into
your new job. You should take
care of the new baby, you know,
but like, that's, that's okay.
You know, we're, we're here and,
you know, it's, it's, it's a
place where people are always,
um, happy for your achievements
and then, and when you get to
make it back. We're always happy
to see you. So it's cool. Super
Bekah: I feel like there's a,
this is, this is a hot topic for
me right now, but I think that
there's such a focus on, people
providing support to large groups
and people that have a hundred
thousand. Followers or members
or, or whatever. And I really
think that the impact that gets
made in tech that gets passed on
that gets rippled through the
industry, happens in small
groups. it makes me mad. Anytime
somebody says, oh, you know, why
would we give support to a small
group? Because we don't get the
same audience. you, you get much
more than that audience, right?
You get every person that was
affected by that community who
goes out into the tech community
and spreads that same positivity
and empathetic approach and
support. And I think that if
you're looking to make change
with your, with your support,
with your money, whatever, then
you find those communities that
are doing good intimate group
development, support, that kind
of stuff. And that's where the
impact is made. That's my hot
take.
Kirk: Yeah.
Dan: yeah. I agree. And it like,
the we've talked about this
before, and this is like our, we
have stuck pretty strongly with
this, with that exact mentality.
You know, the, the word audience
is something we, we never, ever
used, never even think to use,
you know, with, with Virtual
Coffee stuff. Right. Cause we
don't, I don't know. It's not
that sort of thing. And that's
it, there's a lot of community
resources, right. That are based
from that standpoint of all of
these people are an audience, you
know, or followers or whatever.
Right. That's not us.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. The there's an
article. I'll post it in the show
notes. I'll find it. But the one
of the first lines was the
difference between the community
and audience is the way the chair
is facing. And I thought that did
a really nice job of kind of
framing are they just are all the
chairs facing you. Are you on a
platform where people are
listening to you? Is there
engagement you know, like to talk
about the coffee table method of
Virtual Coffee, like we're all
sitting around a table together.
Everybody is equal in the room.
has the opportunity to talk and
participate. It's not me talking
at you or you talking at me and,
that is that's how change is
made,
Dan: Except for if you're sitting
and listening to this podcast
Kirk: I mean, in this moment,
right now you in the audience,
Right now, as soon as the podcast
is over then, like
Bekah: everybody's invited to
come to virtual
Dan: I was just joking. Uh, no,
it is. And that's the thing that
makes Virtual Coffee, you know?
Good. And this is the reason I.
So much as the, is that fact,
right? It's not something that,
um, that any of us are talking
at, you know, so it's good stuff.
Kirk: And I think even the
freedom sometimes too, sometimes
it can be very freeing to listen,
you know, and you know, a lot of
members. Some days you don't want
to chat, you know, you don't want
to be sort of like the center
it's just nice to, I'm just
gonna, I just want to hang out in
this room. I just want to listen
to my friends. They just want to
like cue the voices, um, happens
in the co-working room as well.
You know, sometimes people just
pop in. They're like, Hey, I got,
you know, I'm about to do. We
just want to pop in and say hi to
my friends. You know, there's no,
that's not a, there's no real way
to monetize hellos, I'm sure as I
say, this is probably some like
hello dot JS, which
revolutionizing the way we send
audi-whatever, but you know, um,
yeah.
Bekah: Oh, Hey. There's no. Hello
dot JS. So you better grab that
up real quick.
Kirk: Ooh. Um, Roger Gentry, if
you're listening, Roger will
instantly get that domain for us.
we ask
Bekah: Um, wait. I'm I might be
lying. Actually. I take it back
there. There may be a hello dot
JS package. I'm not sure what you
use it for, so somebody else can
explore that. Sorry. What a
dissappointing way to end the
episode. Should I read a dad
joke? Is that a better way to
Kirk: alright, alright. one dad,
one dad joke
Bekah: joke?
Kirk: what a good one. got to be.
Bekah: no. Uh, Sorry, just trying
to find the best one. There's so
much pressure now. Um, uh,
Kirk: for those of your who...
Bekah: here we go.
Kirk: oh?
Bekah: Why should you avoid the
restaurant on the moon?
Dan: Why?
Bekah: You don't even wanna think
about it.
Dan: if it's a joke, is it a joke
or a riddle? I mean, I was
supposed to solve it or
Bekah: You try and solve it?
Dan: Like trying jokes with my
kids, don't understand
Kirk: tech hiring situation. This
is the questions. And if you get
it right, you get to move on to
round 14 of 37.
Dan: Uh, I'm out.
Bekah: because it doesn't have a
good atmosphere.
Kirk: We really
Bekah: you put me on spot?
Really? I had
Kirk: This one was on me. I, I
encourage this. We stayed in the
boat.
Bekah: Where does Bruce Wayne go
to use the toilet?
Dan: Now, I don't know if I'm
supposed to solve it or am I
supposed to just
Bekah: I mean, I
Dan: where I say, don't know
what,
Bekah: it. I guess I do jokes
wrong, to the bat room
Dan: oh,
Kirk: We can edit all of this out
Dan: you guys, I gotta go man.
Bekah: Well,
Dan: This is good.
Bekah: well, this is the end of
the podcast, so thank you all for
listening to four seasons of the
Virtual Coffee podcast, We're
going for six seasons and a
movie, right?
Dan: Please stay subscribed.
Bekah: I promise I have better
jokes next time.
Kirk: may not be the podcast you
need, but we're the podcast you
deserve.
Bekah: I think, I think this is,
this is probably it.
Dan: Yeah, this probably it. Uh,
so we'll, we'll, we'll be back,
um, I think in the new year,
right. Uh, for, for our next
season. So, um, you know, in the
meantime, keep coming to Tuesday,
Thursday, Virtual Coffees and,
uh, yeah, I don't know. I'll see
all of you later.
Kirk: See you later.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel, and was edited by
Andy Bonjour at GoodDay
Communications. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
our newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website at virtualcoffee.io. And
of course join us for our Virtual
Coffee Chats every Tuesday at
9:00 am Eastern and Thursday at
12:00 pm Eastern Please subscribe
to our podcast and be sure to
leave us a review. Thanks for
listening and we'll see you next
week!