Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
Season Five, Episode One of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned
and we're here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan: Yo what's up. We are back
season five, took a little break
off a couple of months off there.
Um, but now we're back. We're
ready to get going again with the
new season, we have a bunch of
great guests lined up and. I
don't know. I'm excited.
Bekah: Yeah. And it's not just
season five of the podcast, we're
also rolling into year three of
Virtual Coffee, so I feel like
this is not only to be a fun
season, but a fun year for
Virtual Coffee.
Dan: Absolutely. Uh, three years
is a long time. I don't know.
We've been through a lot. I feel
like, I feel like I'm still
excited about the whole thing, so
I don't know.
Bekah: Yeah, I think, see, I
think the third year of Virtual
Coffee is really exciting because
we're kind of established, we
know what we're doing, we know
who we are and now there's space
to grow and innovate and do new,
cool things. And I'm really
excited to be able to do that and
keep talking with the members of
our community as we do that. And
a lot of the people that we have
on the podcast this season are
people who've been around a
while. Um, We, we have some newer
members too, but it's, it's cool
to have that balance where
there's a different history of
Virtual Coffee that we're talking
about.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, I
agree. And it's cool to have all
of that mix going on at Virtual
Coffee as well. That's cool. So,
yeah, we're gonna kick off season
five of the podcast with, uh,
Brian Rinaldi. Um, Brian is a
developer experience engineer at
LaunchDarkly, um, and he's also
actively involved in the
community. He runs to some
developer meetups. One is called
cfe.dev. And he also runs a local
meetup, uh, Orlando Devs. Um, he
edits newsletters. He authors, he
has co coauthored a book about
JAMstack. Um, and he's just, he's
been around for a long time and
it was a really great time
talking with him.
Bekah: I'm, I really enjoyed this
conversation with Brian because I
use it as like my personal
mentoring session of how do you
DevRel, how has it changed? How
has community changed? And so,
um, really, we always start with
a list of questions, but I'm not
sure that I really looked at my
list as much as I was like, I
want to know more about this
thing. Please, please tell me
about it. So, uh, we, we cover
all of those fun topics of
DevRel, what it is, how it's
changed and, uh, getting his
advice as an expert in the field
was really awesome.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. Okay,
we're going to take a quick
sponsor break and then we'll hear
from Brian Rinaldi.
Bekah: Looking for developer
centered online events? Want to
share your knowledge with the
developer community? Attend and
host online events at
codementor.io/events. That's
codementor.io/events. We start
every episode of the podcast like
we start every Virtual Coffee. We
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do and a random check-in
question. We hope you enjoy this
episode. Today's random check-in
question is: what is your
favorite genre of movie? My name
is Bekah. I am a technical
community builder from a small
town in Ohio. And my favorite
genre of movie. It's probably
action superhero movie. I feel
like those are the things that
can keep my attention long enough
to get to the end. Um, uh, I like
a lot of TV shows and that, that
would be comedy, but that's not
the question. So.
Dan: Um, hi, I'm Dan. I do
computers. I was trying to think
of a new thing to say this this
season. And, uh, I didn't come up
with anything. So I generally do
front-end stuff and I am in
Cleveland and, uh, yeah, I'd say
action-y you know, with, with
like, uh, like with the little
sci-fi touch, I think is my, my
sweet spot. You know, so not the
hard scifi stuff, but like Star
Wars even, you know, is like,
it's not really scifi it's, it's
more action in space, you know?
And like superheroes are cool. I
go along the same, same lines as
Bekah.
Brian: And hi, I'm Brian Rinaldi.
I'm based in Orlando, Florida. I
am a developer experience
engineer at LaunchDarkly. And
this is a tough question for me
to answer, because like I was
thinking about it, I'm like, The
probably the best way to answer
is like, okay, what are my
favorite movies? And like all
time, it would be like, um,
Raiders of the lost Ark,
Ghostbusters, of the Rings
series. And, uh, and, um, well,
the Batman, one's not then more
recent Batman stuff. The, the,
uh,
Dan: Burton ones?
Brian: No, no, no, no. The Batman
Begins, and, uh, and, uh, what
was it? Dark Knight, Dark Knight.
Christopher Nolan ones. Yes,
exactly. I guess a lot of those
are action, but like Ghostbusters
is comedy. I mean, Lord of the
Rings is kind of fantasy, so I
don't know. That's where I'm
like, okay. I don't really know
if I have a genre
Dan: How about adventure movies?
Like you said, a
Brian: Indiana Jones.
Dan: Jones made me think of that.
And then, you
Brian: Yeah.
Dan: maybe it doesn't quite fit
in there, but like
Bekah: of
Dan: it kind of, you
Bekah: we'll have those common
themes.
Dan: all good movies.
Bekah: Yeah.
Brian: So anyway, um,
Bekah: movies.
Brian: I think, I think, you
know, nowadays I ended up
watching a lot of action in
movies. but that's, I feel like
that's partly cause like That's.
almost all there is.
Dan: That's. Yeah, that's our
only choice.
Bekah: Well, welcome Brian. We
are very, very excited to have
you here with us today. I'm
talking about developer advocacy,
advocacy, um, fostering
community, what you're doing with
cfe.dev, we always want to start
with origin stories here. So why
don't you give us your, how you
got to this point in your life.
Brian: Hmm. Well, um, I'm old,
first of all. So I got my, I got
started in web development, uh,
in like the mid nineties and, um,
and this was during the dot com
boom. And I started, I think, uh,
started messing around with flash
early flash and, and, uh, cold
fusion and in stuff like that.
And a buddy of mine helped me get
a job at a startup. Cold Fusion
development and kind of went from
there. Um, but how I got into
like developer advocacy is, is I
was, I was started writing
articles and running user groups
and meetups while we didn't call
them meet ups back then, which is
called the user groups. But I ran
user groups and, and I ran
conferences and stuff like that.
Most of them around like Adobe
products. And then I got hired by
Adobe to do community management
and, and, uh, well, call it
evangelism, I guess back then,
uh, we kind of dropped that term,
which I think is for the best.
Um,
Dan: I haven't heard that one for
a, but
Brian: Yeah. So that was like,
12, 13 years ago, something like
that. I don't know. Um, and I've
been doing devrel-ish jobs ever
since I, cause you know, devrel's
one of those areas where like
everybody has a different take on
it and everybody's role is kind
of different. So I've had very
different roles. Some of them are
straight devrel of like, you
know, you're kind of speaking at
conferences, writing blog posts,
and some of them were more behind
the scenes, like handling content
and stuff like that, but always
in a very similar, Um, devrel
adjacent kind of role.
Bekah: It seems like you've been
in devrel since the beginning of
devrel, right. Like right as that
started to pick up and I'm sure
it's changed a lot. What do you
think the biggest changes have
been.
Brian: Oh, God. Yeah, I mean, I
guess it was very early days of
devrel at the time that I got
into it. It was like, it was
like, Okay. there's a handful of
companies. And most of them were
big. Um, you know, Microsoft,
Google, uh, I had like some
devrel folks, but like most
companies did not have several
folks. Um, I think it was, seems
kind of superfluous. Uh, and now
I, one of the big things that's
changed is you see companies
they're startups and there, they
don't even have a marketing
department yet. They don't,
haven't even done their first
marketing hire. Their first
marketing hire is a devrel
person, right. They're like,
Okay. This person can handle all
the community things and can be.
Nope, authentic voice is this
kind of, you know, the, the term
that's used. And, and so like,
I've even had some of those roles
where I'm sending email campaigns
and stuff like that, which would
normally be a marketing person's
job. But, but we don't have a
marketing person yet. So, um,
that's definitely a big change.
So like every company seems to
kind of come out the gate. If
they're focused on developers,
they want to have a devrel person
right off the bat. And so lots of
jobs in it, whereas before it was
very hard to break into. Um, and,
and one of the great things about
that is there's a lot of room for
varied levels of experience.
Because back when I got into it,
you had to already be kind of
like a known entity and have been
around for a long time. And, and,
and this kind of limited
opportunities, I think for it was
a very well, the industry as a
whole was. White male centric.
It's still is unfortunately, but,
but even more so like that
limited opportunities, I think
for lots of people who, you know,
it basically leaned very heavily
towards um, white males because
that what they were looking for
was people who are already
well-known in that field. And it
was very hard to find women and
who were known. So I think
having, having it opened up to
different experiences and. The
types of people, not just the
road warrior as I call them who
would go to conferences and
conference to conference, to
conference and speak, which is
also a hard life that only fits
certain people. So, um, you know,
that's changed. And so I think
we've, we've now opened it up to
like, it's a, it's a completely
different field, um, in many
ways. And, and, and for the
better.
Bekah: Yeah, that's great. And I
mean, the pandemic of course has
had a big impact on what it looks
like too. It's just constantly
shifting.
Brian: Absolutely right. I mean,
you know, especially for those
people who, whose job was to go
from conference to conference
conference, like it didn't, it
wasn't even there. It's still
really, isn't, there's very few
in-person conferences. So you had
to kind of adjust.
Bekah: Yeah, somebody online
who's in devrel was saying it was
a tweet that DevRel people in
devrel need to really focus on
upping their video game because
they thought that was going to be
the next big thing. like, how do
I, I don't want to learn how to
edit a video. I just figured out
how to. Use a microphone and have
a camera that's not connected to
my laptop. So I feel like there's
just always so much to learn,
which makes it simultaneously
fun. But also like there are all
these other skills that you have
to bring with.
Brian: Yeah. And, but I think,
you know, the good companies that
do this, understand that not
everybody has, like, you can't
find very many people. I mean,
there are people. Seemingly good
at everything. Um, and you know,
and I love those people and hate
those people at the same time.
But, uh, but you know, it's
really hard to find somebody
who's like good at writing. Good
at video. Good at public
speaking, you know, Um, And so I
think that the companies that do
this right. what you're, you
know, kind of build on your
strengths. Right. me personally,
I'm also not, I can do videos. I
don't consider myself a
particularly good at video
person. I, it, it drives me
crazy. I love to write, uh, and I
love to run events and things
like that. And so like, you know,
when I've had the roles I've had
played to those strengths,
particularly when I'm at a
company that knows how I, I feel
like does differ. All right. Then
they play to your strengths and
don't necessarily feel like,
okay, you can't do video. You're
failing in some way. And, um,
because you can't get everything
out of a single person. That's
why you have, you have a team and
different people have those
different strengths and we play
to those strengths.
Bekah: Yeah, so, okay. So I'm
going to back up kind of a little
bit five years ago, maybe now.
Um, you, so in the midst of all
of this, you also started
cfe.dev. So why don't you talk a
little bit about what that is and
why you started doing that?
Brian: Yeah. So cfe.dev, uh it's
yeah. It's about five years ago.
I started it. And it's all
virtual events. Um, it's we run
two virtual meetups a month. Uh,
and then I also run obviously
virtual conferences and stuff
like thejam.dev, which has
finished yesterday, um, and moar
serverless and, and other, I have
flashback conference as well,
which was. Well, that one wasn't
person, but, Um, what's my one in
person events running under
cfe.dev. But anyway, uh, and
yeah, so this was before pandemic
forced us to go virtual. Uh, I, I
was, uh, I love running events
and I wanted to do some more of
it and I just kind of like,
honestly, it was initially
supposed to be in-person events
and then the in-person events
are. They're a heavy lift and
they're expensive and, and risky.
And so I was like, oh, you know
what, I'll start running some
virtual events and like in build
an audience and then run, uh, an
in-person event, you know, Um,
using, you know, kind of, I
already have an audience and then
I'll maybe they'll come to my
in-person event. And it
transitioned to be like, okay,
you know, virtual events actually
aren't that bad. I was not a
believer. I was like, I'll do
them just because. And then
there, there are things that
virtual events are great at. Um,
they're not great at everything
and you know, that interpersonal
react interaction. They're not
right. Although you all run one
that does do that well, uh, which
goes to show you can do it, but
it's hard to do. It's, it's hard
to get everything out of one
event, like to get great speakers
and interpersonal reaction, like
interactions and stuff like. Um,
but they are good. Like for
instance, one of the things I
love about running the online
conferences is people get to
interact with the speaker, even
if it's via chat and ask their
questions. But like asking
questions in an in real life
event is super, like, it just
never works out well. Right?
people start leaving at the end
when the speakers taking
questions and it's, you can't
hear the questioner and things
like that, like it's just never
really worked out. Um, But you
can get, you know, kind of
directly with the speaker in the
virtual event. Like ask, get your
question to answer it and have a
good conversation. Um, when it's
not prerecorded, um, open it up
to speakers who are anywhere in
everywhere and get speakers who
you might otherwise get, because
it would be too, or complicated,
or they can't travel. Um, You
know, or, you know, and you can
get attendees from anywhere,
right? Like if they don't have to
travel, they can the events are
free. So there's a lot of great
things about them. I, and, and
this is coming from somebody who
started this as a complete
skeptic. I was like, yeah,
virtual events suck. But, uh, you
know, I'll run, I'll run some
and, you know, cause it's, it's a
way to get started. And then now
I'm fully committed.
Dan: That's that's it's really
cool. I mean, it's, it's really,
I've been a fan of, uh, what
you've been doing at CFE for
awhile. And obviously we do a lot
of virtual events well. Um, I
kind of actually, it was going to
swing back. I had a question
stick in my head. I want to ask
it before I forget, but, um, so
it's. When you were telling me,
um, your origin story, you were
talking about how you've had
these communities that you
created your user groups, um, way
back, you know, when they were
still user groups. Right. And,
um, and I think that's really
interesting. I mean, I, I,
haven't heard of a lot of, um,
You know, current devrels that
have that sort of experience, you
know? And so I, I guess one of
the things I was wondering was
like, what, you know, Bekah
asked, what, what changed? Um, I
was wondering like, what what has
stayed the same? Like what are
some through lines you've seen,
um, from running communities, you
know, over however long, that's
been 20, 30 years not to put a
number on it, but
Brian: not quite 30 yet.
Dan: Yeah.
Brian: Um, so, you know, luckily
people can't see me and tell me
the hell. Wow. Yeah. he's old.
But, uh, um, you know, well that
part of it hasn't changed like,
like the, the need for like
local, you know, for developers
to kind of meet up in person. Um,
we, we don't call it. User groups
so much anymore. We, we call them
meetups, but like, would they
still exist? And they're still, I
think, an important part of, of
building a developer communities,
particularly. Uh, on a more like
local level, like, you know, I
run one here called Orlando devs.
Um, and, and we're probably the
biggest, we're the biggest
developer group here. I think
we're like 6,000 members, which
surprises people when they hear
Orlando, they don't think like we
have a big developer community.
Um, but, uh, But yet it's, it's
very different because while I
love the virtual events, I think
we still need to kind of meet up
in person. Right. And, and so
like I started running when
pandemic came, I ran some virtual
events for Orlando devs, and I
was like, it's weird. Cause I
love virtual events, but like
this doesn't work for, for
meetup, for my meet local meetup,
because these are people I just,
Dan: Yeah.
Brian: want to meet in person. I
mean, the speaker is. I love the
speakers, but like, I go there to
see the people then they hit the
speaker, the speaker. Whereas I
go to the online event to hear
the speaker and then, hopefully
meet some people it's kind of
like flipping it. So I think
that's a through line that, that
has stuck. Um, You know, I think,
know, we, a lot of, a lot of it,
things haven't really changed
that much in the fact that like,
you know, the in-person events
for devrel stuff is still
important. I think, you know, Um,
there's developers have, I think,
as a community, have a real need
to kind of connect, I think,
because this is a hard job and as
Bekah noted takes constant
learning. Um, and so like we're
always connecting to try and
learn from each other and, and
get new techniques and learn
about new tools. And because. You
know, it's not the kind of job
you can rest on your laurels, as
I say. Um, so, so all of that's
kind of the same. Um, the
technology has changed and, and
it's expanded, but, but it's not
that different. I mean,
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. That's that's
interesting. Yeah. I, I noticed
the same thing. We had, I run a
react meetup in Cleveland and
it's pretty new, you know, but it
was in person and we did the same
thing. We started trying to do
virtual events. Um, yeah, never,
never had the same feel. You
know? The, the people that would
show up were we're the diff we're
different people. I think, you
know, some people want to have
the in-person stuff and. You
know, it was, yeah. It never, um,
never felt right now. That's
interesting. And then you're
going to, you can find good
virtual events. Uh, but I feel
like the ones that have the ones
that have started fresh during
the pandemic are almost almost a
better, uh, in better shape, just
because, um, they start with that
in mind, you know, if that makes
sense, um,
Brian: Absolutely. I've watched,
cause one of the goals of, of
Orlando Devs is for actually a
not not-for-profit. um, Like we,
when we fund other local groups.
And so, like, I kind of have my,
know, kind of eye on all the
local groups and a lot of the
other local meetups went away
completely. Like they tried to do
the virtual thing when this went
on much longer, that it just was
hard to kind of keep that
momentum going. And so
Bekah: Okay.
Brian: hard to run the meetup.
Number one, like, I mean, it's,
it's a lot of effort. Um, and
yeah. To run a meetup and try and
keep that momentum virtually, uh,
when you really just want to meet
the people in person is,
difficult.
Bekah: Um, I, I'm going to circle
back a little bit to when I met
you, Brian, um, as you're talking
about this idea of developers,
they need community, they need
support. Right. And I had, I
don't know when we first met
Virtual Coffee had been going on
for awhile. And, you know, if you
know about Virtual Coffee, it was
not an intentional group or
community that started it just of
started from tweet and went from
there and we just kept doing it.
Right. And so it was all of his
learning as I was going along.
And people were like, well, why
don't you do this? I'm like,
well, okay, we'll do that too.
Um, but then at some point I
think it Meg Gutshall going to be
on this season of the podcast to
Hey, there's a meetup that's
awesome. It happens on Thursdays
at the same time as Virtual
Coffee and, and we can't ever,
like, I can't do both. So why
don't you figure something out?
And I'm like, oh, okay. so you
and I met up and I just remember
it being such a good meeting for
me because I'd been going through
all of this community building
and didn't really know exactly
what I was doing. And, you know,
there were good things that were
happening. There were things that
were frustrating or felt
overwhelming. And you were the
first person that I really got to
talk to about that. I talking to
you, like, why, why are you doing
cfe.dev? Cause I was still like
trying to figure out, like, why
am I doing Virtual Coffee? I
mean, it made sense, right?
Because I love the community and
I loved being able to learn and
grow with. But so many people
kept telling you, they're like,
it is not reasonable for you to
be doing Virtual Coffee. And I'm
like, is it? Like, who can I talk
to about this? And so I very much
appreciated being able to have
that support and talk openly with
you about that. I don't know how
I came off in that meeting,
probably came off like I was
falling off the deep end a little
bit, but, but I, I appreciate it,
like being able to have that
support as a community builder
with someone else that had, you
know, talked about those things.
Brian: Thanks. I, I mean, I don't
recall it being, I remember it
being a great conversation, so,
you know, it's nice for me. Cause
I honestly like, even though I've
been doing this a long time, I
don't have a lot of people I
could talk to about it. Most of
the people really, you know, I
don't know a lot of people who
run communities like Virtual
Coffee or like CFE dev or even,
even meetups. I mean, it's a
small. Group of people often,
even your local meetups are often
like run by like the same handful
of people who run multiples.
Right. Because they just, um, and
it's people who are passionate
about communities because you
certainly don't do it for the
glory or the money. Um, because
if you're waiting for those,
those. They don't really come
with with that. Um, you know, so
you just really gotta, you gotta
love doing it. I mean, every time
I ran, for instance, every time I
ran a conference, you know, I'd
be like, why do I put myself
through this? Why do I do this?
It's so stressful. It's so, and
then, uh, and then it was like
the, it came in. It's like, Oh,
my God, this is so awesome. I
loved seeing everybody. I loved
hearing the speakers and, you
know, um, And so, so then, then
I'll do it all over again and
I'll go through that same
process, even though I've been
doing it, like for like 15 years,
it's the same process. Why did I
do this? Why did I get myself
into it? Um, so it's, I think,
you know, being a community
organizer like that, like is, is,
uh, involves feeling like you're
going to quit, all the time-
Bekah: Yeah.
Brian: -had it, this is too much.
And, know, and I think people
also don't realize like kind of
the demands put, you know, they,
they want to share their ideas
and they're passionate about your
community
Bekah: Yeah.
Brian: then you have all these
input coming as the community
grows, like from all over the
place. And it's like, okay, I
can't, I can't please, everybody.
Um, so. Yeah, it's, it's not
easy. and so I, I totally, I
totally get you. And I'm amazed
by what you all have done with
Virtual Coffee. I mean, you know,
the you've got a really, really
great community there. I think
Bekah: Oh,
Brian: it feels, uh, you clearly
found.
Bekah: yeah.
Brian: A kind of gap in what
people needed, right? Like in,
especially during the pandemic,
but obviously I think you're
going to live well beyond the
pandemic, which is just. An easy
way to kind of connect with other
developers. And it's a very
casual kind of friendly
atmosphere. And, and I, you know,
and nobody's afraid to kind of
share their struggles or, you
know, talk about, Um, you know,
the they're working on and be
open with with everybody else. I
mean, and that's very, very rare.
I mean, Um, You know, even, even
when, when I've run, like the
in-person ones, right? Like, and
we all kind of know each other
right. In, it's just like, I'm
running this thing. And I got
speaker lined up and everybody
comes in this room and it's like
sitting there and I'm like, you
all talk to each other? Please
just can somebody just, you know,
speak to another person here
instead of sitting in the chair,
waiting for the speaker to come.
I mean, that's the point of this
you know, Um, so, so find that
you've created a space where
people feel open to talk like,
Nope, I've never been there where
like people don't share. Um, so
that's honestly, that's amazing,
you know, you've done something
special.
Bekah: Thank you means a lot.
Dan: Oh, no, I was just, I was
still just laughing about the,
the, you wanting to scream at
people to talk to each other. I
tried to solve that with a pizza
and would just come and get
pizza, and then sit back down
their seat.
Brian: I know.
Dan: just, just I'm putting all
the chairs away. Just talk.
Bekah: I, I've gone to a couple
of in-person conferences in the
last couple of months. And you
know, that idea of meeting people
in person and talking about that
being important. I like, I very
much felt that at one of the
conferences, for sure, because I
met other people who were doing
like small community building,
like we're doing, and to be able
to talk to them and hear, you
know, what they're going through.
And that really resonated
because. We are all feeling the
same thing. And I continually try
and go back to the spot of like,
how do we all figure out how to
support each other? Because I
think small communities are
really important because you get
to have those open conversations,
like rather than jumping into a
slack of 6,000 people or, you
know, whatever that.
Automatically overwhelming, but
you know, finding, trying to
figure out these ways. I haven't,
uh, haven't figured it out yet.
So if anyone has ideas, let me
know. Uh, but it is nice to be
able to have those conversations
openly with people that, that you
wouldn't see normally, or, you
know, I met someone. One of the
things that he does best is
connect other people at
conferences. He's not running the
conference, he's just making sure
people meet each other and can
have those important and
pertinent conversations. And
that's allowed for a ton of
growth and in a way that I would
be hard to have somewhere else
because you're just spending so
much time with people over a
period of 48 hours or whatever,
um, that it just like, I dunno,
There's a different energy and
investment into it. I think
Brian: yeah. Yeah. Couple of
in-person conferences too. Um,
since things have eased up and
how so think when, when you go to
these, they're not, they're
smaller than they were before,
which isn't necessarily bad. I
mean, it's tougher on the
conference organizers because,
you
Bekah: yeah.
Brian: they still need to kind
of, uh, you know, keep
Bekah: know.
Brian: the black, you know, not
lose, lose their shirts. Um, but
it's, it's kinda good for, for
the attendees because like, you
know, everybody there is like
there because they are eager meet
and talk to people. And so, like,
I found it to be different, like
conferences before, especially as
there were bigger, it's like, oh,
I go with a group, maybe a couple
of colleagues I kind of stick
with that group and I never
really get to interact with other
people outside of that. And it's
hard to kind of break people out
of those little groups that they
came in. Um, but the people at
events I've gone to, like more
recently, like they were there
because they're the kind of
people like first is a minute, it
opens up even a little bit. I
want to go out and meet people.
so it was, it was kind of, you
know, it was neat to be able to
kind of in a small group and be
with people who like really.
wanted to kind of get out and,
and meet other people and we're
open to new conversations. Um,
but I think, you know, as we open
up more, we're going to have to
find ways to kind of keep that
connection going as the events
bigger. And, and, and that's
always the tough part, right?
Like every community. That starts
small. And it's like, this is so
awesome. I'm meeting so many
great people. And then the bigger
and the bigger it gets, it's
like, oh wow. Now it's gotten to
be a lot of noise. And it's hard
to like, know, I don't know as
many people and the people I used
to know don't show up anymore.
And, you know, it's, it's the
hard part about keeping a
community going for a long time,
like in and growing it without
losing. What it was that made it
special, um, that, you know, I've
seen, I've seen a lot of
communities kind of struggle with
that and I've even struggled with
it myself. Um, you know, like
particularly the Orlando Devs
that got, it's gotten really big,
like it's, it's hard. Um, and so,
yeah. Um, I guess I don't have
any, any special answers I
sympathize with-- I'm always
figuring it out myself.
Dan: Ah, it's really hoping
you're about to solve all of our
problems.
Brian: I think we, you know, we
solve it together, right. Like,
you know, we all know each other
and we share our struggles and
like, you know, we can help solve
it together.
Bekah: So I was talking to some
other small, uh, community
organizers, and I said, you know,
what, if we all just get into a
meeting and we talk this out and
they're like, that sounds
dangerous. Like,
Brian: Yeah.
Dan: Okay.
Bekah: all right, maybe we need
an agenda. Uh, I think, you know,
the other, the other thing that I
see with communities that have
been around for a long time, they
can be really great. But I think
sometimes you have those groups
of people that are always there
and they continue to come to
those things. And if you're a new
person, You don't feel like you
belong in those situations or,
you know, there's there's
assumptions. They, there's almost
a, uh, They're not able to look
at the thing that they've built
the community and say, you know,
how are we welcoming new people
who don't feel like they're part
of this club? Because so many of
the people that are there are
part of that club. And for me,
like that's really hard,
especially in person conferences.
I am afraid of strangers. And so
I don't talk to anyone unless
they talk to me first. So I just
like, sit there. And try and make
eye contact with people and like,
hope someone takes pity on me and
they talk to me. Uh, but, but
when everybody is all in their
own groups and there's not an
opening for you to kind of step
into, there are a couple of times
I like tried to jump in and eat
like lunch with people at a
conference recently. And they're
like, got up two minutes later,
like, all right, see you later.
And then I was like, At my table
by myself, I guess I think that
there are ways around that. And
like, I've talked to a couple of
conference organizers now about
like, how do we make it welcoming
for new people in these spaces?
But I think it's that you just
have to constantly be evaluating,
you know, w what is it like to be
a new person? And it's not just
conferences and communities, you
know, it's jobs and, and school
groups or whatever else. It can
always be hard.
Brian: Yeah. Absolutely. And
there's, I don't know that
there's any magic solution. I
think think organizers have to,
you know, as an organizer, you,
you try to create spaces that in
opportunities that give people
room to meet other people when,
if they, um, And then I think
people like the person you met,
you need kind of people there
who, and often the conference
organizer is that person as well.
Like you can know all the
different people in like, oh,
Bekah, you should meet so-and-so.
Um, come here and join us for,
you know, uh, whatever coffee or
a drink or whatever it is. Yeah.
You know, so that you, and then,
you know, cause oftentimes all it
takes is that first introduction.
And then that person introduces
you to other people who
introduced the other people. And
then all of a sudden it's like,
Okay. I met so many new people,
but um, but you need to have
people there who can kind of
help. And I don't want to, I
think it's it's you gotta there's
people like you who, who want to
meet people, but are. A little
shy about doing it. And then
there's people who like, you
know, aren't really, so you got
to kind of know that they've not,
they, they, they're not as
comfortable in those situations
and they're not, you know, so
maybe they don't actually want to
meet people. So you have to kind
of gauge what the person's
looking for. But there are people
who I think are kind of natural
connectors and can, can do that
and have a good sense. Um, what
that, what, what you, what you're
looking for.
Bekah: Uh, so I have this idea. I
don't know if it's a good idea,
but I keep telling people, so
hopefully it's kind of good. So
have you ever been to a, I think
it's called like a Brazilian
barbecue where they have like
those big things of meat and then
you have these like chips on the
table and you put up green, if
you want some. Or if you don't
want some me. Right. And so like,
what if we take that to the
conference experience? Right.
Because it's always like a thing.
If you're there by yourself,
like, who do you eat lunch with?
If you don't know anybody and
sometimes people don't want to
talk. Right. They just want to
sit there by themselves. So when
we have chips that are green or
red, and if you're sitting at a
table and you're open to other
people and talking, then you have
a green chip on your table or a
red chip, like I just want to eat
quiet lunch by myself, but I feel
like that reduces a barrier for
people to come in. Um, or my
second idea along with that was
like, what if there are topics on
tables and then you have a person
kind of like a Virtual Coffee. We
always have a room leader. So you
designate people for that table.
And like, maybe one table says
like front end developer or
another table says like community
and you know that those people
want to talk about those things
at that table. So then it's like
welcoming and you get. A teaser
into what the conversation
already is. And then you can kind
of like, oh, okay. That seems
like it would be a good pet fit.
And that person is safe because
their job is to talk to me. So
those are, those are my ideas. I
keep telling people about, I
don't know. I still don't know if
they're good, but.
Brian: First of all, I love a
Brazilian barbecue. I actually,
the first time I went to one was
like, I was still in high school
and this was in the nineties, but
it was literally in Brazil. So.
It was called El por cow, which
is like the pig. Um, and you sat
at these giant tables, like pig.
They were like huge picnic
tables. The place was massive.
And just like the amount of meat
coming through there. Crazy.
Anyway, so that's a whole side
issue, but yeah. You got me
thinking about that meat. Um, but
I think those are great ideas and
actually I've seen similar ideas
done at conferences. I think it's
just not consistent. Like I I've
seen ones where they have like,
you know, you can put, if you
have your, your badge and you
have the little badge, like the
flags or whatever, I don't know
what they call them. You can put
there someday. I I've seen, I
know I've seen conferences that,
that like have kind of, you can
that almost like the green
indicator, like, yes. I want to
meet people. Um, I don't I don't
know that it's always like
obvious or that people really
participate and that's the hard
part. I like.
Bekah: yeah. Or you're like
staring at someone's chest,
trying to figure out, like, do
you have a green thing on your
tag?
Brian: Yeah. So, and, and even
like, O'Reilly, uh, used to run
this conference call, uh, fluent,
which is like a web call in the
conference. I mean, it's not the
only conference that did this,
but they, they would have at
lunch, they would have. Uh, I
don't remember what they called
them. I was like, maybe it was
birds of a feather kind of thing
or something where it's like and
they would usually be like
speaker who had agreed to like
sit and be
Bekah: I like that.
Brian: so that. at least there
was somebody there who was
talking about that topic, because
that's the hard part. Like you
can put a topic on the table, but
if nobody's there, I'm not going
to be the first one to say, so
they would have like the speaker
go. And usually I know I got
picked for that before, like as a
speaker and I go grab like a
couple of people so that, you
know, it's not even just me,
cause even that can be awkward.
Right. Like you have what looks
like a small group already going.
Um, and then, and then you start
those discussions. So I think
those are, so those are great
ideas that like, you know, it's
just, um, know, uh, I, I
definitely think could be
implemented more consistently as
we get back to in-person events,
um, to help.
Bekah: it's interesting because I
think every conference I've been
to has had some place for speaker
feedback, but I don't know that
there's a conference feedback,
right? Like how did we do as a
conference or, you know, what
could we do to create a safer
space or a more welcoming space?
And it's hard, you know, I mean,
we both know like taking feedback
is a challenge because you get so
much of it and you have to try
and figure out what to do with
it. So, um, I don't know if
there's a, maybe there's some
kind of space for doing that more
effectively.
Brian: Yeah. that is tough often.
You know, I think even the
speaker feedback, like often
times it was like, Hmm, it
wasn't, it wasn't always that
valuable. Usually it was only the
people who, who really just
wanted to complain about
something who actually submitted
something or was actually was
very, it was either the people
who like just gave to every five
stars across the board. Cause
either. Whatever, and or they are
they wanting to complain about
something and, you know, I think
the valuable, most valuable stuff
kind of sits in the middle there.
It's like, yeah, I enjoyed that.
But here's some ways to improve
like constructive criticism as
opposed to like, yeah. The
speaker sucks... for reasons. Um,
So same thing on the conferences.
It's it's, you know, so I've seen
some that do have more of a
general, but I don't think
they've asked about what you're
looking for, which is like, did
we help you connect with other
people if that's what you're
looking for.
Bekah: Right. I, the best
feedback I ever got in a talk as
somebody fell asleep. And so then
I knew I needed to do something
to take that talk to a different
level.
Brian: I don't, I don't recall,
like when I I've seen, I've
gotten lots of feedback over the
years, but maybe once or twice
there was something actionable,
but I mean, generally
Bekah: So you just, so you just
wrapped up thejam.dev, right. Um,
and I, I made it to the first
day, didn't make it to the second
day, but it's really great. And
you do a really good job of, um,
you know, like emceeing or
facilitating those conversations
and like bringing the questions
through and asking things, which,
which provides like a really more
of a sense of community, then I
think some of those other online
events that I've seen. So, you
know, what is the thought process
that you have going into that?
And do you organize that all
yourself or do you have support
Brian: So, um, so to answer your
second question, first, I
partnered with the folks at FITC,
who I've known for a long time.
Um, and that is fantastic. Cause
I mean, I run all the meetups
myself, but like, this is a whole
other level where like now, you
know, you have sponsors and all
kinds of stuff and you know, the
video, the quality of the video
feed has to be super and you have
speakers coming in and out during
the, you know, throughout the
day. And. The a lot of the
logistics involved that. Um, so I
handle all of like the website
and the, and the, and all of the
speakers, like getting all the
speakers and choosing the content
and building a schedule and
emceeing obviously. Um, and then
they handle like the video and
other like speaker logistics and
sponsor logistics and stuff like
that. So like, that is amazing
because it's a lot. Um, and I
don't know that. You know, I'm
sure I could do it by myself. It
would not be as good an event.
Um, and, or as polished and I
think maybe not as great for the
attendees as well. And then he
sets his, so I think the
combination works. um, but you
know, in terms of how I think
about the event, I mean, I think
you're right. Like, I try to
think about what makes virtual.
Better in ways that then, then,
you know, not better. Okay. I
love in-person events, but like
what, what things are virtual
events better at? And, and so,
like, I can't stand virtual
events that are like, I call them
glorified YouTube playlists.
Bekah: Yeah.
Brian: It's like, if I could go
to your YouTube, play to a
YouTube playlist and get the same
basic effect, because it goes
from recorded session to recorded
session. And like, you know,
other than adding that little
chat or something like that. And
it's like, that's, that's not an,
that's not an event to me. the
event has to be like, has to be
about the community that's there.
Right? Like it's about the people
that's there, there. So, you
know, um, I think. Those live.
Even when we have recorded
sessions, they always have, like,
we have a significant amount of
time dedicated to that live Q and
A. Um, so like we have like was
30 minute presentation and then
15 minutes of live Q and A. It
gives everybody an opportunity to
their questions and get them
answered by the speaker, which is
kind of the critical piece to me,
because I could watch your video
on YouTube, but I can't directly
ask you questions. Right. Um, and
get those questions answered. So.
So that that part I think is, is
great. Um, we try and throw in
like, you know, we try and bring
in speakers from all over the
place, which I think is great,
which would be difficult. I mean,
we had speakers from, um, you
know, every, almost every part of
the world. Yesterday, uh, you
know, we had attendees from
almost everywhere. Um, so, those
are things that, that, can be
great at. Um, it was free, which
is, been, I've been pushing to
kind of make these free because
there's a lot of costs involved,
like I think, you know, I finally
was able to win over and make
this free, which to me makes,
opens it up to everybody. Um, So,
I mean, those are the things, um,
that the me are important to make
it, not just like, I want to make
it fun. I try to keep them
somewhat lighthearted, which is
why, like, all my events have
like weird names and stuff like
that. Like, like the moar
serverless or jammed dot dev I ha
I go off with the themes. Like
this was a kind of eighties rock
band theme. last year was.
Wasn't, it was also like
eighties, nineties, hip hop
themes. So, you know, it's like
it has, I just try to keep the
stuff lighthearted and fun and,
know, um, and hopefully people
enjoy it. it seemed like people
did. So I'm happy about that.
Bekah: That's awesome. Um, we're
at about time here, but is there
anything else that you'd like to
anything that's coming up for you
that you want to share or any
last bits of advice for other
people maybe working on
communities right now?
Brian: Um, you know, I I'd say
I'd love for people to join
cfe.dev, We obviously we run
after the afternoon crowd, uh,
Bekah: Thank you.
Brian: Virtual Coffee. So you can
go to Virtual Coffee and then
come join a session. Um, I'd love
for people to join that. We have
a, um, you know, uh, one a second
and fourth, Thursday at 1:00 PM
eastern is when we run those. Um,
and then trying to expand to do
some more stuff on the. I also
have a book I wrote with Raymond
Camden, that's come. We finally
finished. It should be it's
already available. And like, you
can download it, but like actual
print book out print book,
imagine that, um, we'll be out in
the next few weeks. it's called
the JAMstack book if you're
interested in jam stack stuff. So
obviously I am. Uh, and yeah, I
mean, I'm in, of course for you.
to check out LaunchDarkly cause I
think it's awesome. And that's
why I work there.
Bekah: All right. Thanks so much,
Brian. We are very, very happy to
have had this conversation
Dan: Thank you Brian
Brian: thanks. Thanks so much.
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
newsletter, check out any of our
other resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io. If you're
interested in sponsoring Virtual
Coffee, you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!