Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season five, episode two of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we are here to
share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost.
Dan: Thanks Bekah, what's going
on. Um, today we talked with Amy
Shackles. Amy is a senior
software engineer at MURAL.
MURAL
is a really cool company, a real
cool product. Um, it's a sort of
an online collaboration tool,
um, and lot of cool stuff you
can do
with it. So we got to hear a lot
about MURAL and working there
and
also the tool. Um, we, what else
did we talk about?
Bekah: Yeah. We talked about how
much Amy loves her job, but she
always like talks about it.
She's like, I'm not, I'm not
just
saying this because it's my
product, but it's really nice to
hear her talk about enjoying
what she does, because I feel
like
we're always getting. Almost
like horror stories of terrible
jobs.
And sometimes we lose sight of
like, there are good places out
there. And so it's, it's great
to have, uh, Amy's energy and to
hear about what that, what that
path was.
Dan: Yeah. A hundred percent
agree. It was really great
hearing about her journey and
what do they do at their, at
MURAL that makes, um, that makes
it a good experience and. God,
I'm so bad at ending things.
That's my worst skill is ending
sentences, paragraphs, whatever.
Bekah: Yeah. I'm not
particularly good at it. We do.
We're good
podcast hosts. We should like
bring in a guest ender for
things, and they're just there
to finish our sentences and our
paragraphs and the end of the
show. That's just their job.
Ender. Like a closer in
baseball.
Dan: I like it. Let's do that.
Um, okay. Well, we don't have
out
closer yet, so, um,
Bekah: If you want a job as
closer you can email
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
Dan: yes, audition start
tomorrow. Um, anyway, uh, it was
a good time. It was all, I was
trying to say. We had a great
time talking with Amy and I know
you're going to enjoy it.
Bekah: Yeah, she does a better
job of ending things. So go Amy.
We start every episode of the
podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We
hope
you enjoy this episode. Today's
check-in question is if you were
a vending machine, what would
you dispense? And I'm cheating a
little bit, cause this is the
one that we use this morning,
Virtual
Coffee,
Amy: was going to say I'm prime
for this one,
Bekah: yeah. I already know my
answer. I don't have to think
about it,
Amy: except I had a bad answer
Dan: I'm just getting punished
for not, not
Bekah: yup. That's right.
Dan: the
Bekah: I'm Bekah. I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and I
would dispense kindness,
Dan: Aw, that's nice. That's
heartwarming.
Bekah: you making fun of me for
dispensing kindness?
Dan: Um, hi, I'm Dan. I am a web
developer from Cleveland, Ohio,
and, um, yeah, well, I mean, The
questions, you know, like what
would you want to dispense or
what would you actually
dispense?
Because those answers are
different, I think right now.
Um,
yeah, I would dispense be
dispensing free anxiety for
people. That's all I have a
surplus of right now. Um, you
know, I think, uh, if I, if I
had to choose anything, maybe,
um,
maybe like camping, camping
tools or camping supplies,
something
like that. I think that'd be
kind of cool, you know, Uh,
titanium
silverware, or, uh, you know, I
don't know as fire starters and
a
pocket knife or something, I
don't know, pocket knife might
be
a little, little, a little
dicey, but you know, stuff you
need for
camping. That's going to be my
real answer. You know that I
think that's it camping. That'd
be cool. That'd be cool. The new
machine.
Amy: That is a really good
answer. Camping supplies. I
agree
with you with the avoidance of
including knives and that
Dan: Yeah. Probably not. No,
sir. Yeah.
Amy: know, want to use your
vending machine. If I were a
vending machine, what would I
dispense? Um, I think I would
dispense very intricate paper
hearts with uplifting messages
of
hope.
Dan: Well, that's cool. Like a.
Oh wait, like origami, like to
3d
or 2d
Amy: That's a good question. I
was thinking like 2d, because I
was thinking that it would be
like calligraphy on it with the
messages of hope. So now that
I'm thinking about it, maybe it
could
be a, like one of those, what do
you call those thirds?
Dan: Yeah. Fortune teller.
Amy: Yeah, fourtune tellers,
where you open different
sections
and it would be a different
message of hope stylist.
Bekah: one of those on my desk.
Dan: Yes. I love that. Ah, man,
Bekah: All right. And your name,
where are you from? What you do?
Amy: sorry. Yes. My name is Amy
Shackles. Um, I'm a senior
software engineer at MURAL and,
uh, yeah, that's what I do.
Dan: That's awesome. Hey, I have
a question about MURAL MURAL.
Every time I see it as spelled
in all capital letters. Is it a,
uh,
what do you call it? It's an
abbreviation. No, I mean, uh,
Amy: I don't believe it's an
acronym.
Dan: Acronym. Yeah, it's not an
acronym. Okay. That's just a
stylistic choice. That's cool.
Something I've wondered, you
know, for while. Nice.
Bekah: All right. Thanks so much
for being here with us today,
Amy. Um, we always like to start
off with the origin stories. So
tell us a little bit about how
you got to this point in your
life.
Amy: Good question. Well, once
upon a time I was born, uh, and
probably don't need to go back
that far. So I growing up always
thought that I wanted to be a
psychologist. So, uh, I did my
undergrad in psychology and the
Anthropocene. Uh, because I
loved
people and the study of people,
thus the anthropology, which was
funny because my anthropology,
um, professor understood the
double major was psychology. The
psychology professor did not
understand how those would
relate. And, uh, it was just
funny that there was a
disconnect, um, But I, I re I
realized I'm the kind of person
who, uh, people have the
tendency
to like, open up to me and share
their secrets and their, uh,
like
struggles. And I tend to want to
respond by sharing things about
myself. And you can't do that as
a psychologist. You're like
banned, like no personal sharing
and so on like that, I would be
a
really bad psychologist. I can't
turn that part of myself off.
It's not going to happen. So I
didn't pursue psychology, even
though I have a degree in it.
And so I got out of college and
I was
a transcriptionist for like a
decade, just listening to audio,
uh, typing what you hear, which
is great, except, um, the robots
are getting better at it. And
so.
Bekah: The company, I work for
speech
Amy: we're being replaced. So I,
uh, decided to switch careers
and
my husband was a software
developer software engineer. And
so I had an idea of what that
life was like, and I wanted it
for myself. So I did a bootcamp
and, uh, then just started
working in tech.
Dan: That's awesome. So how long
ago was, what did you do the
bootcamp.
Amy: Uh, I started in April,
2018. I ended in October, 2018.
Dan: Nice. That's really cool.
So when you were doing
transcription
or was it a normal keyboard or
what you're doing? Like isn't
one
of those, I don't know. Isn't
one of those.
Amy: stenography.
Dan: Yeah, that's it? Yeah.
Like,
Amy: a stenography machine. Uh,
I used a regular keyboard,
Dan: Yeah. Impressive
Amy: faster typing speeds than I
currently do.
Dan: man. Yeah. That's that
skill is an impressive skill to
me. I
always, my, uh, I don't know if
I could do it for you in more
than
like five minutes.
Bekah: hard. I, I did it once
for an event. All I had to do
was one
talk and it took me so long to
do that. Talk like this was not
worth it.
Amy: Yeah, the trick is knowing
that foot pedals exist and you
can use them. Uh it's what most
of us use when
Dan: Wait, how do you use foot
Amy: Yeah. you just plug it into
your computer. There's a play a
play pad, uh, fast forward
rewind. You can usually, uh,
configure it to do it the other
direction. Some people decided
to
have rewind on the right instead
of the left. It kind of varies.
You can have your playback, uh,
replay the last 10 seconds or
five seconds or whatever. So it
just depends on your own
personal.
Dan: Oh, okay. So you didn't
have a special keyboard, but you
had
the secret, you had specked
secret tools. That's right.
Okay.
The truth comes out. That's
awesome. That's really cool.
That's I mean, obviously also a
good idea. I have just seen, um,
they've probably been around for
a while, but I just saw them
coming out for, um, like gaming
and stuff, you know, or
streaming
or I dunno something, but oh, it
seemed like good. Yeah. You
know,
on unused. Appendages for, you
know, when you're working
Amy: It's an extension of
yourself. Yes.
Dan: I mean, your feet are just
sitting there most of the time
doing nothing to get them to
work.
Amy: One of the downsides of
being transcriptionist, though,
with a foot pedal is that you
can't really do a standing desk
because you need that foot on
the floor and it would be really
awkward to have to balance.
Bekah: that'd be tough. Okay.
All right. So you went from
transcription, then you went to
bootcamp and you graduated in
2020, right? Oh, And then did
you start working at Muir? No
you
weren't at MURAL first.
Amy: No I was at Skip List
first.
Bekah: Okay. So what was that
transition like from boot camp
into your first.
Amy: That's a good question. Um,
uh, the transition for me was
kind of interesting insofar as
like, When I started my job at
skip list, I was already the
React expert and I was working
on
an application. It was React and
Redux. And so from like the
jump,
I was already the person with
the most experience with React
and
Redux. And I had to like
refactor the entire application
because it
was written kind of generally,
uh, there, it was a lot of
responsibility from the get-go,
uh, which was.
Bekah: Sound super stressful.
Amy: A little bit.
Bekah: All right. And then I,
one of the things that I always
love
hearing you talk about is MURAL.
And just for reference, this is
not a sponsored episode of the
podcast, but Amy, you always
talk
about how much you love it. And
I like hearing you talk about it
because. I often hear people
talk about how terrible their
jobs
are. So anytime someone has a
good experience, I always want
to
know more about that. So what
kind of drew you to MURAL and
what do you think makes it a
good place?
Amy: Um, what drew me to MURAL?
Uh, I'll be honest was that I
had
a friend that works there and
gave me an internal referral. So
I, I'm not one of those people
that knew the product and love
the product and then joined the
company. Uh, But I fell in love
with it afterward. Uh, I use it
all the time. I recommended to
friends. I think I recommended
it to you at one point, because
you
were looking for a tool.
Bekah: Yeah, we got a team
account on there.
Amy: Yes. Um, but, uh, things
that I love working there for
reasons I love working there,
uh, include like the fact that
it's
actually really global. Um, like
some companies say that they're
global, but it's like, you have
a team in India, you have a team
in
the United States and those
teams don't really interact with
each
other. Like if you do, it's
occasional, it's not an everyday
thing. Um, but my team
specifically, like. I think now
we're finally at a point that
there are more Americans than
there are Argentinians, but when
I first started, it was just
Argentinians and I, and so
there's that four hour gap for a
part of the year in five-hour
gap for another part of the
year. Um,
so because we have so many
people from different regions,
there's a
lot of like having to understand
that, uh, communication, uh, is.
Easily misunderstood. And you
have to be patient it's like the
same thing that we've we talk
about in Virtual Coffee, like
being receptive to how other
people interact and like taking
it on good faith that like
they're not intentionally being
abrupt or rude or whatever. Like
there's lots of things that can
be lost in translation. And, uh,
one of the things I really love
is that they're like very
encouraging of me to. Like try
to
learn Spanish. I'm like working
on it. I'm still pretty
terrible.
But learning Argentinian Spanish
is like, ah, I love it so much.
It's like so different than the
Spanish I grew up with in like
high school learning Spanish.
Um, but I, I just love how. Like
every everybody's like open and
receptive, so like helping other
people and like, even if it's
not your team, everyone bands
together over a problem, like
it's just really communal in
the,
in the way that we operate, I
guess. Uh, that's one of the
reasons I love it.
Dan: I, uh, I was just gonna
say, I'm glad to hear that like
that.
And it is also not surprising, I
guess, that, um, a company like
MURAL where their product is
about collaboration and, you
know, team building and stuff
like that, that they also have,
like, they reflect that in
internally. Um, it's cool. Yeah.
It doesn't always, it's not
always true, you know? Um, but
it
says a lot about the product
too, I think. Right. Cause, um,
I
imagine you guys, do you use.
Amy: Oh, yeah.
Dan: in the company. Yeah,
that's what I was gonna say.
Amy: the
Dan: Yeah. I didn't want to make
assumptions, but the fact that
the fact that like you're using
your own tool at, you know, as,
uh, probably pretty heavily and,
you know, you'd probably depend
on it. Um, the tool that you're
making in selling other people
it's, uh, says a lot, you know,
a lot of good things about the
tool
itself. So that's pretty cool to
have to have that, you know, and
I'm working right now on, uh, an
app. The company that makes, uh,
like pressure gauges and stuff,
you know, and it's like, great
work. And like, this is not
anything against my team, you
know, but I'm not like going out
there getting excited about
pressure gauges in my life. You
know, we don't have like
meetings
where we're looking at it, you
know, we're, uh, We talk
sometimes about trying to like
blow into it, to see how, you
know, if we can, if we can get
the pressure gauge to, I don't
know, do something, but it's not
the same, you know, it's not the
same. So it's cool that you guys
have this tool that what'd, they
call it. Oh, I'm dark footing,
right? That's dogfooding we got
it. We have jokes about that. I
don't, I know it's not good.
One.
It's not a good one, but I think
that it's at least the right
thing where you're using the
thing that you're selling to
other people or whatever. And
probably helps it make, make it
better. Do you guys,
Amy: we definitely feel the pain
points that our customers feel
because we run up against the
same blocks and more often than
not like w we develop features
because we want them and at
other
people also want them. And like,
we discover bugs before our
customers do most of the time,
because we are also using the
product. So.
Dan: Yes. That exactly that's
well put, and that is exactly
what I was sort of getting
towards was was that, you know
what I mean? It's like a, you're
naturally improving the product,
uh, even when you're not like,
you know, writing code or not,
not working on it, you know what
I mean? Because you use it so
much. It's really neat. That's
it? It's a unique, uh, customer
zero.
Amy: Customer zero makes it
sound like it's the beginning of
an
infectious disease.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I was thinking
more like some sort of spy movie
or something, but, man. Yeah.
Well, thank you for that.
Amy: How this podcast ends up
being 20 minutes.
Bekah: Oh, okay. Okay. I'm going
to back up and get on track here
a little bit. Uh, all right. So
you went from bootcamp and then
you had a couple of days. And
you are a senior software
engineer
and that's, I feel like you've
accomplished a lot in a very
short amount of time, so good
job and congratulations. But
also
what does that, what does that
career progression like for you?
I know that, you know, a lot of
people, especially who are
coming
out of bootcamp are self-taught
like, am I in entry-level? Am I
mid-level? Like, how, how did
that feel as you made that
career
progress?
Amy: So if my, if I'm honest,
like that's the one thing that's
been like, the struggle for me
ever since I got out of bootcamp
is like, I, I applied for
entry-level positions and I
applied for mid-level positions.
And then sometimes when I'm
feeling confident, I fly for
senior positions and, uh, it
just
worked out that this time they
thought I was a senior engineer
because of my previous
experience. uh, I've definitely
had interviews with, uh,
companies that like mid-level,
uh, I think even some junior
positions where they're like,
yeah, you don't really have the
level of experience that were
looking for. It's just, that's
the one thing that's really
frustrating about the software
engineering, uh, space is just,
there's so many differences in
opinion about what it means to
be
an engineer like. A lot of it is
mindset. I feel like the ability
to learn new things and pick
things up quickly and then work
iteratively on solutions is like
the most important thing. But
it's hard to pinpoint where
people are in that journey. So
like it's a struggle that
everybody has. And. So I can't
really give advice on how to
gauge where you are. Cause I, I,
I struggled with it also. I I'm
glad that a company made the
decision for me and that going
forward. I can just say I'm a
senior engineer because I am.
Uh, but before that I was kind
of
lost with the wind.
Dan: Yeah, I like the way you
said that about, um, excuse me
about, um, being able to like
learn things and then iterate
on,
on like improving them and stuff
like that. I feel like that I
feel like, um, for me, one of
the. Well, there's a lot of
different things going on in
this, in like this process of,
you know, uh, job finding and,
and, and like level-setting
yourself and things like that.
Right. But, um, for me, with
development, especially when you
get to senior levels or
whatever,
it's, it's a lot less, um, or it
should be anyway, a lot less,
uh,
about like a specific checkbox
on a list of skills or whatever,
and
more about mindset. That's just
the way exactly the way you put
it, you know? The ability and
the confidence that you can, you
know, pick things up and, um,
and you know, you know, that
you'll
be able to learn things and you
know, that you have to learn
things like everybody learns
every, like that's part of the
developer being a developer, you
know, uh, experience right. Is,
is, um, having to learn things
all the time. I have, like, I've
been doing this for a real long
time and still I'm learning new
things every day, you know? And
it's one of the things I like
about it, but, uh it's um, and I
feel like that. People get
caught
up. I think when they're
younger, well, not younger, but,
um,
earlier in the career in trying
to match those checkboxes or
whatever, and you know, this job
listings always have these
ridiculous requirements that
were written by a marketing
person
probably. And, um, but that,
like that process of learning
things
iterating on them, you know, uh,
and, and. And then, and then
learning, moving on and learning
new things, you know, is, is
the,
that's the real thing. Right.
And that's the, I feel like
that's
the thing that's sets aside or
sets apart people that maybe I
would call it senior, you know,
senior level, at least then than
not is less like all of the
things I know and more like sort
of internal competence that I
can take up thing and then learn
it
and then do it, you know, I
think that's, uh, I guess, cool.
Um,
Amy: think it's less about like,
pretending that, you know,
things
or like waffling on like what,
you know, uh, like trying
desperately to pull things in
and more like admitting you
don't
know it, but you can't. I, I
will learn it in the future, but
I'm
not going to say that I know it
now because that's a lie.
Dan: yeah, yeah, totally. Like
if I was doing a, if I was
conducting an interview and I
asked somebody, oh, can you do X
or whatever? And they said, uh,
maybe, or so, you know, like
waffling, just like you said
that. Not as like, but, but if
somebody said, no, I didn't know
that. I don't know that, but I
know that I could pick it up.
You know what I mean? Like,
without
like, without any waffling, uh,
that's like, that's a big sign
for me, you know, that that's
um, that's cool. That's good to
hear.
Do you, um, in your position at
Sr or do you do much management
at all or are you doing mostly
just coding?
Amy: I am just doing coding. I
am not in the management track
at
all. Uh, we have two different
tracks and I chose the one that
involves engineering, uh,
because I I've, I've had so many
friends
that, um, They, they level up in
engineering and then become
managers and they hate it
because it's just managing
people and
they never get to touch code.
And they're like, why am I even
an
engineer now? This isn't fun
anymore. And I'm like, uh,
that's
not for me. At least not now,
maybe in the future, but it's
not
where I see myself currently.
Dan: absolutely completely
different skill set too. Right.
So you're all of a sudden
starting from zero in a new job.
I think some people like
companies don't understand that
lots of times and people that
are accepting positions don't
maybe
don't always grab that either,
but that's really cool. That
MURAL has that track. Um, even
at being at a senior level. That
you
can't concentrate on just being
an engineer, not just, but like
only an engineer. Um, that is
another really nice thing.
Sounds
like a pretty great place to
work.
Amy: love it.
Dan: Oh man. And again, we're
not being sponsored. We're not
being
sponsored by MURALs.
Amy: But we are hiring.
Bekah: Um, okay. So, so MURAL we
have established is a very good
place to work and they are
hiring. so you can apply if you
want to. Um, but not everybody
is going to get a job at MURAL,
right? So for people who can not
get a job at MURAL, what do you
think are some things to look
for in a company, um, to help
them to
determine. Okay. Is this a good
company? Is this a positive
space
or, you know, like maybe some of
the things that you just love
about MURAL that they can kind
of think about, uh, when
applying to
other places.
Amy: Yeah. So, uh, one of the
things that I usually try to.
Uh,
ask companies when I'm in the
interview process is like,
what's
your, what's your procedure for,
uh, actually shipping code? Like
what's the process? Do you, do
you have code reviews? If you
have code reviews, how many
people signed off? What's the
process? If there's conflicts,
how do you actually interact
with
your team? Like, what kind of
structure is in place? Like, is
there a hierarchy? Is there not
a hierarchy? It really depends,
uh,
on company, whether they decide
to have, uh, multiple people at
different levels within a team,
or if they'll consider them
homogenous, um, Uh, like asking,
like what, what kind of things
happen? Like how do they handle
conflict is something that I
really like asking companies,
just like, they usually like
asking you, like, it's important
for both sides. Like, uh, I also
tend to ask like for like, uh,
time off, like how they
prioritize. Because some
companies do unlimited PTO and
for some companies unlimited PTO
is a lie that they use to say
that, you know, you can have as
much time off as you want, but
really it's really hard to
approve that. And there's so
many
caveats, so it's not actually a
PTO and no one takes it. Um,
other companies really
prioritize PTO and, uh, even
take it so far
as some people are not taking
PTO and we've noticed this. So
now
going forward every quarter,
there is a day that everyone has
off because we want people to
take breaks. Um, and so like
figuring out how they feel about
time off is also important. Uh,
asking about work-life balance
is a good one. Um, But sometimes
it's important to like find
people that work at the company
and ask them rather than like
asking the recruiter. Who's
going
to tell you the like, company
line, uh, it's always better to
ask real people who are going
through it, what their
experience.
Bekah: Yeah, you learn so much
that way. And I think asking for
examples, kind of like you were
saying, you know, the company
asks you for these things. It's
okay to ask them the same thing
back, but like give me an
example of how your company
prioritizes
work-life balance or, uh, how
their paid time off is. Uh,
something that they prioritize
for their employees or whatever.
Um, cause it does give you a
good sense of the company, but
also
the team that you're working on.
You know, if you, if there's an
emergency and you're worried
that you might miss a meeting or
something like that, that
shouldn't be the priority,
right.
It shouldn't be like, oh, I'm
missing a meeting. She'd be
like,
I need to deal with this
emergency. I think that's a
pretty good indicator that.
Maybe there's problems with the
company
or the team. So asking people
about experiences and getting
examples from people is super
helpful.
Amy: Yeah, one question that I,
I usually ask that I, um,
forgot,
uh, up until this point. Cause
I'm good at things. Um, is, uh,
how do you measure success?
'cause, uh, that'll usually like
give you a good idea about where
their priorities lie. Um,
though,
I'll give you a caveat that,
that some interviewers, uh, will
not
be prepared for that question
and will waffle a bit just
because
it's not a question that
everyone asks.
Bekah: How do you measure
success, Amy?
Amy: So good question. I'm not
prepared. I I'm proving my own
point. I measure success when
people feel comfortable being
vulnerable and opening
themselves up to admitting
mistakes,
admitting, uh, a lack of
understanding, uh, admitting
that
they need help. Like you need to
have a lot of workplace safety.
To get at that point that like
people, individual people feel
like they can be vulnerable that
way. And it's only through
people
feeling like they can be
vulnerable, that you can help
people succeed. So that's how I
measure success.
Dan: That's a really good answer
to saying, well, yeah, there's,
I
mean, there's lots of, uh, bad
ways that people, that
companies,
you know, measure success or at
least today that would call bad,
you know, and that those are
usually like more like check
boxes or whatever, you know, uh,
or how
Amy: Okay.
Dan: that they get done. Yeah.
Yeah. Uh, and your answer is not
that, and that's.
Bekah: Yeah. it seems like. A
lot of the positive things that
we've
been talking about has to do
with, um, vulnerability and open
communication. And those things
are hugely important. And even
going back to what
differentiates a senior
developer to like
having, I mean, there were
plenty of very terrible
communicators
who are senior developers, but I
think that a good senior
developer. Is has good
communication skills. They're
willing to listen to other
people, um, and do exactly what
you said, like express when,
when they need help with
something or
they don't have a clear
understanding of what's going on
because that also sets the
example for everybody else on
the
team that it's okay to have
questions. It is okay to make a
mistake. And it's how, how do
you improve on that?
Amy: Yeah. Uh, I like to say
that there are no stupid
questions.
There's just stupid reactions to
quick. Like the answer is being
stupid. Uh, it's not the
question itself. Um, I used to
be part of
a different developer, um,
community and I built a slack
bot
that would automatically respond
to the, the phrase stupid
question where there are no
stupid questions just cause I, I
wanted to train the juniors out
of saying it.
Dan: Yeah, that's big it. Maybe
she'd get that. Get that on our
site going,
Bekah: I just had like nine
ideas all at once now.
Amy: Infinite possibility.
Dan: it ha it happens every ever
podcast. One of the guest says
something in both Bekah and I
are just like, just thinking,
just
like, oh man,
Bekah: Yeah. I, um, okay, so, so
maybe there's not a connection
here, but your background is in
psychology and. Now you're a
developer. So have you utilized
any of the things that you've
learned with your degree? Or can
you talk about any transferable
skills from that?
Amy: Definitely. I mean,
Interacting with humans in
general that like having some
knowledge of how a consciousness
operates, like how people think
and how different people think
like cultural differences. Uh,
it, it definitely is helpful
when
you're dealing with
communication between people,
um, facilitating
communication and making sure
that different people. Same
page.
Um, it it's something that I've
always had. Like, I always
consider it like a gift and a
curse that I can hear. Two
people
talk about something and see
their point of view. Even if
there are contrasting points of
view and then you get them to
realize. They're saying
different things and coming from
different
places, but really their goal is
the same and you can get them on
the goal if they just realize
what the other person's saying.
So you just have to like
translate to the other person's
speaking style, like how they're
actually thinking. Um, it,
thankfully that, that, that part
of it is less, um, I've utilized
that less at work, but I do find
it helpful in. In life,
especially Twitter.
Dan: Me. Yeah, probably I'll use
a little bit of extra extra of
that on Twitter. That's pretty
cool. It sounds like the kind of
stuff, a really good manager who
says to us. So I was kind of
surprised that you hadn't
mentioned stuff, but I bet you'd
be good at it if you want it to,
but then you'd be managing and
not coding. So.
Amy: for the future.
Bekah: What I would have been
like some of the biggest
surprises along your journey.
Amy: Uh, good question. Um,
well, I guess one of the
surprises for
me is like personally, when I,
when I started getting into
coding, I did coding all the
time. Like all the time I had no
other hobby, it was just
developing things, creating
things and pushing code, like.
Whereas we're always green and
people would always say, Amy,
you're going to burn out. This
is
how people get burned out. Don't
do it. It's bad. And I was
always
like, no, I'll never stop loving
coding. I love this. That's what
I'll do for forever. Um, but now
I'm to the point where I code at
work and I don't usually go to
outside of work. Um, like I got
really big into crochet and, and
so now I crochet and I will talk
people's ears off about regex.
Cause I love regex with a fierce
ungodly passion
Bekah: You're the only person in
the world I've ever heard say
that
Amy: Which is Also
Bekah: you like a
Amy: Also surprising to me
because when I first, when I
first came into contact with
regex, I hated it. Like fiercely
hated it. I avoided it at all
costs. Um, but then I decided
that it w it was just going to
be one of those things that I, I
fear. So I'm going to get in
contact with it. So I stopped
fearing it. Yeah. Conquer it.
And so I got way down into the
deep
rabbit hole that is regex,
trying to build a regex parser.
And I'm
still on that journey. It's
still one of my side projects
that
always haunts me. It's just
taunting me on a regular basis,
but I have so much regex
knowledge, just like in my head
at all times. It's like the only
reason I have any Stack Overflow
credit is, is regex.
Dan: that's cool. Yes, no, I
generally try to avoid it, but I
mean, I know that there's some,
you know, there's problems where
you, you recognize pretty
quickly, like regex would be a
good tool for this, you know?
And then I go Google for
hopefully a
regex solution. And if I can't
find it quickly, I'm like, all
right, forget this. We're going,
we're doing for loops. We're
going through it. That's
awesome. So, wait, you're
writing a regex
parser, um, to parse regex like
threads experience.
Amy: the idea.
Bekah: we just pause for a
second? Because I know that not
everybody listening to the
podcast is going to be familiar
with. Yeah. Yeah. Can you just
give a explanation?
Amy: Yeah, let's see if I can
find a good online. Um, because
I
don't know how I would describe
it to other people. you have a
good definition
Dan: no, it's a, so it's an
expression. That's very regular,
regular expressions.
Amy: not. Okay. A regular
expression is a sequence of
characters that specifies a
search pattern in text. Um, and
Dan: That's exactly what I said.
All right. By the way.
Amy: I love you guys. um, the,
the goal of my project, uh,
which
is to, uh, build a. Tool that
eventually would be extended to
a
vs code extension. Uh, the goal
is that it would scan a file,
find anything that had a regular
expression in it. And then if
you
hovered over the regular
expression, it would break down
what that expression is doing.
Okay.
Dan: That would be dope.
Amy: Human language. Uh, just
because there are so many bugs
that can be caught that way,
because like, you don't realize
that you're over matching. Um,
and yeah, so it's a ongoing
project that I started a while
ago and I I've rewritten it like
three times and I keep finding
new ways for it to be broken and
new edge cases. But one day I
will succeed.
Dan: That's awesome. Yeah,
that's really cool. Yeah. So, I
mean, I
was kind of joking, but yeah,
you use, if you are still
unfamiliar
with what a regular expressions
are, you know, like, do you use
them for things like. For, you
know, matching strings inside of
a bigger string. Right. Uh, so
if you want to find all of the
instances of Bekah in the
podcast, transcripts or
something, that's a really
simple one, right. Um, except
that if
you want to throw in, okay, so
you want, um, you know, capital
and lowercase in case the
transcribing thing. It was
messing up. Right. You know,
there's like, uh there's um,
little, and it looks like
nonsense when you are first
learning it, but a little piece
of code that you stick in to the
matching string. So you can say,
okay, just do lowercase, right.
Or do all cases, ignore cases,
um, uh, things like that. Right.
And, and then you can start
doing chunks of like, patterns,
right.
So you could do. Any sentence
that starts with Bekah is or
something, right. Like that kind
of thing. Um, there's lots of
like, there's a million
different, I'm sure you can
think
of more interesting examples.
Cause I, I use them very
infrequently, but it's, it's
the, that's what the tool like,
that's
what the regular expression tool
in general is used for. And
pretty much all I don't know
about pretty much all, but like
most of the coding languages you
use have, you know, have that
ability right in them. Um, And
it's, I dunno, it's one of
those.
Yeah. It's one of the things
that's like, it looks like
nonsense when you look at it.
And so if you're learning, you
probably would just ignore it,
you know, as fast as you can run
away from it. I
Amy: I use and probably abuse it
too. Uh, do find replace a lot
like text replacement. And
whenever I'm like, I have a
comma
dilemma delineated line, and I
want to turn into an object. Uh,
I'm going to use regex to find
her place.
Dan: Yeah. That's awesome. Yeah.
And so if you use vs code, uh,
you, you have the option of
turning that on in your, in your
final replace, in VS code, it is
regex. It's like S like hiding
around everywhere. Like a lot of
at least in developed in
developer tools, you know,
you'll, you'll see it, you know,
turn it on and then you'll turn
it off because it doesn't do
what
to expect if you don't. Um, if
you don't, aren't already
familiar with it.
Amy: Yeah. You have to know what
to escape. If you have
Dan: right, exactly. Yeah. I,
uh, yeah, no, that that'd be a
cool
tool that would be able to, um,
be able to see that like sort of
interactive, um, stuff with this
stuff you're typing. That'd be
neat. So get to work on that.
Amy: I'm working.
Bekah: Is it, is it, open?
Dan: So I was going to say, is
it open source?
Amy: All of the versions are
public GitHub, but, um, uh, They
might be broken at different
parts. I don't know what state
they're in. A lot of the things
that I build are open source.
So.
I think I have a react selector
that's like accessible. And so
that's opensource. That's like
the one, uh, repo that I
currently have that actually has
a contribution from somebody
other than myself. It was very
surprising. One day when I got
an
email while it was a work that
there was an issue and I was
like, oh no, I'm going to have
to solve this issue. And I got
another email also while I was
at work saying I had a pull
request.
To fix that issue and it was
magic.
Dan: That's that's awesome.
Bekah: we'll have to drop links
to all those in the show notes.
Dan: parse, underscore rejects.
That's one more.
Amy: I wasn't one of them,
Dan: Is that the one we're
talking about?
Amy: I think there's a regular
expression parser, so many
variations.
Dan: There's a there's regex
parser, but it's empty. So this
might be not the right word.
looking around your
Bekah: I created a pull request
today and it was like one file
changed, empty, like, oh, that's
great. Glad that I was very
effective, but that. So not sure
how that happened. Um, uh, well,
so I think the goal may be then
for 2022, should be to complete
one of those successfully.
Amy: that is my goal. I should
stop spending all of my time
crocheting and actually get to
work on this regex parser
Bekah: No, let other people help
you. I wasn't saying to do it by
yourself. That's an open source
channel in slack and posts every
single one of them in there. And
we'll make it a competition.
We'll, we'll send swag to
whoever wins.
Amy: That'd be amazing.
Bekah: I'm having ideas again.
Amy: I'm down for it. Uh, help
would be lovely because. Knowing
all of the, uh, parts of rejects
and I've even sketched out all
of
the different chunks that is
regex. I have a entire, I
couldn't, I haven't ported it to
MURAL yet. I still have it on
whimsical, but, uh, it's just
this very elaborate mind map of
how regex expressions work. Uh,
Dan: That's
Amy: that was redundant. I said,
Dan: You should probably, uh,
yeah.
Bekah: It's okay.
Dan: Well, regular expression.
Expressions now, what do you
call
an individual one. I guess he
just call it a regular
expression.
Amy: Yeah.
Dan: That's boring though. Yeah.
All right. We can fix English
later. One thing at a time.
Amy: What is English?
Bekah: W,
Dan: exactly.
Bekah: sorry, I didn't know what
I was
Dan: Yeah. You almost said
something there.
Bekah: And then I had a thought
and it left me.
Amy: man, I like lost the thread
Bekah: right now. It is.
Amy: thread.
Dan: Yes. Three for three in
this particular podcast for
ADHD. So.
Amy: I really loved that
discussion we had on Tuesday
about ADHD. That was
Bekah: Yes. It's my favorite
discussions when we're in a
breakout room and everybody is
talking about their ADHD and we
go off on the best tangents.
It's just so much fun.
Amy: There's so much kinship to
be had from having a diverse
brain mapping.
Bekah: It is. Yeah. So, so for
those of our listeners who are
not there on Tuesday, they're
just kind of wrapped up. I don't
even remember how we got started
talking about ADHD, then
Amy: remember.
Bekah: a number of people had
ADHD, somebody else that they
might based on our conversation,
Yeah. Do you want to talk a
little bit about your experience
with ADHD?
Amy: Yeah, sure. Um, I didn't
get diagnosed with ADHD until I
was
an adult. The only reason I got
diagnosed was that my husband
got
diagnosed and his psychologist
was like, take this written
assessment home with you and
have your wife take it because
in my
professional experience, as
someone with ADHD and who treats
people with ADHD, if you're
undiagnosed as an adult and
you're married, your spouse also
is undiagnosed with ADHD because
they're the only people that can
tolerate us for that long. And
so
I took the assessment and the
other assessment and yeah,
totally ADHD. And it was totally
mind blowing to me that like my
entire life I've had this like,
anxiety that got worse. As I got
older to the point that like I
would leave the house. And if it
was a windy day, I would have in
the back of my mind at any point
a tree could snap a branch and
then I'm going to be dead. Cause
the branch inevitably is going
to find the back of my cranium
and
smash it and that's going to be
the end of me. And so like, I
was
always looking for danger at any
situation, like. Sit in a room
with my back facing a door. It
was not a thing I could do. And
so, like I had tried to get
treated for anxiety and it just
never seemed to work. And then I
got diagnosed with ADHD. He got
treated for ADHD and my
psychologist was. The only
reason
you have anxiety is because you
have untreated ADHD. Once we
treat that that's probably going
to go away. And that has been my
experience. I am no longer in
anxious anxiety muffin. I am
like
a normal human.
Bekah: I, when I was diagnosed a
couple of years ago, that the
first thing that my doctor
wanted to do was rule out he's
like, is
that ADHD? Or is it anxiety?
Like what is starting this? And
so we
started by ruling out, uh,
anxiety that was causing these
symptoms, uh, and then went on
to be treated for ADHD, which
has
been really good and helped me
to understand things much
better.
And also like how I communicate
with other people because my
whole family is probably
undiagnosed ADHD. And so we have
a very unique way of
communicating with each other
that I just thought everybody
communicated with each other in
that way. And that's probably
why I had a lot of problems,
forming
friendships and relationships
with people because not
everybody
communicates in that way
apparently. Um, but
Amy: mean, not everyone wants
you to finish their sentences,
Bekah: And take you on a 10
minute tangent before giving
them
a one word answer.
Amy: but you have to have set up
to stories. And sometimes those
lead you to different stories
that are tangentially related
and
you have to go into those
stories and then eventually
circle back
and then you forgot what the
original story was. And it's
just
that, that's just how
storytelling goes.
Bekah: I'm like one of two ways.
So either I am like that web of
storytelling or like my brain is
just very direct. So it's either
you get along story or I'm just
going to tell you how I feel
right now in this moment that
directness can be hard for some
people, but, but it has been
good to know that. Okay. There's
a way
to approach this communication
with somebody else and to talk
through things, to make sure
that we are on the same page and
that
we can communicate with each
other successfully. And Yeah. so
I always appreciate hearing
other people's stories.
Actually, Dan,
when, uh, I started working with
Danny, he was talking about his
ADHD and that's how I got
diagnosed with ADHD. Oh, is
that,
is that, is that what that is?
Dan: Yeah. I found out because I
read a tweet that described my
whole life and I was like, oh, I
started reading about it. No, as
I read about it a lot. And then,
um, like, you know, I was
consumed by obviously for a
couple weeks. And then I was
like, I went to talk to my wife
and I need to have, like, I need
to talk to you about something.
I think I have ADHD. Well, yeah.
And I'm like, what? She's like,
I just thought you knew who else
knows. And she's like, I don't
know all your friends, anybody
who's met you, I guess.
Amy: You just thought I was
untreated on purpose.
Dan: Yeah. I don't know. No.
Yeah. I mean it, my, my, my, the
reason I just didn't know
anything about it, you know what
I mean? I didn't know. I had
the. Never thought about it very
much
had to, if somebody asked me I
had the like sort of old
stereotypical, you know, idea of
what, of, what, like ADD is, you
know, that kind of thing. Um,
and, uh, well it turns out
that's
not, you know, accurate
obviously like, you know, the
hyper kid who
can't run, you know, who's
running around, you know, in
school and, and making noise and
stuff, and that wasn't ever me,
but all of the. Everything else,
you know, made my whole life,
like a lot, a little more, a
little more clear, like very all
of a sudden,
Amy: Yeah, I think that's one of
the like unfortunate parts about
add is that most people just
think of the hyperactivity as
being symptomology symptomatic.
And like the opposite is also
kind of a symptom, right? Like
daydreaming and not focusing on
things is also a sign.
Dan: Yes, yes. Yeah. And I,
yeah, no, I, I mentioned this
exact
experience with my doctor a
couple of days ago actually. Um,
and he's like, yeah, those are
the first kids that get
diagnosed. You know, the ones
that are disrupting class
really,
and the teachers are like, you
have to get him assessed or, or
him or assessed, or, um, he's
not coming back. You know what I
mean? Like, and so they get
diagnosed, but the, the people
who, um, are yeah, exactly a
quiet and more. Different. Um,
my
experience was just getting
labeled as well. He's smart, but
he's lazy or whatever, you know,
like that kind of thing, my
whole, uh, sort of school career
as it were. Uh, and, uh, yeah,
so, no, it's, it's been a very
interesting and enlightening
journey for me, but it's kinda,
it's cool. I dunno, I'd
encourage
anybody to read more about it
and think more about it. There's
there's a lot of good resources
out there these days. Um, To
learn about it, you know? Cause
that's what I did for a couple
of
weeks was just like read stuff,
you know, you don't have to be a
doctor to at least start
thinking about it,
Bekah: I just messaged Dan and
said, what should I read?
Dan: Yeah. Yep. And I sent her
like a, like a list of a billion
things. So.
Bekah: I had a similar
experience. I told my
sister-in-law, I was like, I
think I have ADHD. And she's
like, oh, you didn't, you didn't
know? Oh, no, it does. It's all
a
lot of rethinking of those past
experiences, but it's useful to
understand how to talk about
things and to know more about
yourself and your interactions
with other people. So, yeah. I
will second talking about it and
learning more about it. That's
something you think you might
have.
Amy: yeah.
Dan: just a little shout out. If
you are in Virtual Coffee, we
have a neuro-diverse, um,
channel in our slack. So if you
want to
learn more or, uh, you know,
join and talk to people like
minded
people and you're in Virtual
Coffee, ready, uh, you know,
feel
free to drop in that, um,
channel to. W we, we hang out
and chat
there sometimes just posts, you
know, gifs and stuff, but it's a
good,
Bekah: Gifs? mean Jifs
Dan: No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no. We got so far. You're so
close to ending
Bekah: We really did.
Amy: Gif one,
Bekah: Jiff two
Dan: Couldn't just let it
Amy: they're G-rafical images.
Bekah: I can't, I like, it's
painful to my ears to hear that.
I'm like, what is, what is he
talking
Amy: we don't say ragexe so we
shouldn't say GIF. a hard jet.
Dan: Right checks. Oh, no,
that's going to bother me too.
Amy: expression.
Dan: that's
Amy: should be reg X, but it's
not ragexe because
Dan: it red. I reg X from now.
Amy: See, this is, this is how I
get the people who are hard
lining GIF. I'm like, Hmm, we're
not consistent.
Dan: Well, that's true. It's
again, English. So that's sort
of
the only consistent thing is
that it's inconsistent
Bekah: Well, Amy,
Dan: English major right here,
English.
Bekah: I'm an English. major.
Dan: Okay. Well
Bekah: master's in English,
masters.
Dan: yes, no, we fight about
this quite a bit.
Bekah: Never stops.
Dan: Oh
Bekah: I was going to say,
thanks Amy, for being here
today. Um,
and in, during this conversation
with us, uh, this has been fun
and I thoroughly enjoyed it. Is
there anything else you want to
share or any last words of
wisdom you would like to leave
for our
listeners?
Amy: Good question, which is how
I preface everything. Cause I
need to think about it. And, uh,
I would, I would just say that,
you know, times are hard, but we
don't have to be and like try to
be kind to other people, even if
it it's hard sometimes.
Bekah: It's like, if they're
saying GIF,
Amy: Like, if they're saying GIF
and you want them to say Jif or
they're saying ragexe and you
want them to say regex.
Compassion.
Dan: Compassion.
Bekah: I'm sorry. I ruined that
it was like very meaningful and
great and I could not stop
myself.
Amy: I understand the impulse.
Well, I can't even say anything.
it all the time.
Bekah: All right. Thanks so
much, Amy. And we will talk to
you
soon.
Dan: Thank you, Amy.
Amy: Bye.
Dan: Bye. Thank you for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
newsletter, check out any of our
other resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io. If you're
interested in sponsoring Virtual
Coffee, you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening and
we'll
see you next week!