Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
Season Five, Episode Three of
the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and What they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: What up Bek! Uh, we're
back! Season...three... No
wait...what
is this season?
Bekah: Season five, episode
three
Dan: Episode three. Yeah. Uh,
sorry. Nick was a distracted me
on slack and side. Uh, Uh, come
on. That's not how I live my
life, I live my life, one
distraction at a time. Anyway,
um, today we have a great
episode. We talked with Helen
Griffin, who is a full-stack
developer and a founder. And,
um,
yeah, we talked about her
journey through tech and, um,
talked a
lot about her experience as a
founder of her two companies.
Um,
Uh, State of Developers and
Jovial. And so those two
companies concentrate a lot on,
um, developer, personal health
of
developers and that things like
burnout and stuff like that. Um,
so it was really interesting.
Bekah: Yeah, I love talking to
Helen. She's a lot of fun and I
love the idea that she's a
multi-passionate person. She's
got all of these things that
she's doing. She's excited to
talk about them and to share
what she's doing. And there's so
many
great moments. This episode,
there was one moment. I can't
remember which one it was, but I
was like taking a sip of coffee
and Helen said something. I
choked, literally choked on my
coffee because I was laughing.
And then it took me a solid
couple of minutes to get past
that. But, uh, she was a lot of
fun to have.
Dan: Yeah, no, I had to actually
block your video screen from
like
looking at it so that we didn't
just have a total meltdown in
the
middle of the episode, but, uh,
no, it was fine. We laughed a
lot
and, um, Helen was great. Uh, so
yeah, it was a, it was a good
episode and, uh, I think you're
going to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We
hope
you enjoy this episode. Today's
random question is what is one
thing you would like to learn
more about, but have no reason
to? So my name is Bekah I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio. And one
thing I would like to learn more
about, I don't know, it's
either, um, like trees or birds.
They're
both like very fascinating. What
is the eye roll there Dan?
Dan: You stole mine! That's
exactly what I was going to say.
Bekah: I get to go first. So now
you need to think of something
else. there's there's a website
that has, like, people can
submit
sounds of birds and where they
are hearing those sounds. So
there's recording of that and
I'm like, there there's, there's
a
really cool project here, have
not, not figured it out yet. So.
Dan: Um, oh, well, hi, I'm Dan.
I do web development in
Cleveland,
Ohio, and yeah, man, I was going
to do, I like knowing about
things that I see, you know,
it's like, There's like, it's
just
like really cool to be able to
like, look at things and know
what they are. Right. It's, it's
a strange thing that to say out
loud, I guess. But, um, you
know, since Bekah stole the,
that one
from me, I I'll go like, you
know, architecture or something
like that, you know, being able
to like wander around a city
and,
you know, be like, oh, you know,
Thomas Jefferson was drinking
something, I don't know,
something like that. Yeah. uh,
that's going to be that's my
second place answer,
Helen: Okay. Okay. Um, all
right. That leaves me. What's
up. Y'all
I'm Helen. Um, I am a full stack
developer. I'm from Midwest. Um,
howdy. I think to answer that
question, I think I would like
to
learn about some form of martial
art. I have no reason.
Dan: a good one
Bekah: Really good one.
Helen: But I would still like to
learn. Some form of martial
know.
It would be Jiu Ji... Jiu Jitsu
I can never pronounce it. So
that's
probably something I won't learn
since I can't pronounce it. So I
just stay with karate since I
could pronounce that. Um, don't
know want to learn it because
I'm not flexible. I know. That's
it
while I work, I don't even stand
it. So I breath hard going
upstairs. So we see how that
works out.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome. I
feel
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: been my first answer now
that you said that I'm like,
yeah, Brazilian, Jiu Jitsu.
Helen: I just want to, I guess,
growing up, I used to watch
movies, 80 movies, so they
always have some kind of karate
scene. I
don't care, wherever the fight
scene, it always turned into a
karate scene I'm like, how are
you from Chicago? Are you start
karate? I don't... make it make
sense.
Bekah: Okay, so this is great.
My brother, my older brothers, I
have two brothers, an older one,
a younger one. When in that,
that
nineties era of karate fighting
scenes, used to love them and
like, especially Chuck Norris
movies. And so
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: them on the VCR and then
like play them in like slow and
mimic the action so he could
learn I sit there and watch him
the thing.
Helen: Yes.
Bekah: 100% feel you on
Helen: my goodness. Yes, I,
yeah. I, all of the movies,
there was
some karate. What's dude that
use to be in Dirty Dancing,
blonde-haried guy. He passed
little while back.
Bekah: Patrick Swayze.
Helen: He had a Roadhouse that
movie, a lot of karate, how
y'all
from the south and y'all doing
karate? Saying not to be. I'm
not
trying to be. Any ism, but I'm
just saying everybody know how
to
break out into karate. It's just
like a musical Everybody know
how
to break out into a song.
Bekah: Oh, my gosh. is so
amazing. I'm so glad that this
was the random intro question,
but I very much appreciate this.
Thanks Helen, for being here
with us today. Um,
Helen: I don't got nothing else
to do so. appreciate it.
Bekah: All right, get into your
story. We like to get the story
everyone that comes the podcast.
So what has led you where you
are
today?
Helen: Okay. Um, it started off
on is snowy winter night in
April. What I was, I thought, I
don't know. I don't know when.
Bekah: We're getting the birth
stories this season. This is
great special episode.
Helen: no, no. You know, my pop
pop raised me up to the sky she
said she has borns and no, no,
no, no. For real, I guess, I
guess to make it, to answer your
question, I started off my
career
as a front end developer. Um, or
a web developer at the time, I
didn't even know the difference
between front end and back end
back at the time. So I started
as a web developer and got my
first
corporate gig, um, um, at
American greetings. Um, so that
was, that was my first corporate
gig. Um, and then sells front
end
developer for quite some times.
So a good 10 years. And then,
um,
I took, I decided to. Start a
startup. So I, for the past
seven
years I've been doing a startup,
uh, or several startups or just,
but, uh, I guess most of that
time, what people don't tell
you,
like when you launch a startup,
uh, you startup before. I never
worked in startup before. What
that is is it's equivalent to a.
Um, it's just an MBA program
that you don't get at the end of
it.
You don't get no certification,
no degree. Um, and you spend
your
own money similar to like an MBA
program. You spend your own
money, uh, and the tuition
always goes up. So, yeah. so
that's,
that's pretty much was my, the
story. I was a front end
developer. Um, now I say I'm a
full stack developer just based
on my experience, you know, just
have to learn as a, founder, you
have to make things work No.
matter what it's all up to you.
So you don't have another
department or another colleague
go and say, Hey, make this word,
do your fancy. woo woo You know,
you had to go learn it. So I
kinda like that. Um, a little
bit
of backend stuff like that, and
that does gain some business
acumen well. um, I think the
last, last seven years has been
less development, the more
business development and just
learning the business world and
that's his own ecosystem. So
yeah. So now that I'm kind of.
And I don't want to say stepping
away from it, but, um, I kinda
like, uh, decide to go at a
slower pace while my startup,
um, and try to return back to
the,
um, development and land and to
see the world, the, the world of
frameworks and the role of
Jesus, all the frameworks, all
the
tools, all the expectations.
Like I'm going to be the job
descriptions. I'm like, oh Lord
Jesus. Well, who do you think
you
have? You know, Um, I'm like,
okay, I am, I guess I'm back
into, I feel like I'm kinda like
at the beginning stages, you
know, there's some things I
realize where my gaps are. And
so
I'm trying to fix that up and
stuff like that. So that's what
I'm doing lately.
Bekah: Yeah, it's wild because
you know, you have that
experience of front end or full
stack even, and then this pivot.
You're focused on this other
thing you come back, you know,
and there's just so much tech
moves so quickly. I just want to
take a second talk about, like,
why did you jump into the
startup
life to begin with? Like, what
about that was interesting to
you?
Helen: Uh, it wasn't the start
of that. Interesting to me, what
was
interesting was I got tired of
getting laid off that that would
make anybody pivot. I think I
ended up, I was. The I was with
um, the organization for like
six years get laid off and then
it
took another year before I get
another job got that job. And
then, um, and that company, oh
my God, that was like, what's
that
show Housewives Housewives. or
whatever that.
Bekah: oh. Or the real
Housewives
Helen: Housewives. I swear, that
was like the real Housewives of
executives or something like
that, that like we was in a
remote team and the amount of
mess that was going on with that
organization. Like when you find
out executives was punching some
other executive and that's the
great vibe is like, Oh, yeah. I
knew I was like, layoffs was
coming. I just don't know when
I'm just going to collect my
check from working with my
startup and just, yeah, I knew
I, yeah, so. I knew it was
coming. I
just was like, well, I got laid
off before, so we see what
happens. Maybe they might
change. Maybe they, you know,
whatever.
But, um, so yeah, I just, I
think I got tired of the layoffs
and I
was like, and I was around, I
got exposed to other startup
founders. Somehow I went to our
event and it was nothing but
startup founders. I don't know
how I went to this vet. it was
it
was supposed to be for like
developer. And tech people, and
I
just assumed everybody was
developer. And that's when I got
exposed to startups and I
started to go onto other meetups
and
stuff like that. And again, this
bows and at the time the
scenario
was, Andy had some accelerators
that open up their workspace for
people to come and work. And I
just, once I found those people,
I just kind of like was like
white on rice. I just stuck on
them. I wouldn't. Just trying to
consume as much knowledge as
possible. So, yeah. Oh, here's a
funny story. This, this is how I
was so clueless about business.
Um, I was trying, once I found
out about this affiliate
program, I tried to apply for
it. And he
was like, and he had no business
applying. Cause I didn't know
nothing about business. I didn't
have no problem. I was trying to
solve for nothing. I didn't know
nothing, but I still, I was
trying to apply for it. And a
guy, he was so kind, he just
sent
me to the side. They tried to
explain stuff to me and he was
like, product are you building?
And that, and I was so lost when
he kept saying product. I was
like, no, I'm a web developer.
Like what you make fun. was
like, what you talking about?
I'm not
trying to open up a small
business trying to because to
me,
I thought products, which is
what you see at the retail
stores. had
to be some kind of hardware or
some type of fabric, you know,
it
wasn't. You know, had to be
somebody you get off a shelf or
off my hanger. That was a
product. didn't realize that,
um,
a website was a product. I
didn't realize I was a product.
just
like, no, I'm a web developer.
So that was funny. So, yeah.
Yeah.
Dan: Well, that, that whole like
language barrier is, is true.
think of it a lot with
development stuff, you know? Uh,
but it's true. Any, any, any,
like you enter any realm that
you
haven't been in before and
Language different, you know?
Helen: Oh, yeah.
Dan: an interesting, like, I
dunno, aspect to think about for
like, events like that, you
know, is like, where do you set
that?
Where do you set the bar? You
know? Um, and like, what's there
in a world for so long. You
talk, you kind forget that
people don't
like already know you speak,
know?
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: think that's easy. Like a
lot of people walking into a
new,
realm, you know, experience that
a lot.
Helen: It is a face. A funny
thing I realized just came to
realization. Like reading in
some docs kept, it was like, you
know
how you know, word, you know,
what a word means? And he kind
of. might want to say 70%
understand where there, where
the
president's talking about, but
you'd like, there's still a
slight un-clarity in You're
trying to figure out I kept
getting pissed off. Every time I
kept reading all these dots,
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: abstract something. I was
like, what the heck? And then I
realized what they're trying to
say is we simplify it. So you
don't have to write all this
boatload of code. All you got to
do is just write this one line
of code. was just, I was
somebody
create tool where you could just
do a short command and you could
search and copy and retweets,
every word let's say abstract,
something in these dots. And
they say simple. be so much
easier.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean, that's a
huge thing. Like we had talked
about that at some point. I
think there's an issue still up
on
Virtual Coffees. I'm sorry, repo
where they're like a Chrome
extension, right? Like if you
it's specifically for. Web
development docs, you hover over
that thing there's a definition
for it, right? Like, because
there's so many things like
exactly what you're saying.
Nope. People don't remember them
once
they're past a certain stage,
many people don't. And so
there's
no definitions and you just kind
of have to fill in that
education
for yourself. And it doesn't
matter if you're self-taught or
bootcamp or have a degree
because. And they gloss over
these things and there's so much
to learn so quickly that you're
not going to remember all of
that And so being able to have
that
quick reference, there's like
somebody sent me, um, oh, it's a
tech blog and is so, so good. I
can't remember what it is right
now, but does that you hover
over something and gives other
links.
It might be done in obsidian. So
it might be done through
obsidian
publish. so it takes you to the
next thing, if you want to go.
so
there's like examples, there's
definitions. Like this is what
documentation should have
available because not every.
Again, follow that linear
documentation structure. It
should be like a, choose your
own adventure documentation to
help
you figure out what you need in
that moment.
Helen: Yeah, exactly.
Dan: uh, a product we're working
on right now. Um, there it is
that product right on, uh, a web
app that we're working on right
now. Um, we're trying to deal
with that same thing with not
inside the code or not
developers, but for people who
are using it, right. It's like
the first time you use it, or
first few times he use it, it's
all new and probably kind of
confusing, but it's meant to be
a tool that like you use a lot.
Right? And so once you get used
to. Uh, we don't want to like up
the thing with like tons of help
stuff, you know, and trying out
what level of like, you know, or
like, do we really do it? Just,
do we just have a button? Like
you're saying this like, show,
like explain everything to me,
you And then like a button that
says, okay, I'm good. I got this
now. You know,
Bekah: Yeah, it's there's a tab
or
Dan: pretty like set that level.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
Bekah: So give me all of the
links here
Helen: Yeah. yeah. I think that
people, we, we, we, we need to
be
like, I understand the idea of
you just trying to simplify
things. You just trying to give
a basic UI so people can just
get
in there and get work, but you
still haven't barrier. Before I
begin to work. Get used to this
environment. It's just like,
Yeah. I'm used to cook in my
kitchen, but you throw me in
your
kitchen. I'm not going to start
cooking right away. I still got
to go figure out where you put
your pet pots and pans where the
salt and pepper makes sure you
have seasoning, you know, just
check out stuff, you know, find
where they're at, you know? Um,
and it isn't, I'm not going to
be able to just get up and just
the
web up time and gonna be quick.
So I think we have to remember
that. Beyond the, what? The web
app or wherever at we building.
There's also another app we got
to focus before they even get to
get to there. It's called
onboarding. That's a whole, it's
all on the environment.
Dan: Yeah, for sure. Yeah.
Onboarding is like, yeah, we
talk
about that a lot. Um, we talked
about that a lot with Virtual
Coffee too is like the
community, right? Cause we got a
lot of
stuff going on the same, same
situation, you know? Um, I don't
know. I could talk again for a
long time about this. There's
lot, a lot of, you know, a lot
of pieces to that puzzle and
it's
all kind of interesting and
important. Um,
Helen: Yeah. think it's it's. I
think we should treat it just
like how some founders, they had
to put it in their schedule to
go
back and their own, Um, apps and
web apps and products as if they
was a new. So they can see this
experience again, because you so
much time will go by. Cause
you're doing so much other stuff
that you forget and you don't
know what has broken what got
lost in translation. as
developers, we should do that to
be like, okay, let's pretend
I'm, I'm a user. This is my
first time
in this environment. Or let's
pretend I'm a developer. I just
graduated. This was my first
time. And I'm. You know, just to
get an understanding, you know,
is equivalent to like how
executives to go in and do some
manual tasks, just to understand
what their teams go through once
in a while kind of thing. So.
Dan: Yeah, That is like good
advice for not just like the
owners, you know, but everybody
that's doing it. It's so easy to
get caught when you're like
caught in the weeds, you know,
like when you're living and
breathing a project for a long
time, you know, you lose sight
of. Like beginning. I don't even
know what the login or not the
login, but like the new user
screen looks like on this app
that I work on every day, you
know, because I haven't looked
at it for
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: a long, long time. Um, and
it's it's yeah, that's, of very
good advice.
Bekah: Well, like going back to
what you said about onboarding
to
it's part of that, you know,
because I think that it doesn't
matter what stage you're at when
you join a new company. I just
joined company a month ago and
I've felt very comfortable to
give feedback like, Hey, this
is, this is what I thought when
I
read this. And so maybe we can
add clearer documentation here,
right.
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: everybody that's coming
new into a company, almost
everybody is going to have that
new experience and be able to
more clearly point out those
things make sure that, you know,
you, you have the most
up-to-date information, but
sometimes like
you have to invite people to do
that. Right.
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: if they feel like, oh,
you're just supposed to rush
through this thing not. Please
feel free to give us your
feedback on it, then you're
you're losing out on all of the
value that a new employee brings
to a position.
Helen: Yeah. Yeah. Especially,
they feel like you don't want to
hear it, then you definitely
screwed, you know?
Bekah: Like, oh, that takes too
much time. Like, we don't want
to
have to do that.
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: Okay, so Lee, I want to
talk a little bit about, so
first
of all, I've been super
impressed with all of the stuff
that you're
doing and you're always, I feel
like you're always on a drive to
learn and that's, what's so
great because I think that's the
mindset that everybody really
should have app. Asking
questions
and talking about these things.
And so like, what you think that
you've learned from your past
that you're bringing with you
to,
I feel like this is kind of like
the new stage of hell and you're
like moving into this new thing
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: time other places. Do you
have thoughts on that?
Helen: Um, yeah, I get thoughts
on that. Um, let me think about
it. Uh, no, I do have thoughts.
Uh, as I say, one thing I
learned
my whole experience is that, um,
life is hard. But a lot of times
you end up choosing your
struggles that? you're in so
many
things are happening to you,
which is true. But then
sometimes
it's like, you could have, you
have, um, you have a point where
you can make a choice, be like,
okay, no more, you know, and
just
figure out some way to get out
of it or, um, Oh, even less than
the
pain, if you can't get out of
it, because there there's some
problems that are just huge. Um,
also mostly know, most
importantly, my past experience,
I learned that to learn how to
invest in you so many times had
to, um, to, especially by being
a
startup founder, I had believe
in myself try and do something.
Even
was not qualified, when I was
complete ignorant about
something. Um, and then most
important, I didn't have the
resources or the capital, you
know, or the network to educate
me on something. I had to go
learn it figure out what I
didn't
know. And then go find out where
I can learn or get what I need
to
know. Um, I think the first time
I had to drop $1,500 on to
invest
in myself was like, okay, If we
go and do this, I know you just
got laid off. We go and do this.
We can do this. This is going to
give you closer to being a
startup founder. This is going
to
have you close it to this
person. So this, you know, some
people be
like, why would you do that?
That's not guaranteed.
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: guaranteeing, which is
true. There's No, guarantee
whether you're going to, there's
going to be success after your
tasks. You've complete it. And
there's no, guarantee that you
even got to complete the task,
which is funny too, but you
still
had to, I still have to learn to
invest in myself. now when now,
it's much easier to make
decisions. You know, cause I
done
that. I made so many decisions,
both small and big. So it's
like,
okay, what's my values while I'm
trying to attain. Now, this
align
to, what I trying to do? Is this
a compromise or is this a trade
off is or sacrifice? know, so
it's much easier make these mini
choices that we make every day
kind of thing people might
prolong for months on.
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: Yeah, and didn't make me
make y'all depressed.
Dan: no,
Helen: I got quiet real quick.
I'm sorry.
Dan: I was, I was trying to
process what you said. I think
that's, I think that was all
great. Um, I think one of those,
know, you talked, um, at the
beginning about how. You know,
doing the startup process or
whatever, like an MBA, you know,
this cost money and all this
stuff. And I think re like
framing it like that as a, as an
investment in yourself is, is
great. You know, it was a really
healthy way to look at it. And
it's true too. Right. And that's
just like this, this like
decision framework that you just
described, even if you don't
like
call it a framework in your
head. Right. But like, just like
muscle
memory almost, you know, you
practice it. And so you get good
at it. And being able to. Do
that where you, where you're
looking
at a decision and, um, know how
to it apart and like figure out
what you're looking at. Right.
Just exactly, like you said,
like
a, is this sacrifice? Is this,
you know, sort of compromise,
like, I don't know, it's such a
valuable tool, um, or skill. Um,
and that's really cool and it's
my silence finished documents I
was to process that. Cause, um,
it was, uh, I don't know, it was
quiet and it was really well
put, I thought,
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: Thanks.
Bekah: Like I remember when I
was coming into tech a couple of
years ago, we didn't have much
money. I've got four kids. And
somebody said, Hey, like, meet
you at Starbucks a half an hour
away. And like, for me, it was
that same thing. Like I had to
go
through my head and think about
like, there's there's money.
There's a cost to drive there.
There's I had a Starbucks card.
So I was like, I can use my
Starbucks card. I don't have to
worry about that. But like, even
that little bit of gas money
there. Required me to think
about like, am I investing in?
And, and
ultimately, like I was investing
in myself and retrospectively, I
can see that, like, this
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: being able to meet
somebody because that led me to
the support system that got me
through learning how to code,
but
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: hard in that moment
Bekah: to think like, okay, you
know, there's money that I can
spend here is that money worth
it? And like right. Nothing is
guaranteed there. But, you know,
think about what the long-term
investment is and, and where
that can take you. It's hard.
Helen: Yeah. I Al I always share
this with people. I was like,
the
struggle is, well, I'm not going
to even try to downplay that
soccer. The struggles will, but
even when you, when there's no
guarantees and there's a high
probability that you will lose,
quote, unquote, lose whatever,
try to have a backup Like if you
can obtain the thing that you're
get, what else can help you
support you to get you closer to
the thing you're trying to get?
Right. So, Um, so a lot of times
meeting up with these people,
like, cause you have to eat
there. Time is money. have to be
very cautious on your time You
know, you got to make sure
you're
leveraging your skills and your
time appropriately, but you also
want to make sure that you get
something out of it where you
can, um, that were be
beneficial, not to be sounds or
selfish, but
also, but still get the support.
Right. So, so a lot of times
when
I meet people and w I learned to
not accept a meeting or do a
meeting where there no agenda,
was no goal. I had to that out.
I
wasn't with, for the longest
time, I was wait for them to
figure out the agenda, but like,
no, no, no, no, baby, no, no,
no,
no. figure out what you need. A
lot of times people have not
even
take the moment to figure out
what they need and what they
want. Um, unfortunately people
will wait until they hit a Crow
crossroad. generally when some
type of life transition or crap
happened to you, which was
sucks. it's better to use your
make,
take a Saturday and a month. And
you use those times to have
those
life choice, moments, get some
coffee or tea and brunch, you
know, and just figure out and,
and journal and just write some
stuff down or even using no pat
on your phone. If you don't want
to write. Oh, a voice and just
trust are asking those small
questions like questions, you
know, like having a little Oprah
was that, so Sunday we'll have
your own soul Sunday and figured
this stuff out if you don't
figure that out, trust me,
somebody's going to figure it
out for you. So.
Bekah: I love that because it
is, you know, if you're, if
you're
not doing that consistently or
not taking that time out, then,
then it just like keeps coming.
Right. It
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: it never stops because
there will continually be asks
of
you or things that you need to
figure out for yourself. So if
you know, like this is what I'm
going to figure it out, then it
feels less overwhelming the
other three weeks or, you know,
other
six days of the week, however
you decide to plan it. So
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: that. I know I'm going to
make decisions on this day and
then you can do that without
having to worry. Hopefully.
Helen: Have you ever, I'm not
sure if it's me, but I have
noticed for my, in my own
personal life, that lessons that
you thought you had. We'll
revisit your revisit you to try
you out. It's like if it's like,
w like, walk up today and chose
violence was going to let know
what thing you thought you, you
learned. Let's try it again, you
know? So it just come in a
different form.
Bekah: it's like, oh yeah. I
said that I had mastered this
thing.
And then it's like, you, uh, no,
no, I didn't. I didn't master
anything.
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: Uh, man. Yep. No, that's,
that's interesting though,
because that sort of thing is
like, you know, you can process
something after and identify
where made a mistake or what you
could do different, but you
probably made those mistakes or
did things that maybe weren't
good the moment because the.
Well, how you think when you're
stressed is different than how
you think when you're relaxed,
right? How you
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: you're upset is different
than how you think when you're
happy. Right.
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: think that can go along,
like, uh, back to your or your
idea of having a plan like that.
And, um, if you have something
like that to fall back on a goal
or a whatever, or, you know,
these lessons that you've
learned, but, um, when things
are
bad, you know, how. Thinking.
Okay. Does this help my further,
my goal, you know, instead of
just reacting, know, just
reacting to, as, as it comes,
you know, like it's kind of all
ties
in together is really cool.
Helen: Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
Dan: really good way to be.
Bekah: Yeah. So this ties back
into like the things that you've
been doing. Cause you're doing a
lot of like really great things
to help people. And you've got
this, um, state of developers
and
you've got Right. And so, do you
want to introduce what those
things are to our listeners? And
then we'll kind of talk about
like how you're supporting
people through this.
Helen: Yeah. Yeah. Thanks. for
bringing it up. Um, so, uh,
state
of developers is a, um, industry
survey that I launch right
before
Christmas, where I'm trying to
survey developers, um, on
burnout
and their experience burnout,
anxiety, and depression. Um, So
it's, I'm asking it's premium
Lutz, a holistic view on it
because I realized that, you
know, when you're at work, you
bring your whole self to work.
Um, so whatever, all the crap
you
had to deal with at home that
comes to work with you, AI it
carpools with you. Um, and
whatever happens at work
carpools
with you.
Bekah: take the carpool lane
then
Helen: And you could try, you
could try. I think the PoPo
gonna
be like, ah, uh, so yeah, I, I,
cause I noticed that, um, there
was something I struggled with a
lot and I noticed that it wasn't
a very high priority in business
world. You know? Um, this is
always falls under the. The
wellness, whatever will, we time
doing, doing, dowel months. We
can focus on that, you know, but
we have to focus on these OKR as
our objectives or KPIs or key
performance indicators,
whatever. Um, and I, and I, I
always won't
allow myself to focus too much
on it because. Like I wanted to
create a product or app to help
me with this, but because I knew
it wasn't high priority, busy in
a business world, I was like,
that's another way for me to be
broke. And Helen, you already
have bad ideas. I never allow
myself, but I started noticing
that I was like, if I'm burnout
and I had some, some dark
moments. I know someone else has
some dark moments. I know if
somebody else is struggling with
coding and like, and trying to
balance life, life, me, my
current, um, life situation, I'm
trying to, uh, come up from
shutting down a startup, trying
to reenter the market, you know,
trying to learn some new skills
on top of that. I got an elderly
paradigm helping cold
characters.
You know, um, all of that is a
lot of stress. I'm not going to
be talking about trying to do
chores. John, trying to do the
job, honey that's in itself is a
whole day's work and that, so I
have less several full-time jobs
throughout throughout the day.
So
was like, if I'm struggling, you
had to be somebody else
struggling. And, and this is too
important to keep pushing as a
low priority. You know, this
guy, the impact, the bottom line
somehow, you know, and I start,
I start, Um, asking developers
and
tech founders for any of those.
Dan was one of them. So he
gracefully didn't want with me
and just ask him a series of
questions. And then, and the,
the mother stuff people was
telling
me, I was like, oh shit, this is
something okay. We need to get
math numbers for people to
realize, no, this is something
serious. Okay. You think. This
is not important. Like there's
one
insight. I don't want to quite
share yet that across the board,
depending on the developer and
the amount of privilege they
have, I was like in managers
knew they was making they
decisions
like this. were freaked
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: Right. And I saw, I did
like last I. Or damn some energy
engineer managers. And I asked
them, I didn't out, nobody. I
just say, have you lost because
of this reason, age one, I'm
saying, no, no, no, no, no. I'm
like really Cause I, I changed
the way I questioned that. I
said, Hey, have you lost talent
because of this reason. Um, and
if not, and if not, tell me your
secret and people would just
start us blaming their way.
Being
mindful and having their own
wellness programs and stuff like
that. And then there's some that
some men are just like, well,
I'm
not sure, but this is how my
people are struggling. Or this
is
how I'm trying to prevent my
people from struggling. And they
even know that it's the
workload, but like one per one
managers,
like, like he said, if I didn't
have the authority to push back,
I would even quit. That's his
whole. That's this whole guy,
the
jail free card, his bike is the
push mat kind of thing. So,
Yeah.
So, so that's what state of the
developer is. It's just, it's a
holistic survey. I'm trying to,
I have to, um, have them been
promoting it this month because
I'm trying to shorten it. I've
been, that's the number one
feedback I get from the
developers in the last.
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: right now, I'm just
trying to, I'm trying to get con
um,
condense it, you know, Mert some
of the questions and stuff like
that and make it simpler. Uh,
so, but I'm going to relaunch
it, um,
um, March and try to get more
people to, um, fill it. Um, and
I, hopefully I can be with a,
share the resorts results in,
um,
this summer, because the goal
was, I just didn't want to just.
Do a survey and we say, Yeah.
everybody's up because we are
tired and we broke and we tired.
We mentally broke. We just, so,
you know, that's why you got
these crappy products, you know,
but I wanted to also provide,
like, some of the questions is
asking people how they cope, how
did they deal with, how did they
help diddly manage it? You know,
kind of thing. So. Um, compile a
list of resources so people can
try the south. Cause this one,
the thing about burnout,
Bekah: Yup.
Helen: many factors contribute
to it and, and it's just like
productivity, um, is it's it's
not like one, it's not a one
solution is really up to the
person what's in the context of
their life. Are there variables
they have to deal with? So. So
that's where instead of
developers. Sorry, ask that now.
So go ahead.
Dan: no, not at all. I think
it's great. I think it's, I
think it's
very cool. And I, I think maybe
walk into this, but the Jovial
is, it is sort of. About framing
it, not for like the individual.
Right. But for the company who
has developers as employees.
Right.
Helen: Yeah.
Dan: how to this is, this is
like the. This is one of the
parts
that's like re very interesting
to me, right. Is, is like that
turning Cause cause company,
most companies don't like hire
developers and say, I'm going to
burn these people out. Right.
You
know? so they don't like, uh,
that it's probably, don't
realize
it, you know, or don't mean to.
so, uh, I was just wondering,
you
know, what, like what are ways
after it, you know, after
information all of developers
is, uh, if you. Are thinking
more as
a manager or something like
that. Like what are, what are
like some
ways to support your developers
and, and like watch for stuff
like this and prevent it from
happening, things like
Helen: Yeah. Yeah. So, So. just,
just for disclaimer. Shelby has
gone through like his own, um,
evolution kind of thing. Um,
because the, solution that I was
trying to propose as to solving
this problem, didn't pan out,
right? That's one thing about
startup world. So I wasn't sold
on, I'm not married to that
solution. married to trying to
figure out how hell then don't
be. This time next year, That's
what I'm sold on too. So, um,
right now Jovial is the whole
goal is definitely is more, um,
helping teams, um, to manage the
burnout. Um, and it's, it's not
just also just identifying
signals, but I'm thinking of
more
of Craney a developer tool
where, um, it allows both
parties the,
before. Right about the issue.
And that's really meaning being
transparent about different
things about your own goals.
Because a lot of times people
won't say something because you
know, that might go against
company policy, or they might,
that might that developer, the
manager might not want to tell
the developer does the developer
just want to call and he, the
manager might need him to step
up or her to step up and take a
leadership role is it's just
like, like how Can we help each
other along. Our goals and help
help each other instead of
sabotage each other's success
kind of thing. So, um, right now
Jovial is looking like, um,
while I'm trying to, I guess
this is my
first time me just sharing it
and trying to, um, see if
giving, um,
developers like an NPS tool,
kind of like an NPS score, like
on on
like how, like, when.
Bekah: you pause for a second?
What is NPS? I'm sorry, I don't
Helen: So I, so NPS is like a
net promoter score. You usually,
get
them as a customer, like, let's
say you bought, like, I bought
KFC the other day and I on my
receipt. You go to the website,
they was like, how likely are
you to. How buyers buy this
chicken
sandwich is again, how do I get
for employees? They normally get
NPS score that say, how lucky
are you to invite your developer
buddies to platform job here.
trying to gauge how much and how
much you don't kind of thing
with whoever you're working
with. So
mostly it's like, it's like, why
don't we have an MPS score on
just really gauge how much. This
task or how much this woke is,
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: impacting you and also
impacting the company. Because
one of the things I've learned
through the survey is that a lot
of developers don't know if
they're making an impact. I was
like, how do you measure your
progress? How do you measure
your
impact daily? Even know if they,
they make, have an impact, they
only have, like most of the
developers don't even have
metrics. They to judge. Or
they're worth, not even
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: goals or metrics for
themselves, from the company.
Right. it's just more of like
right now, I'm just, I'm
researching it and I'm trying to
figure out how can help
developers to really, um,
measure, uh, what they done and
measure. Um, Like the
conversation, like, did they get
the feedback or the support that
they need? Um, cause one thing
when I did, I did like a
self-assessment, last week on my
own personal experience with
burnout. And once I realized
that. my main problem was I
wouldn't speak up about my own
needs and concerns. Like I would
suffer through like the whole
month of February. was me
suffering through trying to
relearn something. And learn a
new technology, whatever try to.
I got past a technical
interview, but I didn't tell my
family, I
even had the interview because I
didn't want them to feel anxious
about it because we were kind of
going through some stuff
financially. And I didn't want
that burden of pressure. Just in
case I don't get the interview
and which happened, I didn't get
the third interview. Right. So I
kept this to myself. So. But I
have an elegant parent and she's
waking up early. So she started
kind of like interfere little
bit on my time when I was using
to
study. that made me wake up
three hours earlier. So that's.
like,
I'm up five in the morning, you
know, trying to do this stuff,
but could have like really saved
myself some of this agony, if I
just shared this information
where my family says, Hey, I got
this really hard thing I'm
trying to do. why little. And
that is, I
didn't want share because I
didn't want to disappoint. And
also it was just hard because
I'm still learning, trying to
figure
out the language. use with my
family to describe what the hell
I do for a living. Like, I, I
can't figure it out. Every word
it's just like, you know, the
Charlie brown, um, TV show, the
parents. I was like, mama. Why,
why, why watch? That's how
family. Why, why, why, why? So,
yeah, so that's where I'm at.
I'm
looking at. Like really like
trying to figure out a way where
people can be transparent and
just open in their
communication,
you know? So I thought the best
way is just really just the
score. It score it for yourself.
And if you willing, you can
share
next person, but at least help
you break down and identify and
pinpoint some issues. So you can
bring it up to the right place.
So, I'm not sure if I confuse
you or not. I'm still learning.
Bekah: We're also like, for so
important because those
conversations are super hard to
initiate and to talk about. And
last week, and one of my Virtual
Coffee breakout rooms, we talked
about, um, like what have you
taken from a past experience?
That was good, but you know,
your new work experience. And
for me,
that was like, A really
important topic because I I've
been very
transparent about I'm going
through. And I've talked about
the PTSD that I've my life and
Tasha, like the last four
months.
Well, it's like clockwork, like
every two weeks, here's
something
new to trigger you. Like not
stopping now. I'm like, I don't
know, right before this call, I
got a call about my mom had
heart
problems and a procedure and
stuff and it was like, You know,
like what do you do in those
situations? And for me, because
of my past experience, I'm like
able go to boss now and say
like,
Hey, listen, this is what's
going on in my life. I'm to try
but I'm
canceling my meetings for today
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: that's going to be okay.
But like, I don't know that know
for sure that there out there
that would not feel confident
doing that thing. Right.
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: and so if you, if you
have something that that open
conversation, like I am all for
that, because the more that we
can like we can, we can be
transparent with each. Well,
exactly. I love so much what you
said about like, you bring all
of
your experience to table and
that's been my. Talk for the
last
year I've been talking about the
person centered approach to
tech.
It's like, we're not, we're not
developers, we're human beings.
And have we have
responsibilities, we have these
things outside of tech and that
comes, that comes with us. it,
if
people don't acknowledge that,
then you're setting us up for
failure. And so I just really
love that idea that. Working on
helping to support the issues of
the whole people, the whole
person that comes to your team.
Helen: Yeah, Yeah, exactly is.
And it helps the managers too.
Like I'm not a manager, but,
well, I am because as a startup
founder, I had learn how to
manage three people and the man
is the developer. And the men,
that's the founder Hela and add
the man has done invest in Helen
because she was pissed off
because she wasn't getting her
money back. So that was a whole
nother management style I had to
learn. Um, but I think at the
end
of the day, we're just trying to
reduce the amount of risk we're
trying to make the worst case
scenario, the less worse, you
know, if it happens, it's like,
it's just like, I guess that's
why I'm looking at. Cause I
think one thing about burnout.
Um, and
the issue is about tackling it
and trying to get support around
tagging them. It is because
people was, is like, awesome.
Nice to have the tack tackle it.
NOLA is nice. Just like it's,
it's, like it's worst case
scenario. It is the Murphy's
law.
Bekah: Yeah.
Helen: You know what I'm saying?
So, but for me personally, I
even, I had to get, buy in to
tackle it because I always
pushed
it to the side because it, to
me, there was always something
more
poor and more grants bigger I
had to go fight and save kind of
thing. But at the same time it
was making life worse. Right. So
it's like, if you want life to
be a little bit easier, go
tackle
some of those demons. I'm
telling you be a ghost Buster,
figured it
out.
Bekah: It's valuable, super
valuable advice. Cause I think
that, you know, we always want
to do is do things in detriment
of
ourselves. Like, everybody else
going forward. And we, we don't
take care of like what we need.
And it's a thing. Somebody told
me somebody DME, and they were
like, you're the one that said
you should put the oxygen mask
on first. So why don't you do
it?
I'm like, I I should do the
things that I say
Helen: Yeah, no practice. What
you preach is so hard to do.
Yeah. It's just like, cause at
the end of the day, we trying to
manage things, you know? Um, and
we dealing with re reaction. So
when you don't say nothing. And
you do something, people going
to
react. Like I will, the reason I
was waking up early, because I
just found like, this is the
quiet as my house is it is once,
once one person up everybody's
up, you know? So my mom saw that
and she was like, okay, I'm
gonna wake up with, you know, I
need, I
love you, but no,
Bekah: Yes. I feel, I feel that
hardcore, my
Helen: Yeah.
Bekah: you wake me up at five?
No,
Helen: you know, so it's, so as
a manager is like, if you're
trying
to support your team, trying to
China, manage stakeholders and
stuff like that, you, your worst
enemy, your nemesis is that
unknown variable. Right? So why
don't you. The so easy and
comfortable for people to be
open, you know? Yes. He might
hear something. He might not
lie, but even if let's say,
let's say
you hear a developer, he's have
M they're ambitious and they
want
to have they own startups. And
you know, there are way to
thinking one foot out the door.
Don't think that way. Okay. What
can you align? What kind of
projects can you align with
them?
You know, to help them with
their go, but also help the
company
reach their goals. You know,
granted you got competitive
NDAs,
all that stuff. I get that.
Yeah. Don't, developer's going
to be an
ad in that Sesame street. Don't
be, don't be mean bad and
naughty
go against your company, you
know, you know, you know, just
try to align goals, like, like
I'm ambitious too, but I'm also
looking for a job, but I said,
okay, Don't apply for any job
that, that kind of like into
your competition world. know,
flat for
jobs you will want company to be
your. So your last dead there,
you're, we're selling branding
our new relationship, right.
Kind
of thing, where you want to
invest in those relationships at
that company. So you don't want
to screw over people or burn
bridges. You trying to have
strong ties. You're trying to
make sure that people hit goals
because at the end of the day,
get chance to hit yo goals. So
looking at it like that. So a
lot
of times I really encourage
managers and both the talent to
look at in that way. At it more
mutual benefiting because every
relationship have is lifecycle.
Just like every product have is
life cycle, development have his
life cycle. So of us like it's
not there, just being more, um,
uh, um, be, just be more, um,
uh,
intense, uh, thoughtful,
thoughtful,
Dan: I love that. I like, I
really like the framing of, you
know, aligning goals, um, for,
for this sort of thing. So it's
not like it gives you a good,
uh, Tool to conversation, you
know,
starter, you know what I mean?
So if you go into your manager
or
whatever, and you want to talk
about this, you don't just have
to say I'm tired or whatever,
you know, I have too much work
or
whatever, like saying let's have
a conversation where we like
work
together and align our goals
together. I think that it's,
it's
just, like you said, mutually
beneficial. I think that's, I
think that's great advice.
Helen: Yeah. Cause I talked to
my manager last week and it was
like, yeah, I had one person.
Um, last one because they were
so
tired, they was like, but they
also had another start-up and
they didn't tell nobody about
it. And also my, how can I help
you?
You know? that's all on that
person a little bit. You're
right. So, you know,
Bekah: Well, I think like back
to what you were saying about
acknowledging people where
they're at, like there are
companies that make you afraid
to be doing your own projects or
like want to claim your own
projects, right? Like, no I've
been doing this thing on my own
time. Like this does not belong
to you. And so having that
transparency and that clarity is
super important making sure that
everybody succeeds, not just,
you
know, the company or the person,
like everybody succeeds when
you're trans.
Helen: Yeah, you got to
remember, companies are just
like people. I
mean, you got mean people, you
got nice people, you got good
people. You got, you know how
Holly that I, people you get all
sorts of kinds of people and you
got that with companies. So if
you decide to go with a company,
you know, they're very strict
about that. You're making the
decision be like, okay, I gotta
be in the closet. Um, I go and I
can't wait my flag and be proud
about this, you know, kind of
thing. You, you make those
choices, right. you could find
companies where, and you can do
your own, um, D uh, diligent
research and see, do they have
entrepreneurial people? Is there
anybody that work here and also
have their own side project or
they own start up and they are,
they open about it? Do they have
in their bio? I'm a founder of
this and. Or do they just say, I
work at enterprise company, you
know what I'm saying? They had
this incognito kind of phrases.
So well, my views are not my
own. I seen so many of those in
the
engineering manager, Twitter,
Twitter, bio. I'm like, wow. You
know, there's some companies
like that, you know, you know,
so you
know, your own personality, you
know, what kind of, um, you
know,
whether you're. You know,
whether a company profile is
going to
have you, um, filling out some
kind of facade or just living
your own life, living your own
truth. So some companies I know
I'll have to put on a facade. If
I say I have to, right. My views
are my own. I know I'm screwed,
you know?
Bekah: I feel that 100%. And I
just want to say, thank you so
much, Helen, for being here with
us today, like this was an
absolute delight of a
conversation, and I know we all
learn so much from what you
said. So thank you for sharing
with us.
Helen: Uh, no,
Dan: Yeah.
Helen: for inviting me. I'm glad
I didn't bore you. So that was
my
fear. do not bore these
Bekah: I don't know. I don't
feel like you could ever bore
anyone.
Dan: no,
Bekah: are fantastic.
Dan: I had talked to you in the
past. I was not worried about
that even a little bit. And I
just said, am I thanks to you? I
really liked the work you're
doing and, um, I appreciate your
time. I appreciate coming on.
Helen: Oh, thank you guys. And
thanks. And good luck everybody
in the, in the webs that are
listening, you can it.
Dan: All right. Bye Helen. Thank
you for listening to this
episode
of the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by Dan
Ott and Bekah Hawrot Weigel. If
you have questions or comments
you can hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening and
we'll
see you next week!