Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello and
welcome to Season 5, Episode 4
of the Virtual Coffee podcast.
I'm Bekah. And this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And they're here, on this
podcast, sharing their stories
and what they've learned. And
we're here to share it with you.
Here with me today is my cohost,
Dan.
Dan Ott: Yo! What's up, Bekah!
Today, we talked with Yolanda
Haynes. Yolanda is a career
changer. She was previously
working in healthcare as a
certified occupational therapy
assistant and switched to doing
development. And so, we talked
about her decision-making
process through that, her
journey through, you know,
learning, learning on your own,
then some bootcamp stuff. She
did 100Devs and The Collab Lab,
which I was like -- which she
shared a lot about. And it
sounds like a very cool ...
experience for her. And ...
yeah, I don't know. What else
did we talk about? [Chuckles]
Bekah: No. I love being able to
talk to her journey and ... hear
what she ... thinks,
like, in retrospect of that
journey. Because I -- there's-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -always that, "I wanna do
all of the things and try all
of the things. And everybody
else is going so fast, and I'm
going slow or not at the same
pace." And she talks about, you
know, the impacts of being a mom
on that. And so, it's really
great to hear those reflections
because I think they're super
insightful for anybody who's
learning anything, really.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. No, I-
I- I love hearing about it too.
And I always wonder, you know,
I- I started out doing all this
stuff long before there are any
bootcamps, you know, at all. I
always wonder ... how if, you
know, how- how things might've
been different if there -- that-
that was available at the time.
And now, there's of course too
many options [laughs]. But it's
like, swung the other way. But
it was- it was cool hearing it
from Yolanda. Cuz she's -- she
tried a few different -- or did
a few different things and I
think, it was pretty suc-
successful at all of them. And
--
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. She did
an excellent job, like,
piecemealing together a pretty
good educational path for
herself. And like you said, that
could be really hard. Cuz there-
there is so much out there and
you kind of have to wade through
a lot of different things to
figure out what works for you
and gets you where you need to
be.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. Well, we
had a great time talking with
Yolanda and I know you're going
to enjoy listen to it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and
random check-in question. We
hope you enjoy this episode.
Today's random check-in question
is, what's your go-to snack when
you don't feel like making a
full meal? So, my name is Bekah.
I am a technical community
builder from a small town in
Ohio. And for the last three
days, I've eaten chips and salsa
for almost every single meal.
So, that is, for sure, my- my
go-to answer here.
Dan: Chips and salsa always
good. Hi, I'm Dan. I do web
development from -- in
Cleveland, Ohio. And ... yeah,
I dunno. I- I- I think, in those
situations, I like to go the,
you know, lowest effort
possible. If I -- if there's,
like, apples in the fridge,
that's gonna be- that's gonna be
a big one, you know? I'm just,
like, kinda take it out and eat
it. Or a banana or something
like that, you know? If there's,
like, other snacks --
Bekah: You keep your apples in
the fridge? Are you supposed to
do that?
Dan: I think it keeps them
fresher long -- fresh longer
maybe? I- I don't know. I like
when they're cold. I don't-
I don't know why [laughs]. But
the -- I- I just always have --
I don't ... I don't know. Now-
now- now I don't know [laughs].
Bekah: I wasn't sure if I was
doing it wrong or-
Dan: I don't think there's,
like --
Bekah: -just some preference.
Dan: I- I think it's just like
-- was like store-bought ones,
especially. It just keeps them
fresh longer. It,
like, you know, makes them last
longer. I think that's- I think
that's main -- the main thing.
There's nothing wrong.
Bekah: Well, like tomatoes, you
don't keep in the fridge. Cuz
then they get grainy. But apples
don't, right?
Dan: I- I don't know [Dan and
Bekah laugh]. That's it. That's
all I got. I- I -- my- my cold
apples, that's my snack
[laughs].
Yolanda Haynes: Well, hello. My
name is Yolanda. I'm from San
Diego, California, and my role
is a junior software engineer.
My go-to snack, it's -- or easy meal. So, there's this Japanese
thing called Ochazuke. And
that's the- the easiest meal I
can make. It's
rice, hot water, and there's
like a packet of ... flavor. And
then you just kind of pour hot
water over that packet of flavor
and rice. And that is like the
easiest meal. It's not really a
snack. But it's my go-to when I
don't feel like cooking at all.
The rice keeps me full. And it's
just, like, this hot water, it's
just a ... a blend of happiness [laughs].
Bekah: Mm.
Yolanda: So, that- that is kind
of my go-to easy meal slash
snack. But I did not know you
weren't supposed to put tomatoes
in the fridge. Cuz I do it
[chuckles].
Bekah: I've heard that it makes
some grainy [laughs].
Yolanda: But I keep my apples on
the counter. So, I don't know.
Bekah: Tomatoes go really bad
fast too if you keep them on
the counter. So you just have to
eat them really quickly. I feel
like --
Yolanda: [Whispers] Got it.
Bekah: I don't know. I -- one
of my favorite things I've done
in the last year, I always saw,
like, you could buy packet of
rice that you heat up in the
microwave. It's like 90 seconds.
And I'm like, "It doesn't even
take that long to make rice. Why
would you do that?" And now, I
have like a cupboard stash full
of [chuckles] 90-second rice.
Cuz it's so easy [laughs].
Yolanda: Is it- is it good? I-
I- I don't think I've tried
that.
Bekah: It's decent. I like to
buy the jasmine rice. And
that -- I
feel like it's probably better
than what I make on the stove
top, because I normally forget
that I'm making rice. And then
I'm, like, also way more likely
to burn it. So [chuckles] you
cannot -- well, as far
as I know, you can't burn it in
the microwave. I could probably
find a way to do that too
though [chuckles].
Yolanda: I guess it's opposite
for me. Asian household. So I
have a rice cooker. And it's
always ... there's always rice.
There's never a time [inaudible]
isn't rice.
So, it's just ... I- I don't
think I've ever burnt rice. Cuz
rice cooker kind of -- it's easy
peasy just to kind [inaudible].
Bekah: Oh, I think I burnt it in
the rice cooker before [Yolanda
gasps]. I think I had to throw
away my rice cooker [laughs].
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah. Should've
put it in the fridge.
Bekah: Well, this is not a
podcast about all of the ways
I've ruined food. So, we will go
ahead and talk about what we're
really here to talk about. And
that is Yolanda. So, we're so
happy to have you here with us,
and we always like to start off
with your origin story. So, you
know, where are you from and how
have you gotten to this point in
your tech journey?
Yolanda: Oof, good question. Let
me try to make it short. I don't
want to take too much of the
time. So, I born and raised in
San Diego. I've -- I'm a career
changer. So I used to work in
healthcare before I became a
software engineer. But my start
off the journey was probably my
first ... PC — family PC. I
wanna say it was a Windows 3.1
— was the OS. And I thought I
was a bad-ass
by taking apart my family
computer. And, you know, just
saying, "Oh, okay. This is- this
is what the inside of the
computer looks like." You know-
you know, I unplug everything.
I think it's called like a VGA
cable, the HDMI -- I don't even
think there was HDMI back then.
But just all the cables,
and then open up the family
computer, and- and was just try
to take out some stuff, and- and
then I'm like, "Okay, let me put
it back together." And I
thought, "Oh, I'm a hacker now."
Like, "I can- I can do this."
[Laughs] So that was probably my
first taste of tech, was kind of
doing that. And then --
Bekah: So, you did put it back
successfully though? Cuz I was
waiting for, "And then it didn't
work."
Yolanda: I mean, yeah. I don't
remember getting in trouble or
anything breaking. I think,
literally, it was just
unplugging
everything, opening the computer
case, and maybe take out a RAM?
I- I am not quite sure. And
then, just kind of, you know,
put everything together, and
then turn on the computer, and
it worked as if nothing
happened. So --
Bekah: Nice.
Yolanda: Yeah. That was kind of
-- I was very curious, and I
like to work with my hands
[chuckles]. So, that was -- that
kept me busy. And then, I played
a lot of those free games that
came with the computer. So, I
think Space Cadet was the one --
it's like a pinball machine. And
there was like a -- it- it came
with a
computer free trial or whatever,
and we didn't, you know, buy
games. So that was play the same
pinball machine over and over
again. And then, I started
learning how to type was in
middle school cuz they had those
typing program classes. So,
I really enjoyed that, got a
really good knack at that. And
then high school, I started
messing around with trying
to fix other people's computer.
I was helping out a neighbor
messing with their BIOS cuz they
had ... at that time was Windows
Vista, and she just had some
difficulties with that. And
then --
but I had to had my now husband
— back then was my boyfriend's
— help, cuz he was also into
tech. So, college, I was
thinking of doing computer
science. So I took a Comp Sci
101 class. And then, I had a
friend [chuckles], I --
and they told me like, "Oh,
yeah. You gotta be really
smart and really good to find a
job in this field." And at that
time, oof, this was over- over
15 years ago. We didn't have the
nice GUIs that we have today. So
when you, you know, try to — I
think it was Java — and compile
it, it gives you an error. And
it says, "Oh, between lines this
and that." But there's no red
squiggly lines. It was just,
like, find what's wrong with it.
And I would spent hours just
trying to find what I missed.
And there'll be a misspelling,
or a semi-colon, you know,
something- something basic. But
I wrote the code, so I didn't
see it, you know? When I asked
my friend, you know, they'll see
it. And they're like, "Oh, yeah.
It's- it's-
it's right there. And I'm like,
"Oh, thanks." But he's like,
"Yeah. If you wanna find a job
in this field, you gotta be,
like, really smart." And I'm
like, "Oh, that's- that's-
that's not me." So, I- I ...
sticked with my original major,
which- which was Japanese,
cuz I was thinking of going to
the linguistics route then. And
so I graduated with that, with a
minor in media arts and
technology, cuz I still wanted
some sort of tech ... learning.
So that's what I did. Then I
went abroad, worked and taught English in Japan for
about two years, and then came
back, and thought, "Oh, what am
I gonna do?" Then I did
occupational therapy assistant
route. So I was in that field
for about five to six years.
Then COVID hit, lost my hours,
then I learned how to code. So,
that's where I started my coding
journey, October of 2020. Then I
found a job, December of 2021.
So, kind of took a little over a
year. And here I am, with you
guys, today [laughs].
Bekah: [Chuckles] That's
awesome. You have like a couple
career pivots, right?
Because your major is Japanese
in Utah, and then you did the
occupational therapy route, and
then, came over to tech.
Yolanda: Yes. It was a windy,
windy journey. I mean, I had
other jobs. I think I was an
afterschool program aid. Then I
was a dance instructor in
between, so I- I did a lot of
odd jobs here and there ...
before ... right here ... where
I am today.
Bekah: That's awesome. And I
know as you're learning, I wanna
talk about your learning
journey, cuz I think that you've
done a lot of cool things. And
in- in somewhere along the line,
you also had a kid. And so, that
impacts your journey too. So,
let's maybe not talk about the
kid yet, and [Yolanda chuckles]
talk about, you know, what- what organizations -- or- or what ...
like ... things did
you do to help you stay on track
with learning how to code?
Yolanda: Hmm. Good question. I
think -- so I tried -- a couple
of times trying to learn how to
code. I definitely bought a
Udemy course, and it was, like,
"Here's how to build your first
website or a complete website."
So I did that from start to
finish, and then thinking, "Oh,
okay. That's it?" I think that
was, like,
2015, or later, or earlier, or,
yeah. Sorry, my time's off. But
-- so, I did that. And then,
nothing came about. And then, I
wanted to do a career change
with another friend who was
also a COTA [Certified
Occupational Therapy Assistant].
And we were like, "Oh, we need
to figure out, like, how are
we gonna -- what's the, you
know, the end goal?" Cuz we
can't keep transferring patients
in our 60s or 70s. I mean,
technically we can. But it's not
best on our body. So, we were
like, "Okay, maybe we should,
like, really focus on learning
how to code." So we tried the
Odin project.
Bekah: Mm.
Yolanda: And then, [laughs] I
tried that. And then, she had
some -- she had to deal with
some, you know, family stuff.
So, she had to put that on
pause, and I was by myself
again. I'm like, "Oh, okay." So,
that didn't ... happen. And
then, I found a 100Devs Leon's
class, and it was like a free
bootcamp. My husband found it,
like, I think, through Reddit.
And I thought, "Oh, okay. Well,
it's free. I lost my hours
during this pandemic in 2020.
It wouldn't hurt." So, that's
how I started really focusing on
learning how to code because the
community was just there. There
was a lot of people I could just
kind of rely on and have that
accountability. So I did that,
while doing part-time work,
while taking care of the kid.
And just being in that community
was helpful. And then, during
that commun- learning, I -- my
teacher, or Leon, said like,
"Oh, networking is very
important. And then, I found
Virtual Coffee -- no, I found
somebody posted, say, "Hey, you
should check out Virtual
Coffee." And that was, like,
November of 2020. And, yeah. And
then, I just kind of ...
listened to all the devs in
there, you know, or people in
tech, their journey, how they
studied or, you know, their
explanation of things. And that
was helpful. So I kind of tried
to combine listening to that,
doing Leon's class, and, of
course, doing outside stuff like
the freeCodeCamp. I dabbled into
it a little bit, trying to
solidify those basic
foundations. And there are other
free courses. I think there's,
like, Scrimba that I probably,
you know, dabbled in. So, here
and there. But I definitely was
one of those people that ...
bite off way more than I can
chew. So [laughs], I think
it's the fear of missing out.
That was like the- the number
one thing. Like, "I gotta do
them all."
Bekah: Mm, yeah.
Yolanda: "I have to. If I don't,
I'm not gonna get it."
So, Leon's class, freeCodeCamp,
Scrimba, alrite. Networking,
Virtual Coffee, you know, these
other communities. I got to do
them all because if I don't, you
know, I'm not gonna be
successful. And, yeah
[chuckles]. Definitely burnt out
here and there throughout the
journey.
Bekah: Can you tell us a
little bit more about Learn With
Leon? We've had a- a big influx
of 100Devs. And I think somebody
told us that ... his post about
100Devs was one of the top two
most viewed posts on Reddit or
something like that. So, it's
really taken off recently. But
I've heard a lot of positive
experiences from there. And I'm
just curious, like, how things
work with that.
Yolanda: Yeah. I -- this year
is just crazy amount of people
who joined. I think, the first
session Leon had, like, 7000
views on his Twitch. And that
is-
Bekah: Wow.
Yolanda: -that was just crazy.
When I started,
I wanna say we had about 3000 at
the start? Maybe two? And
that- and that was, like, his
somewhat first time of doing it.
I think you had a five week of
course, prior to doing the
100Devs. But when he did the
official 100Devs in October
of 2020, I think there was about
two, maybe 3000 of us. One
guy, Leon, does live Twitch
streaming twice a week for three
hours, and then, he has office
hours for three hours. And then,
we just kind of go -- he does
live coding, and then we follow
along, and then he assigns
homework. So, the experience,
this is my first bootcamp.
So there's nothing much for me
to base or compare it to.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: And I've tried to learn
how to code on my own, and I
failed miserably [laughs]. So,
yeah. Leon's class helped me, at
least solidify that foundation
and allowed me to kind of expand
my skill sets through that. So,
I liked it because it helped me
... [sighs] stay focused, I
guess, is -- and- and not do too
many things at once. So, I
thought, "Okay, Leon's class.
Let me just commit this. Class
is Tuesday, Thursday. I have to
be on class." So, I would change
my work schedule to make sure I
make it to those class. Because
I'm one of those people, if I
miss a class, I- I don't know if
I have enough time to play catch
up. So, if I ... make it -- if
I'm sex- sussex- successful --
oh, I can't even say this word
[Bekah and Dan chuckle] is --
then, you know, if I'm at that
class, I -- I'm there. I'm gonna
learn. And the chances of me to
be ... to find a job in the end
will help me, then I- I will do
whatever I can. So, you know,
I talk to my husband, and say,
"Hey, can you watch the little
one?" Okay. Talk to all my
patients, "Hey, I'm -- this
block, I can't see you because
I'm busy." So -- and it was
helpful for -- to establish
that. And then, I relied on that
Discord community. Because when
I have questions about homework,
I'll reach out, say, "Hey, I
don't get it. I don't understand
JavaScript. I don't -- it
doesn't make any sense to me,"
you know? And then, going
through Virtual Coffee, I was
like, "I s- I don't get
JavaScript.
I -- am I ever gonna get it?"
Like, "I -- how do you guys
get it?" And it's -- it was very
comforting to hear stories, you
know? People would say, "Yeah,
it- it sucks at first. It- it's
gonna click. It's going to take
some time. Don't worry about
it." Or, "Hey, try these
resources. It might click seeing
it this way." So ... I hope that
answered your question. I think
I- I went -- I deviated. I'm
sorry.
Bekah: No. That was great.
Dan: We're all about mean-
meandering topics here [laughs].
It's- it's the best way to --
it's the best way to be.
Bekah: Were- were the hours --
the office hours live stream
too?
Yolanda: Yes. So, he was live
... originally, it was- it was
on Saturdays. And then, he
switched it to Sundays for three
hours. So, I think, in the beginning, it was like homework
review. And then, it became more
of just, "Hey, if you have
questions, I'll answer it." So,
he'll open up and there'll be
like a flood gates of questions.
And he'll- he'll answer it live.
So, sometimes, it'll be about
the homework. Sometimes, it'll
just be about the dev journey,
or, you know, s-s- about not
understanding the syntax of
something. And he'll go over it.
Or he'll try to show it in a
different way. So, for me, that
was helpful because it just kind
of ... that review was- was
nice. So, I liked it. It was
helpful.
Dan: That's- that's really cool.
I- I mean, that's a- a pretty
interesting, and I think, pretty
unique ... approach. And it
sounds -- well, I mean, a lot of
people seem pretty into it. So
... it's cool.
Yolanda: Yeah. It's -- I think
it's cool.
Dan: Mm.
Yolanda: Just a lot of work.
Because it's ... you have to put
in the effort. I -- like I said,
I don't have any other bootcamp
experience. So, this is, like,
really relying on yourself and
others.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: And from -- I guess
what I've heard what other
people who's been through
bootcamp, and physically been
through bootcamp, there's this
kind of nice face-to-face,
you know? You could directly ask
the teacher exactly at that
moment when you have, you know,
questions. And the
accountability, I have a feeling
is much higher doing in-person
bootcamp. And then, also, you
pay. So, you really want to make
sure that you complete this
bootcamp. While this was free,
but it kinda give you that ...
if you have other priorities, you
don't feel like you have to pick
one or the other. You could
always try to play catch up. And
there's no money lost, only
time. Which is ... not a bad
thing [chuckles]. But I like it.
It was enjoyable. And I'm
helping out right now as a mod
[moderator]. So, trying to give
back-
Dan: Oh, nice. That's nice.
Well, that's cool.
Yolanda: -with what I can.
Dan: That's really cool. I --
and I- I -- you said something
about ... you know, when you --
when- when you first started
this, how- how it helped you,
you know, sort of focus your
learning energy, or [laughs] you
know, like, kind of direct it.
And I think that's a -- I think
that's something I wanted to
call it too, is it's- it's an
important thing to do. And it-
and it's one of the -- when
people are talking about
learning, you know, and they're-
and they're just starting out,
it's- it's one of the biggest
reasons for- for- for doing some
sort of class, something
structured. A bootcamp, or a- a
course, or- or the 100Devs, you
know, style or whatever. But
there is -- our -- there's just
so much that you could learn,
right? [Chuckles] And it's
almost impossible to just, on
your own, when you- when you
don't know anything to start.
It's almost impossible to
self-direct yourself through ...
without- without a plan, you
know what I mean?
Yolanda: [Whispers] Right.
Dan: So, we've -- I've- I've-
I've heard other stories,
you know, it's kinda similar
experiences of, you know, being
like, just going all over the
place [chuckles], stuff- stuff
getting overloaded, right? And
then ... yeah. And then- and
then, like, something like a
course or whatever will- will
just, like, help you kind of
narrow it down. I think, it's
important. I'm- I'm glad it
obviously worked out --
[chuckles] worked well for you.
Yolanda: It did.
Dan: It's cool. Yeah.
Yolanda: [Chuckles] It did. I
had to, like, think about it
too. I was like, "What's the
best way to describe this, you
know, feeling and experience?"
And I -- and the best one I
could think of is, you know,
when you go into, like, an
all-you-can-eat sushi bar, or
like, you know, a buffet, and
you are just overwhelmed with
this plethora of, like, food.
And you're like, "Where do I
start? I'm gonna eat it all."
And that's what I feel like
[laughs] when this is -- the
starting of the coding journey.
It's like -- people was like,
"Oh, you gotta learn -- you
should learn Python. You
should learn j- excuse me, Java,
JavaScript, HTML, CSS. And
you're like, "Okay, sure." So,
I'm, like, going down the buffet
line and just grabbing different
stuffs [laughs]. And that's-
that's how it felt, like, in the
beginning. I was like, "Okay, I
should grab them all. I need to
grab them all. If I don't, I'm
gonna miss out. And if I miss
out, I'm gonna miss, you know, I
won't know the taste of this
delicious food." And I feel
like, that's how it was in the
beginning, before I finally
slowed down to one plate
[Yolanda and Dan chuckle].
Bekah: I love it. That's such a
great analogy. And people often
ask too, like, "Well, what are
you interested in doing?" And-
and kind of like you're saying,
like, well, you haven't had a
taste of everything. So if you
are -- wanna know what you're
interested in, then I guess you
should probably sample all of
the things, you know? Which is
really not ... probably, like,
it's -- I think, it's really
hard to know what you're
interested in, until you really
have tried it for awhile.
Yolanda: That's true. It's like
asking a kid, "What do you wanna
be when you grew up?"
I mean, they could answer. But
it's always changing. And ...
I don't know. If I were a kid, I
feel like, for me at least, it's
like, "I wanna do -- I wanna be
a pediatrician. No, I like
animals. I wanna be a
vegetarian." It was just like
... I don't know what I really
wanna do. I still don't know.
Bekah: My daughter once said,
she was like, "I either want to
be a princess, a cat, or a
doctor." And I was like,
"Alrite. Well, that seems pretty
easy, doctor." [Laughs]
Dan: [Chuckles] Go for- go for-
go for cat. Cat seems like a
really good life [chuckles]. If-
if you, I mean, if you have a
good home anyway. I feel like if
you're a cat, you have it set,
right? [Laughs] Yeah. No, that's
a great point. And you know
what? Honestly, it- it -- so,
when- when you were talking
about you're -- you were in
college and the intro to CS
class, and sort of made that
choice to, you know, that's an
experience a lot of
people have too. And, like,
you're talking about what do you
wanna be when you grow up when
you're a kid, but that question,
like, hangs around forever, you
know? There's not like a- a
thing, and that -- there's
not a point where that can, you
know ... maybe you've found
something that you're fine with
or whatever, but it's always as
we've approved [chuckles]
possible to change, right? But
that experience of, like, going
into freshman year is ... so
fraught, that sort of stuff, you
know? And ... those, like, it's
funny how those- those -- I- I
just keep thinking about your-
your friend telling you that you
had to be smart to do this or
whatever. And you know, when
you're a- a freshman and
everything's overwhelming. And I
feel like you're still probably,
like, trying to take stuff off
of the buffet. It's just a
different buffet, right?
[Laughs] And ... how- how,
like, one- one sentence, like
that can- can change, like,
what you, you know, your whole
... life, really, you know?
Like, I don't really have a
point [laughs] other than I was
just -- I just keep thinking
about, you know, I just keep
coming back to that. Cuz I --
I've had -- I mean, I had
experiences like that in college
too, you know? And I changed
majors a few times and ... all
of that stuff, including being
in computer science major, and I
changed to English instead of
Japanese. So, it was- it was a
little- a little easier for me
[laughs]. Although, you know,
now that I think of it, I was
signed up for a Japanese class,
like, first semester of freshman
year and ... well, I didn't- I
didn't -- I dropped that- that
class very quickly because
[laughs] it was -- it didn't
well -- it didn't work out well
for me. But I feel like it
might've been early in the
morning too? I don't know. It
wasn't the right fit [laughs]
for me.
Yolanda: Morning classes are
hard, regardless of the subject.
Dan: I'm trying to find, like,
a point of what I was saying.
I don't really have a point
other than I was affected by
that -- by- by your story. And
it- it's just, like, an
interesting thing to think
about.
Bekah: But it's -- it is true.
I mean, the things that you say
to other people matter. And it
might be an off the cuff thing.
But, you know, we- we talked
about this in Virtual Coffee.
Like, the- the impact of your
words does matter. And I
remember I had a student. My
first or second semester
teaching freshman English. And I
always tried to write something
positive on everybody's paper.
And he ... I think, was ...
taking this course for -- this
was not his first time
taking the course. And he came
up to me after the class and he
said, thank you so much for
saying whatever nice thing I've
said. He was like, "I have never
had any teacher say anything
nice about my writing. It's
always been, you know, red marks
or negative comments." And it --
that kind of thing just made
such a huge impression. Because,
you know, one- one small remark,
and it made a total difference
in-
in all the- the way that he
communicated and his investment
in the class. And I think that
positive or negative, that's-
that's what it does. And, you
know, unfortunately I think
women have experienced a lot of
negativity and gatekeeping in
more scientific or technical
fields — at least many stories
that I've heard. So, it's
definitely something that- that
I hope gets better. And I
appreciate people telling
stories about that. So we're
aware of that kind of thing. So,
100Devs isn't the only program
you did, right? You -- did you
also do Collab Lab?
Yolanda: I did. Yes. So I was in
Collab Lab summer of last year
from July to August? June to
August? Something like that. So,
yeah. Another community I am
happy to be in and help out. So
love that- love that ... team,
people ... everyone [chuckles].
Bekah: Do you wanna talk a
little bit about what they're --
The Collab Lab does?
Yolanda: Yeah. Oh, I hope I do
... justice. It's an awesome,
awesome group -- or
organization, where they help
... people who are new to the industry and teach them how to
collaborate in a team on a
project. So, you are given a ...
you are -- actually, you- you
have to apply to- to join Collab
Lab. And once they accept your
application, then you are put in
the team of four new developers,
and then about two to three
mentors. And then, it's a eight
week, I think ... process or
journey, where you create a
React app. It's like
a shopping cart. Everybody does
the same thing. It's the same
application throughout other
teams. And then, from start to
finish, you build your- your
application. So -- and then, it
just kind of ... every week, we
go through kind of what we've
learned ... ooh, hold on. Sorry.
Let me try to think what else.
And then, every week, you are
paired up with another dev. So,
it's like you, plus another dev.
And you work on this small task
that's been given to you. And we
go through, like, the GitHub
repo. You're assigned the task,
and then, there's, like,
acceptance criteria. So they try
to mimic a real life's work
scenario. So, in that week time
span, we have to try to complete
that task and push it, so the
mentors could take a look at the
-- do a code review. And then,
we also do a code review of our
partners or the other teams ...
code. And then, they teach us,
like, how to do a proper code
review. You can't just say,
"Everything looks good. Thumbs
up," you know? Try to give a
better feedback. Like, "Oh, what
does this do?" Or, "I don't
understand this. Can you explain
it better," type of comments.
And then, if it looks good, then
the mentor will give, like, a
thumbs up kinda thing, and then,
we push it to- to that main
branch. And do -- and then you
-- the second week, you get
paired with a different dev. So
it gives you that collaboration
and getting used to working
with- with different people.
So, the team I'm on -- was on,
was a fantastic team. I wasn't
strong in React, so they
definitely helped me get a --
gain a better understanding and
kind of teach me through it.
And I just learned what AC was,
which was Acceptance Criteria,
you know? And then, when you
do the GitHub, there's like a
template, and then, try to give
it that nice structure of when-
when you commit the code. So,
it's not just code. You're
explaining exactly what you're committing, you know, instead of
trying to have the other people guess what you're committing.
So, that was really nice. And
then, they talked about
accessibility. And ... it- it
was -- it's -- it was an awesome
program. I hope I did it
justice. I'm like -- it was like
a really-
Bekah: Well, we --
Yolanda: -terrible explanation
[chuckles].
Bekah: No, I think you did a
really good job. And we'll have
a link to it so everybody can
check it out afterwards. We've
had a lot of Virtual Coffee
members go through Collab Lab.
And I really appreciate that ...
the collaboration that's focused
on. Because I -- my bootcamp
experiences similar issuers [??]
in that. It was like self-paced.
I was- I was really by
myself. There wasn't a lot of,
like, one-on-one meetings, or
... any collaboration happening,
which it's -- and made it doable
for me at the time. But like, in
retrospect, I feel like I needed
to make more of an effort to do
those types of collaboration,
because then, it was, like, kind
of a learning curve to figure
out how to communicate about
things and when to communicate
about things. So, did you feel
like that collaboration -- what-
what was the
learning curve from where you
were when you started to
have those good quality
collaborative meetings?
Yolanda: Ooh, good question.
I- I was going to apply ... I
think it was their ... spring
cohort? The beginning of the
year. And I
think that was after a month of
just learning JavaScript. I
reached out to another Virtual
Coffee member, and ...
either she applied or she just
went through it. And she told
me, "Hey," like, "Try the next
one. Because you should have
some sort of a good foundation
before. Cuz they -- Collab Lab
does not teach you how to code.
It just teaches you-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: -how to collaborate.
So having that coding foundation
is- is vital." So then, I
pushed it until summer. So I
started 100Devs at October of
2020, then I got into Collab
Lab, let's say, like, July. So
... like, eight months? Seven,
eight months? Sorry. I had to
count [all laugh]. Before -- you
know, I- I mean, even then, I- I
didn't feel comfortable. I
didn't think I was gonna get
accepted to tell you the truth.
Then, an- another 100Dev-er, she
said, "Hey, you gotta shoot your
shots. You don't know-
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: -until you try." Cuz I-
I have this, like, very low
confidence, you know? I was
like, "I'm not good enough," or
"I'll- I'll need another year
before I -- I'm -- I can even do
X, Y, and Z." So, she's like,
"Hey, if it doesn't work out,
there's- there's no negative
impact. Like, you just try again
at the next cohort." I'm like,
"Okay. Yeah, there's nothing
wrong. There's no consequences."
So, I applied in, lo and behold,
I got accepted. So, I just
thank to that person, that
helped me out and pushed me for
that. So, I- I think, I had,
like, eight months ex-
experience before I applied to
Collab Lab. And then maybe a
month of React experience. So,
very little. Very, very baby
chick stage of that [laughs].
Bekah: [Chuckles] Do you feel
like it helped you when you ...
moved on?
Yolanda: It helped ... me gain a
better understanding of how
collaboration works.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: In the 100Devs, we did
work on a team project. So that-
that was helpful, but it's-
Bekah: Nice.
Yolanda: -a lot of newbies as
well, [chuckles] you know,
working on a project to-
together.
So, there was a lot of ... "I
think this is what we're
supposed to do," kinda thing.
Or like, "How do we share the
code?" Or, you know, "If- if one
changed, do we just share it
through, like, Google docs?"
So, it was -- it's still a
lot of how the process, kind
of, "What do we do?" "I don't
get it." So, it's a lot of
builders with tools, and we're
just eager to build, and we were
like, "Okay, so what do we do
now?" "What's a blueprint?" You
know? [Laughs] It was like, "Oh,
okay. Maybe we should do that
first," kinda thing. And that's
how it felt. And then, with
Collab Lab, it's like, "Okay,
you guys. This is the
blueprint," you know? "This --
these are your roles." "This is
our expectations of you," you
know? "And this is -- you should
finish this task," you know?
And then, "Before you go on to
the next one." "Don't worry
about this," you know? "Don't
worry about the color of the
house yet. That's at the very
end," you know? "Worry about
building that ..." I don't know.
I'm not a construction worker.
So, you know, like, the
foundation, the frame, you know?
Focus on that first. So, for
Collab Lab, I was taught, you
know, "Focus on the ... kind of
-- the functionality. Does it
work?" You know, versus making
it look pretty. Cuz I'm- I'm a
visual person. So, I was like,
"Oh, maybe it needs to look this
way first." And they were like,
"Yes, it should look this way,"
or, "It's great to look that
way. But maybe, we should focus
on ... does it work? Does this
button work, no matter how ugly
it is? [Laughs] Is it -- does
it click? And if it clicks, does
it go to or do its thing?" So,
that's what I've learned is,
"Oh, okay. There's this way of
building things," which was,
like, fantastic. And very
different from what I've learned
in 100Devs. So ... yeah.
Dan: That's great. It sounds
like a- a- a great learning
experience. And- and something
that I thought I would ... just
having -- I mean, I haven't ever
done it, obviously. But like, I-
I would encourage anybody to do
because that's sort of the ...
you know, learning, like, actual
coding is important, obviously
[laughs]. But there's so much
that goes into a job, or- or- or
a project, or anything like
that, that isn't just writing
code, you know? And there's ...
you know,
lots of people have lots of
trouble, like, getting kinda
started up with any project or
with, you know, in a new
company if they don't have this
sort of experience. And ...
having that, like, confidence
to, you know, to know like,
"Okay, I know how to do code
review," you know what I mean?
"I know how to do ... oh, you
know, pull requests even. All
that -- all of us -- all this
stuff, I know," you know? I ...
just -- that it -- that it's like
something that ... you know,
to go through this level of
practice at it, you know, it
gives you that, like, the full
confidence to ... "I don't even
worry about it anymore," right?
It almost becomes second nature,
right? And so that -- so, like,
if you go into a job interview,
for instance, you don't have to,
like, sweat about that part,
[chuckles] you know? Anything
you don't have to sweat about
is- is good. And I think,
usually, like, the job
interviewers can probably tell.
Like, when you're sweating, when
you're not, about- about certain
things, you know? And, you know,
but work with people, it's -- it
is -- it's been an important
skill [laughs]. And it's hard to-
hard to, like, display on a
resume too, you know?
So, The Collab Lab, you know,
completing The Collab Lab thing
is- is, like, a nice, like,
easy- easy to point to, you
know, thing. Oh, that's really
cool.
Yolanda: Yeah. It's like --
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: Oh, sorry.
Bekah: I was just gonna say, I
think that you've done a great
job, like, constructing your
learning how to code journey
through all of the opportunities
that you've done, and, you know,
all of the skills that you've
learned. It feels like you've
got a very well-rounded
experience coming out of that.
Yolanda: I -- yeah, I think so
-- I hope so. I mean, [Bekah
chuckles] better than when I
try to do it on my own.
So, [laughs] I- I cannot
complain. It's ... you know, I-
I just wished ... I wish I knew
it was gonna take this long.
Then I would have really-
Bekah: Mm.
Yolanda: -took my time with it
and just kind of savor the taste
instead of trying to rush and
try everything [laughs] or do
everything. But, yeah. I'm --
but- but then [sigh], it's just
been helpful because ... awful
-- but, you know, the, you know,
the situation that we're all put
in with COVID. And I don't know
if I would be where I'm at today
... if it -- if that didn't
happen. Because, you know-
Bekah: Mm.
Yolanda: -when I try to learn
how to code, I was working,
you know, 30, 40 hours and try
to do coding on the side.
But with COVID, I was able to
focus, you know? And- and try
to, you know, find the community
that I felt comfortable in. And-
and then just kind of, "Tada,
here I am." [Laughs] [Dan
chuckles] It's just -- it's-
it's help- and it's very helpful
to have these free communities
too, you know? Virtual Coffee,
100Devs, Collab Lab, you know?
It wasn't out of my pocket.
So the money that I was able to
save a lot goes through, you
know, bills, food, or, you know,
emergency, whatever. So, it's
just ... it's really nice that
this -- in this day and age,
there's still a lot of people
who want to help other people
without ... you know, with the
kindness of their heart and
their time, you know? Cuz it's
not- it's not an easy thing to
do and ... yeah. Anyways
[laughs] --
Dan: Yeah, no. It- it -- that's
important. It's just like you're
helping with ... 100Devs, right?
You're volunteering with them
and stuff. It's- it's always
cool to be able to, like, once
you have ... s-some amount of
time or- or space available to
yourself, to ... you know, to be
able to give back in ways since
... it's neat [??].
Bekah: Yeah, well--
Dan: It's cool that -- oh, go
ahead.
Bekah: I was gonna say too,
like, you have done note-taking
for us too at Virtual Coffee.
And you're- you're usually
there. You are on the west
coast, but you are there, 6 AM,
your time, frequently.
And I- I just, I love to see it.
I -- it's- it's so, you know ...
I know, like, what a testament
it is to your character, that
you are so willing to give back
and to support the communities
that you've been a part of.
Yolanda: Yeah. I think it's-
it's because, you know, I- I
feel comfortable being
in the communi- community, you
know? Virtual Coffee from the
get-go. I think, I- I messaged
you, Bekah, it was like- it was
like love at first sight. That
first meeting, I -- it was very-
it was very nice. And I mean, I
probably really doing it, get
involved with Virtual Coffee,
until months later. I know,
like, Nerando would, like, edge
me. Like, he was like, saying,
"Hey, [unintelligible]." He was
like, "What do you think,
Yolanda?" Or like, "I want you
to, you know, have a
conversation too." Cuz I was
mainly a fly on the wall in
every meetup, you know? It's
just like, I just wanna listen
[chuckles]. Cuz I feel at that
time, I can't contr- or -- yeah.
As silly as it was, I felt like,
"Oh, yeah. There's this new --
I'm the new person. I- I can't
contribute to this discussion.
There's -- I can't say anything.
There's no vital information.
So I'm just gonna keep my mouth
shut and just- and just listen."
And that was, oof, for a f- a
few months. But with the
consistency, I think [chuckles]
other members, like, sees me,
and they're like, "Hey, so what
do you think, Yolanda?" Or,
"Hey, Yolanda. Long --" you
know, "Good to see you on here."
And because of that, and then
reaching out to me, and kind of
putting me on the spot, kind of
broke the ice. At least for me,
it- it helped me get more
comfortable. And then, finally,
took the plunge of like, "Okay.
I think I could help out with
the note-taking." I think it
was, like, Meg needed a help or
something in one of the rooms.
And I'm like, "[Breaths fast]
Okay. I- I think I can do this
[laughs]." [Dan chuckles]
Bekah: Yeah. So I wanna back up
a little bit, kind of? I don't
know if it's backing up. But
[laughs] you mentioned that
you're a mom too. And we talked
about this journey and ... is --
we all, you know, that it's
challenging to be a parent
[chuckles] and to be working,
especially during COVID times
and- and learning. So, I- I feel
like, anytime we can hear the
story of ... you know, how you
survived [chuckles]
being a parent and learning,
or working through things, I
think that that story looks a
lot different than- than other
people's stories who, you know,
might not have all of the same
responsibilities. So what do you
think -- w-what -- how was that
for you as a mom?
Yolanda: Oof. It was tough. It
is tough. It's still tough.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: It's-
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: -not easy. I ... I
mean, I'm very fortunate that I
do have my husband, you know?
And he does help out. But it's-
it's just ... [sighs] it- it was
-- it is, it's difficult. It's a
lot of trying to figure out when
can I study, you know? I have —
at that time — 2-year-old saying
like, "Hey, play with me," you
know? Like-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: -"Let's play together."
Because he sees me here, you
know, on the computer, at home.
So, it's, you know, play time
[chuckles]. No matter how hard I
try, it was like, "Okay, give-
give me five minutes," or ...
you know? But they don't- they
don't understand time. You-
Bekah: Yep.
Yolanda: -you say five, they
think it's, like, now [laughs].
So ... and then, you know, it's
just trying to adjust the
schedule. I remember trying to
wake up, you know, five in the
morning to try to learn how to
code. And then, of course, my
little one — three, at that time
— he would wake up, and he
wouldn't see me or he'll look
for me. So, I couldn't really
code. Cuz then, he wants to --
you know, I can't keep him up
at 5 AM. He still needs to
sleep. So-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: -and I'll go back in
bed and try to put him, you
know, back to sleep. And then,
when I try to,
I think I -- I thought I ninja
my way out, but oh, no. He wakes
up like five minutes later
[laughs]. I was like, "Okay,
that didn't work." And then,
I'll try to stay up late to
learn how to code. And sometimes
that doesn't work. Because he
wants mommy to be in bed with
him to, you know, go to sleep.
I'll try to ask my husband, and
he'll try to help out. But it's
always like, "No, but I want
mommy." And I'm like, "Mommy's
busy." [Yolanda and Dan chuckle]
So I will try that. And then,
I'll do like, 11, 12 o'clock ...
at night, 1 o'clock, trying to
code. But then, I'm already
tired.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: So, was it effective? I
don't know. It's -- it felt like
-- it reminded me of college,
where you look at the textbook
and you're reading that same
paragraph. And you're like, "Oh,
crap. I think I just read that
paragraph. Okay. I'm gonna
focus. Let me read it again
[laughs]." But nothing stick.
And you're like, "Oh. Hmm. What
did I just read?" So, it felt
like that for- for many months.
Just trying to find ways to-
to do everything. And then I had
a talk with my husband and
saying, "Hey, is it okay if I
cut back on work and focus on
school, or, you know, Leon's
class? Because the end goal is
to make that career change."
And, you know, luckily, his job
wasn't affected by the- the
COVID. So, he's still -- he was
still working. So he said,
"Yeah, yeah, we can do that."
So ... and then, you know,
I'll -- and also fortunately
we are able to put my kid in
daycares. So, you know, just
part-time. So we did that. And
that -- all those pieces kind of
fell together and it helped me
out, personally. So I was very
fortunate and, you know,
supportive husband didn't lose
his job, had daycare, so this
kind of stars semi-aligned. And
I was able to kind of learn
through that. But it wasn't
easy. A lot of nights that I
cried. A lot of nights that I- I
mean ... argued. A lot of
nights that I -- not even
nights. Just days, I just wanna
scream into the void, like,
"Why?" And, you know, tho-
thought process of like, "If I
didn't have a kid, I probably
would've gotten this earlier,
better, faster," you know? And
... then, kind of look at him,
and he smiles, and gives me a
hug, I'm like, "Damn it. Why did
I think of that?" You know [Bekah
laughs], "They're terrible
thoughts!" And it's like, "Okay,
it's worth it." He's -- he
doesn't know any better. So,
it's --
Bekah: Hashtag mom life.
Yolanda: Yes. He's -- it's a lot
of- of back and forth. Like, I
wish- I wish I didn't change my
mind by- back in college, but
then, I wouldn't have taught
abroad. Then I wouldn't have had
built those friendship and
relationships. And it's just ...
I don't know. But being a mom is
hard. And ... that's just ...
that was my rant. Sorry
[laughs].
Bekah: No.
Dan: No. Yeah, it's- it's hard.
It's hard to- to ... I mean,
it's definitely hard to learn,
you know? It's hard to really do
any development work when, you
know, when you're tired or for
me, I guess, personally. But,
like, I feel like this is pretty
common. But, you know, when your
brain -- it's -- when you're
tired, your brain doesn't work
quite at its, like, its normal
level. And ... parenting is
being tired a lot. [Chuckles]
And, you know, it's just like,
it's hard. It's- it's hard. So,
I -- we are appreciate you
sharing with us. Cuz it's ...
I've- I've had a lot of similar
experiences. It's a lot of late
nights, and a lot of yelling,
and stuff not going through your
brain that you think should be
going through. Like ... I -- you
know, I should be able to figure
this out kind of thing, right?
[Laughs] And then, I'm like,
"Oh, wait. I was up for -- I was
only asleep for like two hours
last night [chuckles]. And then
-- maybe that's why," you know?
So, yes.
Bekah: And I think, you know,
it's hard. I've talked to a lot
of moms who have felt those
frustrations and you- you see
stories on Twitter or wherever,
where people are flying through
things. And then, you play the
comparison game, like, "Well,
how come they're there, and I'm
not there?" And you know, I- I
can't tell you how many times
I've talked to another mom who
was struggling in that journey.
Like, "Well, I'm staying up
late, and I'm waking up early,
and I'm putting in all this
time, and it's still not
sticking." I'm like,
"How many hours of sleep are
you getting a night? Four? Well,
it's- it's not going to stick."
And you know, you said something
earlier about, like, "I- I wish
I would have like savored the
journey more," or something like
that. And I- I think that there
is this tendency to wanna rush
through it, or, you know, "These
bootcampers get it done in 12
weeks or whatever. I should be
able to get it done in 12
weeks." But you know, that's-
that's not ideal [chuckles]. And
it- it doesn't acknowledge the
challenges that- that we face in
our lives ... to be able to do
that. Like, Dan, you're saying
like, your brain just cannot ...
be a sponge when you're not
getting enough sleep at night.
It's- it's not -- it- it's a
physiological thing [laughs].
You ca- you can't break that.
You can't change that part of-
of it. And so, you know, putting
a focus on, like, take the
time to, like, pace yourself and
learn what you're doing, and
savor those moments of the
journey. I -- you -- I'll -- I
say this, like, in retrospect.
But I know, had somebody said
the same thing to me while I was
going through it, I'd be like,
"Uh-huh, sure. Whatever." Like
[laughs], "Well, I just need to
be done with this and get on
with the real life where things
are easier," is- is not easier.
Like, well, [laughs] I thought
bootcamp was hard. Wait a
minute. Like, this is- this is
harder suddenly. And I'm
terrified. So ... there are
so many other factors. And --
alrite. Somebody had once said,
you know, bootcamps should have
... I dunno. Like a- a warning
or something to say that this is
gonna put intense pressure on
your relationship. And a lot of
people break up during this time
[chuckles]. Because
there is so much stress and
pressure. And nobody talks about
that. Cuz it like, "Oh, did you
finish? Did your project get
done? Did you get hired?" Not
like [chuckles], "How were you
impacted in your life outside of
work and learning?" And so, I
think it's, you know, I very
much appreciate you sharing all
of that. Because I think that --
I wish that more people talked
about it. So, people who are
coming into tech, like, know
there's a lot of pressure in
these things.
Yolanda: So much pressure. I --
pressure on ourselves, I think,
you know? And I-
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: -keep comparing myself
to others — that comparison
game that you said, you know?
It's a terrible game to play.
Terrible, terrible, you know?
Bekah: I was comparing my ca-
self to Kent C. Dodds. I'm like,
this is [Bekah and Yolanda
laugh] ... I don't know why.
That's not really realistic, but
I'm like, "Why am I not like
that?" Like --
Yolanda: Yeah, it's just -- cuz
you see it, you know? Like, all
-- you know, they- they did it.
They get it. Why can't I? You
know? Or I'll ... forget that
I'm- I'm a- I'm a mom, you know?
And-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Yolanda: -I have these
obligations, because I was
thinking, "Ah, in college, I
didn't struggle this much, did
I?"
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: Like, "I got it." Like,
"What- what's different from
college and now?" I mean, I was
-- like, college was like 15
years ago. I had to calculate it
[Bekah chuckles]. It's just
like [Dan chuckles] -- you
know, and back then, it was
just me. I was just -- like,
there's no other- there's no
other ... little ones or, you
know, people that I have to kind
of focus on to take care of. So,
yeah. So, I -- somebody told me
like, "Compare to yourself." And
I was like, "Oh, that's not
fun." Like, compare ... you
know, like, it's just -- I- I
should -- and it -- I get what
they're saying. Cuz you --
I'm looking back a year ago.
Where was I? You know? What is
today? March? And I think, I was
still learning JavaScript. And
s- probably feeling frustrated
the year ago saying-
Bekah: Yeah.
Yolanda: -"I don't get it. What-
what do you mean I have to do
this? Like, it doesn't make
sense." And right now, it still
doesn't make sense. But it's a
little ... a little -- I get a
better idea. So ... yeah.
Somebody -- I- I try to do that.
And he's like, "Okay, where was
I before?" You know? "Where was
I yesterday? Did I have a least
1% of improvement today, kinda
thing?" So, I think that was,
like, through also "Atomic
Habits", you know? Just that
microscopic improvement and- and
focus on that. So, I think that
helps me out as well. Just the
tiniest of the tiny victory.
So, if I could just put in, you
know, five minutes of whatever
learning, "Yay, I did it!
That's my victory. One step,
tiny step forward [chuckles],"
instead of saying, "Oh, I only
spent five minutes," you know?
It's like, try to change that
mindset. Which is so hard. But
the pressure is hard. The
comparison game is hard
[chuckles]. Everything is hard.
So hard.
Bekah: Is it -- is -- you -- I
feel like -- I was like, "Oh,
there should be Calendly links
to, like, meet with your mentor,
slash meet with your therapist."
Like, [chuckles] they should be
right next to each other. Cuz I
think it would be useful
[chuckles]. Well, I wanna thank
you, Yolanda, for being here and
sharing your journey with us.
Cuz I think this is super
valuable and a lot of people are
gonna learn from this episode.
Are there any -- do you wanna
share any of your biggest
lessons or tips for those out
there listening, before we head
off for the day?
Yolanda: Ah, biggest question.
Um ... take your time. It takes
time. Sorry. I should say, it
takes time. Everything takes
time. Try to have that ingrained
in your head. It's just ...
everything takes time.
Networking takes time. Learning
how to code takes time. Finding
a job takes time [chuckles].
Then, you know, the- the main
foundation is -- it- it just, it
takes time. So, I wish I had
that ingrained in me, instead
of hurry, hurry, hurry, fear of
missing out. It's just stop,
breathe, and like, "Okay, it's
gonna- it's gonna take time. And
that is okay. That is definitely
okay. I'm not gonna miss out
on jobs. I'm not gonna miss out
on opportunities. Because I'm
just gonna focus on what I can
do at this moment in time. And
if that's all I can do, that's
all I can do." So, just- just
take it easy [chuckles].
Dan: I love that. Yeah, I love
that advice a lot [chuckles]. I
think that- I think that's a
great note to end on. And I
wanna say, thank you to Yolanda,
too. I- I really appreciate
hearing about ... well,
everything, really. It was- it
was- it was good. I think what
Bekah said is right. A lot of
people are gonna find this
really valuable. So, thank you
again for coming on.
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for the newsletter, check out
any of our other resources on
our website, virtualcoffee.io.
If you're interested in
sponsoring Virtual Coffee, you
can find out more information on
our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast,
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening,
and we'll see you next week!