Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season five, episode five of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost Dan.
Dan: Hey Bekah. Today we're
talking with Roger Gentry. Roger
has spent a lot of his career
managing security and compliance
for clients across the United
States. And this episode you'll
hear from Roger about
perseverance, his drive to solve
problems and his process for
finding solutions. He shares some
tips for working through
frustrations and how to ask for
help.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We hope
you enjoy this episode. Today's
random check-in question is if
you could be an article of
clothing, what would it be? My
name is Bekah. I am a technical
community builder from a small
town in Ohio. And if I could be
any article clothing, it'd
probably be a sweatshirt like a
hoodie. Um, because I have a
collection of them since the
pandemic started, I just keep
buying them. I can't stop.
They're very comfortable and I
like them. So I'll go with
hoodie.
Dan: Yeah, hoodies are good, um,
hi, I'm Dan. I am a web developer
from Cleveland, Ohio, and yeah,
if I could be an article of
clothing. I mean, hoodie was like
up there. I think, um, I think
I'm going to go with like a rain
shell. So like a rank. Yeah.
Raincoat. So I say shell, cause
it's like, that's, that's what
you call it when it's camping.
Right. So shell is something that
can go. Yeah. Yeah. People who,
people who know, who know, and,
and if you don't know them,
that's fine too. But, uh, it's
like it's called a shell because
you can put it on top of, you
know, if you have a hoodie or
whatever, you can still wear it.
You know, your rain color, it
keeps you protected, but you can
wear it in summer and stuff too.
But raincoat.
Bekah: It goes over your rain
coat.
Dan: No, no, no, it's a raincoat,
but like not like a fancy
raincoat that looks nice. It's
like a raincoat that is, you
know, a utility, you call it a
shell because you can put it
over, you know, you can like
bring the same raincoat camping
in the summer and the winter and
whatever, you know. So in the
winter, I just put it over top of
all my layers and summer put over
top of the t-shirt or whatever.
That's why he called it shell.
Bekah: I would like it to look
like a turtle show. shell.
Dan: Okay, well, you can have the
turtle shell rain, Rachel, and
that'd be fine too.
Roger: Hi everyone. My name's
Roger, and I'm a full stack
developer and sunny Southern
California. And if I was an
article of clothing, I'd have to
be a zip-up hoodie, specifically,
a zip-up hoodie, because
everything else just sort of a,
you get caught in the, in the web
of the sweater, the zip up, you
can just go quickly from hot to
cold. And, you know, I love that.
Bekah: Yeah, I, like the zip-up
hoodie too. It just depends on my
mood, but also like sometimes
it's hot and sometimes it's cold
and it's much easier to remove
one that has a zipper
Dan: yeah. I mean, zip-up buddies
are clearly better than pull over
something.
Bekah: Not all the time. I mean,
zippers are cold too. So if it's
cold outside and they touch your
skin, then it's cold Roger.
Thanks for being here. Very glad
to have you on the podcast. And
when we start the podcast,
everyone, we like to get people's
origin stories. So how, what
brought you to where you are
today in life?
Roger: You know, it's kind of
funny. I kind of remember the
first time that I saw somebody
building a website and it was
some friends of mine in the
school library and, uh, they.
Just we're having fun. And I
wanted to do that as well. So I
kind of acquired a free computer
and, uh, just set that up in my
room. Like, you know, this is, I
can't even remember the year
early, two thousands. So, you
know, it wasn't that, uh, I
advanced to have a laptop quite
yet for me. And once I kind of
figured out how I could build a
website with HTML and CSS and
notepad on the windows, I kind of
was hooked. And it just sort of
became a, almost like a hobby
that just kept me going all the
time. And. I took that skill set
and immediately did the thing
that I've done kind of forever
now is turned it into a way to
make money, which I did by going
to just the businesses that were
in my town and finding the one
that just had a terrible website
and convincing them that they
needed a new one and I could be
the person to build it. Um, kind
of. As I went along in school and
eventually high school, I had an
opportunity to take kind of a, a
multimedia course, which taught
me a lot of like Photoshop
illustrator, just a lot of, uh,
photo editing and video editing
skills that I kind of combined
into this, you know, love of code
with the web design side of
things. And, you know, that kind
of propelled me forward and I've
always had a knack for fixing
things. I kind of landed in this
weird place of, uh, fixing a lot
more things than I was building,
but then using the skillset of
being, you know, a developer at
heart to build a solutions, to
solve problems in ways. People
weren't thinking about, and that
excited me more and more, and,
you know, I'm kind of a, a person
in necessity. If I, if I see
something that I really need,
I'll figure out a way to get it.
And I wanted to build a SAS
product for fun. I, and the kind
of. Managed to make that possible
with a company I was working at
and we, we had a lot of fun
putting it together, but then I
kind of found, I had a lot more
fun building kind of the
prototype and understanding the
code and coming up with the
methodologies and how we were
going to do things and looking
at. Back. I kind of have always
been a, like a web developer, but
it was at that point where I was
putting together this weird
little cloud service that I
really saw a need to become on
everything developer because you
know, there was so much more.
That was missing from what I
wanted to put together. And that
led me to, just to kind of absorb
into building iOS and Android
applications and then a web
backend and, you know, combining
everything together and finding
the glue that works the best,
which surprisingly there's no
really good fit all solution.
Despite any of the marketing that
you'll see on anybody's products.
And. Getting everything together.
And finally seeing like an API
that I wrote and connect to the
apps that I helped build with the
website that I put together for a
customer that I sold an idea to.
Like that was the moment that I
really kind of found like. The
group that I liked to exist in,
and it's always propelled me to
have ideas and projects that I
like working on, but, going back,
I still think of the dorky kid
that was sitting in his room,
reading the HTML and CSS for
dummies book that he bought at
the thrift store for 50 cents.
And, you know, that's propelled
me into a lifelong period of not
only learning, but also figuring
things out and solving problems
in just a different way, because
you know, Come from a place where
I've been building out a
necessity. And if you tell me
that there's a problem, I'll
figure out a way to fix it. The
way to fix it might not be the
best way, it's working.
Dan: I love that. I love that.
You're. And, and like, I, I
think, uh, maybe not where you
ended up in your career path, but
the beginnings of your career
started off very similar to mine.
Right? Uh, I think I had that
exact same for dummies book that
I bought at their store as well.
Um, and, yeah, I mean like the,
the cool thing for me is, is that
like how, how you. Sort of
organically followed. Right? What
you, what you found interesting,
what you saw, you know, neat.
Like you saw there was a need for
different pieces to different
puzzles, right. And, um, the idea
that you don't have to stay in
one lane or, or, or one specialty
or anything like that. Right. I
mean, full stack developers is a
pretty common phrase these days,
I think, but, um, I think. I
think that my favorite part about
that, the full sec ideas is the
idea that like you have the
power, any person has the power
to kind of go and chase down, you
know, something that they want
to, that they find interesting
and want to, and want to build
it, want to fix or solve.
Roger: Something that would
happen when I was working as a
technician is, you know, I'd come
in and I'd fix a problem. That
for the user was really, really
difficult. And I made it seem
impossibly easy, and a lot of
them would say, wow, you're a
wizard. You fix it like magic.
Right. When you sit in front of,
you know, a terminal for the
first time, so to speak and you
run that code and it does the
thing that you told it to, like,
it feels like magic. It feels
like you cast a spell and
something cool happened. And, I
feel like that that magic is
captivating for, for a lot of
people. And like, once you, once
you see it, once you realize that
you can cast that spell and make
that magic happen, like it's
almost an addiction. Like you're
like, well, what other things can
I do? It's like, oh Yeah, this
doorbell is no longer supported.
Let's see if we can, you know,
hack it and make it something,
something useful. Again, like
it's just, you find solutions to
problems that, you know, you
didn't even know were problems
because now, you know, the magic
behind how it all works.
Bekah: Yeah, I love how you talk
so much about the magic and the
problem solving. And I think
that's one of the things that
interest, so many people about
being in tech and it's
simultaneously one of the most
frustrating things about being in
tech, right? Like can get hard
and you're stuck on those
problems in Um, sometimes it can
be. Feelings of self doubt, like,
oh, what kind of program or am I,
I can't figure this out. So how
do you approach problem solving
and, and maybe avoid those
feelings? Or do you have tips on
how to avoid those feelings?
Roger: You know, so much of what
I've been able to figure out has
been a, let me just change this
line of code refresh and see if
it fixes the problem. And. You
know, I come from a background of
fixing a lot of weird problems
that I never had a say in
creating. And so a lot of the
times it was like, okay, this was
doing a thing correctly before,
and this is how we got to there.
Now, when I try to do these
steps, this is what happens.
Well, now I know how to replicate
the problem. And I got to just
work backwards from there and try
to figure out why it's failing in
that step. And okay, well now we
know it's this problem. Let's
search around and see if we can
figure out if there's a solution
for this somewhere that we can
use or. If we just keep having to
dig further down. So it's kind of
more of a beat it with a hammer
until it shows you like something
that's useful. And then you take
that little spec and it's like,
okay, let's analyze this and go
down a rabbit hole and solve that
problem and then move on to the
next error. And eventually you'll
find kind of the answer. And then
once you have like that
experiences to that one problem.
You know, that that networking
piece of equipment in the closet
was actually the faulty, you
know, problem, the whole thing.
And it was a bad ethernet cable
that somebody. Broken the door
that caused everybody's issues
for the day. And now in the
future, when you're sitting in
there looking at that similar
problem, you know, your mind is
thinking about these things as
well, whereas before it may have
taken you hours to get there.
Well, now I know I can overcome
that because I had to do it in a
time of crisis. And I can, if I
can overcome that this little
error that I'm dealing with, I'll
figure out eventually. And it's
the same thing with programming.
Like I was dealing with like
just, uh, Data formats that I
wasn't familiar with. And I
wanted to just sort of see if I
could figure it out. It took a
little while, but eventually, you
know, I put enough pieces to the
puzzle together and I got the
answer I needed. And like, it, it
was one of those moments where
it's like, I overcame something
that was only existed because the
way that I formatted the first
time wasn't necessarily the
correct way to parse that data.
But then once I figured out the
right way, It worked. And then
I'm sitting there being like,
huh. Now how it works instantly.
I was trying to find the next
problem to solve.
Dan: Yeah, that, um, dopamine
rush from. Actually solving the
thing. Right. And it's like
greater. I feel like for me, at
least most of the time, anyway,
it's, it's greater. The harder it
is, the deeper down the rabbit
hole you go, right. There's
sometimes where I get all the way
down and I figured it's taken me
so long. That I'm just like, I
just hate this. Like finally, his
bug is squashed, you know, but I
think lots of times I get that, I
get that same, um, that same like
spike of, uh, just feels good and
like, okay, let's find out what's
next, you know?
Roger: I've had times where I
spent a lot of the night in a
networking closet, trying to
solve some weird networking
problem and trying to get
something that was on the network
that was working before I got
there. Wasn't working now to back
to that working state and it's
hot and it's terrible and I'm
hungry. And so anytime that I'm
sitting in front of my computer,
working on a hard coding problem,
I think. I think back to myself
and the networking closet and
remember I'm not there and I
can't eat something and I step
away and is fine because I will
figure it out. And it's kind of
like the sense of encouragement
that I tell myself when I'm
dealing with the hard problem.
Just knowing that eventually it
will be solved one way or
another. And there's only so much
I can worry about with it right
now. And eventually you just have
to say enough's enough, walk away
and come back to it later. And
then you're like, oh yeah, you
know? what? I don't know why this
is so hard earlier. I was just
grumpy.
Dan: I think that's great advice.
And I like, I want to reiterate
that cause that's the, one of the
hardest things to remember, and
it's so easy to get stuck in that
like, It's it's so easy. It's
it's like when you're down in
some hole, you know, trying to
figure something out and nothing
makes sense. It's hard to step
away. It's at least for me, it's
hard. I hard time stepping away
and, you're right. Roger. Like
every time that I do, it's
helpful. Like it's always helpful
and I'm always like, why didn't I
just do this hour ago? Like, why
didn't I stick go walk around the
building or go get it, you know,
across the street, get a cup of
coffee or something like that.
Every time, not every time, but
it happens to me so often, you
know, and it's like, I don't
know, almost physically hard to
get myself to step away. I'm
like, I know I can get this if I
just,
Bekah: I always get annoyed when
people are like, just step up,
you just need to go for a walk.
I'm like, you just don't need to
tell me what to do. Right. And
then like an hour and a half
later, I do it. I'm like, oh,
okay. Fine. Like, yes, now I get
it.
Roger: I think part of that is,
uh, you know, that there's like
that dopamine rush when you're
going to solve the problem. And
so you're like, I, if I just do
this a little bit longer, it will
be solved and I'm going to feel
good about it. so you're, you're
you're so in the middle of like
that frustrating piece where you
just like, you know, the payoff
is going to be so much better
than more frustrated at the
problem that you're going to you
are want to finish it. And
stepping away is almost like a
sign of defeat into yourself. No
one else cares. But you, but even
so like that, that step away is
what you need and yet doing it.
is so frustratingly difficult.
Bekah: Yeah, was working on this
problem last week and I knew that
I was close. Right. Like I could
feel it there, something wrong
and I, I just needed to spend
more time going over. Line by
line, which I had already done. I
had already done with other
people too. And then finally, I,
uh, well then I go into this mode
of all right. I know that one of
these things is wrong. And then I
just start like throwing code.
Chaotically does not what you
should do because in there I had
the right piece, but then I
messed up the other piece that
connected it. so then it still
didn't work. And then I was, uh,
debugging it with a coworker. Um,
said, oh yeah, it's this thing.
This is what I expected. It was,
you know, you, you forgot to. I
was like, I did have that. I had
it at one point I just deleted.
Okay. And so instead I had this
mess of a, a code base that
that's not what you want. So like
taking, I think that taking that.
Advice of walking away thinking
through the problem, rather than
just like throwing all of the
things at it is a skill I need to
learn. Maybe.
Roger: The other approach that I
like to the mingled code base is
the burn it all to the ground.
Take what we know is good. And
let's just start over for a
little bit. Cause we learned a
lot and throwing all of this
spaghetti against the wall, but
yet nothing really stucks, but
we've learned some stuff in the
process. going to take what the
good bits that we know go back to
where we know the data is good
and try to do what fit, what we
want. Right. Probably starting
over with a fresh slate is going
to give us the answers we need,
because we were not good. When we
were writing that other kids, we
were frustrated.
Dan: Yeah, and I think that's
great advice and it helps sort of
isolate, you know, you can still
add things a bit at a time, you
know? So starting from that
fresh, the fresh, like the fresh
slate, you know, add things step
by step, you know, and, and you,
you very like, you know how you
want it to work. So maybe the
route will be a little bit more
straight forward this way. Right?
Cause you have like a plan in
your head. But it'll help you
sort of isolate the problem too.
And that's good advice. The
spaghetti on the wall method,
right?
Bekah: My favorite method. Um, so
one of the things that we talk a
lot about advertorial coffee is
questions, and I think that this
kind of goes along with. The
conversation about, you know, how
do you ask questions? How do you
ask for help? Like, what is the
right approach to doing that? And
it can be in your code base. It
could be when you're interviewing
for a job, but what do you think
is a good approach to asking
questions or asking for support
or help finding it?
Roger: Uh, so it kind of, kind of
depends on the problem, right? If
you're talking about, you know,
you're sitting on an interview
and you want to know if they do
X, Y, or Z, right. You just ask
and like, it seems scary at
first, but every company that
I've been in the first interview
with, and I've been like, so what
kind of like hardware stack are
we dealing with? They are always
like, wait, why do you care? Like
you're interviewing for this
role. And it's like, well, no, I
genuinely want to make sure it's
something that I'm gonna be
interested in dealing with
before. Like I get excited and we
waste everybody's time and then I
get to the job and it's not
exciting. Like. Each time that
I've asked like weird difficult
questions or just something that
I was just curious about, it's
always needed a good result in
the interview. Like, uh, I
remember in one where I asked
the, uh, founder of the company
where he sees himself in the in
five years, and that was a, that
was a fun question to see the
last on all of the other managers
where they're just like, But the
answer that he gave me was more
about the vision of the company
and where they wanted to take it,
which was really exciting. And so
you. Take that same approach when
you're dealing with code, right?
If you have a problem, you look
at your message. And I just start
by taking your message copying
and pasting to the search engine
and then say, stack overflow,
give me the great answers to my
problem and combining that with
whatever language you're writing
it in and what you're trying to
do, typically nets somebody else
on the internet who has the same
problem. And there's probably an
XKCD that's relevant to that
exact topic because I've linked
to it many times and it's just,
it's kind of that, like, you
know, it? doesn't matter what the
problem you're dealing with.
There, there's an answer out
there somewhere. Somebody knows
that answer to the problem you're
dealing with it's just, how do we
get there? And sometimes the
answer is you need to call the
vendor or email the person that
wrote it and. It seems terrifying
the first dozen times that you
email somebody that wrote some
piece of code, it's something
that I've learned about and
people that work in technology is
an opportunity to talk about
something nerdy. We're going to
waste as much time as we possibly
can, because it's so rare that we
get somebody who's like excited
about the same thing that we're
doing. And then it's a slight.
Okay. Yeah. that took so much
effort to write that email. But
now, like I know this guy and
we're going to totally meet for
drinks when he's at this
conference, because like that's
the connection we made. And it's
just about asking the questions
and just finding right person
and. Everybody's got an email
address on their code, or you can
message them and Twitter, which
is still a weird experience just
to be to message random company
being like, Hey, I have this
would you be interested? And next
thing you on a meeting to, you
know, meet the person that posted
that tweet. That's kind of the
whole power that we have today
where we didn't have. like when I
got technology, there was no
Facebook, there was no MySpace.
It seems like a weird time
because I'm not that old, but
the, in the age of you know, you,
it moves at such a rapid pace
that you are, get dated very
quickly if you're not paying
attention. And at that time
period, like finding information
was a lot harder, but now it's
just. And
Bekah: Yeah.
Roger: it depends on how you are
how bad you want that thing. Or
in that answer, if you really,
really want the answer to the
question, you'll find it. It just
might take some time.
Bekah: Sorry. I was, I was
thinking I was deep in thought.
Dan: I was just reminiscing back
when there was no stack overflow.
Bekah: My kids like to refer to
that as the olden days, we
watched the S the amazing
Spider-Man the one with Andrew
Garfield this weekend, and
they're like, oh, we didn't know
that you had movies with this
good CGI back in the olden days.
It's not even that old!
Dan: Kids.
Bekah: Yeah, well, okay. And so I
think that making those
connections is so important and
then like asking, asking informed
questions too, right. Because
when you're DM-ing someone or
emailing someone, you let them
know what you've been working on
or how you've been approaching
that thing. Or, you know, one of
the things that I like about, um,
our Virtual Coffee repository is
we have issue templates. We have
PR templates. Or is that what
they're called? Templates forms,
issue forms,
Dan: Well,
Bekah: templates. How am I saying
it wrong? I wasn't asking
Dan: I don't think that's, I
don't think, I don't think that's
a wrong
Bekah: if there are called
templates.
Dan: Wrong situation, but. I
think that's more of a local
dialect situation.
Bekah: It's not what I was
asking.
Dan: Uh,
Bekah: issue.
Dan: issue forms. That's what
they're called. They started as
templates and other forms. That's
it? Yeah.
Bekah: one of them is a form,
Right,
Dan: right. right. No, that's
what I mean. That the issue ones.
Yeah, they used to be, we used to
have issue templates and now we
converted them to issue forms.
Roger: And now he just has an
issues everywhere.
Dan: Now there's just issues.
Lots of issues.
Bekah: Um, but it breaks, it kind
of like breaks down how to ask
questions. And because we work
with so many developers at all
stages of the journey, nice to
kind of create a methodical
process for question asking, um,
or helping people to go through
this process of, is what I see.
This is what I've done. This is
what I want to see done, you
know, and providing some evidence
for that, because sometimes you
have a random question it feels
exhausting or overwhelming to try
and answer a question. If there's
no context there, right. If you
already have a full slate of work
on your desk and somebody asks
you, Hey, have you, I don't, I
don't know. I can't think of a
good example right now, but like,
Did I use this thing, right.
Okay. Well walk me through your
coat. Right? And I think that
that's one of those things that
kind of, it's a skill that takes
time to develop that question,
asking ability. And another
reason why I love the coworking
room too, because you have the
time to have those conversations.
And Roger, I know that you've
spent some time in the coworking
room as well.
Roger: Yeah. I, always love just
kind of hanging out in there
cause you never know what kind of
conversations are going to have.
And it definitely feels like.
You're at work and these are your
coworkers because, you know,
there's, there's a sense of, of
community to it. But at the same
time, you know, like the
conversations, aren't going to
take a weird turn. They're going
to typically stay around a
centralized set of topics. And
it's comforting to be able to be
just around other people who are
programmers and nerds, and just
generally interested in pretty
much the same thing as you are.
And just being like, Hey, I'm
working on this like weird code.
Is there anybody that wants to
jump in and like, give me some
advice on what I'm doing wrong or
how I can make it better. And,
you know, it's kind of exciting
just to see the problem solving
that other people go through. And
sometimes just the patients that
some people have mentoring
people, it's really amazing and
kind of, you know, uh, lead by
example in some places where you
see these things happen and
you're just like, wow, I want to,
I want to improve how I instruct
people based off of like what I
just kind of saw. And it's just.
Kind of a cool place just to meet
people from kind of all around
the world who just are hanging
out, just wanting to just chill
for a few minutes and just talk
about whatever, whatever you're
talking about, jumping into the
conversation and jump out. It's
really like, uh, been a great
sense of community since, uh, you
know, honestly I found Virtual
Coffee when the pandemic kind of
was going on and like I dived
into there and I became kind of.
A lot of the close friendships
that I had, because it was just
always open and you meet a lot of
really cool, interesting people.
And actually my current, my
current job, um, I was actually
interviewed, uh, originally in
the coworking room, which led me
to being interviewed by the
company, accepting the role with
there. So I always think that's
a, that's a fun little story
with, uh, Virtual Coffee,
because, you know, there's so
many of these people that joined
looking for a job and. Or hoping
to find something, but sometimes
you end up finding something in
the same room, but you're just
hanging out. And then for fun
sharing, just some project that
you had an idea about or
passionate about. So.
Bekah: I love that. That's such a
fun story. Um, okay. So.
navigating through like enjoying
that that aspect of coding. So
what is the, um, maybe strangest
or most complicated that you've
had navigate?
Roger: So I think this goes back
to the days winning. I was
working in a support role at a
managed service provider, which
means we ran their whole help
desk. And this is one of my
favorite stories to tell because
it's just so weird. So the
customer I was supporting is a
company that does. That paints
boats. When I'm talking about
boats, I'm talking about big
ships that are, you know, the
ships that they have at
Disneyland type size. And they
have an oven that is the size of
a literal warehouse, where they
put these boats. To have the
paint cure and all of this data
from all of these temperature
sensors from all around that
warehouse get fed into one
computer. And what happened is
that aging desktop, which was
running probably windows 98 or
something similar, and some
version of. Xcel it died and
suddenly their whole business
wasn't able to operate because
the computer that ran the sensors
that gave them the data to
certify all of their work wasn't
working. And I remember trying
everything that I could to build
a virtual machine that had that
operating system to fund this
thing and just constant problems.
And eventually I solved that
problem by getting it stood up
with a new version of windows and
everything working inside it.
And, and a version of Excel that
I found on an abandoned ware
website that was like a release
candidate that they didn't put
any product activations in. And
it was the least to the clear
version of Excel that I could
find to. macro that business
relied on to capture this data
from the sensor. It was, it was a
lot. We had adapters to serial
cables pulling in this data into
a macro unexcited Excel.
eventually this all got ran, ran
into a windows 10 bucks
eventually and virtualized and
indefinitely, but it was just
the, the amount of sheer is going
on and how are we going to fix?
Like to get over the finish line
was just astronomical. And like,
I look back and I think to
myself, like, you know, could fix
a boat up and none of these other
problems seem that hard, little
figure it out. Like it's the same
thing about being in a network
closet. Like. You just like all
of these problems have solutions
you're going to get there.
Eventually. It's just a matter of
what ridiculous thing you're
going to need to get it across
the finish line in the moment.
And I, I feel like when
programming, it's a lot of. More,
a lot more critical thinking and
sometimes you just need more
information and just like,
dealing with the problem with
databases, you can't really
figure out what the heck you're
doing. Stop. And like go look at
some databases. And then you're
like, oh, that's what I was doing
at Gronk. And suddenly things
click into place. And you know, I
just remember so many times as a
technician where there wasn't
documentation or somebody to ask
it was figure it out too. The
that you can because they're a
vendor that built this, uh,
system went out of business
before you were born. And that's,
and that's a fun, that's a fun
exist. But the thing that I've
learned the most about
programming and programming
languages specifically once you
learn the basics, they all start
to kind of merge together. And if
you know, how an if loop and a
while loop works well, you can
pretty much program like 90% of
the crap you need to get the job
done. And that's really what it
takes. Like a few, a few if
statements and you've got most of
the programs that are running,
some of the largest systems are
just simple things. And when you
can look at a coding written in
something that some random
developer came up with and you're
just able to read through it and
understand it because not because
you understand the language. But
because you understand that a
loop's going to keep going back
through these things and
eventually it's going to do this.
So now I'm looking for this
problem. can pretty much go down
any rabbit hole and find what
you're looking for. Just as long
as you're just willing to keep
It's same thing with the boat of
it. I just kept looking and I
found eventually found a way to
fix it.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. And I,
and I think that, and I feel like
I've said this probably before,
but that's like one of the
biggest things that separates
somebody that has more experience
from somebody who is more
starting out is not necessarily
the knowledge accrued, but more
the sort of confidence. You can
do the thing you like that, like
you can probably solve pretty
much anything given enough time,
I suppose. But you know, like,
like you said, like that, if you,
if you have less experience, you
just have less black practice,
uh, reading code and being used
to loops and if statements and
stuff, um, Jumping trying to read
some other code in a different
language that you're not used to
is going to seem probably a lot
more daunting, you know, but
having done it for a long time,
it's is a sector. That's a
practice, you know, the practice
of just like, I mean, it's just,
like you said, you know, like I
have solved this huge bug in the
past, so I just kind of know that
any other bug that comes up, I'm
going to be fine. Right.
Roger: Or on the, on the other
side of it is like, I know I've
taken down production once. So if
I do it again, I know what to
expect. It's sort of like, I've
been chewed out. Let's just get
chewed out again.
Bekah: You don't feel like
terrifying experience to me?
Dan: Have you done it live on a
Twitch stream though.
Roger: There's still time.
There's still time.
Bekah: No. you.
Dan: Uh, yeah, that was not my
best moment, but eh, I got
through it right.
Bekah: You, you did you? I think
I would just, I want to crawl
under the bed and stay there.
Roger: I think this is a good
point to mention how important
backups and version control are.
And don't be afraid to commit
that code, even if you're not
quite ready for it. Just having
something in there that you can
go back and look at and be like,
that's what I did four and a half
hours ago.
Dan: Yes.
Roger: It's so helpful.
Bekah: Even like that project
that I was just talking about, I
was talking through it with Kirk
one day. Um, was like, well, you
know, have you committed
recently? don't have any
commitments, but just like, you
know, I, wasn't going to be a big
project. I thought that I could
it really quickly and get it
done. And then it was like, oh,
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: a mistake. Yeah. That
would have been that for sure
would have been useful.
Dan: Yeah, no, that's very good
advice. See, it's like at the
times that I've done it, it's
been, it's been super helpful and
it helps with that. Um, and it
gives you more confidence with
that. Um, the approach of just
kind of trying stuff out, right.
Throwing stuff at the problem,
because, you know, That. I mean,
it's easy. It's easy to go back.
Right? It's easy to throw things
out. It's easy to go and look at
your history. Um, and you can
always by that the commits or the
like, It's kind of quashed them
right into, like once you finally
solve it into one commit, you
know? Uh, I, I mean, I'll have
commits that are just like, well,
let's try this, try this, try
this, that didn't work, try this,
try this, you know? And that's
like, that's not what you want to
push up. Uh, ultimately, it's
perfectly fine when you're in
your, when you're like, you know,
trying to work your way through,
through a problem. Uh, at least
at least I think it's, I don't
know. Other people might disagree
with me, but.
Roger: I am definitely afraid to
commit until like the code is
perfect, just because I feel like
so many people are going to be
judging me, based off of what
they're saying. Um, but. at the
same time, that causes me to
forget, to commit my changes. And
I have a habit of doing that
frequently. The best part about
being a developer is you can
always automate solutions to your
problems. Uh, of mine has been,
uh, every 15 minutes. Take a get
commit, and just go ahead and
just save that with the
timestamp. I've written that as a
bash script, because that was the
easiest, lowest hanging fruit
that I could Do And it works
marvelously. And I've used that
for a number of other projects
where I wrote a whole, a whole
set of scripts that took and used
them as a note, taking
application with an auto-save and
sync functionality by getting
bashed. That just was a few
hours. together because I was
annoyed that I forgot to save
something important into the
thing that I was using as a
notepad. So I'm like, I'm never
going to do this again. And it,
you solve a problem and you just
use the tools that were available
and
Bekah: Do you have a blog post or
a tutorial on the things that
you've done? Cause that would be
super quarter eight.
Roger: I definitely should write
this one up because I think I had
intended to, but then I, again,
got distracted and forgot to
complete it, which I, I, I could
say that a lot about a lot of the
domains that I purchased is about
being like, Hey, this is an idea.
Ooh, the domains available. Oh, I
should build this. And then I get
the renewal notice a year later.
Bekah: You have a domain with an
emoji in it, right.
Roger: So I am actually the proud
owner of the email emoji.fm. And
I have been trying to figure out
the best way to create an emoji
base, social networking, email
platform around that. That is
just purely nothing but emojis,
but, uh, amazingly. It is a
surprisingly difficult to get
emails delivered that contain
emojis. So I have been trying to
overcome a lot of, um, fun
technical problems getting that
service spun up. But, uh, yeah,
that's, that's a lot of
entertainment in itself is just,
uh, Hey, go check out this, uh,
emoji email and or domain. And
you're just like, I didn't even
know emojis could be domains.
Hmm. It causes a lot of things
that you shouldn't be buying two
interior, a credit card bill.
Bekah: I love that. I always
hearing stories. You tell stories
about the things that you're
doing, cause like, They're super
entertaining, but then also you
come out with stuff like that.
Like I've bought an emoji domain
that never would have crossed my
mind to even try doing.
Roger: I don't just have one. I
have a specific one that been
putting together for an
authentication service that is
themed about a wizard. And the
link is literally the link emoji
with the magic wand because there
they're magic links. And so the
whole idea is making a, a single
sign-on magic link service that
uses emojis is the links just
because like in the right
audience, it's, it's really
entertaining. It's also a lot
harder to, to forge those because
you know, how many people are
going to be using emojis and
their thing.
Bekah: Well, Once you, you get,
going to be using it. It's going
to be the next big thing. It
won't be something of the olden
days. It will be of the new end
days.
Roger: Well, the thing that I
love about emojis is. Especially
like in Virtual Coffee is a good
example. We have an international
community of developers that come
together. But the thing that is
most universal is the wave emoji.
Like everybody knows what that
means. Everybody can react and
like emojis in themself, almost a
universal language. Doesn't
matter which one you speak or
read the emojis pretty much being
the same thing.
Bekah: Okay. So, so you have, I
was going to ask, one of my like,
what is the coolest problem that
you want to solve? And you're,
you're talking about some cool
things. So I don't know if you've
already mentioned it, or if
you've got another big idea that
you want to share.
Roger: I think, I think the one
that when I talk about the, the
eyes light up of behind everybody
being like, why I didn't even
know that that was like something
that people were thinking And
it's kind one of the things that
I found, like the first love of
communities and its surrounds,
uh, zombies actually, which is
kind of like what makes everybody
laugh and. And I am building a
whole platform that does
essentially a distributed network
of servers that cash basically a
copy of like the internet
archive, the public domain
knowledge stores them, of a way
that makes it accessible. The
idea behind it is this, uh, this
whole nonprofit in
self-sufficiency and being
resourceful with just what you
have. And part of it comes from
desire just to want to host what
I call zombie con and where you
got a junk pile of computers and
a challenge. And you throw a
bunch of nerds that say, okay,
rebuild the internet. And here's
what you get to use for it,
because I think when you're
building out of necessity,
problems become so much different
than when you have the luxury of
both time and resources. And I
feel like something special will
come out of that, that I don't
even realize. I just, uh, every
time that I kind of talk about
that particular side of things,
like it gets people excited
because, you know, there's a
sense in all of us that I feel
like you want that dopamine
effect of being like, I did it's
solving a problem with your code,
it's fixing a server. Or if it's
like just something simple as
patching that drywall and looking
back and be like, you can't even
tell. It's that sense of pride
and accomplishment that you get
out of like the work that you do
that drives all of us. And the
thing that I've really wanted to
build is the, just the way that
we can share that and like make
these things being like, this is
how you patch a drywall and open
sourcing those and them available
as many people that are
interested in it. And just trying
to figure out ways to make it
accessible and last through the
apocalypse, because I feel like
that's the hardest challenge you
could ever possibly think about.
And. Thinking about ways to solve
that, to just make your, I don't
know, it just keeps me up at
night.
Bekah: Yeah. that's really
interesting.
Roger: Like our most valuable
resources, our knowledge. And if
we have to start over losing our
knowledge base as a humanity
would be the most detrimental
thing. And so the more that we
work to figure out a way to not
only maintain that, but also use
that data and, and part of what
drives the fun on this is like
you can download the entirety of
stack overflow as SQL database.
To your computer. And now you
have the entirety of all of the
question and answers that you've
needed to fix your programming at
your fingertips. It's only up to
you to figure out how to query
that data, to find the answers
you need. And I think like doing
that offline, where you don't
have connection to the internet,
like makes you more resourceful
and like you, you solve the
problems in a different way. And
I feel like. I feel so excited
when I do it on my own. So I just
like trying to build the
platforms and giving the people
the encouragement and the support
to know that like all of this
stuff's possible here. Here's the
way to get started.
Dan: That's awesome.
Roger: Like I said it causes
cause everybody to just go down
that rabbit hole and you start
thinking about these things and
you're just like, man, I don't
even know how to store, you know,
flour for longer than a couple of
days. Like, how am I in a store
for years? And there are
different problems you have to
try to solve.
Dan: yeah.
Bekah: Yeah, I've I really liked
that idea about things get done
differently. If it's out of
necessity, there's a very
different approach. And a lot of,
I don't know, I don't know if I
want to say like innovation that
comes out of it, but you know,
when you have to do something,
you're going to think about it in
a different way. And you are
going to change things to make
sure that it gets accomplished.
Uh, that I feel mind, building
like a scientific on what that
looks like, you know, like let's
make these people do it out of
necessity and then these people
can brainstorm. How that turn
out?
Dan: I yeah, but I mean, I think
that's a, it's a really
interesting point. And it's one
of the, like, sort of through
lines of the way you've been
talking, you know, especially
about your career and, you know,
the choice you made, right. Is,
is that, is that doing by
necessity? And it's a much
different, um, Learning path than
school, like a normal, like a
sort of traditional school or
even a bootcamp, right. Where
you're learning, because somebody
told you to learn this thing. Uh,
so maybe somebody that comes out
of, if there was some, I don't
know if there is these days,
they're not a front end
development, like actual degree,
these who knows, but you know,
like, uh, somebody who graduated
school with that sort of thing
will. Have a, sort of a, maybe a
different knowledge set than
somebody who was working for four
years, right. In, in that field.
And there's going to be that they
do know that the other person
doesn't and vice versa, you know?
Um, but that necessity, uh,
driving is, is, uh, I don't know,
it's an important, interesting,
interesting thing.
Roger: You know. Absolutely. And,
and I started, I started in my
whole career before I feel like
boot camps were a thing. I tried
going to school to learn it. But
by that point I understood more
than they were trying to teach
me. And I couldn't, it was, it
was, it was a difficult time.
when I realized that can just
sort of get the job with. Needing
anything more than being it. Like
that just caused me just to, oh,
I'm going to this. Okay. Yeah, I
can do that. And it just, for me,
it's, self-propelled because I
always had the tools to figure it
out because that's how I started.
I started, know, not having the
luxury of being able to search
the internet for something. Cause
I didn't have the internet to
search. I had HTML and CSS for
dummies. had to find It in that
book and you use that resource.
And so going from that to, to
now, And having to be able to
figure things out, out of
necessity, because there are
people that couldn't work because
their technology wasn't working
and you're responsible to fix it,
being like, okay, now we have
these massive sets of problems.
How can we resolve all of them
with automation or how can we
solve an unknown problem or build
new problems with And that's,
that's kind of exciting because
like, for me, I never learned the
fundamentals like you would in
school. And I there's great
benefit to going through because
like people learn different ways.
And I feel like I had an
understanding from what I learned
on how. How all the programming
language kind of overlapped, but
when you're in school or you go
through bootcamp, you learn those
same things. You get that same
sense of encouragement that, you
know, I had to go through and
overcome kind of in the life,
life field, there were real
consequences. If things didn't
work out. But going through a
traditional or going through a
school or a bootcamp, you know,
you get kind of, battle-tested
early on because they're shifting
you through all of these ideas
and concepts and you learn
fundamentally how all these
things work, which gives you
enough confidence to sort of
jumpstart where you need to be,
because go from having no idea
how any of this technology works
to being like, I know how magic
works and I will figure out how
to cast a spell dagnabbit. And,
and that in itself has power.
Dan: It is power. It's awesome.
It's such a good feeling, whether
it doesn't matter how you, I
learn like that, that feeling of,
of knowing how to do the thing,
knowing how to catch the magic
spell. I love it.
Bekah: That's great. Well, Roger,
just about out of time. So I want
to thank you for being here. Is
there any last bits of advice or
things you want our listeners to
hear?
Roger: I I never, I didn't think
about this. I should have come
prepared. I just think like, if
you're looking at something and
you feel out of place or you feel
like you can't do it, or you're
not good enough, or what have
you, like feel discouraged
because at some point everybody
been that. And has looked through
and has gotten over it. And it's
just matter of you getting to it.
just have to do it. And then once
you've done it, it's easy. And I
try to avoid saying things are
easy because it wasn't easy for
me when I started. once I did it,
it became easy. so just
remembering, like getting over
that first hurdle and having the
confidence of doing the thing,
matter what that thing is.
Eventually you're going to do it
doesn't matter how long you wait
to do it. You'll get over that
hurdle and it's going to get
easier from there because once
you do it, you figured it out.
You can't figure it out. It only
goes one direction. It's a
one-way street. Once you start
walking, it that's it. You're
just going to keep figuring
things out. And when you start,
when you start out, I feel like
everything is overwhelming. You
know, there's just a lot of
information coming in. And when
you first sit down and you're
falling all of these, you know,
tutorials like, Hey, it works.
But then when you try to do it on
your own, it doesn't,
frustrating. Cause you're like, I
should be able to have this
thing, do the thing. And it's not
that you're ever wrong. It's just
that you have to take a little
bit more time to figure out which
step that you missed in the
process because it's somewhere
and when you do it once you can
do it again. A dozen times
suddenly they're calling you a
senior developer that's just how
it goes. It just takes time and
persistence. And eventually
you'll overcome everything.
Bekah: Love that as a great way
to end. Thanks so much Roger for
being here with us.
Roger: Thanks for having me.
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!