Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season five, episode six of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost.
Dan: Hello, Bekah. Today, we are
talking with Andrew Bush. Andrew
is a mobile engineer specializing
in React Native. Um, and so if
you've been to, um, Virtual
Coffee.io recently checked out
our members page, you might have
noticed, we now have, we have all
of our members there and. Now we
have a little tags that say what
roles they have, uh, if, if
people are volunteering, helping
out in Virtual Coffee. And so
Andrew is one of the people that
has been helping out with us for
a while he's been doing, um, he's
been helping lead the monthly
challenge team, um, for the past.
I don't know how long has he
been? I'm not sure. I can't
remember off the top of my head
how long, but it feels like a
while.
Bekah: It has been a while.
Dan: yeah, it feels like to me,
it's been while,
Bekah: last year, for sure.
Dan: Yeah. And, um, so monthly
challenges you can read more
about on our site as well. Um,
but we do a different challenge
every month and, um, and yeah, so
Andrew has been helping lead that
group along with Ali and, um, who
was on the podcast season. I
don't remember which season, but
she was on, she was on, she was
on a while ago. Um, so yeah, we
talked about that for a while.
And, um, Andrew also, he kind of
talked about. You know what it's
been like leaning the leading in
the group and, uh, helping, you
know, facilitates challenges,
stuff like that. And, um, we'll
stop a while about, you know,
what it's like to be a mobile
developer. Um, some of the
experiences with React Native
and, uh, of course his journey
through his.
Bekah: Yeah, it was great talking
about that. And I really love
that the tags recognize our
members and what they're doing. I
mean, not just because we want to
recognize our members, but also
it helps other people to see
who's doing what and how they can
get involved in Virtual Coffee.
And we actually haven't. Get
involved section on the site. So
if anybody is out there and wants
to add a tag to their name, can
fill out one of those forms and
we can, um,
Dan: And they can get involved.
Bekah: yeah.
Dan: Yeah. Uh, yeah. So if you're
listening and you want to check
that out, um, it's in the
resources section
VirtualCoffee.io/resources, and
then I dunno, click through in
there. It's in there somewhere.
Um, so yeah, uh, it was a good
episode overall and, uh, I know
you're going to enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do and a
random check-in question. We hope
you enjoy this episode. Our intro
question is if you could live in
an animated movie, what would it
be? My name is Bekah. I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and I would
live in. I feel like it needs to
have some kind of magical aspect
to it, because that would be more
fun. I was going to say beauty
and the beast. Cause that's my
favorite movie. I'll just stick
with that.
Dan: Uh, pre beast conversion or
post, like, is he still The
Beast? Basically, I mean, and all
the other, you know,
Bekah: Yeah, there's no more
magic if he's not the
Dan: Right, right, That's my,
that was my question.
Bekah: kind of boring.
Dan: But if he's at The Beast,
then, you know, you got a whole
other problem to deal with.
Bekah: Yeah. I wonder if his fur
is soft.
Dan: You know, I actually just
watched it with the kids. Uh, you
know, it was their first time,
like a week or two ago. I didn't
watch it for a long time. Um, so
like all the furniture are his
servants or whatever his
household staff, well, what. Did
he not have furniture at all
before that? Or did they all turn
into furniture? And then they
like just threw out the existing,
alive furniture.
Bekah: furniture. I think it's
kind of got that Encanto vibe
where there's in the house. the
head of all of the cups is Mrs.
Pots, but not every cup is a
household worker. They just have
the magic now.
Dan: Oh, wait. So you're saying
like alive cups, but they weren't
actually people before they just
like,
Bekah: right.
Dan: the magic is like turning.
Bekah: chip, like they were
people, but there are other cups
that move around and do but
that's just the magic that is
commanding
Dan: Got it.
Bekah: and echanting the house.
Dan: Okay. Uh, alright. Hi, I'm
Dan. I do web development in
Cleveland, Ohio, and, um, I think
the first thing that popped in my
mind was Moana um, the, uh, you
know, the life there seems pretty
simple. Um, you know, on island
plus canoeing is one of my
favorite things and, um, That'd
be cool. Uh, Maui seems like a
cool hang. So I'm going with, I'm
going with Moana as my, as my
animated universe to live in.
Bekah: Are you taking your rain
shell with you?
Dan: Uh, probably I won't have to
use it very much, but you know,
I'm sure it rains there sometimes
there's like a rainy season,
right. I would think. Thanks for,
thanks for that.
Bekah: Just making sure you had
it. I know it's important to you.
Andrew: And I'm Andrew and I'm a
mobile developer in the React
Native space based out of
Wisconsin. Uh, I, I think I'd
live in the valley in Encanto,
but I have a bit of a recency
bias. I just like, that's the
most recent animated film I've
seen, but I, I. In the intro
sequence. There's these. So it's
in Columbia and then the intro
sequence. There's these kids who
like, are like running with
little cups of coffee and they're
shaking and the coffee splashing
out of the cups. I'd be like one
of those little kids. That's my
vibe.
Bekah: Yeah, Yeah, that is my. my
kids love, or my five-year-old
loves that part where. She says
Maribel Mirabelle says, that's
why coffee is for grownups. They
just laugh every single time. Um,
so welcome, Andrew. Thank you so
much for being here with us for
this episode of our podcast. And
we always like to get started
with the origin story of each of
our guests. So what brought you
here to the state of your Andrew
developer career?
Andrew: All right. I should've
expected a question like this. I
got to work on my elevator pitch
anyway. Um, Yeah, it's sort of a,
I don't know if there is a
traditional path, but I would say
mine is non-traditional. Uh, I,
the first time I ever wrote code
was, uh, HTML, not even like
full-blown HTML, just tags to
make my MySpace page cooler. Um,
and then like a long time later,
I thought I'd go to school for
that. And. Um, you know, that
didn't go super well, super well
for me, I, uh, my major wasn't
partying, so they kicked me out
and, uh, you know, I did, you
know, after sorta like, you know,
trying to figure out what I
wanted to be when I grow up for
many years, I was like, you know,
I actually really liked
programming and I really liked
web development specifically. So
I. I have sort of sorted things
out. And I actually, I went back
to school again, got an
associates degree and thought,
all right, I just need to get a
job. I need to get into the
space. Um, and I took an
interview for like a very generic
you're going to write code, but
they didn't tell me what. And I
ended up writing React Native
code, uh, and I did not expect to
be in a mobile developer space.
Yeah. I actually really enjoyed
it. And that's where I've stuck
since then. And that's gotten me
to here.
Bekah: Yeah. So this is always
been fascinating to me because I
don't know that many React Native
developers. So can you talk a
little bit about how you ended up
there? Cause it's not, you know,
at least, I don't know a ton of
people doing react, native
development. First of All wait,
maybe let's pause and what is
React Native development. And
then answer my other question.
Andrew: All right. Yeah. So React
Native is a, cross-platform
framework, uh, for mobile apps.
They are into the web space now.
So you can write all in one, uh,
stack and then deploy wherever.
But yeah, the original intention
is so that you can have. A single
code base in single skillsets to
be able to write Android and iOS
applications because native
Android applications that are
going to be in Java or Kotlin and
native iOS, that's going to be in
swift. So rather than having, you
know, especially in a
professional environment,
distinct teams, knowing distinct
stacks and trying to always keep
those things in sync react.
Native is one of the solutions
that was out there. Uh, Uh, when
I first started, we started with,
uh, native scripts, which is just
another one of the options out
there, and then ended up pivoting
because of the community support
for React Native it's made by
Facebook. So there's just a lot
of support and funding behind it.
Um, but yeah, it's at its core.
It's JavaScript. Um, but
professionally I've always used
TypeScript on top of it.
Dan: That's cool. And so does
that work out? Um, from what I
understand, I've never really
worked in it from dabbling. Um,
but. From what I understand, you
have the ability to do some
native stuff, if you need to, or
whatever, in like real app, you
know, in non-classroom apps that
you'd like the kind of stuff
you're actually working on. Do
does the cross-platform thing,
like honestly, like work out
really well, uh, as opposed like,
or do you need to end up having
to do like little weird little
things for, for, you know, for
different platforms, from time to
time.
Andrew: Yeah, well, it, uh, in my
experience, um, which I would,
you know, for context, I've, I've
been doing this for, I've been
doing it professionally for about
three years. So in my experience,
rarely do we actually need to
write native code. Occasionally
you'll run into like, We had some
weird issue with splash screens
at my previous job and the
solution wasn't native solution.
But a lot of times you find, you
can just get a package, that'll
handle that for you. Um, but
yeah, actually most things are
pretty seamless. The, the, I
guess the overhead you get is
recognizing that sense. It builds
across multiple platforms. It's
not always gonna like, come when
it gets compiled, it's not going
to behave in exactly the same
way. Every time. There's always
like little corks and sometimes
it's specifically on device. So
we've got like, we, when, when
you write it, you frequently,
when you're devving, you're like
using a simulator or an emulator.
And, but then like before you
roll out to production, As our QA
is telling me when I'm doing dev
work to, I need to test on
physical device because that
uncovers more issues that you
don't see. So that's like the big
thing with it, I guess, more so
than, I dunno, I sort of lost the
plot there.
Dan: More so than, than different
platforms and stuff is, is really
just a, if I can understand what
you're saying, more, more of the.
The fact that you're working
specifically for a, you know,
you're building an app for it
device that somebody holds in
their hand. Right. And so as
opposed to something on a screen
with mouse or another pointer
device,
Andrew: right.
Dan: so yeah, that seems like
probably probably good advice and
probably easy to forget when
you're, when you're in the weeds,
you know, Kind of been developing
for a long time on a, on a thing.
And just looking at your
simulator, um, on your computer.
Um, I certainly like even on
websites have that same thing.
Right, right. I forget, uh, I
look at it, you know, I see what
it looks like on the iPhone, you
know, a simulator or the, that,
that Indev tools even, you know,
which is even another further
step removed from the actual
thing. Right. Um, but it's always
good to take a pass, you know,
see what it feels like, swiping
things or just scrolling, like
out, it looks scrolling on the,
on your. You know, for an iPhone,
at least it has the, what you
call the scroll that keeps going
when you, when you flick it. Um,
I can't remember what it's
called, but there's, there's a
name for it, but like on an
iPhone, when you scroll, you
know, everyone used to it, you
scroll with your finger and you
kind of flick it and it keeps
going. Right. Which is what most
people on, um, computers, you
know, are using, uh, don't have
that, right. They're using a
touch pad or a scroll bar,
whatever, and it stops. Right.
And that experience is a little
bit different. You're going to
see some, you're going to see
things, um, especially if you
have interaction going on, uh,
You know, it scroll interaction,
things like that. Um, it seems
like a pretty important step to
take. So
Andrew: that's an actually really
interesting, uh, the. Is there
might be a specific name for it.
I'm not thinking of it either,
but like, you know, continuous
scrolling or maybe something like
that. But yeah, that is it's
interesting when developing and
it, there are certain things that
each platform will natively do on
its own. And. In my experience, I
try and create apps that are
consistent. So an iOS user, I
want them to see exactly what an
Android user sees, but you also
have to be aware of, well, what
are platform specific things that
say an iPhone user is going to
expect when they're in their
apps? Right? Navigation is one. I
phones don't have hardware
buttons for back navigation.
That's like by default, they've
got, they usually have a little
back arrow in the corner. Um, but
yeah, until that scrolling, um,
it's interesting on those types
of scrollable things in apps,
there's a really slick animation.
I think that just kinda is native
to iOS that when you get to. It
does that infinite scroll. And I
just think it looks really smooth
and you get to the bottom of the
list and it kind of balances
there at the bottom. And I think
it looks really good and that
just doesn't happen natively on
Android. And it's like, Hmm.
Dan: Uh, I looked it up at the
it's called momentum scrolling.
And, uh, I think that includes
that scroll past that exact
behavior you're talking about.
Um, but it, so it's because it is
cool and I've, I've like looked
at it and tried to recreate it a
couple of times in, in
JavaScript, whatever, but it, it
does have momentum just going,
it's a great name for it. Cause
it's like, it really does. You
flick it in and it starts fast
and goes in and slows down and
stuff like that. Um, It's
momentum scrolling. That's that's
what it's called.
Bekah: This has been a really
long week. And in my mind, I was
like, I want that to be my
nickname. That doesn't make any
sense, but like,
Andrew: I'd say by itself,
momentum is a pretty cool
nickname.
Dan: Yeah.
Andrew: scrolling part is sort of
weird to assign to a human.
Bekah: Um, Yeah, I'm not sure
where to go with that either. Um,
so I want to, I have some minimal
experience with React Native. And
so one of the questions people
ask me all the time is, well,
what's the difference? Like how
what's the learning curve. From
React to React Native, which I
actually think that React Native
is easier to learn, but I say
that as somebody who learned
React first, I don't know if you
have any thoughts on that,
Andrew. I just like, you know,
here's a view. This is, it's not
a diff it's a, it's a view that
makes sense.
Andrew: Yeah, I've gone the other
way. I wouldn't say I've learned
React so to speak. I sort of
vicariously have by doing React
Native, but yeah, I went the
other way. I started with React
Native and I've done some
dabbling in react. Um, I think.
Right. The, the distinct
differences I noticed one is like
in the JSX. So where you're using
traditional HTML type tags, you
just, you don't use those in
React Native. You use.
Traditional native tags. Um, I
remember seeing like view a
scroll view, text input, like
very these very declarative
names. I did a little bit of
development in Xamarin in
college, and that was a mobile
framework, uh, that uses like XML
type markup and. It had very
similar naming structure. So like
that, that stuff was super
familiar to me, but yeah, I find
it like that's that kind of stuff
just makes sense. Um, yeah, I
think really the other sort of,
it's more of a, like a mental
contextual. Between the two, like
knowing that you're working on a
mobile device, that it receives
taps, it doesn't receive clicks.
It receives like swipes and, you
know, it's, you gotta just be
aware of the user experience is
very different. Um, I think of
like our, another member of VC,
uh, Louis, he coincidentally
joined my team. Um, and at, at
work. He had never done React
negative and he ramped up so
fast. He had React to experience
and he was instantly making
contributions. Um, so I think,
yeah. Want one skillset can
really help you with the.
Bekah: Yeah, I for sure. And it's
interesting because I heard
somebody talking about React
Native documentation once where
they. Said initially there was an
assumption that everybody who was
doing React Native was coming
from react. And then when they
asked for feedback, they found
that actually there were a lot of
non-reactive developers that were
coming in. So there were
assumptions built into the
documentation, um, about where
folks were at. And then they took
that feedback and updated things
and, and made it approachable
for, um, I would say more of an
entry level. Learner to navigate
through the documentation, which
is always fascinating to me.
Andrew: Yeah, I'm, I'm no
superhero. So like, I read that
those documentation, like I read
that still on a regular basis,
but you know, I'm not pouring
over it like I did in the
beginning, but. I would
frequently have to pop back over
to like, well, what's the React
documentation, because that has
like context that I need. I've
found that definitely to be true.
Um, but yeah, it was it's
interesting. I I'm coming from,
like, when I was in school, they
taught us angular, JS, whatever
the. I think it's the framework
that people don't like as much,
uh, the version of angular and,
uh, it's like is framework
experience. That's what I had.
But otherwise it was just
JavaScript, HTML, CSS and some
PHP. So like it really coming
into like choosing a framework,
it kind of was like, well, I know
Java script, so I can, I can kind
of figure this out.
Dan: I love that mentality that,
you know, Just being just like
the confidence to, you know, be
able to be able to know you can
like pick something else up, you
know, even if it's going to take
a minute, um, we were just
talking about that with Roger. I
think I didn't realize, oh,
that's podcast recording. We, um,
yeah, we're talking about like
learning and, and, and how that
that's one of those things once.
Like get some job experience, you
know, and you realize like
everybody's kind of in the same
boat, um, and like new big things
are become a little less scary
because even if it's just a big
black box, you know, that you
don't really know anything about,
uh, not like once you've, figured
out your way around one, one
programming, you know, I don't
language it paradigm and
whatever. Um, so many of the
things. Transfer it, somebody
that concept's transfer, you
know, Roger was saying, they're
like, oh, you really need to know
is like, if, and for loops, you
know, or whatever, and you can
pretty much get your way through
any language. Sounds like that.
Which I agree, which I agreed
with, you know, in, in principle,
it's, they're all, they're all
kind of doing a lot of the same
stuff. So.
Bekah: Um, I'm going to shift the
conversation just a little bit,
because I know you said that
you've been a developer for about
three years and that's where I've
been to. So I know for me, COVID
impacted a lot of my early job
experience, and I'm just curious
how, if that impacted you as
well. And I know, you know, early
career developers trying to find
community and then suddenly being
isolated. Creates extra
challenges on top of things.
Andrew: Yeah. So my. Story there
is I, I had a job at a local
company, um, and I mean,
Wisconsin cost of living. Isn't
very high. I mean, depending
where you live, where I live,
it's not, uh, therefore pay is
not very high. So I took a local
job and, uh, you know,
compensation. And, but I was
sticking around and because it
was my first job at the time, and
I just worked with that company
to get career growth. And, and
then the pandemic started, I was
at, I've been doing it a year and
a half, almost two years at that
point. No. I don't know what time
math is hard for me. there are
libraries for that. Uh, I, and
then the pandemic started in my
company was immediately like,
everybody go home. We're going
virtual. And I, I left the office
that day and didn't look back. I
didn't, I was, I was stoked to
come work from home. Because I
am, uh, I'm legally blind. So
like commuting, I just depend on
somebody else to get me to work.
That was, uh, inconvenient for my
fiance. Um, inconvenient for my
wallet. If I needed to. You know,
get like a ride share or
something. I mean, my work was
six miles away. Maybe somebody
can bike that every day if I'm
just not for it. Um, um, I'm
realizing I'm giving a really
long drawn out answer to
Bekah: was
Andrew: So, yeah, so then it,
and, uh, To that same point,
like, um, with my vision, it's,
it's way easier for me to get
comfortable at home. Like the
ergonomics of my setup, you know,
I have, my monitors are mounted,
so, you know, I, I have 27 inch
monitors. They're like a very
modest size, um, even maybe on
the large side and I get that.
Inches from my face, but because
they're mounted, I can have my
keyboard, like, you know, way
farther back. So I get that nice,
you know, 90 degree in my elbows,
but I can still see. And like, I
just can't do that in an office.
I can't be comfortable. Um, yeah,
so it was like really good for
me. And, but I quickly noticed
like, Especially when you took
away, like the being at work,
water cooler type stuff, you
know, spending time with
coworkers, it's like, I, I don't
like this company that much and
I'm not, I'm very alone. Um, and
so I needed a new job. I started
looking and I was just not like,
even with two years experience,
right. I was, I was taking
interviews and they wanted
people. With more experience than
me or, yeah, I just wasn't it,
whatever it was, they were
looking for. I wasn't it. And,
uh, I thought, well, okay. So
everybody tells me, I remember in
school and just throughout my
life, they're like, oh, it's
about who, you know, not what you
know, and you should do
networking. And, and I thought I
am. An introvert. So, no, thank
you. I don't do that. And I was
listening to a podcast, a tech
podcast. I can't remember which
one now, but actually you were on
it Bekah and you had talked about
Virtual Coffee and I was like,
okay, that sounds different. That
sounds like, you know, it's
networking. Right. But it's.
Traditionally what I think of,
and it's a community of people
doing the same thing that I'm
doing, and I need that. And I am
so glad I listened to whatever
that podcast was.
Bekah: Maybe the React Native
podcast.
Andrew: It's very possible. yeah,
and, and it's, it's, it's struck
me and I'm like, I'm going to
join this community. And I did
that and yeah, ever since, like I
joined VC, I got this like sense
of, uh, self-confidence that I
really needed. I think for
finding a job outside of where I
live and, um, and, and a
community of like other people
working to better themselves.
Technically or even on
technically it's the thing I love
about this community too, is it's
not just about the work that we
do. Um, so that was, Virtual
Coffee. It was the launch
platform that got me to the job
that I got it actually like in
actual, tangible terms. I got my
job through a different avenue,
but I think sort of the
confidence in myself that I
gained the, you know, I, I had
like access to people who could
help me, you know, how do I, how
do I present myself at
interviews? How do I get better
at that? How do I answer? X
coding question. And that all led
me to, I think, finding success
in finding a job and finding an
equitable job, right? Like, so I
like, I, like I opened with, you
know, I was, I had a hard, I had
limited options locally, you
know, limited tech stacks,
limited pay, limited benefits,
and I was able to get a fair
compensation. By being able to
look elsewhere and being
confident enough to look
elsewhere and say, I am worth
this.
Bekah: Thanks so much for sharing
that I. Really appreciate it. I
appreciate everything that you're
doing at Virtual Coffee. And so,
you know, we're happy to have you
here no matter what, but
especially you're one of our
monthly challenge team leads. And
so I feel like. You're really,
you've really invested in the
community and supporting other
people to find that that feeling
of connectedness and community,
that seems pretty important to
your journey. You want to talk a
little bit about what you do as,
um, monthly challenge co-team
lead.
Andrew: Yeah, for sure. For me,
for me doing that, that is right.
That is my opportunity to give
back to Virtual Coffee. And in
terms of, I got so much out of
Virtual Coffee and it feels like
I can't give back to this
community, what it gave to me.
And I think it's, I feel, I just
feel compelled to, to like
volunteer and help, help others
get what I got, because my life,
like from before Virtual Coffee
from me sitting at my desk at
that last job to where I am
today. Oh my gosh. I, I, I have
grown so much and I'm so. Happy
with where I've ended up in a lot
of, you know, there's a lot of
influences in how that happened,
but I recognize the part that,
that Virtual Coffee played in
that. And so me doing the monthly
challenges is giving back to
that. And so, yeah, at four for
Virtual Coffee, we like, I mean,
obviously you two know this, but
we, so we do a monthly challenge
and that will consist of, we
have. 12 ish or I think a little
bit more like maybe 13 topics
that we will cover throughout the
year, uh, and assign them to a
month. And that's what we'll
focus on. And folks in the
community are free to participate
in those challenges as a way to,
you know, expand their own, uh,
skillset or as their own
opportunity for growth. So. For
this upcoming month for April, we
are doing, um, we are focusing on
jobs on the job search and job
preparation. And so like what,
what I do for that and what that
will look like, I guess is each
challenge looks a little bit
different, but there are some
commonalities in, so we, we like
to. Try and engage with the
community throughout the
challenge and, uh, provide
resources and basically support
for them to, to, to grow. And,
um, so. I coordinate and help,
like get the documentation and
stuff that we need set up in
order to make that magic happen.
Um, I, you know, I work with
people who want to be involved
like, Hey, do you want to run
like meetings associated with
this challenge? Or do you want to
try and hype people up about this
challenge? Or do you want to help
me write documentation about this
challenge? So I try and rally
around that kind of stuff. Um,
Yeah, I don't do that alone.
Yeah. As, as you alluded to back,
I do that with, um, like my co
lead on that is orally and that
is so wonderful that we co lead
that together because you know,
it's a volunteer position, right.
It's we do what we can to give
back, but we also do have jobs
and families. And so sometimes we
can. Do as much as we'd like to,
and it's nice to have somebody
else there to help balance that.
Bekah: I keep hitting the mute
and unmute button, like multiple
times. I don't know what's going
on extra cookie today. Uh, sorry.
Um, yes, that is a great overview
of what our monthly challenges
are. And they've been a lot of
fun, I think, working through
them. And like you said, we've
had. I think at least 13, and
we're kind of iterating on that
the second year around trying to
figure out how things work. And,
uh, one of the great things I
love to see is how many people
are helping each other through
that process, you know, or
continuing. We had month of
pairing a couple months ago, and
somebody messaged me recently and
said, I really loved being able
to pair with other people and I
want to keep that going. Um, and
those are the kind of stories
that really. Um, I didn't make my
heart feel happy. I'm not sure
how else to put it because
there's this, this love of the
community that develops through
these things. And you know, for
us, we haven't made a competition
out of it. Although we have we've
had leaderboards and stuff, but
It's not like, oh, it's a race to
the top of the leaderboard. It's
just cool to be able to see what
everybody's doing and how they're
doing it. And, um, I'm, I'm
really excited as we're going
into this second year of monthly
challenges with this team of
people to see all of the
connections that are continually
made and how we can keep
supporting each other.
Andrew: It's hard to say, like
all I want to say about it. I
getting like lost in my own
thoughts. Uh, but yes. So some of
the challenges that like, so we
did a, uh, writing challenge in
November where we, we support it.
Each other members in like in
writing blog posts or putting out
content and right there once like
a leaderboard individually, you
could see who put in how many
words, but that wasn't the
challenge. The challenge was to
like the number challenge was we
had a goal to hit. How many can
we hit this many words? I think
was it a hundred thousand?
Bekah: I think it ended up being
over that. Right. Did we hit the
one 20 Dan? Do you remember?
Dan: Yeah, I just looked at it.
I'm trying to remember. I, I like
literally looked at it yesterday
cause I was doing this. I can
look it up real
Bekah: Yeah, our challenge was
like 50,000 and we
Dan: Yeah, we blast the best that
in like a week. I think
Andrew: Yeah.
Dan: I see, well, we got to 125
over 125,000. So
Andrew: Yeah, absolutely
Dan: it was pretty dope.
Andrew: And we had individual
contributors there, right. Who
they wrote a lot of words and as
amazing. And, but we also
succeeded together in crushing
that goal. And I think on another
individual basis, I think people
succeeded in just writing
something for the first time. Um,
as, as someone who runs the
challenge, I don't I've, I've
tried to balance me participating
and running it. And I just can't,
I can't do well at both. Um, but
that's, I do love supporting
that. And so right. Giving
somebody an avenue to do
something for the first time to
write a blog post for the first
time you see a lot of developers
do that, and if you want to do
it, it can be super intimidating.
Being on a podcast can be super
intimidating. And so when you see
other people doing it and you
have that support, you're able to
do that kind of stuff. And, but I
wanted to highlight too, like one
of the challenges, one of the
monthly challenges we did that I
really liked. Um, I think it was,
we did it for December and I, I
can't remember what we called it,
but it was about. It was about
doing like, uh, your own. What's
your passion outside of your job?
What's your passion outside of
the technical skillset you have
that brought you to Virtual
Coffee? Let's talk about that.
Let's celebrate that. Uh, there
was really cool stuff. Uh, in, in
music, we had people sharing
their own musical talents. I
think that was Jessica who, um,
shared some cool videos in that
we saw tons of. Uh, yarn work a
lot of knitters in VC.
Bekah: in new knitters too. Some
people just took it up. It the
creative community challenge.
Andrew: Yes. So right then. So
even in that, like people were
inspiring other people to pick up
new things. And I think I love
that about VC is getting to
share. That kind of stuff too. I
get to talk about programming all
day at work. Sometimes I just
want to talk to people about the
things that I like to do, like
for creative community. I think I
built a 3d puzzle and I had a lot
of fun and it was very Zen and
not stressful.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's so
important. And I'm glad that you
brought that one up because it's
something that more and more I'm
finding that I need to do. A
break from coding things because
it's just constant coding or
community. And I love it, but I
do find that my brain is
sometimes just exhausted and
anxious because I'm overwhelmed
with all of these things that I'm
doing and trying to learn. And
you're never gonna learn it all.
You're never going to, um, be an
expert at every single thing. And
I think that really, for me,
it's. Like, okay. I I've learned
how to do these things, but I
need to make space for, for other
things that don't feel
productive. Um, that helped me to
learn how to relax, which I, I,
here's a thing that some people
do. I'm still trying to figure
that one out. And, and so I think
it is initially Kirk's idea that
monthly challenges should have
four quarters and one quarter,
one month per quarter should be
devoted to non-tech things. And
we've even been like doing more
non-technical topics in Virtual
Coffee, just to say like, It was
okay. When one time we talked
about like cleaning products for
almost the entire time, I'm not
good at cleaning and I don't like
it, but I think I'm fascinated
that there are all these tools
out there that I don't know exist
because I avoid knowing anything
about it, but it was really a
great conversation like, oh,
okay. Now, now I know this adult
thing.
Andrew: Yeah, we are the IM
virtual. The, and in any
community you form, I think we're
all, we're all diverse people
with diverse interests. In the
case of Virtual Coffee, we're
brought together by one common
interest. Um, but we get to learn
from each other about all this
other stuff. And I think that's
one of my favorite things about
visa.
Bekah: Same same. And I, so I've
been doing a lot of research on
communities and community
building, and there's different
categories that communities are
often grouped into. And I kind of
love that. I don't feel like we
really fit into one category.
Yes, we are here because we're
all interested in tech. But if
you look at the conversations
among people and the connections
that are created, Most of the
deep connections are not because
we're here for tech it's because
we relate to each other on a
different level. And that comes
with, you know, like bringing who
we are and our interests outside
of tech into the conversation,
because that, that to some extent
allows for more vulnerability and
openness to happen. And I, I just
love how great that is and how
it's something that, that we work
hard. Kind of preserve as part of
our community.
Andrew: Yeah, very much. I, I
keep thinking of like all these
instances of. My interactions
with other community members. So
I keep name-dropping them. And if
that ends up being an issue, we
can just throw like a clucking
chicken sound or something over
me the names, but Kirk and I will
have a zoom calls sometimes. Like
sometimes we talk about
programming topics, but
oftentimes I find with him, we'll
just like wax philosophical for
an hour. And then it was like,
where did the time go? Like we
came on this call to, you know,
just chit chat and that's always
sort of where we end up, but I
love that. Like, that's why I
keep coming back, uh, is to talk
about philosophy with Kirk.
Bekah: Kirk is great. And so
this, well, once this episode
airs, this will have been a
couple of weeks, but we, this
week we won Most Welcoming
Developer Community. I think
that's it. Is that what it is?
Cause I keep saying that to
people on live. Something,
something about welcoming in my
mind, we are definitely the most
welcoming developer community.
Um, I think we won the award for
welcoming developer community. So
that would make us the most right
by default because
Dan: No, I think there were the
words called the most welcoming
developer community.
Bekah: then I'm right. Okay.
Excellent.
Andrew: That
Bekah: where it's going with the
accident. I was just going to
drop that. We want it.
Andrew: well earned well-deserved
I, when I first attended a VC
meeting, I very much felt that
it, like, it felt like I
belonged. And I got into the
slack and I started like
messaging people. Like there
were, there was a subset of
people who've made me feel like I
belonged and those names will, I
think will always stick out to
me. Um, and like, these were the
people who, when I joined VC,
they were very active. They were
very present and they made me
feel a part of, um, I think very
much about our friend. Mike was
one of those.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. So much, so
much of that welcoming spirit.
And it is, that is what makes a
community special and the ability
to, you know, have those. Quiet
conversations or, you know, even
just, there are tiny things that
I think are that are hard to put
into words that, you know,
somebody might remember. So, um,
I got a package in the mail for
Christmas, no name on it, and it
was a box of my favorite tea.
Where did this come on? So I ask
her and Kirk, Kirk knew who's
done it. It was somebody from
Virtual Coffee and it just tiny
things like, that. I mean, well,
sending a package, I feel like is
a big thing because that requires
a lot of energy, but the idea
that somebody remembered what my
favorite tea was. Was really
special. And there are like small
moments like that, that happen
all the time with people or
someone will remember something
that you've said a long time ago
and, and say something to you
about it. And it just makes you
feel like, yes, these are, these
are my friends. And when people
are like my online friends, I'm
like, no, these are my friends,
you know? Um, and so I, I for
sure get what you're, you're
saying there, Andrew.
Andrew: I think of like, One of
my big passions is running and we
have a channel in our slack
that's health and fitness. And so
I get to post about that running
there sometimes. And it's a
opportunity for me to share that,
like the friends I have who live
around me, they, they don't care
about my running. I don't think
that they're not like. Oh, look
at this runner over here. They're
done. making fun of me for doing
it or something, but they just
don't care and that's fine. Um,
but there are people at VC who I
can share that with and they
care. And it's like, it means so
much to me, like running does as,
as a hobby and a passion and to
have other people like. Get
invested to and care. It's
priceless.
Bekah: Yeah, W even, you know,
you ran a race recently, right?
And I, remember thinking like,
oh, I know that he's running a
race. I need to go check and see
if he posted about it and ask him
and like that that's it. I'm not
a huge runner. I've run a couple
of five Ks, but I'm invested in
knowing how you did, because
you're my friend.
Andrew: Yeah, I, I see that like,
um, I see that with you with, um,
Weightlifting that you do, like
you'll, I've seen videos of you
doing squats and I'm like, she
can definitely squat more than I
can. But, because you know, I'm
not, I'm not much of a
weightlifter, but it's the exact
same thing, right? Where I, I
look at that and I'm like, I am
here for this. I am here for this
success. Your success makes it
feel like my success let's be
successful together.
Bekah: That's such a great way to
describe it. I feel like maybe
that's the episode title let's be
successful together. Right? It's
just all about lifting each other
up. And when times are hard,
especially in the last couple of
years, being able to do that is,
is, I don't know, just like
sometimes key to keeping that
momentum. I'm going back to my
nickname.
Andrew: th the, um, one thing I
did, I did want to. Um, talk
about kind of related to a lot of
the stuff we've said is like, one
thing I've learned in, VC is I've
learned, I don't think I've ever
tried to put this into words. So
let me give this a shot. Like I.
I'm learning how to be myself and
be respectful to myself and allow
myself space to be a certain way.
I guess I see that, like I get, I
am my own worst critic. I am so
hard on myself. Um, You know, I,
I make one mistake and all of a
sudden I'm not good enough. And
you know, a lot of, some of this
plays into like imposter
syndrome. Type deal. Like I, my
favorite, uh, analogy for this,
and I do feel like this sometimes
is that I am two children in a
trench coat who snuck into the
movies and I going to get caught.
One of these days. I literally
was in a work meeting a couple of
months ago. And I remember I was
talking, there was our CIO was in
the meeting and like, PI up
people. And for some reason I had
the floor and everybody was
listening to me and I just like
froze right in the middle of
talking. And I thought, what am I
doing here? Like, I am too much
of a child to be doing this, but,
um, I think other people in VC
who experienced this and have.
You know, some success some days
at overcoming it have taught me
how to, to deal with that and how
to be okay with that. Um, and one
thing I guess, in, in sort of
this similar vein, uh, that I
carry with me a lot and I've
carried into work is as we talk
about, uh, in our VC meetings, we
use the raise hand. Um, little
reaction on zoom. Yeah, too. So
that people can have space to say
what they want to say or share,
because it can be really hard to.
To just find space in a
conversation that is a reality in
like the real world, it can be
very difficult. People have
different communication styles
and some people they're like, if
you want to say something, but it
just interrupt me. You know,
that's not me. Um, and, and I I'm
very much a listener. So if I'm
around a person who talks a lot,
they will, I'll just sit quiet.
Um, and if they don't ever give
me space to say something, I
don't say something. There is no,
uh, you can literally raise your
hand in real life. I'm not going
to too fat, but in zoom there's
that raise hand functionality,
which allows me to find space.
And I know I've talked a lot on
those podcasts, so it sounds
contradictory to me saying that I
do that, but I feel like this is
somehow a unique case, but I
think. That is one of those
little things. And maybe it
wasn't little when it was thought
of, and maybe it's not isn't
little, I don't know. But it
seems like a small decision that
was made, right? It's all you do
is you press the button. Right.
But it is so big to me. And I
carried that to, to my work when
we have work meetings and we've
had like retros and I'm like,
Hey, there is not space for some
of our quieter members of our
team. Be themselves and to share
their thoughts and we need their
thoughts. So, you know, we use
that at work now too. And that's
a mind dump of like a sort of
being myself type thing that I've
learned, uh, from VCs.
Bekah: Oh, I love that. I, and it
is that is those tiny things that
make a big difference, especially
if somebody is an introvert or is
neurodiverse, or it's just not
really sure of what to expect
within, um, the way that things
are happening. And so having
those things, I know that. At
work we use, um, Google meet and
there's not a hand raise
function. And I realized how much
I love the hand raise function
now that we've been using it. So,
um, actually. It was infinite
red. I think that introduced us
to the hand raise function
because one of their founders
wrote a blog post about it, but
it's finding those things like
that and then bringing them to
the community and integrating
them in to make everyone feel
welcome. That that does allow for
everyone to feel welcome. Well,
Andrew, I appreciate you being
here with us today. We're just
about out of time. Are there any
last things that you'd like to
share with our audience or, um,
any words of wisdom?
Andrew: I think I've said a lot.
Um, but I guess the, the, the
closing thought to tie all the
stuff I've said together is I
just want to emphasize how much,
uh, this community, uh, is
valuable. And I, you know, to
those listening, you know, if
you're members of VC or potential
members of VC, You know, there is
more here than an opportunity out
of job, um, or an opportunity,
uh, at growing your technical
skills. Those things are here,
but there's an opportunity to be
yourself. There's an opportunity
to be around people who are like
you. And I think just don't be
afraid to, to join in all the
parts that our community has to
offer and, and, uh, You know,
share yourself. If you get
comfortable with that, it's worth
it.
Dan: I think that's awesome. Uh,
thank you Andrew so much for
coming on. I really appreciate
it.
Andrew: Thank you for having me.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!