Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 5, Episode 7 of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Hey, Bekah. Today, we're
talking with Meg Gutshall. And Meg
is a Ruby on Rails developer,
she has a passion for open-source,
and tech for good. She on the
podcast, talks about community
building, you know, and all the
stuff that she's done with
communities throughout her time,
and what brought her to her
love for Ruby. And, also, if
you know Meg, you might know
that she's from Philly. Is that
came up once or twice in the
podcast [laughs]?
Meg Gutshall: Ninety.
Dan: Oh, yeah. Nine [laughs] -- 98 million times, which was- which
was delightful to -- I- I have a special place in my heart for
Philadelphia. So it was a -- it's
always- it's always good to hear.
Also, Meg is- is another one of
our big volunteers at Virtual
Coffee. Like Andrew last year --
last week. [Chuckles] Sorry. And --
so, she talked what she's
been doing with her
accountabil- accountability
buddies group. Accountabil-
buddies [laughs]. And- and- and
all the work she's done. Making,
you know, making spaces at
Virtual Coffee for everyone.
Bekah: Yeah. We're happy to have
Meg here with us today. And
actually, before we get started
with the podcast, Meg is here for a
special announcement.
Meg: This episode is dedicated to
our friend, Mike Rogers. We miss
you, we love you, and we'll
never forget you.
Bekah: Thanks, Meg. We start
every episode of the podcast
like we start every Virtual
Coffee. We introduce ourselves
with our name, where we're from,
what we do, and a random check-in
question. We hope you enjoy this
episode. Today's question is, what
board game would you play for the
rest of your life, if you could
only play one board game? My name
is Bekah. I am a technical
community builder from a small
town in Ohio. And if I could play
one board game -- I'm not using
the word board game, like kind of
loosely, so, a- a- a table game,
maybe? I really like Splendor.
I- I've been into that. I'm not very
good at it. I lose all the time.
I think I lost to my 12-year-old,
but I like it. So I'll just keep
playing Splendor.
Dan: Splendor's cool. Hi, I'm
Dan. I do development stuff in
Cleveland, Ohio. Yeah, I don't
know. There's a lot of good board
games. Do the rules allow for
expansions, you know, and stuff,
or is it just the base?
Bekah: No, you can only play
the base.
Dan: [Chuckles] Only the base. Okay.
Because that change, you know, that- that
changes things, right?
Bekah: All about that base.
Dan: You know, Catan is really
good. I don't- I don't have to
pick one though. It's tough. I
think I'm gonna go with Dominion
because ... that -- well, there's a lot of
different combinations. Like, e-e-each game
is a little bit different, you know?
So, I don't know, it's a little
different options. So I'm sure there is
... I don't know, the factorial height?
[Laughs] I'm sure there's some way to
calculate how many different, you
know, set up so you could do for
each one, but I'm not gonna do
that right now cuz, you know,
it's- it's late at night
for me [laughs]. So- so, yeah.
That's my answer. Dominion.
Meg: My name's Meg, and I'm from
Philly, the home of Gritty. And I
would play Yahtzee for the rest
of my life.
Dan: Ooh.
Meg: Yahtzee is my jam. I love it.
Bekah: I like Yahtzee.
Meg: Yeah.
Bekah: I lose the dice though. So
then I would be out of luck. I
couldn't play anymore.
Meg: Yeah. But then you can just
ransack your other board games
and find five more dice. It's
pretty ... yeah.
Dan: It's true. Cuz you're not
allowed to play any of the other
ones. So, you know? [Chuckles]
Bekah: No, it's not true. I have a large collection of games.
So they are -- [chuckles] well, welcome Meg. We're happy
to have you here with us today.
We are -- this is like kind of a
special episode because we're
recording in the evening, and we
normally don't do that. So, I
don't know if I need to apologize
for that in advance [laughs], like, my
brain stops working at 3.45, every day.
So --
Meg: Night time edition.
Bekah: Welcome- welcome to the
evening edition. Well, we're gonna
let you get us started with your
origin story. So, how did you
get to this points of your --
Meg: Oh, geez. That's a long --
that's a ... I don't know. That is
kind of a long story, but I'll
compact it. I- I went to
school on to college at
Temple University. That's in
Philadelphia. Once again, home
of Gritty, the mascot for the
Flyers [Dan chuckles]. Dan earlier
said that it was for the Philly.
Dan: Oh, I know -- I knew it was
wrong. As soon as you said it.
Meg: Yeah. Gritty's, the Flyers
mascot. And I studied
Spanish at Temple, and graduated
with a Bachelors of Arts, and
didn't wanna teach. And then I
was like, "Oh, oh, what am I gonna
do?" Translation jobs didn't
come too easily. So I just
kind of wound up doing admin jobs,
and I ... got a job. My first job was
that field hockey coaching and
training facility for girls 18
and under. And, it happened
to be like the number one
facility in the state of PA. And
I just knew nothing about field
hockey. I still don't [chuckles]. But
like I just communicated with the
parents about, you know,
having their kids register in the
leagues and stuff, and set up
tournaments. And I learned so
much just through like running
business. And also, I did some web
development there, just because
it was me, and my boss, and
one other employee. And then
after that, I -- one of the
parents, when I had on-site left,
she asked if I was looking for
another place and -- to work.
And she worked at a IT
recruiting place, and they
were looking for an admin. So
that's how I got into tech. I- I didn't
know really anything about it. And
once again, I [unintelligible] their
website, and I saw, you know, what people
were making, and I was like, "Dang,
that's a lot [chuckles]." And these kids
coming out of college, I was
just like, "Yeah, I'm definitely
smarter than you are [chuckles]. Like, [Dan chuckles] why
am I not doing this? Why am I not trying this?" So, I took
like a Coursera course, and ...
tried it, loved it. The -- it
was like HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
just a very basic web thing. And so,
since I loved it so much, I dove
into it with the freeCodeCamp
bootcamp -- or, no, sorry. Oh
my gosh. Flatiron bootcamp! But
although I do very much recommend
freeCodeCamp — freecodecamp.org
online — and Flatiron bootcamp.
And that's where Bekah and
I met. And, yeah. Just -- that was-
that was a lot of work. Self-paced
online, well, working three
jobs, like part-time. It was- it
was more of like, I dunno for you -- I
don't know how you'd say it. Freelancing?
Cuz I was con- consulting for a
job, and then, I have a tenant,
and I had a pet sitting business for the
time pre-COVID [chuckles]. And, yeah.
That took a while. It was a lot
of work, but it paid off cuz now
I'm with -- I'm a consultant
with Penn medicine and talking to
my manager about getting hired
on full time, hopefully before
the end of June. So --
Dan: That's awesome.
Bekah: Yeah, that's awesome. I think, I-
I'm trying to think of the first time
you and I chatted, but I know
that when you were at Flatiron,
I was always impressed. So it
was like self-paced remote. I
didn't know anybody. I, like,
hardly talked to anyone there
just because it's kind of ... hard
to, like, I dunno, make friends
online when you don't see people.
Like, you can't, like, accidentally
run into them. And-
Meg: Yeah.
Bekah: -you were running a study group there, that met up. And
I was like, always like, wow. I- I honestly -- I thought you
worked at Flatiron because you
were so active in the Slack and
doing all these things. And I was
like, "That's awesome." And then, I
came in, I gave a talk. I think
you invited me to give a talk.
Meg: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: I was going to give a talk
at a conference, and I think you were
like, "Hey, wanna practice here?"
And I just remember it going so
horribly. And I'm like, "This is gonna
be really awful [laughs]." But like, I
appreciate it, kind of being able to
do that in a safe space, like,
where nobody was going to get up and
walk out of the room [chuckles] because
it was so bad. But it, like, helped
me to recognize like where I
really needed to practice and I
needed to work on get- getting through
that talk.
Meg: You- you know, I remember it differently
[chuckles]. But -- yeah. You -- so
you're definitely not the only person who
thought I was an instructor [chuckles].
I would get hit up by a lot of
other students, like asking for
help and stuff. And I- I literally
had to impose a limit for myself
of how much I'd help people per
week. And I would just tell them,
"I reached my weekly limit of
helping people. So, I'm sorry. But
you should ask this person. I
know they're on that section
right now." And the group you
talked about, I started with
another classmate. Her name's
Sherry Martin. And she
came to me with these -- this
idea. We called it co-talk,
cuz she said she talk to someone
about -- at their bootcamp,
they had -- took turns presenting
code, and talking about
it, and using technical terms
talking about it, and how she
thought that was so cool, and like,
helpful. And she wanted someone
to help her start this. And
she, actually, left Flatiron
early for a job. She's just like
woman on a mission, could not
stop her. And so we would do a
technical challenges. I think it
was every week. And then, when
I found people like you, who
actually had something present or
maybe going to a conference, I will
pitch them that, "Hey, do you wanna
practice?" And I don't remember --
your talk ... being, like, good.
And it was like you said of
relaxed, like, ditching it, like,
"Hey, yeah. Just practice here.
We'll record it so you can watch it
back, and see how you did." And I
remember you saying to me, "I realize
that I need to read off a script.
So that's what I did for the actual
conference, and it went so much
better." And I was like super happy
that, like, you practicing in front
of people helped- helped you
figure that out before the big
day [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah, for sure. I mean, so
many people were like, "Oh, no. You
don't read off of -- like, you
shouldn't read off of anything, or
like have notes. Like, you should
be able to do it." I can't do
that. Like, my memory does not
work that way. I have to have
something in front of me. I
distract myself all the time, or I
go off on tangents, or I'll
remember that I meant to say
this thing five minutes ago, and now,
like, "What am I supposed to do? Do I
go back to that point [chuckles]?" But --
so, it was- it was really, really helpful to,
like, have that experience.
Meg: Nice to know.
Bekah: And I- I mean, I feel like you've done lot of that throughout
all of the stuff that you're doing. And the, like, at Virtual
Coffee now, you know, you- you've
come on it -- you have like a
really great knack for knowing
people. I- I love that you said
that you set limits back then. Because
one, I think that's really good, and
really important, because it couldn't be
easy to, like, to help everybody all the
time.
Meg: Oh, my god. Yes [chuckles].
Bekah: And -- but- but, like, you have these
connections too, like you knew, "Okay. I
can't do this, but I can connect you with
other people." And I think that's so great
because you're- you're able to
help so many more people, and like,
hopefully preserve your- your
own self from falling into total
exhaustion by creating boundaries.
But also like showing
that it's okay to have boundaries
with things.
Meg: Mm-hmm. Yeah. I think, like I say
in the beginning with- with all the
work and just like pushing
through, like you said, it's -- it-
it wasn't like ... Flatiron didn't do
a great job of creating a community for
the online self-paced students.
They're just like, "Here's
Slack. Here you go." And, so, I did kind of
what I'm [chuckles] -- I started doing with
the accountability buddies group,
just posting incessantly and
being so annoying that you have
to be my friend and participate.
Like, "Oh, my gosh. Okay, fine.
There -- this person's always
posting. I guess I'll go and see
what it's all about." And then it's
like, "Oh, they're not a crazy
nut job. And there's other people
here. You know, that -- this is pretty
cool," you know? So, yeah. I have to
keep a little bit of my crazy nut job
and check when- when people actually
show up [Bekah chuckles].
It's hard [chuckles].
Dan: Can you- can you tell us a
little bit more about, like, the --
about the accountability group
itself, and- and, you know, what --
sort of what it is, and, you know,
how -- maybe how it started a little
bit.
Meg: Yeah. Okay. So it was Sarah
Strong who put a post on Slack
somewhere, and ... it was just
asking for an accountability partner
when job searching. Because, you
know, it's super fun when you
write cover letters and fill
out applications with like your
address, and you going -- have to
send in your resume ,and then type
in everything that's in the f-
attachment you just sent, like,
that's all really fun. Also
getting rejection letters and all
that stuff. Super fun. So, you
wanna share the fun with other
people, right? I'm being sarcastic, just in case
[Dan chuckles] y'all can't tell [chuckles]. But,
yeah. It's like, I'm sure a lot
of -- gosh, so many people in tech
now, when looking for a job, it's-
it's a slog. Just like going
through all this and getting in
your inbox, like, "Oh, are you
interested in this?" And, like,
another recruiter just shooting
out emails to whoever. And
it's nice to have other people
that identify with that, and to
have just like a block of time
set aside. Okay, I'm going to
work towards my goal of getting a
job and this is what I'm gonna
do. And these other people are
gonna show up and do the same
thing. And so, her and I, and
Aditi ... Green. I'm pretty
sure that's her last name. We
showed up, and it was nice. And I think
we did it two weeks in a row, and
then Sarah couldn't make it. So,
I just kinda kept it going, and
took it over, and she's like, "Oh
no. Yeah, that's great. Like,
definitely do that." And a lot of
people who have joined to our job
seeking accountabilities group
have since left because
they're working during the
meetup time. So-
Bekah: Yeay.
Meg: -yeah, it's pretty awesome. And ... yeah.
Like, people come in, say ... like -- just some
people come in, and they're like, "Ah,
it feels like I've applied for so
many, and it's just so many
rejections," and, you know, it's ... I
feel for them cuz, you know, I've
been there, you- you guys have
been there, like -- I just like,
"Okay. You got this. You- you can keep
going." And I love it when people
just drop in, even if they're not
job seeking. A lot of times,
Brett will drop in from
Australia when he's wrapping up his
day on Friday morning — our Friday
morning, his Friday evening,
I guess.
Bekah: That's late.
Meg: Yeah.
Bekah: What is the --
Meg: It- it's like, his family's in bed,
and he's just like, "Oh, yeah. I'm just,
you know, want to come and say hi, and
keep you company while I do this and --"
Bekah: When you -- so you ran
it through Zoom, and you have
recently been breaking it into
different rooms, right?
Meg: Yeah. Yeah. Because
sometimes we have ... a good amount
of people come out, and, you know,
other -- everyone has their own way of
working. If someone needs it's be a
little quieter, you know, like a
breakout room for quiet
co-working, or you're just in that
flow, but you have the presence
of another person. Like, somehow,
that just makes you feel more
accountable. Having someone there.
And then, since this month we're
doing like, I don't -- like
job-search-type monthly challenge,
I've been adding breakout
rooms for people who want resume
reviews or who are working on
their cover letters. If they
have anything specific, and
got their resume reviewed, say, they
can meet with whoever reviewed it in a
breakout room. And I guess I'll
be adding different one soon.
The elevator pitch room and
portfolio ... stuff room.
Bekah: Yeah. The second half -- well,
that starts today. I- I was off today,
so I keep forgetting it's Monday.
Meg: What [chuckles]? I think
I worked today. Can't be Monday.
Bekah: I mean, my kids are home.
Like, my kids have been home since
last Wednesday. So, all the sense
of time is like, it's- it's
gone. Like [laughs] --
Meg: You're slackers. You need
to be back in school. [Chuckles]
Bekah: Right? I know [chuckles]. I love
it. Having that accountability does
make a huge difference. Because
sometimes it just seems so hard.
Like, you don't wanna do it one
more time, you don't want one more
rejection, you're tired of writing
cover letters. But knowing that
there's somebody else there seems
to make it- it- it feels easier
when you have that accountability.
Meg: Mm-hmm. Yeah. And sometimes, you
need to just vent to other people who
get it, or celebrate with other
people. Like, "Oh my god, I just
got an interview," or, "I just got
this rejection email right now."
And, you know, either when you
gonna get- you gonna get re-
supportive response for either
event, just from Virtual Coffee in
general, but you're in the
accountability buddies session.
Yeah, you can definitely find what
you need there. What are you looking
around there [chuckles]?
Bekah: There- there is like
something -- there's some noise
happening in my room, on the
other side of the room. But we
don't have animals and none of my
children are in here. So, like, my
12-years-old convinced that there's
a ghost in our house because he
heard a splash in his closet one night,
and then there was all this water on
the floor, okay? But it didn't drip
from it, and from anywhere. There
wasn't a glass or anything there.
I, like, literally, I was like, "I
wonder if that was a pregnant mouse,
and its water broke." And then I
was like, "That's too much water
for a pregnant mouse," I think.
Anyway ... so [chuckles] --
Meg: Wait. Your 12-year-old
came up with a pregnant mouse?
Bekah: No, that was me. I came up
with a pregnant mouse. He thought
it was a ghost. So [chuckles] --
Dan: Oh my god [chuckles].
Meg: I thought he thought it was
the ghost of a pregnant mouse.
Bekah: Well, that's even better [Meg chuckles].
But we didn't find any mice babies
either.
Meg: Oh. Yeah. That's -- let's
not touch that one for now.
Bekah: [Laughs] Leave that [??].
Meg: Oh, what if you open the door at
the closet, and Gritty would staring
out at you?
Bekah: That would be super freaky.
Meg: Yeah, right?
Bekah: What if it the ghost of
Gritty, with the ghost of the
pregnant mouse?
Dan: Oh my god [chuckles].
Meg: But Gritty's still alive.
Bekah: Mm.
Meg: He can never die.
Bekah: Well, also, I think the mouse
would probably not be pregnant anymore
if her water broke. So the ghost
of the once pregnant mouse-
Dan: That's [chuckles] --
Bekah: -be held by real-life
Gritty.
Dan: This is- this is going
down real fast [laughs].
Bekah: Told you I'm not responsible [chuckles]
... for my brain at this time of night.
Dan: Oh, man.
Meg: Can I just mention that ... we're
mentioning Gritty ... this is the
8th time. Because it was a
request from Party Tom for this
episode. And Party Tom gets what
Party Tom wants [chuckles].
Dan: That's right.
Bekah: That's right.
Dan: So ... Gritty [all laughs]. We, you know, Meg
-- I- I forget if we said this on the recording
or not, but Meg asked on Slack
for questions, you know, for- for
her -- for- for this- for this
podcast episode. And there was a
lot of good questions, but lot
of them were about Philly cuz
Meg is from Philly. And, you know,
Philly is pretty unique, you
know? I don't know. And- and- and
awesome, but yeah. You know --
Meg: You mean [unintelligible] alone a
great question. You're bouncing [??] --
Dan: I- I have -- and- and, you know,
I -- we've -- Meg and I have talked
about this, but I- I work with
some- some people from Philly. The-
the other side of Sprocket is- is
based in Philly. And so I get a
little bit of Philly culture
just from that. And, one of the
favorite words that I've ever
learned is the word 'jawn'.
And I'm sure I'm not saying it well,
because I'm, you know, from Cleveland-
Meg: No. You got it.
Dan: -and not Philly. But can you- can you
just -- well, I suppose you'll have to
spell it for our listeners, and
then-
Meg: Yes.
Dan: -can- can you just sort of define it, and
then maybe use it in a sentence or two? Just as a-
as a- as a native, you know? I always
try to explain it to people, but I --
it- it feels, you know, it does -- it
feel -- it doesn't feel right, me
talking about it, you know? So [Meg chuckles], can
you- can you -- yeah. Can you -- can -- lay on
some- some Philly knowledge for
us?
Meg: Yes. Jawn is spelled J.A.W.N.
It has nothing to do with sex
work. That's the first thing that people
think of when they hear that word. And --
Dan: Is this [laughs] --
Bekah: Oh, what [laughs]?
Meg: I- I got in that reaction pretty much
every time that word comes up. [Chuckles] So,
jawn is ... just in place of a thing.
It's a thing. It can- it can be used as
like a noun, or adjective, or
adverb ... maybe a verb, I'm not
sure.
Dan: I mean, that's- that's one of
the things I love the most about it-
Bekah: Jawn it.
Dan: - is its utility.
Meg: Yeah.
Dan: So, can you --
Bekah: I still don't understand what it means
though. Like, [laughs] I- I need more than that.
Dan: Can- can --
Meg: It's a thing. Like
something.
Dan: Can you just, like, can you
just use it?
Bekah: You use it in a sentence?
Dan: Yeah-yeah-yeah. To --
Meg: Okay. Like ... okay. For instance,
today Nerando was ragging on Kirk
for his hair being too long and
saying he need a haircut. Someone
from Philly would say, "Yo,
cut that jawn."
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah-yeah. Or a ... alright.
I'm gonna try it out. But you tell
me if it's wrong. It's, you know --
but, like ... alright. So today
I was writing some React, you
know, stuff. And then I needed to
save some states. So I used
that useState jawn.
Meg: Yeah. There you go.
Dan: Is that alright? Yeah. That's
easy. I can do it, see? I- I have a
little Philly -- yeah. As I was saying, I
worked for -- with some [crosstalk] Philly,
so I get a little exposure.
Meg: I mean, you were knighted.
Dan: That's right-
Meg: By the power vested in me
by [unintelligible] --
Dan: -Meg knighted me because I- I translated a
Philly- Philly billboard. I only got one thing
wrong [laughs].
Meg: Yeah, like [unintelligible]
semantic --
Bekah: So it's- it's a placeholder
word.
Dan: Yeah, yeah. It- it's [crosstalk]
a word that you can --
Bekah: It's like, if you don't know -- like
a 'thingamabobber', or 'whatchamacallit'
that can be a jawn.
Meg: Yeah.
Dan: [Chuckles] Right. Right. If
you're not from the 40s [laughs].
Meg: It's a full versioning of 'thingamabobber',
'doodad', 'whatchamacallit', a 'whozitwhatzit' [laughs].
Bekah: Alright, there we go. I
get -- I've got it now. Thank you.
Dan: [Chuckles] That's awesome. Thank
you for that. Thank you for kind of
laying that down for us.
Bekah: So, we have now covered Philly
things. And you are still in Philly-
Meg: Yeah.
Bekah: -and you've talked about other things that
you've done in the past as -- with -- you- you had
an animal ... what business?
[Crosstalk] Why -- you watched animals?
Meg: Oh. Pet feeding [??]
business.
Bekah: Okay.
Meg: Yeah.
Bekah: And you have a Spanish degree. So, how- how these
past experiences play into ... what you're doing now?
Meg: That's a great question.
They make for ... interesting
stories [Bekah chuckles]. That's
one. For Spanish, it does come up in
translation sometimes in, like,
working. And there's a lot of
Spanish speakers in my area.
Bekah: I mentioned to learning a
different language when you're
learning to code it, there's --
it's similar, right? There's
overlap in how you learn and
retain that knowledge.
Meg: Yeah, I- I ... am pretty sure that
I wrote a blog post about ... yeah.
There's -- I've wrote blog post
about, like, learning Spanish, and
learning code, and how that was,
like, similar. It's my "Little Things
Matter" blog posts.
Bekah: Oh, I see it.
Meg: Yeah. So, like, very small things
like, "Hey, I- I forgot a colon or
whatever in coding makes
stuff fail. And in Spanish,
stressing the wrong syllable,
or like, pronouncing, like,
pronunciation --"
Bekah: Did I tell you my story about
Spanish, and sleeping, and married before?
Meg: Yeah. Co- cuz ... oh, I --
Bekah: No, it's tired.
Meg: Yeah, you did. You did tell
me. But I think you should tell it
again.
Bekah: When I was, maybe 19, I went
to language school in Costa Rica by
myself. And then, I had to take a
taxi home, or to the airport. And the
cab driver -- okay. So, though
there's, 'cansado' and 'casado'. One
means tired, right, and one means
married. And so I thought that
he asked me if I was tired, and
I said a little bit. But he was
really asking me if I was married
[Dan chuckles]. And so I told him little
bit. And then he asked me if he could
hold my hand. And then I was afraid he
was going to kill me. So I held his hand
for the [chuckles] 40 minute ride to the
airport. So I- I highly recommend
not telling anybody that you're a
little bit married. Just-
just go- go -- you can be fully
married or fully tired, but don't hold
that hand of a taxi driver in Costa
Rica [laughs].
Dan: Yeah, a little bit seems
like, probably the absolute worst
answer to that question [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. Well, I thought I was
tired, so --
Meg: Can I ask you which one's,
which?
Bekah: I don't remember, Meg
[laughs].
Dan: Lesson learned [chuckles].
Bekah: I'm not gonna use it
at all cost.
Meg: [Laughs] I'm gonna just let you not
know, because I want you to make that
same mistake again.
Bekah: Oh, no [chuckles]. Okay. Sorry.
I've gotten us off on a tangent again.
Oh, oh, okay. I know what I wanted
to ask. So we both went to Flatiron,
it's a full-stack bootcamp, right? And I
know, for me, I really enjoyed learning
Ruby and Rails. And I was like,
"I'm definitely going to be a Rails
developer," which I was not [laughs].
I went to -- somebody hired me. I
don't know why. And then I worked on React
projects [chuckles], which I thought was
never gonna happen. You have stuck with
Ruby [Bekah and Dan laugh]. And how
did- how did that -- how did you ...
stick with it? Did you feel that
way, or did you wanna stick with Ruby, or
were you, like, where I find a job, or, you
know, what- what -- how did
you make that decision?
Meg: I ... I think [silence] [exhales] you never
forget your first ... you know [chuckles]?
Meg: Yeah, I really- I really
fell in love with Ruby. And in
Flatiron, the order that they
taught us — which now is
flip-flopped — they did Ruby
first, and then Sinatra, and
Rails frameworks, and then
JavaScript with React and Redux
frameworks. And I think that I was
able to -- I took a longer time
going through Ruby, Sinatra, and
Rails so it allowed me to get
like a really good appreciation
for the language. And also a
friend of mine from Flatiron,
Heather Miller — she's down in DC —
she invited me to this
conference called Ruby for Good.
And that's when I just started Rails.
Both of us. And it was like the
people there were so nice. It
was, I think three days, everyone
was so nice and friendly. We're
making -- we were working on apps
for social good, to do things
for people. And I knew next to
nothing, but [unintelligible] still like,
"Oh, you can- you can totally help. You can
definitely be, you know, a
contributing member of our team."
And it -- that made me really fall
in love with the Ruby community.
And I found that that's a very ...
universal mindset of the
Ruby community. The people are
very, very nice, and welcoming, and
willing to teach. And similarly,
that's how the Philly tech
community has been in my personal
experience. Before the
pandemic, I was networking a lot
in person, and found a lot of
people very welcoming, and open
like to, you know, a woman in
tech, and someone from like a nontraditional
path. And Philly's definitely a
colorful city, like in different --
in ways of diversity, and
it's blending- it's blending
into the tech community heavily.
And I think ... that makes it
very welcoming. And I saw just
both of those in the Ruby
community and Philly tech
community. The- the issue was,
there- there weren't -- there
wasn't a lot of Ruby on Rails
in Philly at the time. So I was
just like, "Oh, no." So I was
ready to get a job's doing
anything. But then, once the
pandemic happened, like a silver
lining of that, was remote work.
Now the world is my oyster. I
could get a Rails job for anywhere,
just working from my desk at
home. So that definitely-
that definitely helped with my
job search, having like that focus
on Rails jobs. Like, this is
what I love, this is what I wanna
do. And, especially, having
like- like now, I'm on the core
team of Ruby for Good. And I
enjoy -- I really enjoy doing that
and work that's meaningful, and
fulfilling, and that it helps
people. So that was like
something that I really would've --
like, to do as well. And I was targeting
companies like that, that were
Rails companies as well.
Dan: Is the -- so your position with Ruby for Good
is a volunteer ... [crosstalk] position, right?
Meg: Yeah.
Dan: As -- I- I was pretty sure that -- is-
is that -- so, can you talk a little bit more
about, like, what you- what you all
do as an organization? I think you- I
think you talked a little bit
about their conference, but, you
know, can you just kinda explain Ruby
for Good as a, you know, as a- as an
organization and --
Meg: You're saying -- yeah. Ruby for Good
is a nonprofit, and it's volunteer led.
Sean Marcia is the founder, and
it's largely -- it's- it's based
in DC. So the membership is
largely in DC. But definitely
expanding. And basically, it's
uses something called skills-based
volunteering, which is people in
the tech community use their
specialized set of skills like
Liam Neeson. But they do good
things to them [chuckles]. They
build software for other nonprofits,
and, so that might be like a
website, or a sign-up form, or
like an actual software system.
Something that it, like, are
probably -- I think is the oldest
project, and probably the biggest,
is called Human Essentials. It
was rebranded from Diaper Based,
and it had started out as ...
inventory management system for
Diaper Banks, and it- it started
like that. And then, it grew because
they are like, "Okay, this awesome."
Now look at -- the Diaper Banks are
receiving these products, they're
giving the products to their
partners like churches, and food
pantries, and homeless shelters
who then to -- distribute the
products to families. So they
wanted a way to -- for their
partners to track what was
needed and who got stuff. So they
made Partner Base to go along
with Diaper Base. Then it's like,
"Okay. Well, these items aren't
just diapers. They're also
feminine care products, soaps,
creams, like shampoos, things like
that." So, they kind of merged
both of 'em together, and called it
Human Essentials in -- and serving
almost 200 Diaper Banks right
now. But then-
Dan: That's ... really cool.
Meg: -there's also stuff, like, there's a- a lending
library in Chicago, that -- it's a circulation system
for like tools and other types of equipment
for this lending library. And CASA
court appointed advocate --
let me look it up real quicks. I
don't want to --
Dan: A special advocate -- court-
court of- court of special advocate.
Meg: Yeah. Court Appointed
Special Advocate.
Dan: Like, I google from there
[??] [chuckles].
Meg: And that's just a system
to track volunteer time. So it-
it ranges for different needs, and if
-- it feels like it's all open-source
contribution. So people can
get involved with just one
project, do it like one or two
pull requests and be done, or
they can get involved heavily.
And these projects have like
weekly office hours, and
stakeholder meetings, and things.
And ... yeah. It's something that
really spoke to me. And I'm- I'm
a very organized person by
nature since I used to work
as an admin. So I- I told Sean,
I was like, "Yeah. Let me- let
me help out however I can [giggles]." So
he's like, "Yeah, [crosstalk] let's do this.
Come on."
Dan: Yeah, that's awesome. Yeah, I'm sure.
No, that's really great. It- it seems
like really interesting organization. That-
that sort of thing, I always wonder ... so you
make a product for another
nonprofit, right? Does Ruby
for Good end up maintaining that
over time, or- or is it like a
sort of a handoff kind of thing, or ... you
know? This is just of me -- my curiosity.
I've always been curious
about it [chuckles].
Meg: Yeah. I think ... I
think it depends. I want --
Dan: Yeah. I mean, I suppose
-- oh, go ahead.
Meg: There's many where we maintain
it, and there's some that that's
just kind of a one and done
thing. Like some, it's ... I need
something that does A, B and C.
And once it's done, they use it.
They're like, "Oh, can you change
this and that?" "Okay." And then
they're like, "Awesome. Thank you
so much. Now we don't have to go
and buy this stuff." And they can
use their money on other stuff that
they need. And they don't need like
updates, and stuff like that.
Cuz it's not like -- these
other nonprofits are full of
volunteers. Like, they may have
a few employees depending on the
nonprofit, but the goal is to
just spread help to other people,
and especially the organizations
that don't have vast resources.
Dan: Oh, that's- that's cool. And-
and so, they- they do a lot of their
projects, sort of open-source
too, right?
Meg: Yeah. Yep. And [unintelligible] --
Dan: Is it all of them, or is
there -- are there some --
everything? Yeah. That's so cool.
Meg: Yeah. So you can just go on GitHub, and go
in there, and check it out. And [unintelligible] --
Dan: yeah. Anybody who's listening to
this can go or contribute, right? I think
that's so cool. That's such a
cool organization.
Meg: It- it makes stuff like that, like
-- well, I guess we jazzed up about
open-source. Just ... you know how,
when you -- if you toss a rock into
a calm, cool water in the ripples, go
out? It's -- that's how I view open-source.
Like, you can make a change
on some code in that, and
it spreads from there. Whoever
forks that repository gets your
change. Whoever uses the
software gets your change. And
it's spreads however far this
piece of software goes. And you-
you just don't know when you
start. Like, there's that badge
on GitHub, the Mars Rover badge. Like,
so many people contributed to code
that put a robot on Mars, and didn't
know until they got that badge. And
it's ... like, you can say that like,
"Oh yeah, you know, I wrote some
code for the Mars Rover," like, "No big
[exhales]." [Bekah and Dan chuckle] So --
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. I- I was
just talking to someone ... last week,
about HacktoberFest, and that happens in
October [Meg giggles]. But I'm like already
getting super excited for that.
Cuz it's -- I dunno. It's like,
it's great to do as part of
Virtual Coffee and see people
contributing. But, there's-
there are so many good
projects out there that people
can contribute to, and figuring
out ... I don't know. The best way
to put people in touch with them
cuz it can be overwhelming getting
into open-source, but like making
that easily accessible is- is a-
a goal for this year, for sure.
Meg: Yeah. Same. I'm trying to do
that with the Ruby for Good website,
trying to clean it. It's a -- I
have a 3000 line style sheet to
clean up be-before HacktoberFest
kicks off. Also, my HacktoberFest
challenge from last year to
Virtual Coffee went woefully
unanswered.
Bekah: What was your challenge?
Dan: Uh-oh.
Meg: Dan remembers, right?
Dan: I'd [chuckles] -- oh,
I'm blanking now.
Meg: It -- I said for- for every
first time contributor to make a pull
request in October, I would take a shot.
[Dan laughs] And I only took three
shots. The whole month.
Dan: Well, we --
Bekah: Oh, I think maybe we --
you needed to take 70, okay. So-
Dan: Yeah [laughs].
Bekah: -and pace yourself [chuckles].
Dan: Well ... yeah. That- that happened
because it -- I -- we were so burnt
out from HacktoberFest that it
took me like a month and a half to
actually pull together any stats.
And by that time, I had- I had
totally forgotten.
Bekah: Yeah. We should-
Dan: Well, we're just gonna have
to redo it. We'll have- we'll have-
Bekah: -we can fill that in,
this year.
Dan: -to redo this year. Yeah.
We'll- we'll do it, Meg.
A Meg shot counter, you know? We'll-
we'll build [??] it so that we won't- we
won't forget [Dan and Meg chuckle]. I mean, we- we-
we have -- well, I'll have to think of some, you
know, stretch goals and stuff [chuckles].
Because we also don't want, you
know ... well, we don't want you to die
[laughs], like from too many shots. So --
Meg: I'll be fine.
Dan: [Chuckles] I'll be fine.
Meg: I just- I just might forget
some things like how to walk,
or [Bekah and Dan chuckle] ...
you know?
Dan: We'll make sure you're nice and
comfy on your couch first [chuckles].
Meg: Yeah. Exactly.
Bekah: Well, Meg --
Meg: I had- I had a silly origin
story for Kirk, if you had time.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: Of course.
Meg: We talked about forgetting
something. So, in May, there's this
thing called Philly Tech Week.
And this year, it's going
May 6th through May 14th, and
it's hold on by Technical.ly
Philly. A lot of the events are
gonna be virtual, I believe.
I- I think some may be in-person,
but I think a lot will still be
virtual, but this is a annual
thing. I think it's the 12th
year this year. I'm not
positive. But in 2019, I
applied for a scholarship to go
to one of their keynote events
and- and got the scholarship. And
there was just like all day, all
these presentations, and it was at
-- I'm pretty sure it was at the
Comcast Center cuz it's like
one of the big tech hubs in
Philly. A lot of people are reluctant
about that being [chuckles] a big
tech spot in Philly. Gritty was there. Gritty
showed up in-person [Bekah and Dan chuckles].
Yeah. And, yeah. It was really
cool. Got to like network and
meet a whole bunch of people.
And then there was a after party
thing to go out to a bar. And ...
I networked with people at these
tables, and ... I was talking with
this one group, and the people
just seem super nice. I think I put
down my backpack on the table, and
they came to set up, and I was ... I
don't- I don't know. Moving things around
my backpack or something, and
saying, "Oh, sorry. I'll get out
of here." And they're like, "Oh, no,
it's fine," and we just started
chatting. And I found them later
at the happy hour. And it turned
out that, one of their C level
employees was visiting from the
West Coast. And he was buying us all
drinks for happy hour. He's like,
"Hey, do you wanna drink?" cu-cuz
I was just hanging out, talking
with them. And, so I got like
really roped up on this company's
dime [Dan chuckles], and went to the
after parties after party, and they had
this awesome DJ. And that was like the
technically Philly people, we're like, "Now we can
let loose cuz the day's done." And
they're all dancing, and having
fun and stuff. And then I looked
at my clock and it was like
1.30 or something. And the last
train had come and left [chuckles].
Bekah: Oh, no.
Meg: I was just like, "Oh,
no. What did I do [laughs]?"
And it was really warm, so I
just walked around Philly. And
so -- and I was like trying to
make it until the morning when the
train station open cuz I
didn't have-
Dan: [Chuckles] Oh, no.
Meg: -enough money to take an Uber [laughs]. And
there's this guy that -- some guy in a wheelchair
scooter was coming down the street,
yelling at me, [laughs] he's following me.
And I'm just like, "Ah ... [exhales] okay. I guess I'm
gonna have to like take out the credit card, and take
the Uber [laughs]." But it
was a great night.
Bekah: [Bekah and Dan laugh] Oh, that is
awesome. Well, Meg, it's been really great
having you on the podcast,
finally. Before we go, are
there any last fun Philly facts
that you would like to share with
our listeners?
Meg: I would like to say, we have
amazing food. If you're ever in town,
I encourage you go to the
Reading Terminal Market,
basically ... like, weekdays are
best. Because the Mennonite people
are there with like that good
home cook Pennsylvania Dutch
food. And although we
mentioned Gritty definitely more
than eight times at this podcast,
there's also the Philly Phanatic, who is
an amazing mascot. And I- I can't
leave him out either. Yeah.
Those are my fun Philly
facts for all of you.
Bekah: All right. Thanks, Meg.
Dan: [Chuckles] Awesome. Thanks,
Meg.
Meg: Thank you.
Dan: Thank you for coming out. Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel. If you
have questions or comments, you
can hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast,
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week.