Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 5, Episode 8
of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're
here, on this podcast, sharing
their stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Hello, Bekah.
Bekah: Hey, Dan.
Dan: Today, we had [chuckles] a
really- a really fun episode. We
sat down with Matt McInnis. He
is a ... I don't know. A data
scientist, a full-stack
engineer, a founder, used to be
a math
professor. He- he had a real--
he has had a very interesting
journey and a very interesting
career. So it was very cool to
hear his-- can I just say very a
couple more times [laughs]?
I'm
excited though. It- it was- it
was- it was a fun time to sit
down
with Matt-- I don't know. He's
had a cool career-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -and so many at different
things he's, like, gotten-
gotten into. And he's
built a lot of different things,
and-- yeah. It was fun-- it was
a fun
conversation.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. I mean, his
journey is super interesting,
going from math professor to
working at some really big tech
places. And talking about how he
got those jobs by building
things
that were useful to him, I felt
like was super inspiring to
anybody who's trying to break
into tech. But just to see how
he developed his career and
followed his interest is really
... I don't know-- inspiring, I
guess.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And it-
it hit home for me a lot. It's-
it's
one of those things that I- I
never did consciously, and I
don't think Matt did really
either. He- he was-- he would
build things that would help
him, you know, help himself. So
he talked about what he built,
something that was, like,
helping to buy tickets or sell
tickets. And-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -it wasn't, like, a scheme
to make money or a scheme to get
a job [chuckles], you know? It
was just a
thing that helped him-- his- his
own, like, life, you know?
He wasn't trying to sell the
product or do any of the things
that
you hear about these days a lot.
He just was, like, interested
in built something. And then,
some people heard about it. And,
well, you'll hear about the rest
[laughs]. But it was cool.
Bekah: [Chuckles] Yeah.
Dan: It hit home for me. I- I--
that's-- building projects is
just, like-- that's- that's--
my-- that's always my
advice to people, too, is- is-
is just build things that you're
either interested in or could
help yourself. And the rest
will come sort of naturally. So,
it was- it was cool. It was--
we--
I had a good time talking to
him.
Bekah: Yeah. It was fascinating
episode. And we hope that you
enjoy it. And we're going to
start it the same way that we
start
every Virtual Coffee, with our
names, where we're from, what we
do, and our random check-in
question. So, enjoy. Today's
random check-in question is, if
you could appear on any game
show, what would it be? I'm
Bekah. I am a technical
community
builder from a small town in
Ohio. And game show ... I don't
know. If there
was a "Sudoku" game show, I
would like to try that
[chuckles]. I don't think
that's a thing. So, I guess,
I'll go on "Wheel of Fortune"-
Dan: Peep- pretty--
Bekah: -or-- I don't know.
"Price Is Right". I feel like
I'm-- as
an adult, I've
gotten better at that. Like
[chuckles], "Oh, I know the
price of that." But ...
I don't know. I think I'll stick
with "Wheel of Fortune".
Dan: "Wheel of Fortune". Well,
it seemed like a fun- a fun
time, you know?
Bekah: It doesn't seem so
stressful.
Dan: I- I feel like- I feel like
a "Sudoku" game show would be
pretty boring to watch
[chuckles], but before
they compete it- before they
compete it. But because, well, I
can tell--
Bekah: I mean, like, some kind
of obstacles they threw in,
right?
Dan: Ooh.
Bekah: Like, what you fill in
one row, then something
happened, and you get
slimed. Like [Bekah and Matt
laugh]--
Dan: Slimed [chuckles].
Bekah: Did you ever watch
"Double Dare" [chuckles]?
Dan: Oh, man. Okay. So, hi. I'm
Dan. I do front-end
development—mostly—and live in
Cleveland, and ... oh, yeah,
yeah. Game show "American
Gladiators" is the first thing
that popped into my head.
Bekah: Ooh. I did [crosstalk]--
that's what I'm doing [laughs].
Matt McInnis: Oh, how are you
doing, sir?
Dan: [Laughs] I- I always wanted
to do-- especially the one--
the-- like,
thing I feel like they ended
with it. But the- the watery
run around, shooting the-- like,
the Nerf guns at the, you know,
and
the-- like, the- the gladiator
person is up on the top shooting
Nerf gun
stuff at your tennis [??] balls.
I- I don't really know. I
haven't
watched it, obviously, in a long
time, but [laughs]--
Bekah: "American Ninja Warrior",
too. I forgot. Ugh.
Dan: "American Ninja Warrior" is
cool. It-- that seems a lot
harder though. But it
would be cool to try. I would
definitely try that for sure.
Matt: But would you be a
contestant or one of the
gladiators, if you're in the
show?
Dan: Well, I mean, now I'd have
to start- I'd have to start as a
contestant, you know?
Matt: Yeah. [Unintelligible].
Dan: I- I can't-- I'm not gonna
just, like, swoop in and-- you
know? I gotta- I gotta earn my-
earn my way up,
right? [Dan and Matt laugh] But
yeah, I feel- I feel like--
plus it get the-- well, did
the contestants have the ...
what do you call them? Like a
... not a
jumpsuit, but the ... we called
these things that-- they were--
or, like, that wrestlers or
anything?
Matt: Yeah, I think it's a suit.
I think it's a jumpsuit.
Dan: No, no, no.
Matt: No, there's a name for it,
isn't that [laughs]? What's the
thing? We make it--
Dan: We need Nick here
[chuckles]. What's the thing
that like
wrestlers wear, like- like--
Bekah: A singlet?
Dan: Nah-- yes, singlet maybe? I
don't know.
Matt: I think there's another
word for it, but it's- it's not
leotards, is it? No.
Dan: No. I mean, it's basically
leotard, but it's like singlet.
Bekah: It was a singlet. Singlet
is what you're wearing at
wrestling.
Dan: I don't know [chuckles]. I
don't know. That doesn't sound
right, but you're
probably right [Bekah and Matt
laugh]. We- we'll ask Nick
after- after the- after the
podcast [laugh].
Matt: Yeah. I-- good to be here,
guys. Thank you for having
me. I'm Matt. I'm a developer
from Toronto, Canada. I run a
small company called Typist
where we make educational
software. And
if I was on one game show, my
first, like—you know, "American
Gladiator" wins—but my first
reaction was "Kids Street". It's
this old game show. I don't know
if I-- like, if I was 12 years
old again,
I think it-- you know-- and
everyone kind of clapped over
their head, like, there is this,
like, thing that they did if
they
got a question, right? And if
you won, it was, like, every
kid's dream. You got to
go into, like, this middle
platform. There was like stock,
like a toy
store? And you had, like, two
minutes to just grab-
Dan: Oh, man.
Matt: -whatever you wanted.
Bekah: Ooh.
Matt: It was, like-- yeah. So my
sisters and I, we would watch
"Kids Street" and we be like,
"How do we get on this TV show?"
And we
never quite cracked the egg on
that one. It was very- very
disappointing childhood, I
guess, you could say [laughs].
Yeah. I'm kidding. But
it's a-- yeah, kid's dream. But,
you know-- I, you know, also
second Dan's answer
cuz that sounds awesome.
Bekah: Wow. I have never seen
"Kids Street" before.
Matt: Like-- yeah, there's this
funny kind of Canadian, you
know, from
Canada. This is funny Canadian
subculture around some
things. Like, there are these
really kind of weird things that
pop up every now and then that
are extremely popular. Like,
"Household", everybody knows
them. Even, like, music and
bands
sometimes. They were fueled by
this entertainment industry
that, like, out of Toronto. But,
like, these companies called
MuchMusic,
and they're related
subsidiaries, but are just
totally unknown in the US. And
it-- which is funny because the
US is just a two-hour drive from
where I'm living. Like, it
close, right? Like,
we're- we're right there. We- we
go to Buffalo Bills games all
the time.
It's across this, you know, it
feels like it's across the
street. But you go down there,
and they're like, "Oh, they
tragically
hip." And it, like, every--
like, you know, half of Canada
is all-time
favorite band, and people in the
US are like, "Who?" Like,
"Who
is that," you know? It's--
there's these things. So "Kids
Street" might
be one of them too. And, you
know, all these, like, kinda old
TV shows for kids, especially.
Bekah: Yeah, I need to check it
out. I- I, like, pulled up the--
oh, it is a
Canadian's children's game show.
So--
Matt: It is Canadian. I-- ah,
you guys missed out. This was
epic. Like [Bekah laughs]-- and
it would
have been-- it would have,
like-- it would've been way
better if the US had done it
[laughs].
Like, the mall would have been
cooler. Like, it would have just
been-- like- like, production
quality would
have been way up there. Like,
where's Nickelodeon at when-
Bekah: Yeah.
Matt: -for "Kids Street"
[laughs].
Bekah: I love it. It looks very
80s. I need to check this
out [chuckles].
Matt: Yeah, it was cool
[chuckles].
Bekah: Well, thanks so much for
being here with us today, Matt.
We always like to get started
with your origin stories. So, if
you could give us what the story
is that brought you here to
today, where you are in tech.
Matt: Yeah, thanks. Thank you
for having me, Dan and Bekah.
Yeah. You know, I-I guess
it-it-- like, starting--
focusing on
the tech side of
things, I, you know, graduated--
I did degrees in math. I love
math. I think it's still my
Twitter handle [chuckles]. I--
and I-- and, you
know, I went-- I decided that,
like, the change I wanna make in
the world after graduating was I
wanted to improve the way that
people learn mathematics at the
post-secondary level. I- I just,
you
know, my-- their programs that I
took were massacres. We had
such few people
finish relative to how many
started. And, you know, I worked
all the way through university,
and math help centers, and as a
TA, and I saw people in non-math
disciplines kinda drop out of
their, like, early childhood
education program because they
couldn't complete their stats
course. And I thought that was
crazy.
Because if it's taught properly,
I don't think math is hard,
you know? Put that strong
caveat, if it's taught properly.
And so, I
really wanted to kind of affect
change there. I took a job. I
applied everywhere for these--
in Canada, we call them 'math
professorships' at community
colleges in Canada. In US,
it's probably known as a 'math
instructor' at the community--
in the community college system.
And so, I took a job in
Saskatchewan. I moved from the
small town of Aurora,
Ontario—where
I grew up—to Prince Albert,
Saskatchewan, which is 40,000
person town, like, in the-- you
know, it- it was really awesome.
I loved it out there, and I had
some family there too. And
that's
where, you know, I- I guess my
journey to tech started. I--
you know, I was a math person. I
really had no experience with
tech at that point. I was, you
know, 24 ... 23, 24. And
I- I just started wanting to
make things. I remember the
first
thing I wanted to make was I had
read, you know, a book that's
now very
popular, Malcolm Gladwell's
"[The] Tipping Point". And he
described,
like, "Sesame Street" in the
80s, and how they would, like,
engineer this TV show. They
would bring kids in, and they
would put
"Sesame Street" on one screen,
and this thing called the
distractor
on the other screen. And every
seven seconds, this
distractor would display these
still images that would switch.
So, every seven seconds, a
different image. And you'd put,
like, 20 kids in the room, and
the researchers would just look
at
their eyes and be like, "Are
they looking at the distractor?
Are
they looking at "Sesame
Street"?" And then, they would
go back and
they'd graph it after they'd
done, like, a couple of cycles
of
kids. And they'd see what are
the parts of the TV show that
kids
were disengaged with, that we
need to re-engineer? And that
was-- like, the
first that I was like, "Man, if
they could do that in the 80s,
why can't, like, in ..." you
know, this was, I guess, like,
2010. I'm like, "Why can't we do
that, like, in real time, live,
while I'm teaching in class?"
And that was-- my first project
was I
wanted to build something that
did that. And I had learned that
Hasbro had put out this toy
called the hi- like, the Star
Wars force trainer, where
everything was ridiculous
[chuckles]. So I-- we'd have,
like,
a headset that you'd put on. And
it turns out this thing could
actually take a-- like, a low
level EEG reading of brain
activity, like, if
your brain was active or not.
And then, like, the toy would
connect
wirelessly to this base unit
that had a fan, that would spin
a ball
up and down in this toy. And so,
it, like—hence the force
trainer—is you concentrate
really hard, and you can use the
force to move this ball up and
down [laughs]. Like, really cool
toy, right? And I
said, "Well, if I could just get
the electrical signal out of
that into my computer and graph
it, that would be the whole
thing." And that was my first
foray into tech, was-- I, like,
started-- I was like, "Okay.
Well, how do I get the
electrical
signal out? And how does- how
does electricity work? And how
does circuits work?" And, you
know, I learned about
microprocessors, and the Arduino
had to-- like, just come out at
the time. And so, I started,
like, getting these, like--
yeah, I found that
kids' books for Arduino are
actually way better than the
ones they are
making for adults. So that-- I
got all these, like, kids'
books and
started, like, doing these
experiments. And then I- I
needed, you
know, these wires solder. So I'd
go down to the electrical
department and be like, "Hey,
guy. I was teaching, like, math
for
electricians as part of my job
there." They're like, "Hey, can
you do some
soldering for me? And, like, put
these--" And it, you know,
at this
point, it would, like-- kind of
become this, like, project, and
I gotta
working after-- you know, on the
code side. I learned that
there's this language called
Processing, which was Java based
that could do the graphing
pretty easily for me if I could
just
pull the signal in. And I got
that working. And then I, you
know, like, six
months later, presented it at a
conference down in Saskatoon—one
of the cities in Saskatchewan.
And at that point, I was hooked.
And,
you know, from there, I- I
just-- I really wanted to
continue making
things that would make me a
better teacher. And that drove
me
for a long time. And then, you
know, a-a couple of years after
that, I- I started doing
reflection of what do I want in
terms of a
career, and a lifestyle, and,
like, what are the things I'm
after?
And that really kind of led me
to getting interested in, you
know, code
as a career. And there weren't
really, you know,
bootcamps and Coursera. I don't
even think they had been really
created at that point, or
launched, or, you know, the
whole suite of
the EdEx, Udemy, Coursera,
awesome websites for these
things, right? So it was a lot
of learning. It was-- I-- you
know, I did that all while I had
a full-time job. And, you know,
fast forward a-a number of
years, I launched Typist—the
company I
now have run—I made a little
small passion project that I
sometimes call
it. At the same time, I-- AI
exploded. And this was maybe
six or-- a six-ish-- six, seven
years ago now. At AI, if
nothing else,
is a combination of computer
science, and it's, like, a
really strong
math background. And, you know,
back then, more emphasis on
the math. But today, maybe more
emphasis on the computer science
side. And- and so, I-IBM came
knocking and said, "Hey, we are
trying to
hire AI expertise." And I-- and
at that point, I had some
projects that, like-- I was
experimenting a lot in AI. And
so,
they brought me into-- they
offered me, like, dream job to
go in and be on this new open
source team that they're putting
across
Canada. And I'd get to work with
all their-- these huge
companies, and help
them do AI better, and solve
these problems. And that sounded
like a
blast. So I did that for a
number of years. And then later,
I
moved over to Microsoft to do a
similar type work, like, more-
more hands. I wanted to get
deeper into projects, and
Microsoft gave me that
opportunity to go deeper into
data
science projects with, you know,
companies. And all for
free. Like, these companies
would just parachute me in. Or
IBM would just--
Microsoft would just parachute
me in, and it's like, "Yeah.
We-- we're
gonna help you do data science
better because if you do it on
our cloud, we're gonna make a
lot of money." So, I'd get to
go, and just,
like, pick my projects, and go
onsite—I get, like, a badge. It
was awesome—and-- you know, and
build out these data science
projects, and all the while, on
my evenings and weekends,
building
out Typist, trying to get it to
the place where it could
support,
you know, a basic income for me,
and I could work on it
full-time,
which eventually happened. And-
and, you know, that sort of
switch over process was scary
and, you know, different than
I'm-- had
imagined it would be. But
eventually, my boss at Microsoft
was like, "Matt, you gotta go do
this. You- you-- it's there."
Like, "Go do this
thing." And- and I- and I did.
And I-- and that's what I've
been working on for the last
three or four years.
Bekah: That's- that's amazing. I
have to ask about that switch.
Cuz I
feel like that sounds like
s-s-s-- very scary [chuckles].
Like, giving up all of the
stuff that you've been doing
with a team, with all of these
resources, and then just jumping
into this entrepreneur journey.
I- I know
that you said that you had some
encouragement but, like, what
really pushed you to go all in
on Typist?
Matt: Ah, you know, it was-- it-
it was really, really hard.
You know, I- I- I guess, like,
one of the big factors was I
thought
that we- we had a project lined
up for Typist. And- and Typist--
maybe this is the appropriate
time to kinda speak to what it
is. We make software for
community college students who
are taking a certain set of
courses. So, our- our first
product was
for community college students
who are taking keyboarding
courses. And
those are people studying
programs to be law clerks, or
legal assistance, medical
assistance, or even executive
assistants. And very-- and, you
know, there's interesting
demographics
in those programs, such as-- a
reason I'm really passionate to
work on and honored to build
software for that group. And
then we have this second
product, which at that point,
Bekah, was--
I was really-- we had scoped it
out. And it was the-- and this
thing called
'document production'. So, you
know, people that go in these
fields need to be able to make a
professionally formatted
business
letter that has these exact
traits and the-- it's sort of a
vocational skill. And in that
particular field, it's rated as,
like, a top three employment
skill to-- by all every
industry
survey that's ever been done.
And it's really, really hard to
teach. And I-- we had-- one of
the colle- I've been, like,
kinda kicking the tires with the
people who are using our
keyboarding
software, and be like, "Hey,
does anyone wanna partner to
build this with us?
And by partner, just, like, give
us feedback, tell us- tell us
what
to build, like whiteboard. And-
and ideally, if we build you
something
that you really liked, be the,
you know, the person to use it
and give us
the reference so that we can
maybe expand this." And I-- and
that was a big part of the
decision was I had all that
lined
up. And so, for the six to seven
months prior to that—and
this was the final push—I had
outsourced the development of it
to a really great developer
who-- it-- like, grades-- you
know,
really, really talented Rails
developer. And we had a
prototype. And we went back to
this college and presented this.
And I'd take vacation days
anytime I had to go take
meetings, right? So, all of my
vacation for those, like, four
years was
consumed by Typist. And so, I'd
take a vacation day. I'd go,
and we'd present this back to
the group. And they had said,
"Yes. If
you can build it, and it can do
these things, but we need these
changes, you know, we'll use
it." But at that point, I looked
with-- like- like, how we had
constructed the software. And I
said, "It's not
gonna get us to the finish
line." We were, you know--
specifically, we'd
built it in Rails, and it--
like, it all works with file IO.
So, either you
need to upload this file, and
then we would go compare it to
this
other file. And they're both
Word documents, which are
incredibly hard to work with.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Matt: And we, like-- you know,
the- the way all the existing
previous software, like, if
there's a typo in a paragraph,
you lost all the marks of the
paragraph because doing fuzzy
matching is, like, really,
really hard. And we just-- I- I
sat
there
and I'm like, "We can't do this
in our web server. This-- it
takes, like, 20
seconds to process a single
file. We'll be in classes,
they'll do a test,
they'll get 30 uploads at once.
We'll never be able to handle
the spike in
traffic, we'll never be able
to-- we- we don't wanna web
server
sitting idle for it." And I
just—long story short—knew, and
I-- we had to
rebuild the software completely
from scratch. And we had five
months to do it. We had gone in
and already produced, like-- we
already done the demo and been
like, "Yeah, it's working.
Look."
And I knew that we had to throw
away everything that we'd done,
and build it from scratch, and--
which we did. So, that was,
like, the imme- there's an
immediacy which helped, I guess,
make that decision
of, like, I'd-- like-- so, when
I went in and had that
conversation with
my wonderful, wonderful boss, I
was scay [??], and I was
explaining
this all to her. She's like--
I'm- I'm like-- I was scay
[??], I've like, "If
we're gonna launch this thing
and this could push Typist over
the mark of, like, it could
support a couple employees,
I've got to go now. Like, I- I-
I can't wait till next week.
I've- I've got to
start, right now." And she's
like, "Yep, do it." And at that
point, I ... like, almost on the
spot gave my notice. I talked to
my
wife and- and that was the jump.
And it was a hard summer, by the
way [chuckles]. It was tough.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, I mean, that's
pretty intense. [Chuckles] I
mean, obviously I don't [Dan and
Matt chuckle] ...
but it seems like it worked out,
right? I mean, kinda betting
on yourself and-- I mean, it-
Matt: Yeah.
Dan: -might be wasn't much of a
bet. Have you-- did you have a
good idea of-- so, you said you
had to, you know, tear it down
and- and rebuild
it. Did you have a good idea at
that, like, moment of, like,
what it was
gonna look like when you were
finished rebuilding it or were
you just like, "We have," like,
"are-- start from scratch, and I
have no idea," you know?
Matt: Yeah. We- we knew that,
and- and I did. And maybe, you
know, I-- and
I'm happy to speak to the--
kinda the details of it, because
I think they're interesting if
that's-- you know?
Bekah: Yeah, sure.
Dan: Yeah.
Matt: So, like, we-- you know, I
mentioned we couldn't do this on
web servers. Because, like, you
know, the really simple use case
was that if 20 students are
doing
a test, and they all upload
their documents at once, and
they take
25 seconds to process, web
servers just can't do that. We
would have
to have, like, this incredible
scale that would just be so
expensive, we couldn't run the
business. And so, the-- my-
my theory was that we needed a
couple of things. We needed to
not be
using Ruby because, like, a- a
Node based system made a lot
more
sense in the way that a Node
event loop works, you know? And-
and the second thing was we
needed a way to deploy these
sort of algorithms that we were
building in a way that can
handle
these spikes in traffic, and at
that point, sort of lamb- this
Lambda architecture. Which is,
you know, all the clouds have a
product for this. So, in
Microsoft is called Azure
functions, in AWS
is called Lambda, in-- you can
have-- net- Netlify just
launched one, I
think, actually, and Cloudflare
has one called Cloudflare
functions too. But they
basically work that, like,
something happens,
and these-- they spin up your
code, and they do the thing you
want it to do, and
then they spin down, and you can
throw a thousand at them. And
they, you know, a thousand
instances will spit up, you'll
pay for the time they're up, and
then, they'll turn off, and
you're done. And so,
that was kind of what I knew was
that we had to rewrite this into
that--
this Lambda type architecture
that could handle these spikes.
We had to use-- we had to switch
languages. So, we had to
use a
language that was compatible
there in-- while supported, and
Ruby
wasn't supported at all. So that
had to go to JavaScript. And
then
there was, you know—to your
question, Dan—there- there were
questions that I was really,
really concerned about, which
were, "how
are we going to go in and, like,
that problem on evaluation?" So,
if
you're a student, you upload
this document, and you're off
by, like,
two characters, we couldn't take
off all of the marks, right? So
we had to be able to go in and
compare the texts. We expected
students to type in the text
that they did type, and take off
some of-- like, of-- like,
type of marks of as proportions
to do that, and give meaningful
feedback on the other side. And
at that point, I had no idea how
we're gonna solve that problem.
Yeah, which we, you know, later
figured out a way to. And even
just converting, like, how do we
even-- so, you know—just as a
quick comment—DOCX files are
really
hard to work with, but here's,
like, a fun thing you can do.
If you're on a Windows machine,
take a DOCX file to your
desktop, rename
it to '.zip'. And then, extract
it, and you'll see the general
how these struck-
files are structured. In-
inside, there is all this kind
of markup
that will be a little bit
familiar to you if you've seen
XML or HTML before. And you can
see all the stuff in there.
So we knew that we had to, like,
deal with that problem too,
which
we didn't know how we were gonna
handle because we were using
these Ruby libraries that kind
of abstracted that away for us.
Bekah: Mm. Yeah. So you made
this career journey, I guess.
So, from
math, and then you were doing
AI, data science stuff, and then
Rails back-end stuff, and- and
now JavaScript and React, right?
Matt: Yeah. And- and, you know,
I think the first part of that
would be like it's worth
expanding on, like, it was--
like, when I started learning
code, it, like-- I-- you know,
data science is generally on in
Python and R. Like, those are
the
language for data science, and
heavy emphasis on Python these
days. Like, academic, C's are.
But nobody else really does.
And so the-- like, I really
didn't know a ton of Python, but
it's
such an approachable language. I
really-- that-- like, that seven
years of learning code, like,
you know, I- I breezed past it
in a
sentence, but that was really
hard. It was a lot of evenings
and weekends. I was working full
time that whole time. I, at some
points, had, like, even taking
on contract gigs, doing
statistical
consulting for some stuff. And-
and it was webdev that I was
learning during that time,
Bekah. And it was, you know, I
had started the-- with a-- like
[chuckles], you know, I started
with HTML, and
CSS, and had-- like, learned
that, and built a personal
website. And
it was, like, you know, these
projects, all the way through,
like, I wanted-- like, at the
time people were downloading TV
shows,
and movies, and stuff, maybe
[chuckles], you know, maybe they
shouldn't. But it
was, like, really hard. So,
like, if I wanted to go-- if I
download the new season
of "The Office", I wanted to
search "The Office", and have it
organized,
like, Episode 1, Episode 2,
Episode 3, and then get rid of
the ones that were,
like, somebody holding their
camera, and do others, so does
a website
to do that. And it was, like, so
basic. It was a single PHP file
that just went and, like, kind
of scraped the Pirate Bay, and
then
analyze the file names. And
then, I- I had no idea how to
use databases, so it would just
stick the results [chuckles]
into, like, a text
file [laughs]. I'm like, "Go,
daddy." So it was-- like,
that's where I was starting
from. And-
Dan: That's awesome.
Matt: -it was-- so, there's--
like, there's that. There were
... oh-- like, oh my god.
There's so many other. Like,
another one that was fun was
when I was teaching at the
college, you'd put all your
marks into, like, an Excel doc.
So I was like,
"Okay. Well, I want, like, to
give my students more contextual
feedback
on how they're doing in the
course." So I put it into a
Google
doc, and I was like, "How do I
get this thing to send email?"
And
then, that was, like-- one of
the first things I had written
in
JavaScript was to, like, go take
all my students. And if they're,
like-- if they've not done well
on the first two quizzes, send
them
an email that's like, "Hey, you
know, John. I- I saw you didn't
do very well in the first few
quizzes. Here are my office
hours. There's also the math
help center if you need support.
I'm
here for you," like, you know,
like, "really wanna help you
turn
this around [chuckles]." And
then, if they were doing really
well, they'd get,
like, a more positive note with
different content. And there
were-- I had, like,
six different templates. And
then, I would just hit go, and
then
everybody would get an email
from me, and, like, my five
[unintelligible] sections or
whatever. I [laughs]--
Bekah: [Laughs] I- I- I need
that 10 years ago. That would
save me so much
time. Wow. That's amazing.
Matt: It's great. But, like, the
part that I felt guilty about,
Bekah, it was I'd get
these responses, and be like,
"Wow. You-- thank you for
taking the time to
write me this email." [All
laughs] Yeah. You know- you
know? I-- it was-- but they
were, like--
Bekah: I thought that's a--
wait. Is that not a product for
teachers? Because if it's not,
it totally should be.
Matt: It should be.
Dan: Was it just, like-- that's
like-
Matt: Yeah.
Dan: -a CRM, right? A CRM—except
for students—is, like,
you have
all the automated- automated
mail campaigns and stuff, you
know [laughs]?
Except, you're-- except, you're
emailing students. It's amazing.
Bekah: Yes. Yeah. Okay. But
this-- I [Matt laughs] need to
Google this after we're done.
Because-
Dan: It has to exist.
Bekah: -if- if it is a thing, I
need to tell everybody that I
know—that still a teacher—about
it. And if not, then
that's my new project
[chuckles].
Matt: Yeah. It's-- you know--
so, that was, like-- there were
these
projects on the way, right? And
they were all usually connected
to something I wanted to see in
the world. Like-- and another
really big one I took on, that
was, like, less code, but it
was, you know,
it was-- my first experience
with Rails was, you know, we
had-- I was teaching at the
college, and I was helping to
volunteer
coach this marketing team, which
I don't know what I was
doing there. I was, like, the
math guy, right? And I-- but I
wanted to get my students more
experiencing the actual-- like,
the part of marketing that
really is interesting to me is
the
analytics of it. There's really
rich analytics and the math is
just super fun to look at. But
there is-- like, Google
Analytics
was out there at the time. But
it was really hard to get
experience
with actual data. So I thought,
"Well, what if we could get,
like, a
website up that would, you know,
have a bunch of data that
students could just mess around
with? And we could, like, do
stuff.
We could go put posters up and
drive traffic." And- and then--
like, I was also really
interested in—and still am—in
volunteerism. And I said, "You
know, I've had these great,
wonderful, like, life-changing
experience volunteering. Like,
you know, what if we could drive
more volunteers to charities?"
And, you know, I was also really
attracted to short video format.
So, I sorta took the summer off
and I emailed the-- sort of
CEOs of
charities in Toronto, and said,
"Hey, I- I went on, you know,
Facebook and
Craigslist trying to find a
videographer who involved here
with me." And I did. And we
went-- my- my pitch was like,
"Hey, we're gonna take your CEO.
We're gonna go onsite where
volunteerism is happening. We're
gonna shoot, like, a 45 second
to one minute video of you
telling volunteers why it would
be so great to volunteer with
your-- their-- your
organization." And we did that.
And we did, like, five of the
biggest charities in Toronto.
And we put them on a website I
call [chuckles]-- that I called
'Where The Good Is'. And
then we took the marketing ever
since. We promoted it around the
college, and then, like, we'd
Google in with [unintelligible],
that they would,
like, drive the traffic to the
website, we got to analyze it
all. And it was really fun. And
that was, like, my first website
in
Rails. It was a static web page
with just a bunch of videos, but
it was a great way to learn.
And- and- and there's probably,
like, a million
other projects that a little,
you know, similar. But those--
that's what I was learning. That
seven years was-- I was really
getting into web development. I
loved it. I loved making things.
And the more relevant they were
for me, the better. And, you
know, my last one, which was,
like,
a full Rails app—that was just a
static page, right?—was this--
I wanted a Chrome extension. So,
my wife, my-- who was my
girlfriend
at the time, we could just hit a
button in Chrome, and we could
share the webpage that we're
looking at with, like, a little
note. And it would just, like,
jumped to the other person's
browser. And so, I built a
little app that did that. And
that was, like,
the first, you know, full ...
like, real, meaningful, like,
web app, you
know? Like, they did stuff on
the back end and use the
database. And- and, you
know, during that time also,
courses started coming out. So
I took wonderful database course
from Stanford, and then, the
University of Washington has
amazing courses. And- and
that allowed me to kinda get to
the bottom of how these things
worked, which I was incredibly
curious about. Like, the
hardware/software interface
course from the University of
Washington is just straight up
one of the best courses I've
ever taken.
Like-- it's, like, how it--
like, it tackles the problem
of--
like, how does the code you type
in Python change things in a
computer and how does the
computer work it all? And that
was, like, the missing gap that
I needed to kind of address. And
that was a wonderful experience.
And- and yeah, that's what--
like, that seven years was like.
And- and then, towards the end
of it, the- the project that I
made—that kind of got the
attention of IBM—was,
I had, like-- had-- this is
[chuckles]- this is-- am I-
am I rambling here? I feel like
I'm talking about--
Bekah: No. This is great.
Dan: No.
Matt: The hat-- I-- the ever big
baseball fan, I've got my
little
Blue Jays hat in the background
on- on the yellow shirt behind
me.
And- and we love going to the
Home Opener—which is the first
baseball
game of the year. And I had
gone, and we buy tickets, but
they always
sell out. So you have to buy
resale. And resales, like, three
times the price. And we paid--
that one year, we paid, like,
$110—which was outrageous at the
time—to sit in, like, $20
seats at, like,
the top of the stadium. And I
was so upset by this, you know?
I was. Really. And then, you
know, one of my friends can
come. So I
had to-- like, I tried to scalp
the ticket. So, I was, like,
outside the
stadium [Bekah giggles] instead
of like-- and I, like, had, you
know, a couple of
bottles of juice to give myself
the courage to do it [Matt and
Dan laugh]. And- and so, I'm-
I'm
standing outside the stadium
with my best cover, and I was
like, "Tickets?
[Bekah laughs] Do you guys need
tickets?" And I remember,
there's this-- I'd-- like, of
all-- there's 50,000
people there—of course—like, a
friend walks by, and he's like,
"What in the hell are you
doing?" and-- "What in the heck
you do?" And then, I'll--
there-- I never forget this mom
and her daughter. The
daughter must've been, like, 17,
18 years old, right? And
they're- they're walking
by, and I'm out there just,
"Tickets?" [Bekah chuckles] And,
"You need a ticket?" And she's
so
politely says, "No, thank you."
Everyone just ignores it, and
she just, "No, thank you." And
she looks at me, and then
looks down at my shirt, and I've
got my University Western shirt
on [Bekah chuckles], and she
doesn't-- like, her face just
drops. And she looks at
her daughter who's, like, also
got a Western shirt- [Matt and
Bekah laugh] shirt on. It just
had this,
like, sad look of horror as they
walk into this thing, you
know? Like, "This
is what my daughter is gonna
be." I've-- but anyways, that
whole
experience has really upsetting.
And so, I'm, like-- well, you
know, I learned that if you
bought season tickets for, like,
all 90 games in a season, then
you would get, like, a 15%
discount,
and then I could get the $20
ticket. And so, of course, you
know,
what- what's a reasonable thing
to do is spend $9,000 on season
tickets. Yeah. So I basically
took 2/3 of my savings in
my bank account, and I funded
the money on season tickets. But
my theory was, I could sell them
at face value to my friends. And
since I got this, like, 15%
discount, that would more than
make up for the gap. And- and
Pam and I could go to, like,
three
or four games for free—which is
all I really wanted. And-- but
to do that, I needed to figure
out how to price all these
tickets. And so, I wrote a
Electron desktop app that went
and scraped
all the data from bluejays.com,
and scraped all the data from
StubHub, and I wrote an
algorithm to-- it, like-- you
know, if you scrape
StubHub one day, and you scrape
the next day, you can figure out
what tickets are not there
anymore. And then, you can
figure out what's sold and for
what price-
Bekah: Oh, wow.
Matt: -since you knew [??] all
the things. And so, I built a
really nice clean data set, and
then I
trained an algorithm to price my
tickets. And, you know,
again, I have this Electron app.
And I just click a button, it'll
price on my tickets, send an
email to my friends, and- and
then people just earmarked what
tickets I want. And- and it
worked. And I did that for, you
know, I've been doing that for
four,
five years now-- or six years, I
guess. This is-- there's, like,
two year gap that I, you know,
decided not to do it because of
COVID. And- and then, that got
the attention of IBM. I
mean, like, "Hey, that's a
really awesome project." And
that's what
kind of opened that door. But it
was, you know [laughs], all
these--
Bekah: That's-- when I- when I
was leaving education to come
into tech, I made money. I- I
remember the most money I made,
I bought and
resold Justin Bieber tickets on
StubHub [Bekah and Matt laugh].
And it was a lot of
research. Again, that would have
been something that would have
been very useful to me during
that time.
Matt: Oh, yeah.
Bekah: Wow, that's amazing.
Justin Bieber also made me a lot
of money, so I
don't hate Justin Bieber. He's
great [chuckles].
Matt: He's Canadian, yeah. He's
from down the road there. The--
Bekah: That's right [laughs].
Matt: And we have a lot of mixed
feelings about Justin Bieber.
But they're generally positive.
He's- he's doing his best [Matt
and Bekah laugh]. I'm glad he
did well by you, Bekah.
That's good.
Bekah: Yeah. Wow. That-- there
... I don't know what to say
other than that's
amazing. And oh, what I did
wanna say was, for-- we have a
lot
of people who are listening to
the podcast, who are coming into
tech, and I really love all
these stories that you're
telling
because all of the things that
you made were useful to you, and
they made sense for you to make.
And so, there's always that
question of like, "Well, what am
supposed to be doing? And what
am
I supposed to be building?" And
you- you don't have to build an
Electron app that analyzes what
to price your Blue Jays tickets
at [laughs], but,
like, find that thing that's
meaningful, and then go for
that,
and- and see where that takes
you, and who notices you based
on that.
Matt: Totally. And, you know, I
have a- a friend-- I've- I've
had these experiences where I--
you know, while I was at the
college, Bekah and Dan. I-- you
know, I connected with this
group
called Hacker Paradise that
facilitates these remote sort of
work
experiences. And they were, you
know-- it turns out that was
really impactful
for me. And there's a- a- a
woman I met there who is
amazing.
Her name is Nicole Keller, and
she has had this really, really
cool career path. But one of the
things she was doing down in New
York was running coding classes
for kids. And the thing that I--
I brought to visit-- Pam and I
had gone to New York and, you
know, called up
Nicole. And then like, "Hey."
And she just like, "Oh, yeah.
I'm working.
I'm doing this coding class for
kids." And I'm like, "Can we
come see?
That sounds awesome." And we
went in, and it was, like, the
attic of this
church. Like, you know, in- in,
like, mainland New York. And
we-- so I'm
just going to say mainland New
York. New York island. What is--
what are you guys call it
[laughs]? What ... Manhattan!
That's it!
Dan: Manhattan. Yes [Dan and
Bekah laugh].
Matt: Yeah. Manhattan. And we
[laughs]-- and it was-- but,
like, the thing I
loved, Bekah, was that they
started the kids who were--
like,
they were just building static
sites, and they use like a
website builder.
They were, like, as young as,
like, eight, nine years old,
but they started them with--
they had gone to the UN's ...
and
I forget what it's called, but,
like, basically these are, like,
our principles, and they had
asked the kids like, "What's
one thing
that you'd wanna affect change
with, and let's build a website
to do that." Like, they- they
started-- they didn't start
with
teaching JavaScript or teaching
HTML, and CSS. They started
with, like, what's the change
you wanna see in the world?
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Matt: And how can we use these
amazing tools to do this? And I
think that for people
who are getting into tech, you
know? It's-- and there's a lot
of
people that are coming in for
many, many reasons into tech.
And
especially now. It's, like-- I
think people are realizing that
you can
have this great lifestyle with
it, which is wonderful. And
that's a great reason to come
into tech. There- there's these
other
things that are connected to it.
I- I think one thing I'd love to
introduce to that, sort of, you
know, thought processes that
this is a tremendously
powerful thing. You can make
computers do stuff
automatically, and that's
awesome. And it can really
affect positive change on the
world. And
so, you know, as you're figuring
out what your learning projects
are, think about what you--
like, what you wanna change
about the
world. Like,
you- you know-- can you make
something for your-- f- your
friend group? Can
you make something for yourself?
Can you automate something that
you're doing regularly? Can you
make something that would be
just
really funny or cool, you know?
Like- like, what do you wanna
make?
And- and I think, if you start
with that, like, that can be
really powerful. Because, you-
you know, if- if you're
self-taught, one of
the biggest challenges you're
gonna face—and one of the
biggest challenges I faced—is
how do you do it regularly?
There
would be weeks I, you know,
couldn't bring myself to have
the energy to code at,
like, 9 o'clock at night, right?
And- and to continue that
learning- learning is so hard.
And it's such an emotionally
challenging journey too. But if
you're connected to something
that you just wanna see out
there, that- that's a deeper
level
of motivation than, you know,
than somebody on one side [??]
can be out there. I think that's
powerful.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I- I- I love that a-
a lot. And, you know, and this
is-- we actually-- we
just released Roger's episode.
We talked to him a couple of
weeks ago, and- and he- he said
a lot of the same things. He- he
has sort of a-- I mean, not the
exact path, but, like,
self-taught
and- and solving his own
problems—sort of thing—to
learn
coding. And so, I was-- I'm on
the same boat too. I think my
first website ... well, that
wasn't, like, a GeoCities site,
it was, like, my--
site for my band, right? It was,
like, in Flash or whatever.
Matt: That's awesome.
Dan: Just the-- yeah [chuckles].
I mean, it's fine.
But, the- the-- we--
nowadays, there's so many
learning, like, opportunities
or the bootcamps,
and everything like that. And
there's so much-- so many
different choices to- to make,
so many different paths you can
take. And
I-- it-- when- when I came up,
it's-- there was nothing, you
know, nothing
like that at all. There was some
books that were out of date as
soon as they hit the shelves,
and-- you know? And then the
internet,
right? And blogs, and- and
things like that. But I found
success the
same- the same way it was. Doing
things that, like, were either
fun or, like, I wanted to fix,
right? And you were tell the
story—w- when
you were talking about the- the
automated spreadsheet—the
thing that, you know-- there-
there-- I was thinking in
my head, this-- it's
like a- a curse and a blessing
of- of people who learn program-
like,
once you start down the path,
like, once you've figured out
some
stuff is that you start seeing
this everywhere. Like, "Oh my
god, that--
I could make this easier,"
[chuckles] right? And it's,
like-- and it's- and it's-- when
you do it,
it's, like, a blessing, right?
But it's, obviously-- I have
this-- for me,
anyway, I don't-- maybe this
isn't for everybody. But it--
it's, like [chuckles], I start
to think about it
all the time, for everything.
And sometimes it gets out of
hand,
sometimes [laughs] I'm
automating things that don't
actually take me that
long, probably. It-- probably
the work is taking longer than
it did, but, you know, it's-
it's ... I don't know. It's such
a-- once you get into that habit
of thinking that way, and,
like--
and the making things, it's-- it
can be such-- it can- it can
improve your life. And—like you
say—you
can improve- you can improve
little annoying things or
little things, you know, like,
small things with your family,
or your friends, or, you know,
large
changes too. And it-- it's- it's
cool. Well, there's so many
apps, so
many possibilities out there.
Matt: I mean, are there- are
there any other projects that
you've done, Dan, that are, you
know, particularly redundant or
[chuckles] maybe, like, not the
most, you know, effective use of
time? Or any-- do you
[unintelligible]--
Dan: Oh, well, I-- how many
color lights case here behind
me? [Dan chuckles, Bekah laughs]
Matt: [Laughs] Quite a few
actually.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Back in-
back in-- I was-- every time
we start-- like, there was a two
months or
something where I-- so, these
are all, like, hue light bulbs.
And there's-
there's one you can't see too.
And I've spent so much time--
cuz I
hated the lights in here. I
had-- before these, I just had,
like,
lights. Like, lamps. Everywhere.
And never could get the lighting
right. And then, I got these,
you know-- so, I have-- now I
got these
hue, I'm like, "This is the
perfect solution. Hue bulbs. Cuz
you can connect, you know, you
can connect them with your phone
or your, you know, there's
probably a- a web, or a Mac app,
and all that stuff." A-a-and so
I replaced all of [chuckles] the
bulbs with these
things. And now- now there's too
many op- like, now, it's, like--
[Dan and Bekah chuckle]
there's too much to do. Like, I
can-- I have too many options.
There's too many
colors, too many, like, ways. I
can turn them up and down. And
also,
I-- and I kinda-- exactly how I
wanted it. But then, it was,
like-- okay. Well,
it's still a pain for me to,
like, open my phone, and, like,
to push the
button, you know [chuckles]? So
it's, like, time to these--
like, time for automations. I
finally bought-- oh, you can't
see it, but I bought-- so, hue
has
this, like, a button that you--
it is just, like, a little- a
little
click button. And you can put it
on the wall, or you can put it
wherever, and you can set that
to do whatever you want when
you click it different ways
[laughs].
Matt: Cool.
Dan: So, I have that on my wall
now. So, I-- yeah. I- I spent,
like, five days of- of being
happy. I'm- I'm like,
"Huh? This is- this is it. I
have it." And, like, just this
morning, I
sat down, and I'm like, "I
should change the colors of
these lights- these lights [all
laughs] right now, but--"
So it was-- I sometimes struggle
with being satisfied
with- with things. But I still--
it is-- it's also fun
though, you know? [All laughs]
Matt: Man, it-- the-- Bekah,
you-- like, you have a-- and,
you know, Virtual Coffee, I
think
it would be totally fair to call
that, like, a-- like, an amazing
project that both of you have
created. It's the community I
love and love being part of. And
so, like, does that-- is it
sort of-- the same sort of thing
that has happened with you,
Bekah,
where you've had these things
that you've taken on, and you've
made, and
resulted in these learning
experiences? And I'd imagine
Virtual Coffee has been an
amazing learning experience.
Even for yourself [??].
Bekah: Oh, for sure. It's been a
learning experience, and it's
been
great. I feel like I'm always
dropping things. We have the
maintainers channel. And so,
you-- there- there will be
times where
I just, like, drop a bunch of
different ideas. Like, these are
all things that I think we
should be doing. And a lot of
times,
like, I'm writing out all of the
processes, or what this means,
or what
support we need. And then,
obviously, we don't do all of
those because there's only 24
hours in a day [laughs], and
it's just not
possible. But-- and that was,
like, I- I got four hours of
sleep last
night. And it was because last
night before bed, I- I was
having this
idea about a tech summit that I
wanted to be doing. And I was,
like,
messaging Kirk and Nick Taylor
about that. Like, "Hey, is this
a-- is this a idea that's too
out there? Or is this something
that
maybe is useful, or good, or
worth, like, talking about?" And
then, I fell
asleep. And then, it was, like,
three in the morning, I woke up,
and my
brain was like, "All right.
Yeah. Let's- let's figure this
out
right now [laughs]." Like, "No."
But I feel like, you know, it's
a lot of
that, but learning has been
really great. And now I feel
like
I'm going down this-- I- I don't
like Notion. I have not
liked it
anytime I've used it, but, like,
my methods of storing all of
these
ideas and writing about them is
just unsatisfactory now. And so,
I've started going down the
Notion rabbit hole of like,
"This
is- this is what I need to do.
And I need to automate these
things to my Notion because I
know that I can." So, I feel
like you
could probably automate, like,
hi- what your lights look like
through Notion,
right? If you just select what
mood you're in, and then it will
automatically set your lights.
So, Dan, you should try that
[chuckles].
Dan: Yeah. Last time I messed
with Notion, I had, like, a
nervous
breakdown trying to get
everything exactly like
[chuckles]--
Bekah: Kirk is making me a
template. So [chuckles]--
Dan: Yeah. That's the- that's
the issue I have with Notion is-
is-- it's
a great product and it's a very,
very cool initiative. There's
just too many possibilities, and
it's too pop- it's, like,
possible
to get it-- it seems possible to
get it perfect [chuckles].
And it's, like--
when that- when that, like,
perfect thing gets in my head,
it's hard to-- sometimes hard to
let it go. So [chuckles]--
Matt: Yeah. We- we've spent a
lot of time in Notion too. We--
you
know, it's ... things that are
highly customizable are often
not the best tools, right? Like,
it's--
you know, I appreciate software
that has opinion sometimes.
Bekah: I say that--
Dan: Yeah. My- my-- oh, go
ahead, Bekah.
Bekah: It-- my-- right now, I've
just collected way too many
different ways of doing things.
Like, you know, I've got all
these apps to help me with
planning or note taking or,
you
know, whatev- there's just way
too many of them. So, I feel
like I'm
just very ... all or nothing
kind of person. And so
[chuckles] I- I can't have all
of
these. Now, I just need one
thing, and Notion is the- the
one thing to rule them all up,
apparently.
Matt: [Chuckles] And so then,
you know, in-- circling back,
like, Bekah, you
have this awesome job. You're an
amazing community manager. Did
you have
those skills before you started
the Virtual Coffee or was that
something that you
learned and kind of just figured
out, go into the process?
Bekah: When I- when I was in
undergrad, I- I graduated in
three
years. So I took a bunch of
credits, but I was also in 10
clubs, and I was an officer in,
like, five of them [chuckles].
So, I- I feel like
it's been a lifelong journey of
community building, and many
points where I've tried to
reject that. Like, "Please let
me just be in
a hole by myself [chuckles] and
not talk to people." But I keep
coming back to it. I feel like I
finally hit the point where I'm
like, "Okay,"
like, "this- this is a skill set
I should utilize it and- and
figure out
how I can best do that thing."
So, yeah. It's- it's ... I guess
part of me.
Matt: That's really cool. I--
you know, I think that, like,
one of the
things that, you know-- I was
hard to figure out, and I'm- I'm
hope-- I think it's okay. I'm
kind of like left turning the
conversation a little bit. One
of the things that was really
hard
to figure out in- in running a
business is, like, how do you
hire? And you need to figure it
all out from scratch. Because,
like, we had hired a bunch of
people that make stuff at IBM,
but
it was all a very catered
experience. Like, we had-- we
outsourced all of the hard out
of front work [??]. And we got
these, like, just, like, 50
incredible candidates, and we
would divide them up on our
team,
and figure out who's gonna do
round one, round two, round
three,
right? And that-- like,
interviewing is easy, but hiring
is hard. And hiring is all that
other stuff. It's like finding
people and evaluating them. And-
and then, you know, you read
about all the bad things that
happen to hiring process, and
you
don't wanna do those, and you
wanna do the good things, and
you wanna get the right person,
and then the right people. The
thing
that has always stand out to me
is personal projects. And it's-
it's
probably not surprising given
the history I just described,
right?
Like, I-- like, I value them a
lot. But I think that when
somebody
comes in, and they say, "Hey, I
made this thing, and here is why
I made it,
and here's-- like, how it's
important for, like, small
businesses,
especially," that is so helpful
because it's, like, the person's
thinking
about a need on the other side
of what they're doing. And,
like, you
know-- it- it's-- we don't have,
like, tickets where we're
working through.
We're too small. We, you know--
we don't have a ton of process
around things. But, like, when
people come in, and then I
imagine this is the
case for you, Bekah, and you do
this amazing community
management, and
all this other stuff. And you
have Virtual Coffee as this
incredible example
of you doing that, in tech, at
scale. And- and I just-- that's
awesome.
Bekah: Yeah. I-- and that's what
led to the job that I have
right now. I wasn't looking for
work. My team lead reached
out to me and it was based on
Virtual Coffee. And somebody
else
had—who I'd interviewed with,
who had reached out to me
last summer ... because they
knew about Virtual
Coffee—recommended
me. Like, I was on the top of
the-- their list.
And so, once he
started looking into Virtual
Coffee—I think he watched
some of our Lunch and Learn
videos and read blog posts—like,
there- there is a-- my community
building resume is out
there because of all of the
things that we do. And so--
yeah.
It is. It is like a project. I
hadn't really thought about it
that way,
but it is this- this living
resume of all of the things that
I've been working on.
Matt: Totally. And- and, Dan,
watch out. Cuz, like, Phillips
is gonna come
knocking, and gonna say, "Hey,
[Dan and Bekah laugh] I heard
all these things you're doing
with our light bulbs [laughs]."
Dan: Yeah.
Matt: I'm, like, the CTO.
[Unintelligible] you [laughs].
Dan: And they gonna come, and
say, "Hey, buy this product
[laughs]. This
product will finally solve all
of your problems."
Matt: [Chuckles] Oh my god.
Yeah. I hope all the-- our
conversation in this podcast
has an index cuz it'll go to
these Google searches. I mean,
this is gonna be all Philips hue
light bulbs.
Dan: [Laughs] Right.
Bekah: But we are open for
sponsorships, so--
Dan: Yeah. That's right.
Matt: [Unintelligible] Oh my
gosh. Yeah. It's-- that's
really interesting. I
think the-- those personal
projects, they- they really
standout. And, you
know, and certainly there's
merit if you're going to a
bootcamp, and going through
that, you-- like, you wanna
stay on task,
right? And if you're gonna get
great learning, great feedback
by building something that it--
like the bootcamp is saying,
"Oh, we're
gonna build like a, you know,
shopping cart," that's totally
cool, right? But
those- those other pieces of
like, "Hey, I've got this skill
sat down. I can use it to just
really do anything I want," it-
it is just so
attractive to me in a hiring
process. Like, it really
separates
people out. And I'd imagine
that's been the experience for
both of you from what you've
described too.
Dan: Yeah. And- and, like, if
you are-- if your only project
is coming out of
a bootcamp or what you did in
the bootcamp, and everybody else
is trying
to get a job too, you know,
everybody is going to have the
same set of projects, right? And
so, that's- that's another thing
is doing those. And maybe it's--
maybe there's not enough time
to do it while you're in the
bootcamp, you know? Maybe kind
of do it after, but the-- those
personal projects, I- I totally
agree with you, Matt. It- it- it
says- it says so much about ...
you, without even speaking
[chuckles]. And then, it also
gives you something to talk
about—that's easy
to talk about—because you did
it, and you know- and you
know it. So it's not a
theoretical thing or, you know,
school assignment that
you weren't connected with, you
know? And it-- and again, it
doesn't
have to be world changing or a
successful product or anything
like that,
right? You- you were talking
about that Chrome extension that
you made. That's literally just
you and your wife [chuckles],
right?
Matt: Yeah.
Dan: And that- and that's it.
Like, but it-- that's- that's-
that's a cool project. And I
would like-- like, I enjoyed
hearing about it, and I
would—if
I was hiring—I would also enjoy
hearing about it. Don't-- you
know, you didn't, like, sell it
to somebody or, you know, it
doesn't have to be some-- I
don't know--
huge thing. It's- it's just a- a
thing that you
decided to do on your own, and-
and you figured out how to do
it. And that's- that's the cool
part for me.
Bekah: We just wrapped up a
hackathon at Deepgram. And one
of our participants had, I
think, five submissions. And
this is a month
long hackathon. And the
submissions were all
interesting, and they
were all beautiful. The design
was really great. I'm really
terrible at design. And the- the
fact that all of these looked
really
wonderful were meaningful, and
interesting projects was great.
But I interviewed that
participant for a blog post
highlight. And being able to
hear the stories behind it, to
hear how he
communicated, what he did, his
approach, how he did it, I--
that's-- he's a
person in the top of my book
that I would recommend for a
job. But I know that he's
looking, and he's going to be
more actively
looking soon. And so, when
anything comes up, I know that
I'm going
to reach out to that person. So,
you know, if it doesn't catch
the eye of somebody who's doing
the hiring,
it might catch the eye of
somebody who's in a position
where people
reach out to them and say, "Hey,
do you know anybody?" Like,
"Yes, I
do. This person would be really,
really great for this role."
Matt: Yeah, that's- that's
really interesting. And, you
know, and
another sort of related thing
that I hear a lot of hiring
managers articulate, and there's
famous examples of this, too,
is- is, like, a really strong
indicator of success in a
businesses or in a
particular role is how-- has
that person achieved a success
or excellence in a completely
different area, right? And,
you know, the-- Shopify has this
famous example where their
CEO
gave an internship or a job to
someone because they are, like,
ranked in the top 50 at
StarCraft, you know?
Dan: That's awesome.
Matt: And there's, like, similar
sort of conversation in- in
sales, like, you know, this
other sort of area around
people who have had a-athletic
success, you know? So there-
there are people who are sales
managers, they were like, "Oh,
you were division to athlete and
track?" Like, that's a really
strong indicator for this other
type of thing. And I- I think,
like, you also see it in, like,
volunteers. I'm-- like the stuff
you did when we're describing in
university, Bekah. Right?
It's interesting, these signals.
Because the way that we
typically interview is like in
front of a whiteboard
[chuckles], and we
just-- we know it's- it's- it's
a hard process to take on--
anyways, all- all I have to say.
Bekah: Yeah, it is- it is really
hard. And I think, even hearing
a lot of
conversations around hiring
where people are trying to do
things,
there-- there's still so much of
the process where we're stuck
inside this box. So, rather
than, like, really trying to ...
rethink how we
do the entire process, we're,
like, well, we're gonna
rethink but we still have to do
all of these things. And we have
to ask these questions because
you have to. [Chuckles] You- you
don't have to.
That's not-- what is that ...
indicating? And how does that
tell you
whether or not that's going to
be a good person for you to work
with or a good team for you to
join? How do we rethink the way
that we're ... doing hiring? How
we're onboarding new people? How
we are
looking at junior developers in
this hiring process? I can't--
in- in
my mind, it has to be-- there's
a much bigger shift that needs
to happen than, you know, these
tiny changes that we keep seeing
happening.
Matt: Yeah. I, you know, I--
there's a part of me that--
and I- I wanna sort of say this
in the, like, the best possible
way that I'm-- I- I wish that
people generally were more
deliberate
about what they wanted out of a
job. And this has been something
that's been
incredibly important for me.
And, you know, there's these
books
that, like, sort of get you
thinking on these topics, but,
like, really early on, for me,
was it-- that- that juncture
where I'm like,
"Oh," like, "a career in tech,
in- in ..." specifically,
there's a shift I
had, you know, a couple of years
after learning code where I--
I've
very deliberately, I wanna run a
business. I- I wanna run a
technology based business. And
that wasn't for the sake of
wanting to do that. It was
because of these other things
that I wanted. I sat-- literally
had a moment where I
sat down, and I
say, "What do I wanted in my
work life?" And, you know, for
me, they were things that were
connected to autonomy. I
wanted—like,
in a perfect world—I would work
where and when I wanted to.
I would-- like, I- I ne- was
always confused that we had
this, like, 40
hour a week box that we often
live in. Like, why does that-
why does
that have to exist, you know?
Like, what are the reasons that
the edges of that box are there?
And, like, I-- what if one week
I
wanna work less and one week I
wanted that type of control to--
you know, there were these-- I-
I wanted to work on any type of
problem that I wanted. I- I
wanted to have the potential for
financial independence, you
know? These types of things. And
that put, like-- you know, to
me, that was really helpful
because
it determined the types of jobs
that I wanted to work at and-
and why.
And so, when I started applying
to-- and I-- like, I think I
applied
to, you know, putting IBM and
Microsoft aside because I- I
never actually put an
application into either company.
It-- they-- like, once you get
in, it-- I
just wanna go there, but it's a
different process. And-- but
I did apply to two technology
companies to be a programmer.
And
that-- my purpose in applying to
them was, you know, the- the
conventional wisdom that working
at a startup will help you do a
startup later. And that's what I
wanted. I wanted to run my own
business. So, I was applying to
a very particular type of
company
because the purpose of that
learning was to help me do this
thing later. And, you know, the
funny thing about people who are
junior devel- developers and who
are graduating, like, in 2022
is in a very short period of
time, they're the hiring
managers.
And, you know, I-- like, I-- my
gut feeling is that if people
were
approaching that process with,
like, a very deliberate set of
values and intentions, that
hiring would change on the
back end later, or maybe not,
you know? [Laughs]
Bekah: Yeah, that's interesting.
I hadn't really thought about
that. And it- and it can be
really hard, especially with so
many people
looking for jobs on the market
right now. And-- I knew that I
spent a lot
of time telling people, when you
join your first team, it should
be about the people and not the
project. Because I've seen so
many people jump into-- I--
particularly, EdTech companies.
I don't know.
I just-- generally, EdTech
that's really toxic or what, but
just
really bad experiences. And
there's been the whole, like,
mission trade-off thing.
"Well," you know, "We've got a
great mission." Well, but you're
doing a
terrible job of managing a team,
being kind to other people
[chuckles], you
know? Like, those things matter.
Matt: Yeah. You know, I- I-- if
I was, you know, the key-- talk
about EdTech—and I
completely echo that sentiment—I
think it's totally correct.
And video- video game industry
is notorious, right?
Bekah: Yeah.
Matt: For-- like, it's not being
a great place to work. If
there was one thing that I
learned working in big tech,
like, you know, going from a
college where you're-- you know,
you--
like, you make this amount of
money, you need a $1,500 raise a
year, and it's unionized, and X,
and Y, and Z. And then, like, I
remember
the week that I joined IBM,
they, like, flew me down to
Silicon Valley for two
weeks. We had this-- then we
had, like, this event. And there
was, like,
this music, and it was just all
catered, and it was all free,
and it was crazy—the amount of
money. And I got the opportunity
to work
with you. It was really great. I
loved both of those jobs.
Loved, loved, loved both of
them. And I think, one of the
things
that I've learned is, that a lot
of the things that we want in an
employer, a really, really
strong indicator is the health
of the
business. If you wanna- if- if
you wanna work, you know, my- my
wife works at Shopify. She loves
it there. And, you know, they
have-- Shopify makes
so much money that they can hire
people, that all they do is
think
about diversity and equity. And
they hire another-- they have a
whole team that all they do is
think about culture. And they
have
whole teams that do all-- do
nothing but, you know, run an
internal events and try to make
that a great place to work, you
know? You can do that if you've
got a ton of money.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Matt: And, you know, in terms of
diversity in tech, my AI team at
Microsoft, we were
extremely diverse by every
standard. We had more women than
men, and- and that's an AI
where-- like, its AI and data
science is enormously
behind computer science. It's
where computer science was,
like, 15 years ago. But we were
able to have a diverse team at
Microsoft
because we could outbid
everybody, you know? We- we
could go hire the best, and the
best one are to work for us. And
we can afford it. And there's a
million
other examples like that. So,
it's, like, I think, going full
circle,
a lot of EdTech can be a really
tough place to work because
that's a really, really hard
business to be in.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Matt: And you're- you're
pinching every corner. And
usually, you are. And same with
the video game
industry is-- it is, like, you
know, if that game does well,
congratulations. But if it
doesn't, you-- it-- like, it's
really-- it's a tough
environment to work in. So, you
know, if you wanna have a
really great place to work, I
think the best, most simple
indicator you can look at is,
like, how much money did they
raise in
the last round—if it's a
startup. If it's a publicly--
big
publicly traded company, is it
growing? Look at their stock
chart for five years. Does it go
up? You know, if it does,
probably
a great place to work. If it's
flat, it- it, you know, you
might be getting,
like-- you might not have budget
to go to that next
conference.
It's ... you know? And
similarly, people might not be
attracted to work there, in the
same.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's
great advice. I wanna thank you
so much for being here with us
today and having this
conversation. There's a lot of
really great takeaway cuz I feel
like--
from all these stuff that we
talked about here, is there
anything that you wanna share
before we leave or any last
words of wisdom for our
listeners?
Matt: No. Thanks everyone. The--
thank you, Bekah and Dan, for
having me.
It's- it's great. If nothing
else, I think one of the things
we all
take away from today is build
personal projects. Go make
stuff.
Like, you know, the- the old
Y-Com motto, make- make stuff
people want, right? Make stuff
you want.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah.
Matt: It's cool. And share it--
Bekah: Share with us too. We
wanna see 'em.
Matt: Yeah, totally. Thank you
so much for having me.
Dan: Thanks, Matt. This is
awesome.
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast,
and be sure to leave us a
review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week.