Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and welcome to
season 5, episode 9 of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan, and everybody's
favorite maintainer, Kirk.
Dan: Hello! Welcome to our season
finale of season 5. As we
traditionally do, we have Kirk on
to hang out with us because we
all love Kirk very much. And
we are going to talk about some
choices we made with- with
Virtual Coffee and some feedback
we've had over the last few
months, and what we have
going on in the future. So, glad
as always to have Kirk here. And,
yeah, it's gonna be fun.
Bekah: Yeah. And we're gonna
start off this episode of the
podcast like we start off every
Virtual Coffee. We'll introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. We hope
you enjoy this episode. Our
question today is what was your
favorite game to play as a child?
My name is Bekah. I'm a technical
community builder from a small
town in Ohio, and my favorite
game to play as a child -- I mean,
like, due go up to here [??], I
really loved Othello, so I played
a lot of Othello with my dad.
And then I'm gonna go outdoor
games. We also played a lot of
kickball and badminton in my
backyard. So I can't really
decide between kickball and
badminton, but I have very fond
memories of all of those things.
Dan: All right, so you're going
three games.
Bekah: Yeah. Okay. [Crosstalk 00:02:07,000]
I can do what I want, right? [Laughs]
Dan: What are your three favorite
games? [Laughs]
Kirk Shillingford: Pick your favorite
game. [Unintelligible]
Bekah: You get one, Dan.
Dan: [Laughs] Hi, I'm Dan. You all know
who I am. My favorite game -- I don't
know. This is like when my mind just
to the next --
Bekah: Wait- wait a minute. You said,
"We- you all know who I am." [Dan laughs] What if you have a
first time listener here, okay?
Dan: Okay. Well, first time listener. Well, I'm
Dan. I live in Cleveland. I make
websites stuff with code.
Sometimes in frontend -- most of the time,
frontend, sometimes backend.
I do a lot of other things too.
And it's all on my computer [Dan & Bekah laugh].
I'm sorry. I'm having trouble
today. All right.
Bekah: You should participated in the monthly challenge last
month for the elevator pitch. I
think it would have helped you-
Kirk: No, that's the perfect [unintelligible]-
Bekah: -refine your intro.
Dan: I should have.
Kirk: -angel word.
Dan: I- I make computer
things [chuckles].
Kirk: Real quick.
Dan: So, games as a child ... we had this- we had this
board game called "Omega Virus"-
Bekah: Yes! Yes, "Omega Virus".
Dan: -is the first thing that popped in
mind. You know "Omega Virus"?
Bekah: Yes!
Dan: [Chuckles] Oh my god. That's amazing.
Bekah: I think I
accidentally called Omicron "Omega virus" [laughs] one time in public. And
somebody was like, "What?" [laughs].
Dan: [Laughs] It's amazing! Okay. So
that game was really fun. I- I
mean, I don't even know if it's a
good game, but it had -- you know,
a guy that yelled at you, and
robots and stuff. And so it was-
it was fun. That was the first
thing that popped in my mind. So
we played lots of games
growing up. But that one has
a special place -- you know, in my heart. So ... for
my one favorite game I'm picking
"Omega Virus."
Bekah: I was the one -- I wanna
add another one.
Dan: Cuz I thought the rules --
Bekah: Number four. Computer game, loved Monkey
Island, and it's coming back. And
I'm so excited about that. So, now
I'm done. Go ahead, Kirk [chuckles].
Kirk: By so many thoughts, the
thought of a trailer for a Monkey
Island, it's so strange. It looks
like the strangest game in the
world. And then I said, "Of
course, Bekah likes this." You know, craps.
Games that I liked as a child
is "You're-not-leaving-this-table-
until-you-eat-these-vegetables-
jokes-on-you." I have a book. A
game. Because me and my mom
played that a lot. And I won a
lot, like, "I guess you can't get to finish
your food," and I'm like, "I'm just
gonna read until we get bored, and I'm gonna go [chuckles]".
Okay.
Bekah: [Chuckles] It's not a real game.
Kirk: It's a real game and I'm
the champion. Board games
"Risk" is -- I know a lot of people
hate "Risk". I love "Risk." I'm super
into roll those dice, fighting
those armies, you know? I
love -- I got beaten up at "Risk" by, like,
an 86 year old woman. And I sort
of like dedicated six months of
my life [chuckles] to revenge on the board
game, not -- you know. So, Risk
is pretty big ... computer
games? There's this really -- this
is computer game called "DX Ball". And
it's basically just like
glorified, like, "Pong". It was like
super "Pong". And if I get 200
levels, there were explosions and
it was like a real -- there's a lot going
on there. I really liked that.
That was really fun. And I also
remember at the age of seven, my mom
got me like a "Reader Rabbit."
Learn math on the computer CD
cuz that seemed like a great
idea. And it immediately crashed
our computer and it like never turned
back on. So, I don't know what the
life lesson there is. Don't [unintelligible]-
Bekah: There's a lot of "Reader Rabbit."
Kirk: -your children arithmetic.
Those are my answers.
Dan: I -- all right. I'm gonna add --
I'm having an addict- an addition. I thought about --
I remembered "Wolfenstein" on a
computer game.
Bekah: Yeah -- no. You're not allowed.
Dan: Yeah. "Wolfenstein" is awesome.
Bekah: Sorry. Take it back.
You're done.
Dan: So I played that lot.
Kirk: Now that I think, you fire this? [??]
Bekah: Yeah. Well, Dan's in
trouble, so he doesn't get all of
the things [laughs].
Dan: In trouble [chuckles].
Bekah: He's being punished.
Dan: For what?
Bekah: I won [chuckles].
Dan: I don't even know what I did.
Kirk: Well, I don't really swift the -- you know, no old game of Othello or
something.
Dan: Othello was pretty cool
too. I liked the artists. I don't
know if they all do, but ours had
like a felt boarders, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Okay. Yeah. That's cool. I don't know. I appreciate that it had -- thought I had a- I had a
really nice tactical feel to it
that the pieces in the- in the
felt and stuff.
Bekah: Yeah. I started playing it
with my 12-year-old, but then,
like, one of the other kids got
ahold of it. And so now we don't
have all of the chips. So from --
Backgammon. I like Backgammon
too. I like games.
Dan: I never learned how to play
Backgammon.
Kirk: I had one of those chess
boards. It was like chess on top
and then back-end low. So below
was just like -- it was like in the
Lion King. Like, just don't go
there cuz it's bad.
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah, same. I played the -- I played chess
a lot and never played Backgammon
and never -- I dunno. I --
Bekah: We have very cool
Backgammon suit -- it was like a
suitcase. It looked like a small
suitcase and then we were like pop
open. It was very nice.
Kirk: I played to defeat my father. Like, I
only -- I found the game. I pressed
him every day for months and he
would beat me every day. And so
the day I beat him, and then ... it
was like the happiest day of my
life [chuckles]. And then we kept playing
until it was pretty even who
would win. And then he was like,
"I'm not playing anymore [laughs]." The
whole point of being here, "Is it I beat you at being [unintelligible]
all the way around?" And that's
pretty much the last time I
played chess. I did what I set out to accomplish.
Bekah: Okay. But, we are not here
to talk about games the entire
time, although that might be a
fun episode [chuckles]. So, we put it out
there to the Virtual Coffee
community, what they wanted to
hear about. And I think they
wanted to hear about what we had
as our back pocket topic anyway.
So, today we're going to be
talking about our decision to
pause membership with Virtual
Coffee, the things that we've
been doing and what we see for
the future. So, Kirk, do you wanna
give a little bit of a recap
of where we're at?
Kirk: Yeah. I think how it
can be sort of like summing up
of the- the concise way.
Membership -- incoming members has
been paused with the Virtual
Coffee community for a couple of
months now. This -- the decision
was not made lightly. We spent a
lot of time thinking about it and
trying to figure out if there was
like another way to not have to
do that, to sort of like get the
desired outcomes. But I think we
just realized the only way we
were gonna sort of keep things
okay for our volunteers. And also
just like give us the bandwidth
to make things better for
incoming members was to take a
pause, right? And it's- it's like one
of those real ... you know,
sometimes like you just have to
make priorities when you do not
have internet resources. And that
was a decision we made and I
think it was the right one. I
think -- we think it was the right one.
As it's given us a lot of space to
really go with like, "Hey, when we
open back up, what do we wanna
do? What do we want this to be?"
Think back to what our
mission is. Think back to like
what's working well, what's not
working well, how can we empower
the parts that are, like, really
valuable for people, one of the
stress points or the pain points
that we can, like, reduce. So, I
think that's been good. And I
guess there's a little bit there
about having the ability to do
that type of thing, being just
like a friendly community, but
also, you know, not- not a service or
a product or something. It- it makes
it easier for us to say like,
"Yeah. We can- we can still just
like be us for a little bit
before we start being forecast [??], be with
people again."
Bekah: Yeah. And I think during
the time, right, after we decided
to pause membership, we were
nominated for most welcoming,
new -- most welcoming developer
community, which we did win
at the DevRel award, which was
really fun. But I- I know that
that was, you know, there- there's
probably a hesitancy, like, "How
can you be the most welcoming
community and not be having new
members at this point?" And for
me, I felt like it further
ensured that we are a welcoming
community because we're taking
the time to figure out how we can
best welcome people, how we can
continue to welcome our existing
members. And in the last year,
I've talked to a lot of
different, small community
builders, and I've seen them, you
know, fold or say like, "Hey,
we're gonna stop doing this
because we're burnt out and we're
just gonna send everybody to
Virtual Coffee. And it's- it's
like a house of cards, right?
Like, one small community folds
and then all of the people go to
the next small community, into the
next. And so, we wanted to make
sure that- that we weren't
falling with- with those
other small communities, which I-
I don't think that we felt that we
were, but you can definitely see
that coming down the line. So, for
us, it was super important to be
able to think through all of
these processes, exactly like
what Kirk said, like, you know,
what makes Virtual Coffee
special? How do we preserve that
intimacy and how do we scale
that?
Dan: Yeah. I don't really have
anything to add. I mean, you both- you both
kind of hit all the- all the
points that we were thinking
about it, you know? And I'm -- our- our-
our growth chart or whatever. We
don't actually have growth chart [laughs], but
like, you know, you- you can just --
when you're in the community, you
can get a sense of it. And it's --
you know, it- it was increasing
rapidly, you know, and ... which
is cool obviously in one- in one
part. And we- we all very much
want more people to be joining
again. Like, we're all, I think,
very excited about getting back
to the place where we can open
membership again. And that's
just a matter of building up
our ... you know, different
resources, building up our
processes, and- and figuring out some-
some paths for, you know, how we want to
handle things. We have -- just recently, we took two
steps. We did one thing where we
were able to highlight our
members that are, you know,
giving back to the community by
volunteering and in leadership
positions or- or just helping out in
different roles on our
website. So, on virtualcoffee.io/members
now, anybody
who's -- who has ... you know, who's-
who's actively helping with the
community has- has a little tag, you
know, based on what they're
doing. Things like room leaders,
and note takers and, you know,
the -- our-our monthly challenge team,
and everybody else. And then
after that, we have been working
last a little bit — I dunno,
the last couple months, I guess —
on describing better ways that
people can- can join to help.
Because we'd been kind of just
grabbing people [laughs], mostly, to- to
help. And they've been, you know --
everybody has been amazing.
But to support more and more
people, like, we need -- like, if
we're going to scale, the
volunteers need to scale first
before the- before the members.
Do -- you know, the- the -- if you just take
our- our coffee meetings, for
example, we have awesome
team of room leaders and note
takers, and they do a great job,
but there's a limited amount of
them, right? And so, that means
there's a limited amount of
people that we can actually have
at the meetings. And it's not
that high [laughs], honestly. And so,
the -- so, what we wanted to do:
Okay. How do we get more room
leaders and- and also hosts? So
up until ... yesterday -- so, we're
recording on- on Friday the 13th,
and so yesterday was the first
day that we had ... not a
maintainer -- host one of our
coffees.
Bekah: MC.
Dan: MC. Sorry. I- I say
host. See, this is why -- it's a- it's a bad name for it. But, but like --
Bekah: We're also working on
titles [laughs].
Dan: Right. We're working on
titles. But what I mean is, yeah,
MC. I-I-I always called host in my
head cuz that's what I
think of, but the person who's
running the coffee meeting.
That- that is talking to everybody. And- and it was Suze and she did
an awesome job. But that-
that sort of thing is we can't
just ... we- we- we feel very strongly
that we want these to be good
experiences, and they always are.
But they -- that- that- that's because we
put a lot of thought into
the MC stuff, and the room leaders,
and all -- everything like that. And so,
we need to make sure that people
are supported and have
what they need to, you know,
bring good- good experiences to all the
other people. And so -- as sort of
like a top-down scaling situation [chuckles] for us. And so, that's one of
the big reasons we needed to -- we-
we felt we- we should- we should
be pausing membership was- was
that. And it's been -- we've
gotten a lot of good
responses from people ... yeah. I
don't know if I actually said
this out loud [chuckles], but we made some-
some ... like documents and forms
and stuffs to- to make it easier
for people to- to- to volunteer for us and --
for Virtual Coffee. So, that was
the- that was the -- our next step. And
that's been going well. I don't know.
Bekah: And I think that makes it
easier for us, because like you
said before there wasn't a clear
process and even we'd have
members like, "Oh, I want to help.
How can I help?" And so much of,
because Virtual Coffee was not an
intentionally planned community,
it's always been like keeping up
with the needs of the community,
the excitement of the community, and
doing all these cool and fun
things. And I think we've done a
pretty good job of keeping up
with processes, but things
like that, like what- what do we
need help with? And I don't think
that's something that's
particularly a Virtual Coffee
problem. I think that anybody
who's running a community, if- if you
don't have things set up, you --
like, you know that you need
help [chuckles], but it's like, "How do I get
people? How do I onboard them?
What do- what do I really need
here?" And so, like, pausing to
take the time to think through
what do I need, what are the
processes that need to be
updated? Those are the things
that are going to help you to
scale down the road because it's
set up. I can bring in a new,
like, four new note takers this
morning. I added to our
organization and set them up with
the documentation that they need,
and walk through the processes.
And I've -- we've got a couple
more volunteers that I
reached out to as well, but all
of that needed to be set up in
advance. So when somebody says, "I
would like to help, where can I
help?" there's a place to send
them to.
Dan: Yeah. And like ... oh, I was
just gonna say, at the -- having-
having more people helps do things, like
we've- we've talked about adding
a day for coffees, right? But we
can't -- you know, up until now,
we've- we've only had our maintainers
being, kind of controlling
those -- that, dealing MC first for
these events. And while we're-
we're just sort of expect it then as it is. So, adding-
adding them, see, like Suze is a
big step for us and, you
know, we don't wanna just do it
willy-nilly. So, like, just like
Bekah was saying this, having all
that stuff written down and
having clear paths for people,
it's turned out very
important [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. And we sent out
a community survey or- or we had the
community survey that we were
posting in Slack and during our
Virtual Coffee meetings for a
couple of weeks to get feedback
from the community. And so, we're
also taking like, what- what does
the community value? So, we know
that there are things that
everybody values, but like really
getting that down, having
conversations, having maintainers
Q&As allows us to get
feedback and really think through
what we're- we're doing. Kirk,
do you wanna talk a little bit
about the results of those
surveys? Some of the key
takeaways that we had?
Kirk: Yeah. Well, in the sort of like
overarching ourselves that we
had. First of all, generally
positive responses, which is
nice. I don't know. It's just
nice to not be told, like, "You
suck [laughs]," in another time [??]. So, mostly positive. A lot of it was like existing
systems that people want, maybe
like a little bit more, you know?
And I think a lot of it was
maybe just like a little more
like fidelity and we've talked
about. Like, "If I wanna volunteer,
how do I do that?" So, there are a
lot of people who weren't like --
or they're new, or they're still
sort of getting into things like,
"How do I do more?" And making
that really, really transparent with
people, with something that seemed
to resonate. Right now, we have a
few sort of like key events that
happen in the community. We have
our Lunch & Learns, we have the
Lightning Talks, but we also
have -- I guess this concept
that wouldn't be about -- like, this
Coffee Table groups, which are
really just things started by the
members where they saw like a
need or a space for something
they were interested in and they
just self-organized. And that's
super great. And we, like, we like
those things. So there's a
question. Okay. How do we support
people who wanna do this?
How do we, again, like, avoid
some of the pitfalls or some of
the dangers of like doing a lot
of volunteer work, right? So it's
like, if you wanna do this
group, what can we help you with?
Like, what support can we give
you? What support do you need?
Can we equip you to kind of like,
have an idea of like how much
effort it's gonna take, if you
need to stop — I think it is like
most important that — if you need
to stop performing a role, can you
do that -- communicate that in a
way that is safe for you,
comfortable for you, like minimal
pain points. So there's been
a lot of things like that, you
know? Basically just people
saying like, "This stuff is going
on here. I really like it. How
can I get more involved?" And then
us figuring out a way to like,
take people's enthusiasm and then
like put them on a path to
success for what they're gonna
do, which I think is super
important, you know? Like a lot of ... I don't know.
When I think of like what it
comes down to with like these
types of initiatives, it's ... you
find two issues. Sometimes
someone has a great idea, but a
system's not set up for it so
they can execute it and they get
bummed out. Or they have idea and
they sort of like go headlong
into it and, you know, kind of
like burn through their life
force like a Phoenix. And
neither of those is great. So, a nice
middle ground and it -- you know, I
think this idea of sustainable
leadership, I think is something
is really important to us. If
you wanna lead something, we
wanna help you do it, but in a
way where you can keep doing it
on your own terms and not feel
like you have to because of other
people, or you have to because
it's like, you know, just ... I wanna do
this while it provides value and
joy for me, and then when I'm
ready to stop, you can stop. And
that's okay. And I think that's
the thing we've- we've kind of gone over
this community. We like the fact
this is not a space where
you have to come in perfect, you
know? We like the fact that
people can grow here, there was this little space
to grow here, there's a
space to make mistakes within
reason, there's a space to
practice things that you're not
perfect at, you know? A lot of
times people hesitate, I mean even
things like, why don't you learn --
just like, "I've never," you know,
"I've never done speaking before,"
but like, if you haven't, this is
probably the best space to give
it a try. It's a non-hostile
audience who only is interested in
just like supporting you as much
as possible, you know? So,
yeah. It- it the -- well, I was really
validated by a lot of the
survey responses kind of echo
what we were feeling as
maintainers and everyone seems
to kind of be on board, like
making this even more awesome.
Bekah: Yeah. Dan, do you wanna
talk through the things that you
implemented to help support our
Coffee Table groups?
Dan: Yeah. I mean, we -- the -- I think
the- the biggest thing -- the first
thing is just the -- is just that
the form and the stuff that we've
been talking about a little bit
i-i-is making it available. Just
letting our members know that
it's- it's a thing that they
could do, you know? And then
after that, I've just kind of
scratched the surface about
supporting these groups on a
technical level. But ... you
know -- so, one of the things was-
was setting up a calendar
system so that I -- you know, people
can log in. Our- our members -- I mean,
our -- the- the group leaders can
log in and add their events,
you know, recurring events or one
off events. And then those
events get filter back out through
our website and, you know, onto our events' page. And they also -- I added
a Slack bot sort of thing that,
well, we'll- we'll send reminders from
that. So we moved on from
Meeting Place and are using
that for our events now too, and not
just the special interest group
stuff -- Coffee Table groups [chuckles].
Sorry. We call them the special
interest groups for a long time.
But -- so- so- so, yeah. So
that was like, this is like kind of
step one, is- is allowing
our group leaders to sort of
roll their own stuff, you know?
So they don't have to ask us to
add things to the calendar, ask
us to add things to Slack-- in Slack, you know, Slack
reminders, and things like that.
And- and with -- along with
that, sort of copied the
co-working room experience and [chuckles]
made it -- so that we could -- so
our group leaders could use our
Zoom for events, which was
another sticking point because
if you don't have a paid Zoom
account, then I think you were
still limited to 40 minutes or
something like that, you know?
There's limitations for- for free
accounts. And so, having a central
place that you can trust that we
will have things to get taken
care of and have some moderation
tools in place, things like that.
So- so, yeah. And then I
think I have -- you know, next is gonna
be some things more for general users
to log in and be able to
maybe RSVP for events or add
things to calendars, things like
that. So, that's coming down the
line. But- but, yeah. That's -- all
the- the- the group membership
stuff is in place right now. So
it's kind of- kind of exciting.
Bekah: Yeah, I think it's been
great. And I'd like -- I would just wanna
share what some of our Coffee
Table groups are, just so if you
are listening, you have an idea.
We've got -- at -- well, every
Monday, in Slack and our
announcements channel, it drops all of the
things that are happening this
week. So it gives an overview.
We've got tech interview study
group where they go through job
preparation materials, give each
other feedback, answer questions
and things like that. Meg —
who you heard from this season — is
running the accountability
buddies sessions, where it's,
again, I think job focused or- or
working on projects, that
kind of thing. We have the React
group as well. We have ... let's
see. Indie hackers, and we've got a
new one, which is like a
Virtual Coffee speaking group
where -- actually Kirk, you and I
are up first, next week. Is that
next week, or the week after? Well,
we're giving short speeches. So
we should prepare for those,
right?
Kirk: We should really find out. If it's [chuckles] next week or few weeks.
Bekah: It's in the calendar for
sure.
Kirk: There you go!
Bekah: So [chuckles] I should write something. I know I'm missing
some of the other groups that we
have going on there, but those
are the ones that- that I can see
right now and are coming to ...
my thoughts. So, I don't
know, just like a lot of really
fun stuff in the- the VC's speaking
group — the Virtual Coffee, we've
refer it as VC — is a cool
one that's just started meeting
this past week? I don't know.
The last couple of weeks. So it all kind
of blend together. So [chuckles], we- we
met fairly recently for the first
time and kind of plan things out
and things are growing from
there. So, there's always
something that there's a need
that can be filled or there's an
interest like, honestly, I- I was
thinking about like, "Okay, what
Coffee Table groups would I like
to see?" And I don't know if this
fits into a Coffee Table group,
but, like, I don't know
what to call it ... Happy Hour-
Happy Hour Special Interest
group? I -- it kind of like falls
outside of there, but like
something low-key, let's get
together and hang out. We've done
some happy hours or social hours
before. And- and just like seeing
the community interact in those
ways has been a lot of fun. But
are there other groups that you
two would like to see a Virtual Coffee?
Kirk: It's ... see, this is ... I don't
know if it's different from the
happy hour group, but we've been
talking about VC
karaoke for like, forever.
And I'm- I'm so down. So down with the karaoke.
There's a -- okay. So this is
one that came up just yesterday,
actually. I was talking -- who was I
talking to? People [Bekah chuckles]. And we were
talking about ... oh, yeah- yeah. We were
talking about poetry. And we were like,
where -- if you were gonna share
your poetry and music, like, where do
you put -- content creation is
slightly different. It's not
necessarily content, right? Like,
it's just like -- it's like art for
me that I'm sharing with like
friends. So then it's like, "Hmm. Maybe
that goes into --" I think we have
a -- so -- do we have a channel about crafts? Is it craft --
Bekah: Making stuffs.
Kirk: Yeah. I'm not in it cuz
I thought it was about macaroni,
but it's not [Bekah chuckles]. I get this idea. So yeah. It was -- maybe there-
maybe there's like another space
for that, but, you know, that's --
those- those are the two that
immediately came to mind. But I
feel like there's a ton more
like ... I don't know. I- I think since
the [chuckles] -- since we get -- we got past
the- the time of Bryan [chuckles] making
channels [laughs], we've been a lot more
judicious about them. We made a
channel for making channels,
which I actually think has worked
out pretty well, as like giving
people like a clear space to
discuss wanting certain channels.
The -- yeah. What I like about
the special interest groups is
like, it -- we don't predict them,
right? The members -- someone has
an idea, they will typically like
find some way to poll the
community, you know? Get feedback
and like, general random, if
there's enough interest and
people like hype enough, they give it a try.
And then, like, we, as the
maintainers only come in, like,
"Hey, you're doing an awesome
thing," you know, "Let's see if we
can, like, help it out with it." Yeah.
[Unintelligible] a process, too.
Dan: Yeah. I mean I --
What was that? What did you say?
Kirk: I mean, having a process for that
is good. It's like some things
end up not being like -- they
just -- it's like, okay. Like, if we have
external events, right? Which is
where people can basically, you
know, if they have a thing that's
going on outside of the
community, you can always
like put it in there. A lot
of stuff ends up like, well, this
is probably just an external.
Coffee Tables, or, spec- now I'm
saying special interest groups.
Dan, what have you [chuckles] --
---
Dan: Well, we call them that for
like a year. And then we figured
out Coffee Table groups, which I
like. It's just- it's just the
other one is stuck in my head.
So --
Kirk: Yeah. The- the- the key thing is that
it's- it's a -- by members for members. I
think that's like the- the -- sort of
the core concept, you know? So,
it's not like an outside person
coming in all that it's just like
a seminar hold by our member [??]. So if you're gonna
maybe expand it to everyone, then
it sort of, you know, the ability
to like, make sure it stays like
VC oriented will be diminished,
right? Like, sticking to the CoC,
there's like all these other
things you just can't control if
it's not. So, you know.
Bekah: We- we have talked about some
cross community collaboration.
And I know that there has been
some talk among our members, like
what if this small interest -- oh
my, I did it now! [Deep exhales] Dan. Why you of all people --
Dan: [Unintelligible] [Laughs]
Bekah: [Chuckles] What if our Coffee
Table groups collaborated with
somebody else? Like, you know, had
another -- a community, a
meetup, like, maybe freeCodeCamp
Philly. Meg was talking about
join accountability buddies. And
so there's definitely something
that we're considering. And it -- you
know, it goes back to like, what
are the needs of our members and
the leaders of those groups. So,
you know, it- it -- always talking things
through and figuring out like, is
this a good fit for our
community? Is the priority of
everything that we're doing?
Kirk: Yeah. We, you know,
acknowledging that we can't be
everything for all people. And
also like we can't ... ourselves
necessarily, like, handle like every --
like there's lots of good things
that members might want or like,
but we're just not equipped to
provide those things. So if there's like
a great partnership with somebody
else who is doing that, then
that's awesome. Brian Rinaldi
comes to mind with like
cfe.dev, you know? Like,
consistent guest speakers, great
quality talks, like, that's
something to takes a whole team
to organize and through all that
consistent basis. We, you and I
have the battle [??] for that if he
does. And so like letting
members, "Hey, every two weeks,
you're getting like a high
quality thing that you can just
check out," feels good. Like, everyone
seems both sides are sort of like
getting something out of it. So,
if there's ways to do more of
that, it's great. Yeah. But
those do always require like
extended -- you just have to like
work them out more because now
you have to like check in that
this other group are aligned with
you, you gotta figure out timing,
you gotta -- you have your own
cadence of work, they have their
own cadence work, it becomes this
thing, you know, but -- or not. I don't
think we're opposed to like
anything that doesn't bring value
for them in.
Bekah: Yes, 100%. So, you
know, as we're working through
all of this stuff, there's
obviously still pain points that
we need to solve. So I thought
maybe we could talk a little bit
about, you know, some of the
things that we're still trying to
work through and- and maybe some
of the ideas that we have or
just thoughts that we are
trying to work through.
Dan: Yeah. So I [clears throat], excuse me, I
think one of our based -- I mean, we've
talked about some of the
struggles and, you know, some of
them when we were talking about
why we pause memberships
wh-with regards to having
leadership support and things
like that. But a-another side of
that was -- is just handling
incoming members, right? So I- I
think probably a lot of people
have had the experience of
joining some community at this
quarter, Slack, or whatever,
and being just overwhelmed [chuckles], or
not having any idea what to
do, or- or maybe it's a little
clear, but it's still just a huge
community with a million channels
a-a-and no, you know, personal connection for
you. And so, you put your
name and [chuckles], you know, you fill out
the intro thing and say, "Hello
everybody," and, you know, some
people react and say hi and
stuff, and then- and then it's
kinda -- right [chuckles]? I wouldn't want
that to be -- I mean, if peep- if that's
what happens in Virtual Coffee
that, you know, so be it for- for
a person, but in general, we
don't want that to be that case,
right? And so our -- and this is
why we've stuck pretty hard with
our- our -- how you join Virtual
Coffee is by coming to one of our
coffees, right? First, before any
Slack invites happen, things like
that. [Clears throat] One of the difficulties
with that is- is -- it was a very
manual process, right? The --
you know, Zoom has its own
authentication stuff, and there's
no way to have people signed into
like a Zoom account, all of the
same account. Otherwise -- I mean, it --
or- or unless they were paid members,
right? So if you are on a work
Zoom or something, you know, that- that
your work is paying for every
single seat [chuckles]. And so, that's
obviously not a- a solution for us. So
when you join a Virtual Coffee's
Zoom, you're just joining on your
own account, and you can fill out
whatever details you want.
There's no way for us to managing
that. What that means is
there's no auto -- there's -- it's
very complicated and possibly
sometimes impossible to connect a
Zoom account with a person, you
know? And whether they've joined
or not before, and things like
that. And so, our solution was
just to have people fill out the
membership form and, you know,
we'd have a little link after
coffees and they would fill out
the form and then we would
essentially go and make sure that
they actually came and then send
them a Slack invite, sort of all
manually -- wa- wait, peep- thus,
maintainers were just doing
that. And that was hard too,
you know? I mean, that was time
consuming even when there was
just five people that, you know,
joined that week, it took up
time. And we have more and more
people coming, things like
that. And, so, that's one of the
challenges that I'd like to nail
down i-is just like what- what it means
to be a member? How to- how to
join things, you know?
Those sorts of topics, right? And
then how can we- how can we keep
the sort of intimate nature of-
of joining Virtual Coffee
while supporting multiple
members -- you know, more and
more, a larger and larger group
of people, and then also how to
onboard them gracefully and
things like that. Not overwhelm
people and not call with them
with, you know, a million
channels and huge group of people
that they don't know anything
about. So, that's -- we -- we've- we've
been talking a lot about that
too over the past few
months.
Bekah: Yeah. And along with that,
when you have more people, you're
gonna need more moderation,
right? So for us, moderation
hasn't been a huge issue, but as
you onboard more people and have
less of a personal relationship
with every single person that
comes in, it- it becomes a little bit
trickier, right? And so you wanna
make sure that you're prepared
for something that might happen
and dealing with those types of
issues, and making sure that
everybody has access to that
information that they need. Not
everybody needs access to all of
the information. And so, providing
each group of volunteers with
that information, making sure
that they're up to date and can
communicate openly with each
other when something needs to be
updated or changed is -- those are
also priorities and pain points
that we're trying to work
through. Kirk, do you have
anything to add?
Kirk: I think we should go
back to trial by combat for
membership. I think we should go
back to the old ways. Now,
no. I think you guys, you hit
the nail on the head. I was just
thinking through things
being conscientious. You can only
get so far, just kind of like
going with the flow and
eventually, like, if the flow
becomes like a delusion, you kinda
need to have a plan.
Yeah. And it's- it's- it's just us sort of
being a lot more thoughtful about
stuff and kind of stepping back
and saying, "Okay, if something
works now, why does it work? Is
there a way to like, clarify
that so we can reference why, new
people can reference why," and
like, we start, you know, building that up.
You know, we recently had
like something that make -- the maintainers
were discussing and were like,
"Hey, is this in the Code of
Conduct?" And we were like, "No,"
like, "We should probably like put
it in there," right? Just so we
don't forget later if it happens
again, there's like something
that we can reference and go,
"Well, we're not just making it up
on the fly as we go along." Or, I
mean, we are, but like the things
that we wanna keep [chuckles], we're
putting it somewhere where it- it
can, you know, stay. Yeah, I don't know.
And there's something about like
habits and traditions. If
something is good and provides
good value for you, you should
like find a way to keep it. And
if something is not providing
good value for you, then, like, you
should set it free. But it's
hard to do that if you're not
keeping track of those things.
So, yeah.
Bekah: But I think along --
Kirk: [Unintelligible] thing, we can totally ... I'm ready. Dan, are you ready? Dan is [unintelligible].
Dan: I'm always ready.
Kirk: There you go. Bekah, you're ready?
Bekah: Always. Always ready.
I- I think along with all this
too, when we're thinking about
these things, we also have to
think about them on a much larger
scale, right? So, if it works now,
will it work if we have 500
more people? And the biggest
value of Virtual Coffee, I think,
comes from the intimacy those
small group connections. And so, I
say 500 people and like, that
sounds scary to me. But, you know,
there's potential for that.
There -- we would love to have as
many people as we can, if we can
replicate that same intimacy. And
so trying to figure out how do
you do that? If you add another
coffee chat, are- are 500 people
just going to suddenly appear in
Slack? I mean, they wouldn't
suddenly appear right there.
We'll be [chuckles] -- we're not going to get
500 new people overnight. But
that's something that we have to
think about. I don't think
it's bad to have another pause
and membership in the future. Now
there are some communities that
have opened membership as one-
one month during a quarter or
something. Or one week they
onboard new folks who are coming
into the community and otherwise
they're closed. So, there are a
lot of different ways that you
can build that into the process,
give everybody a break, kind of
like a vacation to pause,
breathe, think things through.
But, you know, ultimately we
have to be thinking about how do
we replicate — exactly what Kirk
was saying — is- is good about this
community as we scale as well.
Kirk: Yeah. And there's something
that's been bouncing around in my
head a lot about, like, community
size. And I have a working
hypothesis, which is that I ... don't
think community size is
necessarily a problem. I feel
like it's almost like a
precursor, like, having the
community getting bigger can lead
to other things. Like, those
things are actually the problem
or like a lack of certain things. But if
you know what it is and you're
prepared for it, I don't think
it's like -- so, like, obviously
suddenly having 500 members would
probably be a bad thing, you
know? But I guess if there was an
increase in 500 members over
the course of like 10 years,
like -- I don't know. That's a
bad thing. So the problem might
not be the 500 members. It's just
like, what does it mean when new
people enter the group, right?
And we found ... too many people
in at once, it starts to get a
little-
Bekah: Dilutes the experience or
something.
Kirk: -it gets a little -- yeah. Well, it gets a
little -- it's like more strangers
in a room. And as much as
possible we try and like remove
the feeling of like strangers in
a room, you know? Like, there -- it's like, this is
like friend-I-don't-know-too-well-yet versus
like, person that I- I- I just -- I
don't want to interact with. But
we also know like having fresh
new faces is just a way of -- it
just -- it keeps things fun, it
keeps things healthy.
Communities are dynamic systems.
People enter, people leave,
people return. And like, being able
to like handle all those steps of
your journey as a community
member is really important for
like having a good for me, you
know? So, yeah. Let's say we have
like a thousand members, but
we're probably not gonna have
like a thousand people active at
the same time. They'll come in
waves, they'll come and go, and
it- it, you know, there's -- I
think there's a way of like
living in that space that can
feel really good. Like, very
quickly you figured out, "Oh, it's
not so much." Zooms can have lots
of people. As long as when people
finally start talking, they're in
like a small enough space that it
feels comfortable. And that's how
the breakout room started.
So -- and I think there's like
similar techniques, so we can
grow and not necessarily it's
like ... I don't know. This will
become like a thesis at some
point. But the key metric may not
be total numbers, but sort of
like, how are the people
interacting with other people?
Are they still getting a chance
for like intimate moments with a
few members at any given time
and we can make that work? And we
think we can make that work. We
also think we can have like the
greatest conference of all time.
We have big thoughts.
Bekah: Next summer.
Kirk: Am I right?
Bekah:  Well, I'm gonna
push back a little bit, Kirk. Cuz I disagree slightly with
what you're saying. I do
think the total number matters.
And I keep going back to -- it's
Dunbar's number that you can
maintain 150 connections at once.
And I think that- that allows for
Slack intimacy. So, I think that
we also have to think through two
things here, right? We're
thinking about, like, what does it
look like, in the breakout rooms,
in Tuesdays and Thursdays? We
like to keep it to eight to 10
people per room. And I think that- that
is- that is good. But I also
think that having that small
experience where you know
people in Slack is important. And
it is tricky for the reasons that
you say. Because people come in
and they come out all of the time,
you know? Somebody has -- is
super active, and then they get a
new job, and then you don't hear
from them as much, right? Or they
can't participate anymore, which
is totally fine. So it's a -- this like
constant flow of people coming
in, so, you know, we might have --
might say we have 500 people in
Slack, but we certainly don't
have 500 active people in Slack.
But I do think that that idea of
having 150 people says something
for the intimacy of the group.
It's like their extended network
of people. You can go to an
in-person conference and be like,
"Oh, I know that person there from
Virtual Coffee. So I'm going to
talk to them because I'm standing
in this corner alone by myself."
Maybe that was me [chuckles]. But I- I
would like to figure out, or I --
you know, I think that we're
making progress towards
figuring out how to maintain that
intimacy in both places. So I
think that maybe there is a world
where we do have 500 people in
what- whatever platform we're on, but
can still maintain that, like, 150
person asynchronous
communication intimacy, as well
as those breakout room
communications.
Dan: Yeah, I- I- I agree. And I- I
think that [clear throat] to like, kind of
combine what both of you were
saying together, you know, it's the --
like the large number isn't the met-
isn't the important metric, you
know? And I think that's the
biggest, like, thing that I love,
what- what was Kirk was saying was
like, if we- we- we aggressively
don't have metrics [laughs], but like,
if we did, like, that — and it was
possible — that would be the thing
to measure on, right? Is, like, are
our members making intimate
connections, you know? Are our
members, like, part- part
of a group, you know? You know
what I mean? And so ... and I
totally agree with you, Bekah.
Like, i-it's like, it- it -- when you say,
oh, it -- the number, it doesn't
matter, you know? It's -- you're gonna --
like, the number does matter,
right? And whether that 150
numbers is- is, you know, feels right
or not is- is probably up in the
air. But like, it's- it's one of
those things where it's ... and
this is why we pause membership.
And this is why we're like
thinking so hard is because we
want to be able to keep the- to
keep the ... intimacy and the
sort of shape of our [chuckles] community
while growing. And that's hard and not a
lot of people have done it. And we
think we can crack it, and I
think we're pretty close,
honestly. And -- but, yeah.
It's- it's -- and it's very
important to us, I think. And
I think it's important to our
community members as well. So
I, you know, when you are on out-
outside of the community of
Virtual Coffee, or maybe you're
brand new member, it might not be
as clear. Or maybe if you haven't
thought about it [laughs], you know, and-
and you just kind of along for
the ride. I know for- for my -- at
least personally, like sometimes
I just don't -- I don't think about
why something feels great, or like
why something is because I enjoy
it, you know what I mean? And
that's okay too [laughs]. Like, it's
okay to just enjoy things. But
like, this is why we wanted to
talk about this. This is- this is the other
side of the coin. And it's like [clear throat],
we use it so that we can help
support it. We are thinking very hard
about why, you know? And- and- and how we
can do more. So, yeah. And it's-
it's hard, but it's fun. It's
also fun and very gratifying too.
So ...
Kirk: There are people --
Dan: I'm excited.
Kirk: Yeah. So I'm just gonna-
just gonna set the tone by
saying a bunch of buzzwords
related to this scalability,
continuous integration,
[chuckles] continuous deployment. Because I
can't help -- even as we're talking
about this and like, "I dunno. Like,
kind of feels like that other
stuff that I talk too much about."
[Unintelligible] it's- it's sort of -- it's-
it's the same -- it's- it's a
similar concept of ... there is
a thing that you are a part of
and you're working on and, you
know, if- if that big core
concept is there, and like the
people are there, and the energy
is there, it grows. And that's good.
But there are different problems
at different sizes. And like part
of keeping something going is
knowing like, not just how to be
the like plucky up and coming
thing, but also how to be this
sort of like mature, ongoing
thing. And we're- we're at
that point. Which is a good point
to be, you know? I don't know
what the- the tech equivalent is.
Series C ... I don't know the words.
Bekah: [Chuckles] That's right. We're Series
C community.
Kirk: Sure. That sounds fine.
Dan: Capital C.
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: You can tell the nearest --
Dan: Or a capital C plus plus
community [laughs].
Kirk: Oh, no.
Bekah: Not, Dan.
Dan: I see if I can get Kirk to
yell at me about C++
again [laughs].
Kirk: I mean, I didn't yell at you. You were just [Dan laughs] like -- you were like walk the difference between C# and C++.
And then I immediately thought of
like a thousand thoughts at a time. I'm
like, "Will you give [??] it back or watch it," you know?
Dan: Oh, man.
Bekah: Dan, you're derailing us.
We have done so well. We- we-
Dan: I -- listen. I --
Bekah: -recovered from the initial intro
question and then we were -- we're
good. And then you were like-
Dan: I have a --
Bekah: -I'm going to break this up before
the end of the podcast.
Dan: I just -- there is- there is a set limit of the
amount of time that I can be
serious for [laughs] the amount of time
straight. I'm sorry. I've -- I feel like I'm
proud of us too. I feel like we
held it together for a long time.
And we had some good- some
good thoughts and stuff. But then Kirk
started yelling at me about C++
and it all just went up from there.
Bekah: He didn't yell at you during
this podcast.
Dan: Yeah, no, no. I had him do it. Yeah.
No, it's -- that's what- that's exactly what
happened. We're all --
Kirk: [Unintelligible] you let me do it. It is ... this was [laughs] ... one [unintelligible].
Bekah: Okay, listen. I think the
key takeaway from this podcast is
Dan is the instigator in every,
every one of these situations,
okay. Go back and listen to all
the podcast episodes. It is Dan.
Every time.
Dan: Nope. There's always
somebody else there. And there --
the -- their- their fault.
Bekah: Then it's- it's you [??] [chuckles].
Dan: If I was just on my own, I would get in no
trouble.
Bekah: Oh yeah.
Dan: And that's not true [laughs]. Oh- oh, also -- oh, no, this will
be out ... this is gonna come out
in a couple of weeks. So we'll
already have a couple, but Kirk
and I are starting a new
streaming series called
TypeScript Tuesdays. And --
Kirk: I just want to --
Dan: So, there'll be a couple of -- so- so come find us on the Virtual
Coffee's stream on Twitch. It's VirtualCoffeeIO-
Kirk: I just wanna-
Bekah: VirtualCoffeeIO.
Dan: -I think like that. But,
yeah. I imagine that Kirk is
going to be yelling at me a lot
there too. So if you like hearing
Kirk yell at me [laughs], he's holding his
breath very aggressively right
now. So [Dan and Bekah laugh], come join us on
Twitch every Tuesday as well [laughs].
Bekah: Yeah. And I think that's
something that we're working on
too. Like, while membership is
closes, how do we provide ... nope.
My brain stopped. How do we
provide --
Kirk: Finding [unintelligible] spaces where we get to
interact with people outside of
the community?
Bekah: Yes. Value to the external
tech community.
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: That was what I like to go.
Dan: Yes! Oh! And Bekah started
that Twitter ... that was --
Bekah: Chat. Yes!
Dan: Tweet -- Twitter chat. That's what we call it. Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. So --
Dan: How did that go?
Bekah: It went pretty well.
It was fun. I have some ideas for
some ways to update it. So,
basically I took the intro
question and the backpocket topic
and put it out there for
asynchronous Twitter chat last
week. I did it on -- I think, a
Wednesday. So that was prior to
doing the Thursday coffee. And
I'd love to be able to combine
those two. So if we have related
topics, then what might work
in the future is having an intro
question for people to get
to know each other and including
both of those conversations. And,
you know, both of our- our
members who weren't able to
attend can engage in those and
the external community as well.
So, we'll try it out for a while,
see how it goes. And
hopefully people will find value in it.
Kirk: My topics will never be
related [chuckles].
Bekah: [Chuckles] They --- Kirk. We're going to
meet on Monday and we're going to
figure it out.
Kirk: My topics only exist to sow
the seeds of chaos. And then I
have to spend half a day feeling --
Bekah: Loki. You're Loki. I think next
time we do this, we should -- we --
our intro question should be
like, what character -- what
super villain would one of the
other co-host B.
Dan: Hm. I'll put --
Bekah: So, like you, Dan, would have to say Kirk's super
villain character, Kirk --
Kirk: So you're talking through him. You just say --
Dan: Okay. But we're saving-
we're saving this for next time.
Kirk: Yeah, I'm like -- I'm putting --
Bekah: Or unless you- unless you
have it now.
Kirk: Putting the thought in your
head now. [Unintelligible] Doctor Doom. He's evil.
Dan: I don't- I don't- I don't have to think about it -- yeah. Wait. Doctor- Doctor Doom? That what you said?
Kirk: Yes. Wait, what was that
tone? Whoa. Whoa-whoa-whoa.
Dan: Oh, I thought you said Doctor
Who for a second. And I was a bit like,
Doctor Who. I don't think he's a
villain.
Kirk: Ah [unintelligible].
Dan: When you said Doctor Doom, and then makes more
sense.
Kirk: I can- I can upset an
entire fandom right now [laughs].
Dan: [Laughs] I mean, go for it. I -- I'm
not a Doctor Who -- I mean, I'm not a
not-fan-
Kirk: You can [unintelligible] --
Dan: -but I'm not a fan
either, so you're not gonna make me upset.
Bekah: I've only seen one episode of
Doctor Who and I think mannequins
came alive or something. And I
was like, it was not for me.
Kirk: They call themselves "Whovians" and
it sounds like children [unintelligible].
Bekah: You mean from "Whoville"? With-
Kirk: Exactly! [Unintelligible]
Bekah: -little Cindy Lou Who?
Holding hands and sing?
Dan: Cindy Lou Whovian.
Kirk: What were we talking about?
Bekah: What a great podcast this
is and we're glad that everybody
has listened to [crosstalk 00:55:01] all of Season
5. Come back for Season 6,
to hear answers [laughs].
Dan: Yes. [Laughs] Please- please stay subscribed.
Kirk: If you're listening --
Bekah: If you like our podcast, please
give us 5 stars and write a
comment to help other people find
our podcast too.
Dan: Yes. If you write a comment that ... oh, I was gonna say
something ... [laughs] I don't want to
prejudge the comments.
Kirk: Dan speak --
Dan: I was gonna say, if you write a
comment that's interesting, we
might read it on the podcast.
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: But like, don't make that -- you know, don't let that stop you
from writing a comment that is ... not
interesting [laughs].
Bekah: We find every comment interesting.
Dan: Yes [laughs]!
Bekah: So write the comment.
Dan: We would hear from
everybody. So, yeah. If you
wanna send us any questions
that you'd like us to answer in
the future or any ideas for
the podcast, things like that,
we're always excited to hear
any feedback, or questions, or
anything like that. So, yeah,
podcast@virtualcoffee.io,
or Twitter, or Slack, or any of
that stuff too.
Bekah: Yeah. Thanks joining us for
Season 5.
Dan: Yeah. Thank you.
Kirk: Thanks for coming to MY
podcast [Dan and Bekah chuckle]. See you later on MY podcast. Like, I let
Bekah and Dan be on because I'm
nice and I never yell.
Bekah: Thanks for allowing us to
be on your podcast, Kirk.
Kirk: You're very welcome.
Dan: Kirk, I'll talk to you on
Tuesday when ar- arguing with
you about tip- TypeScript [chuckles].
Kirk: With hushed tones. And [unintelligible].
Dan: [Laughs] Okay. Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!