Dan: Hello, and welcome to a
special Kirk Day Bonus Episode
of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Dan and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast usually sharing
their stories and what they've
learned uh today we had a little
bit of a different time, Bekah
actually it came up to Cleveland
uh where i work And uh we
actually met in person for the
first time ever after knowing
each other for over three years
and it was fun and today is also
a Kirk Day which you will hear
about uh A little bit later in
the episode and uh also Kirk.
Joins us as well and it was
really fun and it was a fun
little thing we streamed it live
we had some people sharing in
the
comments And we thought we would
share it on the podcast stream
as
well so enjoy and uh next week
we will get back to our regular
schedule Hey, we were muted the
whole time. Why did you do it? I
was just thinking in my head.
Oh, I hope the sound sounds
good. It
was like, I looked at the mute
thing and
Bekah: just so everybody knows,
I just did the most amazing
intro
that I've ever done.
Dan: It's good.
Bekah: So here's my not so great
intro. We are coming from
Lakewood, Ohio. We are
celebrating national Kirk day or
international Kirk day. As we
more fondly, know it at Virtual
Coffee,
Dan: inner galactic
Bekah: galactic, inter I was
gonna say disciplinary. That is
not the right word dimensional
interdimensional Kirk day,
because it is preserved
everywhere because perk is
awesome and amazing. And we like
to celebrate Kirk as much as we
can. Dan, would you like to
introduce what international
dimensional disciplinary Kirk
date is?
Dan: Um, so was it just a year
ago or a year ago today? Yes,
Kirk, um, had a tweet. Where he
showed me that I should read
that. I feel like I should have
read the, the right text. This
is
it, right? Yeah. So Kirk tweeted
today, we achieved the dream. My
made a function called Missy
Elliott. That takes data
structure, flips it and reverses
it. I have ascended. And then,
um, very shortly after that, uh,
Missy Elliott responded, replied
on Twitter, um, actual Missy
Elliott, not, not a fake Missy
Elliott and, and said something
like, yeah, she said, wow, I'm
humbly I'm. So humbly grateful,
much love to y'all. And, um,
that
was the beginning of a legend.
It was, it was really, really
awesome. And, uh, everybody saw
it and perks, you know, Twitter.
Uh, let's see what the, uh, It,
it Kirk's sweet, got a one
13,300
retweets. Uh, and it's really
good stuff.
Bekah: Yeah. But not only that,
not only was it just YouTube,
but
it expanded. So this was not a
one day event. It was, it was on
Twitter. It was on LinkedIn. It
was on Reddit. Everybody loves
Dan: Kirk. Yes. And we all are
already loved Kirk. And this is
just a sort of celebration of,
of, uh, the rest of the world.
Right. Becoming aware
Bekah: of, of the Kirk. So maybe
we should tell our Kirk origin
story.
Dan: Um, I think that's a great
idea. Do you want me to go
first?
Do you want to go first? You go
first. I mean, I don't have a
specific, I don't remember the
like moment right. Of, of
meeting
her. Cause that was back in the
time of. Virtual Coffee being,
uh, a little it's a little
smaller, you know? And so we had
slack, we had, um, the coffees
obviously. Um, but, and I'm not
a
person who, I don't know, I
don't know a lot of people, I
don't
really like people don't stick
in my brain until, until we like
interact. You know what I mean?
And so my thing with Kirk was,
was really the heck Tober
festivals really like leading up
to October Fest that year. So it
was two years ago. And, um,
Bekah
and I, you know, we worked
together and I had known Sarah
because she was. You know, like
she was already like helping
them
with virtual profit and all that
stuff. And, um, I could just
kinda wrote me in for
Oktoberfest
Bekah: to like help. Okay. And
to be fair, you were like, if
you
need help with anything, let me
know. I may have said that. So
if
you offer to help,
Dan: you will. Uh, it's true.
Um, yes, most people find that
out
about eventually. Um, but yeah,
so Kirk was there too. Right.
And
I have, like, I like, you know,
I'd heard his name or whatever.
I, you know, we had been, he was
still TK that's right. He was
just the mysterious TK, which
made me, you know, what to know
him more, you know, because
anyway, that has a mysterious
Bekah: name, you know?
Dan: And, uh, yeah. And then
that, so that it was like that
September leading up to, uh,
That October, it was a lot of
Kirk and
I were, I mean, I was working on
the site and that's when the
first like this, the current
version of the site happened,
you
know, we made the leap like
that. We should probably have a
site
for Virtual Coffee where we're
doing all that stuff. And so I
would be up in the middle of the
night. Uh, and Kirk was usually
there too. And we would like
talk and, you know, throw ideas
back
and forth and think about
things. And then he was doing a
lot of
the work on the, I dunno, more
social aspect of it, the
documentation, you know,
thinking about how like people
are going
to interact with Virtual Coffee
and like how, uh, we need
resources for maintainers and
what those could look like and
things like that. And so I
gained a lot of like both, it
was like
fun to hang out with them. And
again, a lot of like respect for
him, you know, at the same time.
So, um, so yeah, and then after
that, it was just like, we're
just talking every day and had
been doing that for. The last
million years, I don't, it feels
like I don't, I don't know all
the dimensions, you know, in, in
multiple dimensions, I'd say,
uh, if we're gonna use MCU
terminology though, Kirk would
be like an XSP, right. So
there's
only like one Kirk yes. Across
the dimensions. Yes. He's Arco
is
prime Kirkland.
Bekah: Yeah. That's what I mean.
Yeah, for sure. He's the right
Kirk.
Dan: Exactly.
Bekah: I will tell my Kirk
origin story. I don't remember
it
exactly, but I have known Curt
longer than most of the people
I've known at Virtual Coffee.
But back when I knew Kirk, he
was
like a DVO Python image or a
snake. I caught, he was not, I
didn't know his face. And then
he started coming to Virtual
Coffee
and. I am really, um, like
nervous when I meet new people.
And then I was like, I think
this person knows me and I had
to try
and figure it out. And he would
sit in this office, like with a
slag behind him and everybody's
wearing masks back then when you
were on zoom. And so I'm like,
who is this person that is
coming? I'm very nervous about
them. Um, and then Kirk kept
showing up. I'm like, okay, this
is like, this, this person might
be my friend. I think maybe
we're moving into friendship
right now.
And then when we were moving
into heck Tober vest, I was
like, Hmm,
I don't know who suggested it.
Somehow. Kirk ended up on the
HEC
Tober Fest team and it was, um,
me Dan, Sarah, Brian, and Kirk.
And I feel like me, Sarah, Dan
and Ryan were like talk dot,
dot,
dot, dot, dot, dot. Why don't we
think about this for a second,
like you used to be probably
shed. So Kirk was, uh, always
doing a great job of, um, roping
us all back to having productive
conversations and making
progress on all the things that
we were
really excited about doing and
making sure that they happen.
And
like, for me, I had not really.
I ever heard about
documentation.
Like you talk about
documentation, put like, what is
that thing? And then like, Kirk
was like, breaking it down. This
is why documentation is
important. And then, you know,
Kirk has a teaching background
too. And so it was like, okay,
this is starting to click a
little bit more for me. And to
like, show how you can help more
people through the documentation
became, um, something that was
like a change in my life, you
know, like no big deal, but
that's all. Um, so all right,
I'm
going to check out the chat now.
That's my, my Kirk origin story,
and this is how he's become to
be my best friend ever
Dan: since. Yeah. Uh, so we just
got a comment from David saying,
so cool to see you in the same
place, physical physically, yet.
This is the first time that we
have like actually met in real
life. And we started working
with. When did we start
Bekah: working together? July?
This will be, so it would,
would've been three years
Dan: in July before Virtual
Coffee. Like we were working
together before it started
Bekah: Dan fired me. And that's
how Virtual Coffee started
Dan: As soon as I said that, I
knew you were going to say that
I
did not
Bekah: fire. My kids got sent
home from school and then I came
home and Dan was like, sorry,
you're fired. Good luck.
Dan: I mean, sometimes you have
to fire. I didn't fire you.
Okay.
You were a contractor, so I just
stopped paying you and you
stopped doing work. You're the
worst. Uh, in my defense, I
didn't have any money to pay you
with. I didn't
Bekah: have any work for you to
do all right. Five minutes.
Fine.
I'll be fair. It was pandemic.
And there was no work. So he
fired me on accident.
Dan: Apparently Nick knew you're
going to say that as well.
You're
becoming predictable,
Bekah: but I feel like we've had
a lot of new members that might
not have known that you fired me
many times ago.
Dan: Um, so, uh, any way. Yes.
Um, so I don't know about you,
Bekah. I spent a lot of time.
I'm like, okay. So what do I
wear
when I meet a person for the
first time that I've like worked
closely with for three years,
obviously virtual, probably
stuff. I wore the t-shirt and
the hoodie. I just wear
Bekah: the
Dan: assignment. Yeah. Well, we
didn't talk about it ahead of
time. I almost like texted you.
I almost asked you and I should
have, because then we could have
just been totally,
Bekah: you know, oh, wait, Arjun
joined and wants to know who
fired me. Dan fired
Dan: me. No, I did not fire you.
I hate this. I'm shutting this
stream down,
Bekah: so, okay. So maybe let's
go back a little bit so I can
tell the full story and give Dan
the credit that he is owed. Um,
I'm a career changer. I spent 10
years teaching college, English,
and I went to bootcamp. And when
I graduated, I put out a tweet
saying that I was looking for a
job and Dan responded
Dan: not really, but seriously.
Bekah: So I did not. Um, I
didn't take any coding tests or
have to
do any. Strange problems that
make no difference in the world.
And so, uh, we worked together
until the pandemic hit and then
everything shut down. So, yeah.
So then
Dan: as soon as I had worked
coming back in that you had
worked coming back in to, you
never say thank you. Um, yeah,
it
was a re it was a rough summer.
Bekah: It was a weird summer. It
was really rough. And that's how
Virtual Coffee started too,
because I was getting signed
with
interviews with kids at home and
trying to figure out like what
life was like. And then I put
out this week, does anybody want
to
meet up for Virtual Coffee? And
we just kept going with it. And,
and somewhere along the line I
pulled Dan in to cause he owed
me
for firing me.
Dan: So here's the one thing I'm
so used to, uh, like talking to
you on zoom, we're sitting right
next to each other, but we have
the like zoom monitor on the
screen. And so I have been like
looking at, I keep looking at
you on the screen instead of,
instead
of like you next to me, I don't
even
Bekah: understand.
Dan: Right. Exactly. Yeah.
Right. Do I look to camera?
Yeah. No,
it's weird. Um, good, weird. But
it's, it's weird, you know?
Bekah: Yeah. Okay. Let's see.
Let me look at this chat. Um,
Yes,
Nick. Exactly. Dan responded.
I'm looking for someone to fire
eventually. Yes, I am totally
Dan: wired eventually.
Bekah: No, I had no coding
tests. We had a conversation. I
don't
know if Dan remembers it, but I
remember,
Dan: um, I mean, I didn't know
what I was doing either. I mean,
this is the first time I ever,
and to be clear, like you
weren't
an employee, so, you know, my
whole thing was contractor, you
know, cause I'm a contractor
too, but, uh, yeah, I'd never
done
that before. And like, I really
jumped into like very ADHD
style,
like no real plan, no real, you
know, guidelines for myself or
for anybody else or anything
like that. And it worked out
very
well, but, um, yeah, it was, it
was, it was, it was fun. Um, uh,
haven't missed any, uh, you
know, uh, I
Bekah: dunno.
Dan: Uh, yeah. So, um, you know,
with like insurance, I've heard
is
Bekah: a good thing to know.
Insurance is nice. It's useful.
Didn't have that for awhile. So,
yeah. So I've been working a new
full-time job, um, and Dan has
been,
Dan: thank you. If I didn't fire
you there'll be no Virtual
Coffee. I didn't fire you
Bekah: so I can play it over and
over.
Dan: I blamed melts, honestly,
for that, for that one, we went
to a mill in here in Lakewood
and it's, I, we walked past the
first
place. I wanted to go found out,
close for lunch on the weekdays,
which I didn't know. Um, but as
we were walking past Milt, I was
like, this place makes you want
to go take a nap after like,
after. And it's, it's true.
Yeah. I mean the two years
probably
probably didn't help that
either. But, uh, I blame, yeah.
I blame
that on that and the mental
lapse. But once you stand from
that, I did not fire anybody.
Bekah: I mean, what is your
definition of fire? Okay. He was
like, I'm no longer going to
employ you or give you work or
money. So anybody out there
please let me know. So now he's
roped into Virtual Coffee
forever.
Dan: Anyway. Let's go back to, I
was saying that I was right and
that everything that I did was
good. I'm pretty sure that's
what
she said.
Bekah: Well, Dan, it sucks that
you fired back and that was
pretty awful, but at least we
got Virtual Coffee out of it and
you
can fire me any day. I don't
even know what that means.
Sometimes I
like very frequently will spit
out water when I drink it. So I
need to try very hard to not
drink and laugh at
Dan: the same time. Yeah.
Somebody's episode. That was a
really good one to that. Oh
yeah. I watched you do it. I
watched
you swallow or like, you know,
start drink water. And then
Helen
said something hilarious and,
uh, yeah, we, uh, both have a
problem
with, sometimes we, you know, I
don't know if you could get this
in zoom where you, why you're
not like making, I kind of take
what's a real person, you know,
but, but like, you almost can,
like sometimes you know, where,
like, you know, you're looking
at
that person that, you know,
they're looking at you, you
know,
and, uh, you know, we've had
some, we've had some meltdowns
in
the past. We try to keep it on
the podcast, but there's been
some. There's been some moments.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. There are
many moments on the podcast
we've
progressed so much. When we
first started the podcast, I
would
laugh uncontrollably for the
first five minutes. I could
never
do the introduction. I maybe
there's. I don't know if there's
any,
Dan: for sure. We sure have it
all recorded. I don't know if,
yeah. I don't know how much
video we have of it, but like,
uh, we
have a lot of views of, of like
trying to do the intros and
stuff. It's so funny. Cause
you're so good at it. Like
you're
so good at like this stuff most
of the time and like it's the
recorded nature of it. It's like
the reading, the script
Bekah: part. It was like, I was
so nervous. Like I was like
nervousness decided to turn
itself into laughters and like I
could not stop, which I guess is
like better than crying or
sweating, which I have also gone
through those phases as well.
Dan: Yeah, definitely one of my
main skills.
Bekah: Um, just checking out the
chat. Promoted to customer.
Dan: Yes. Congratulations. I
don't know pressure valves.
Bekah: Yeah. As soon as he
probably would fire me for all
of
this it's okay. Oh my sure. I'm
an introvert. I dunno. I feel
like maybe I'm an ambivert
ambivert. I am especially like
intensely nervous and shy and
exhausted when I'm around people
that I don't know. But like when
I'm around people that I know or
people that I'm friends with
and, um, I can often like find
that
energy. I think that extroverts
Dan: have, for me, it's, for me,
it's um, sort of knowing exactly
what, like I was supposed to do
in a situation. That's what I'm
comfortable. Right. And so like
the. This is just you and me
chatting, you know, and like,
we've practiced this obviously.
So it's like, you
Bekah: know,
Dan: can't you tell we did,
like, we did like, uh, this is
yeah.
Very polished, uh, you know,
thing. No. Um, but what I mean
is
like, uh, I know what socially
is expected of me in this
situation.
You know what I mean? And so if
I'm in coffee, like one of our
coffee chats and in a room with
a whole bunch of people, I don't
know. I'm not like I don't have
a problem. Like I don't, I don't
get like, awkward like that,
but, um, but when I go to like
go to a
conference, right. And then
there's like a social hour or
lunch or whatever, and I don't
know people, and I don't know
exactly what I'm supposed to do
or my role in, you know, that's
when I get like, that's when I
get like super and I just go and
sit down by myself and put my
headphones on or something, or I
don't put my headphones on, but
like, cause I'm fine. If
somebody
comes and talks to me, like,
that's cool. Cause that's like
a.
Hey, this is what you're
supposed to do now, you know,
but like
walking up to somebody and
trying to like, that's, that's
what I,
like. I really struggled with
that. That's the kind of stuff
that I struggled with, you know,
is those, those like situations,
uh, Where it's an unfamiliar
territory or like, you know, I
don't know.
Bekah: Yeah. So it's like that.
So my dad was just telling my
oldest, my 12 year old, he was
talking about how great it is to
talk to random people in the
garb and talking to them like
that is
a terrible thing. My dad loves
it. Like he will go up to any
person and he will probably try
and say what their name, he'll
ask them their name and hope
continually try and repeat that
throughout the conversation, but
then forget their name and use a
different name. That's wrong. He
tries very hard to be personal.
Um, but that was like, um, my
worst nightmare talking to a
stranger that I don't know about
things.
Dan: Yeah. No, my father-in-law
is huge big on that. And he was
a
bartender and stuff and like, he
just doesn't naturally, like, he
doesn't almost like impulsively,
you know, but like, like, uh, in
an elevator or something, he'll
just like chat up and they
probably don't want to talk to
him. I mean, like not like he's
not being creepy. Right. And
he's not like hitting on anybody
or
anything like that, but he's.
Bekah: Talking to them.
Dan: great guy. You know what I
mean? And like, but that's just
how he is, you know? Uh, yeah.
Uh, somebody said something
about
Joe said, so what do I do with
my hands? That's a big thing
with me
too. And honestly that's like
what I, one of the things I like
about the, this, this phase in
our collective lives of the zoom
stuff is that most times, so
right now my camera's like
scooted back a little bit so
that we can both fit in. Most
time you
can see my hands. And I've
honestly, like during this thing
had been like seeing my hands in
the video and been like, oh God,
get these out of here. You know?
Cause I'm just like, like, I
don't know, what do I do with my
hands? Big problem. Yeah. What
do
I do with my whole body? Like
standing in a group of people.
How do I stay? You know, like
seriously, like I I've struggled
with that. You know, like I do
just put my hands in my pockets
or, you know, I don't
Bekah: know. I like pockets and
I just don't make enough pockets
for women. It's like, even
earlier, Dan and I were like
sitting at this conference table
talking like I move around a lot
and I've like recently become
more aware of how much I move by
seeing other people on camera.
And then I'm like constantly, I
think someone once gave me like
feedback, don't move your hands
so much. It's distracting. Like
whatever, like I'm gonna move my
hands as much as I want it
because I can't. I said, we've
got spinny, Dan's got so many
chairs. So I got to do a lot of
spinning. This is, this is what
I do. I move all the time. But
like
when I'm in front of the camera
in my office, like I very much,
I
have to try very hard to sit
still and not move my hands
everywhere because that is not
my natural state of.
Dan: I ended there. Yes. Um,
Bekah: we do the wave one time
at Virtual Coffee in my breakout
room. We like, we, we
alphabetized everybody and then
everybody went, it was very
exciting
Dan: to Minnesota. Marie had to
go um, yeah,
Bekah: we should. Um, is, is
Kirk around? Can we bring Kirk
on?
Dan: I dunno, it is, uh, Kirk
day, which is where we started.
He responded well, that was 20
minutes ago, I guess. Are you
dealing in, should I give him
okay. We'll see if I can get
Bekah: her on him. Our
celebrity, our resident
celebrity.
Dan: It'll be funny. Uh, because
once we get another person on
this call, You and me we'll be
in one box and, oh man, this
Bekah: is crazy. Rick is at
work. What's word two people do
Kirk: that.
Dan: Don't they know it's Kirk
day. I'm pretty sure they do
because,
Bekah: well, I mean, maybe we
could have any Kirk, Nick has
asked. That's a good question.
So in our slack right now, most
of
us have. Put our profile down,
flipped it and reversed it. But
with Kirk's
Dan: I see him Kirk, or we're
going to try to get Kirk in to
Bekah: join. Remember how to we
are, sorry. We're doing our best
to bring our celebrity on the
stream. At least take 10 fakes
in
the chat as well. I want to
shout out to Abby Perini because
she
DME last night, she was like,
after midnight, put up this in
your profile. So Abby has been
an amazing observer of Kirk day,
and
I could not have asked for
anything better. We don't want
break. Where are we breaking out
to turn off the world, please
stand up. Yes. Oh my goodness.
We definitely need to, um, find
more
ways to put Kirk into music.
Dan: All right. Kirk said he can
join in three minutes. So we
just
talked about this book for, I
don't know, jokes. I can't
really
Bekah: all right. I'll tell my
joke. Um, have you all one about
pizza?
Dan: Nope. I haven't heard that
one.
Bekah: Nevermind. It's cheesy.
Dan: Man.
Bekah: Well, we do the podcast.
Dan always wants me to adjust my
microphone. And so then I try
and tell him jokes, which he
ignores
all of the time. And then some
of our guests are nice enough to
laugh. So if you come on the
podcast, please laugh at my
jokes
and roll your eyes that day.
Please encourage me in my
keynote
talk that I'm giving in July.
I'm just telling jokes for 15
minutes
straight because I can do
whatever I want.
Dan: That's true. You're the
keynote speaker. So that'll be
your first and only time being a
key Joseph's to get away. I did
not fight. I rejected God to
keep trying to trick
Bekah: me. Can't fire me
anymore. All right. But if
anybody else
has jokes, please put them in
the chat and then I will deliver
them
because she needs
Dan: to deliver them because you
are the worst joke receiver in
the world. You know what she
does. Yeah. You know what you do
when you, what I ask you, Joe,
when I like, I have, there's
been
times where I've like pulled out
some jokes. Oh yeah. Yeah.
Because I know that you
appreciate them, but she guesses
the answers. She like, she
didn't say, I don't know what
she like
tries to like it's a riddle. No,
Bekah: no. Oh no. Dan, I don't
know. Can you tell me the
answer?
Dan: No, that's not. What are
you doing? You're fired again.
Not
again for the first time.
Bekah: C. Exactly. Thank you,
Joe. Joe knows. It's not joke.
It's a challenge. Every joke is
the.
Dan: That's not a, it's not a
joke,
Bekah: but a joke then is like a
story that you tell with a
punchline at the end in
Dan: your oh, weird Kirk here.
Um, okay. Well, according to
Kirk, one minute left, so we'll
see, Kirk was not consulted at
all for any of this. Uh, that is
true. I try not to consult Kirk
at a time on things where
Bekah: we need
Dan: right, exactly. Or, uh, you
know, where he might have time
to
think about whether he wants to
engage with us. We try to try to
pull him in, you know, before he
has a channel. You know? Yeah,
Bekah: no,
Dan: we avoid my
Bekah: ridiculousness, Joe. Yes,
we do need a scoreboard. Maybe
that will be next month. Monthly
challenge, 97 and counting.
Dan: Oh God. How did I not see
that coming? Honestly,
Bekah: I don't know. I didn't
even think about it. And so we
started talking and you brought
it up. Yes. A slack channel or a
slack bot that posts every time
that Dan fires
Dan: me. Um, how about a select
button that just announces the
Bekah is fire.
Bekah: Everybody just
continuously buyers' me over and
over. It's okay. Just keep
firing me. It's fine. Just
preparing to
be up here. Yeah, he probably,
sorry, Kirk, we're sorry that
you
have to prepare for us. We were
trying to send a drone that
would
just go scoop up Kirk and bring
him to Cleveland.
Dan: Well, maybe it's you will
cut out the echo. I was just
thinking I have headphones and
then I was, I don't know how to
do that. Really. We're just
going to try it. And I'm going
to count
on you guys to tell us if
there's a bad echo, cause I'm
just going
to play it over the speakers.
And because zoom is actually
usually
pretty good at that. Like, I
mean, if that's all we have to
do, uh, you know, we can do
AirPods or something, but like,
that'll be annoying. I have, I'm
trying to think if there's any
other solution, literally this
is the first time I've ever. Sat
next to somebody and try to be
beyond, uh,
Bekah: you know, I mean, if I
have my computer, I can, yeah.
And then like
Dan: you could go over the other
fucking room and do that like,
oh, sorry. Uh, I did not mean to
curse, but she made me have two
beers and she, you know, she
forced me to do it and, um,
which
I've been meaning to talk to HR
about. And they said you're
fired. The reason I swerve is
because like you going out
somewhere else sounds not
nothing is my
Bekah: point. I meant just have
my computer and log on and I
would sit here, but just so I
could put the sound in my ear,
Dan: I feel like you'd get a
delay, plus you'd hear me
through
there too. And through here too.
So we're going to try.
Bekah: Do they have like covers
for your air positive. You're
sharing them for someone else.
Like, you know how like they
have
like the tongue depressor and
they cover it or like the ear
thing, they put a little thing.
Do they have one of those for
your AirPods?
Dan: The, uh, that's as soon as
I thought that that's where like
my
AirPods or like grocery now, I
wouldn't want to share that with
anybody. So that would be an
embarrassing thing to do as
well.
Um, there has to be some sort of
like, I don't know. I feel like
back in the day they used to
have a lot of cool things where
you'd
split the, you know, I probably
honestly, yeah, where they'd
have
a little splitter. So you have
your iPod and the cord with the
two things, and then you could
sit next to your friend in the,
or in the bus or the car and
both of them the same thing.
Yeah. But
those were recorded, you know,
they were like, no, I feel like
cool. Kids in high school that
listened to cool music and had
cool friends. I didn't have it
either. It just seemed cool.
Bekah: Kirk is talking. It's set
up there. Where is he? Kirk,
are
Kirk: you here? I mean, I can
see you. I want you to know, I
just
shouted watching the stream
while I was getting ready. And
then
there, wasn't a moment where I'm
like, this is there's a lot
going
on here. I don't know where I
fit in. Um, don't have any jokes
and
I don't have any jokes, rule
formats. So, you know, Bekah. I
feel like, what do you think are
jokes and not what other people
put them together and said, that
is all of jokes.
Dan: I'm so glad you're here.
Says that was decades ago. I
know
it was because it was high
school. Thank you for putting
that out there. I appreciate
that. All right. Everybody else
has said there's no audio
issues. We are good.
Bekah: And we got the celebrity
of the year here. Welcome. It's
been a great
Dan: year. The multi-verse
Kirk: yeah, this entire day,
I've just been seeing threats
and
going. I don't remember talking
about,
Dan: I've been having the
opposite problem where I read as
reading through a thread and was
like, Oh, who wrote that? Oh,
that was
Bekah: me. Dad said, I think
we're at lunches.
Kirk: Yes. This is again, I just
want to make the record clear
that I was not consulted about
any of this mocha I saw, I just
assumed slack. Wasn't working.
Bekah: Nick Taylor, like
somebody would maybe read out
was like,
I'm seeing pictures of Kirk and
Nick is like, it happens
sometimes. And it does like
sometimes slack put other
people's pictures
Dan: upside down, you know, and
Bekah: flipped it.
Kirk: Okay. So I'm going to be
clear. I was very dense. It took
me way too long to figure out
that's what that was. Again, I'm
probably just not working. And
then I thought it was like, oh,
okay. Let's add a one way for
Kirk to distinguish himself and
other people. But it wasn't even
about me, which I feel like is
Bekah: the perfect
Kirk: days about. That's really
what, it's a, it's a VC event.
I'm just
Bekah: celebrating how much we
love Kurt.
Kirk: We're
Bekah: lucky that Missy Elliott
responded to you. So we can
remember every day it's like
Valentine's day because some
people don't like Valentine's
day. Cause they're like, what is
this? It's a commercial holiday
too. So us chocolate and flowers
and cars. And, but it's also a
day to like remind you to stop
and think like, oh, I am going
to, um, tell this person that I
love them today. Right? And so
like, we often forget to tell
you
every single day that we love
you, Kirk. So this is our Kirk
Valentine's day slash Missy
Elliot day. We do
Kirk: love you. We love you. Uh,
let's see, I wasn't prepared for
this either, but
Dan: since it's Kirk day, do you
want to back.
Kirk: No. I mean, I feel like I
have to be the one person who
doesn't fight.
Dan: Tell me if people
Bekah: need to think of me.
Kirk: I mean, just based on the
chat response, people seem to be
really into UV as much as like
on their tier list of events,
Kirk
day, back of being fired. That's
what the people want.
Bekah: The people want me to be
fine. I don't even know what to
do. I'm going to have to like,
think about this very hard on my
two and a half hour, drive out.
Why everybody loves me fired.
Kirk: Well, you seem to be like
really enthused about it too,
because you're the one who
brings it up. Dan, doesn't
Bekah: bring it up.
Kirk: It's like your origin
story. It is,
Bekah: it is my origin story.
Kirk: Not the teaching, not the
women who is it's like it all
started when Dan fire and then a
passion live inside, less
Bekah: fire. My other origin
story is not, uh, it's. It's
not,
um, it's rated PG 13 decoding.
Kirk: Oh, why did I get into
coding? I didn't, you
Bekah: can tell that one, but
then people always feel awkward.
Cause like when someone asks you
how you got into coding and you
use the word vagina, they're
suddenly like, oh, weird about
it. Yeah, for sure. I don't
think you can say that in a PG
movie,
you can drop one. F-bomb in a PG
13 movie. So we're still a PG 13
here. We're good, Dan.
Dan: What's
Kirk: it because
Bekah: he already dropped one
today. He thought her one and
only he was like, I'm going to
be the one that hit the
Dan: truck. Cause I was worried
about you leaving.
Kirk: Okay. Yeah. I know you're
in Dan's house now. So you get
like what's the body
Dan: is my office it's office.
Oh yeah. It's actually a
Sprockets
office, which is who I do most
of the work through. But I have
my
own like, well, I don't know
this stuff. You know, I have my
own
room. That is my office.
Kirk: I have like,
Dan: there's a suite of offices.
Bekah: It's got its own little
pod. There's a conference in a
couple of offices.
Kirk: I believe that you are
both in a tree house. I don't
believe
anything you say. I
Bekah: would like to be in a
tree
Dan: house. I laid, I went, uh,
To last week, when was I going?
I
don't know, two weeks ago,
whatever it was to Amish country
and got a tree house like
Airbnb, it's like a newly built
thing
that was like, well, we raised
up in the trees and stuff. It
was
really cool. Yeah. Highly
recommend
Bekah: Gemma. And I drove
through Amish country recently
on
accident. Cause I made a wrong
turn and we went for shopping
and
I, I got some large plastic bins
for $3, each
Kirk: much plastic things.
Bekah: No
Dan: one thing I learned this
trip, lots of Amish people now
are into e-bikes, which was a
surprise to me, but it was cool.
And it made sense once I thought
about it. So like lots of, uh,
and it was honestly, there was a
couple of men, mostly a lot of
women riding around on the
country highways. I mean the
same
house as the buggies are riding
on, but like, but they're just
like, and they usually had a
little bike trailer, you know,
but they're just like fine out.
Um, I went on. That's
Kirk: cool, interesting fun
fact. Early in the history of
bikes,
um, there was like a massive
upsurge in popularity with women
because it gave them like assets
to travel and like see their
friends without having to like
go through their husbands. And
so
there was like a big like
reactionary thing so that people
there like published articles
about like the bicycle. Is it
ruining your woman to stay home
again? Is that how that goes?
But
I just, I used to imagine some
like do just like these
bicycles,
they're hanging out with their
shreds.
Bekah: I don't ride a bicycle. I
don't ride
Kirk: bicycles.
Dan: Well, both. You don't know
how to ride a
Bekah: bike? Well, I, I did, but
then I fell off it too many
times. So I stopped. I don't
know. I mean, do you know how,
if
you keep falling down. I had a
bunch of stitches in my elbow.
See, there's still scar there. I
don't think you can see that on
screen. Thanks for confirming.
It was larger. Okay. For a long
time, I once ran into a pole
while riding on a bicycle.
Dan: I don't ride bicycle as
that a flat path. I think, I
feel
like, you know how you're just
not good at it and that's fine.
I
mean like you you're allowed to
be not good at things, but you
know how to ride a bike. There's
my point. You saying I'm not
Bekah: good
Dan: at riding bikes challenge,
challenge. I just don't
Kirk: know. How can you swim?
Bekah: I'm a great swimmer.
Kirk: Okay. I'm just trying to
figure out like in a triathlon,
like where are you struggling?
So it's like swimming, running,
cycling.
Bekah: Um, yes. Yeah, that's it.
I don't know. I probably would
not ride a skateboard. I tried
to do that with my child's
skateboard and I was like, this
is going to break my hip. Yeah.
I
was just worried about my no
sled riding. I once almost broke
my
hip sled riding. I had to go to
the emergency room. It wasn't
broken, but gave me lifelong
problems. I was on a mattress. I
sled road on a mattress. That
was a bad idea. So I was like,
not
good at sled riding. And so then
these boys in college, they were
like, Hey, let's take this
mattress and we'll go on it. And
you'll land on the mattress and
it's soft. And that makes sense.
Well, okay. So there was a ramp,
but I was like, don't come over
the ring. They promised they
wouldn't go over the ramp and
you
know what happened? Everybody
ditched the mattress except me
and one other guy. And he landed
on top of me and he was 200. I
landed on my head on the sound
good. I
Kirk: started with, I'm not good
at sled writing, but as far as
I'm aware, now, I remember where
I live. So I'm admittedly
ignorant of these things, but
aren't you just, isn't it just
like it's happening to you.
Dan: It's mostly the ramp. That
was a problem. I feel like
Bekah: it's easiest thing.
You're totally
Dan: right though. You just like
sit on the sled and then let us
Bekah: know sometimes like you
reckon,
Dan: I like the part about sled
riding is picking your spot. Uh,
cause if you go where there's
like huge ramps or like, I don't
know where else you crashed, but
like trees and stuff. Probably
not what slides are hard to
steal. Like they don't, they
don't, they don't, they're not
going to like do a sharp turn
steer.
Bekah: I remastered my fear
though. My brother is down the
street and has a great sled
riding. I have gone down that
hill multiple times.
Dan: You see them, you can
affect like, like slow gradual
turns on
sleds. You know what I mean? But
like what I'm saying, you can
turn slowly while you're going
fast, straight down, but you
have
to plan ahead. You have to plan
ahead or just ditch. It is what
I
would, I do want to control.
Bekah: He says I lift heavy
things and I flip them down.
Dan: Somebody said, we should do
a challenge, a bike ride shot.
It
would be it. I can actually sit
on a bike and not move and not
fall over.
Bekah: Deanna has a nickname for
his bike riding.
Dan: Yeah. It's all shot. Yeah,
somebody named, I got it
originally from bike riding,
but, uh, that was, I don't know
what
all that stuff was with. Yeah.
Like beg his daughters, uh, sent
me a poop emoji drawings because
every time they come on, Thing.
And they always want, you know,
whatever they're waving and
stuff. And so I just started
sending people from what he's
named fight or flights. Well,
Kirk: I've always, that's been
very validating to me. Bekah's
family associates being with
like pancakes and hot sauce and
like
van kits.
Bekah: So I don't think anybody
knows this story. So one
morning,
a couple of weeks ago we were
making pancakes and my daughters
decided they were going to make
pan Kirk's some pancakes that
looked like Kirk. Um, and then
they argued over who would eat
the pan Kirk, but then it, we
only had a little bit of battery
life. So there was only one pan
Kirk and it looked like a tiny
baby. So I think Gemma, a baby
Kirk, Kirk is like, that is
strange. And
Kirk: she sent me this like,
look, they made like, there's
nothing special about the
pancakes, small pancake. There's
no like chocolate chip face is
just a pancake.
Bekah: We did our best with what
we had. Okay.
Kirk: Don't tell them it's very
heartwarming, but also quite
strange. Um, I only know how to
make pancakes from scratch, not
the mix. And we're like
proportions. I learned it at, or
the only way I can do it. So I
can only make like enough
pancakes, like a full family,
but my family quickly, like you
don't
want pancakes. So I would just
eat like two pounds of pancakes
myself.
Bekah: Cause I know.
Dan: It's true. They're good.
That way.
Kirk: Or I could eat two pounds,
right.
Dan: So yeah, bragging at this
point is you get to eat two
pounds of,
Kirk: and then I go up to them
like you made them do this.
Dan: I, uh, so we were talking,
I mean, we wanted to hang out in
the stream or whatever, and just
hang out with people. We talked
about doing a podcast, like
making this like a live podcast
episode. I realized that we
didn't do a random question or
anything like that. So I was
just, I don't have a plan for
this. I was thinking about
somebody has a as, as a good,
you
know, random question or Kirk,
if you, while in
Kirk: VC, today or riddle really
icebreaker was which part of
not,
which part of your body hurts.
Cause the answer can be multiple
will, like, which is the one
you've noticed hurting like most
recently. Cause somehow we just
all started talking to you about
the parts.
Bekah: That's my traps. I trust
Dan: which ones are your trucks?
Bekah: I have builds up too much
muscle, and now it's very tight
and it hurts every day. No
problem.
Dan: I didn't do many trap
exercises. So yeah,
Kirk: when I was actually in
school, I did all the triangle
workouts I saw
Dan: I get in the gym and I
think geometry I'm like, you
know, the
strap designs Robinson's and you
got to get the whole, the acute
and the acute and the up twos
triangles, and then make sure
you
hit the, uh, what's the what's
the perfect triangle. Equal
equal
lateral equal lateral triangle
as well. Make sure you hit all
three
of those. If you want to do a
full workout, then you get into
the 3d and you get some cubes
and you know, you get some, uh,
other
Hedron oh man, this is where I
almost had it.
Kirk: And this is what we're
saying. And then someone in the
slack was like, who could lift
more weight? Like who could like
deadlift more? I'm like, it's,
it's definitely that,
Dan: um, deadlift, deadlift,
Bekah would very easily. I mean,
most of these probably she would
anyway, but like a, a deadlift,
any of the ones where you need a
form, you need form and stuff.
Like that's all the proper form
I'm saying I would just kill
myself. Like I would like my
back or something. You know what
I
mean? I have literally never
works out. Like I'm fairly
strong, but Bekah works out all
the time. If it is very strong,
I
feel like a. I feel like a bench
press is where, like, I feel
like
a bench press, I probably could
equal her because I don't have
to
worry about hurting myself very
badly because of my back. You
know what I mean? Then it's just
like, and then it's, you know,
but like any of the ones that
like requires skill, I mean,
Bekah: Jesse and I talked about
it last night. I was like, I
think Dan could crush me in,
Dan: um, I'm like for somebody
who
Kirk: doesn't ever work, but I
want to know is wins cycling. I
think you could have an edge
there.
Bekah: Oh, for sure. I don't
know how to cycle stationary
Kirk: bicycle after like elbow
scar McGee over there. We've got
to change
Dan: if we're going to have it.
So somebody mentioned triathlons
and there's like triathlon teams
too. So like they have like team
for competition, you know, as
well. So. If we did a triathlon,
would you do run or swim?
Probably swim. All right. So
Kirk, that means you're on
running.
Kirk: What am I better at than
the two of you jokes? Oh, be
better at sports wise.
Dan: No, Joe Bekah, when it
pushups easily.
Bekah: Oh, I don't know. I, my
shoulder is Kirk is still in the
a hundred push-ups challenge,
right?
Kirk: Yeah. But I don't do like
the full ones I'm doing like
incline.
Bekah: I, my, I hear my
shoulder. I have a torn
something. Yeah. My
thing
Dan: with, with pushups,
honestly, that bothers me is my
wrists are flexible for my
Bekah: research.
Dan: Like they
Bekah: don't like my right wrist
from using the mask all the time
is definitely tighter than my
left
Dan: one. I'm sure I could work
on it if I want it to.
Kirk: But yeah, the tunnel, the
tunnel I traveled through the
most as harmful for sure. They
have those things, like those
things you can hold instead of
pressing your arms flat on the
ground, they just, they hurt
your arm in a different way. So
I'm
like this just transferred the
pain from like doing this to
like
straight through. So it doesn't
help at all. Yeah. Did
Dan: you read next pivot? No.
Nick just says, I saw someone
mountain biking on a unicycle in
a forest outside of Montreal. I
wave to them and they just
imagine them like doing a jump
on
a unicycle, waving to Nick, and
then like seeing them veer off
into a tree and yelling soccer,
light blue or something.
Kirk: It's like the office. They
have to yell our core, our
Bekah: core. Oh my gosh. My kids
love that
Kirk: that'll away.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I've seen those for sure.
So people do like insane things
on
them. I've I've seen him. I
don't think I've seen them in
real
life, but I've seen them on
YouTube. Uh, if you want some,
Kirk: you know, on Spiderman or
they tell them, do a flip and
then he does the flip and then
it was like, oh, that's it. I
want
it to be on like, both ends of
that. I don't want to be the
person saying, do the flip. And
then someone else does the flip.
And someone says to me, I want
to be able to do the flip in
that
moment. Um, but that's never
going to happen. You're
terrified. What am I better at
than the two of you? This is, I
gotta figure this
Bekah: out. Kindness
documentation. Um, well, I don't
know if Dan's better than you at
games or not. I like games. I'm
very bad at them.
Kirk: Not anymore. That's
Bekah: have you seen the.
Kirk: I would pay money. I
would, I would donate time and
money to
make that
Bekah: Kurt, Kurt is Kirk day.
You were allowed to ask him to
do
whatever you want right now.
Dan: I don't know. I just, I'm
not very flexible at all that
it's a known fact.
Bekah: Kirk poetry, maybe. I
don't know.
Kirk: Are you you're, you're a
poet. You poet.
Bekah: We have debt. We have all
three devils in the poetry. You
may be able to find all three of
our poetry online. If you
search,
Kirk: I used to have a website.
The first website I ever made
was
a WordPress site. It was called.
Shiver sharks. Cause that's a
collective noun for sharks. And
I found out cause everyone does
like a pirate bowels or like
one-on-ones everyone knows. I'm
like, give me a weird shiver or
something like that. And then I
met the, I saw someone who had
the murder of crows and I was
like boring them about that. But
my websites, I don't want to
happen to it. WordPress is just
like, you don't do enough. And I
think I saved, I think I saved
everything from it as a RTF rich
text. I'm like, this is great.
Lost that file. Worthless
unhelpful. This was before I
knew about mark down or
anything.
Really?
Bekah: Yeah.
Kirk: Does anyone remember that
thing we used to use to make
websites? My professor in
university used it. Um, it flips
no three waiver.
Bekah: That was the first time I
ever coded was in Dreamweaver.
Yeah,
Dan: for sure.
Bekah: I want to do yoga with
the goat to Virtual Coffee
retreat at
Glenn's
Kirk: house. I've seen the goat
yoga videos. And as somebody who
like I see goats every day go
prove it. That's a real
Dan: thing. Yeah. It's the go-to
and yoga tour is to go just
like,
Kirk: and a bunch of little like
kid goats, just kind of like
amble about, and sometimes they
just climb you. Cause that's
their thing. Oh,
Dan: sure. I mean,
Bekah: yeah. Can we do a
fainting goats too? And then we
like jump
up and scare them.
Dan: Yeah, Nick, I use fibers.
Yeah, dreamer. So that's the
Macromedia suite, like
Dreamweaver fireworks, and then
like flash, if you do a flash
and, uh, there was another one
that I didn't use very much,
like a more, uh, designing one,
but,
um, yeah, I wasn't doing more
than farmers and like
Dreamweaver
was actually really good. Uh,
even not using the like
generated
stuff, but it was a good like
code editor. Like I used it as
my
like, just code editor for, I
dunno, I dunno when it stopped,
but like a long
Bekah: time. Well, my first job
out of my first full-time job
out
of college, I was a community
organizer for an environmental
non-profit and the executive
director, my first week, he was
like, do you know. How to use,
how do you know a code? Like,
no,
he's like, okay, go home this
weekend and learn HTML and CSS.
I
was like, okay, like Jesse was
my boyfriend at the time. And I
went
home and he had like textbooks
on HTML and CSS. So then we went
over those things like, all
right, I know it. I know it now.
Kirk: That's awesome. All
weekend. I'm pretty much an
expert. Nailed
Dan: it.
Kirk: Um, just to say, Jeff,
Jeff in the chat was like, do
pushups
on your fists or wristband
again, like we're just trading
problems
here. That's not, that's not
better. Um, yeah. Shout out to
that's a Dreamweaver. I remember
like a lot of purple. It was all
like purple involved with
somebody. Oh, I have a great bad
joke. I just heard it. This is
apparently very popular with the
first time I heard it. Bekah
don't ruin it. Um, which are
Kirk's could apply to all Java
developers wear glasses.
Dan: This is where you say, I
don't know why,
Kirk: because they can't see
sharp.
Bekah: Uh, uh, nice. I was not
going in that direction. I was
going more with,
Kirk: if, if you were a software
developer in like 1998, that
would have been incredibly like
back when they were basically
Dan: C sharp in 1998. This is
like C plus plus in that, when
did C-sharp become a thing.
Kirk: Okay. 2005. That's again,
back when
Bekah: what's that
Dan: 13, we don't need to talk
about how old I was, but, uh, I
wasn't, I was a computer science
in college, which was after that
and.
Kirk: That's all the
Dan: validation, I suppose, does
not exist anymore.
Kirk: Yeah. People use it to
write. Whoa, whoa, buddy.
Dan: I don't know. I'm asking.
I'm not saying there's no
difference. I'm literally
asking, I don't know. C
Kirk: sharp is all.net, right?
It's all Microsoft, right?
That's
this, if you're in Microsoft,
90% of the time you're writing C
sharp, um, and C plus plus is
not, um, C plus plus is still
considered like the Lang for
like high-performance stuff. If
you
don't want to get down to see, I
guess, but I feel like C plus
plus dad's favorite thing to do
is like, complain about. Yeah.
Like JavaScript,
Dan: if you get to a certain
level, that's just going to be
an
Kirk: ally. If it's useful
enough, like there'll be enough
code written that it was like
something to complain about.
Like
Dan: Emily tells people, like
she was on a trip with her
grandma
and she's like, yeah, Dan hates
computers. And she knows that
like, this is what I do for a
living, you know, but it's true.
You know, she didn't understand,
you know, she's like, what, what
does that mean? Yes. Like, yeah,
dad hates computers. Cause she
told me a story. Cause I was
like, oh, yesterday I spent like
three hours trying to get, I
wasn't, uh, I almost went over a
PG 13 again, uh, Ruby to work
again on my computer. And um, it
was really annoying and it like
killed my whole day, you know,
anywhere else complained about
it at home and was like, I hate
computers. I don't like them.
So, you know, well
Kirk: the first time I learned
Ruby, it was similar to that
Bekah situation. I was in
internship. Well, we can't any,
can't get any developers up in
this project. So you guys are
going to do it yourself and be
like, okay, any of, you know,
Ruby? No, this was back in the
time. They were like, here's the
instructions for how to install
this on your machine? If you get
it wrong, we'll would probably
break the machine. Good luck. So
that's like, and it was super
painful. And I didn't like, look
at a line of Ruby again, what,
10 years. So, you know,
onboarding.
Dan: Yeah, no, that's, it's
like, it doesn't matter every
time I
have to do something with her
and I just do it so infrequently
that
it's, you know, that's why it's
a problem for me, obviously, to
be
Kirk: fair. I feel like I do
Python stuff all the time and I
still mess it up. Like getting
it to work. I'm just, I just
want
things to work. I just want to
click work and then they work.
Yeah. Specifically the
installation and running part.
Bekah: That's the worst
Kirk: I got into Loreal. I'm
like, oh, I'm going to NPM
installed new thing. And bam did
its thing. Do the thing run
didn't work. I Google the air,
you know, it's bad when you
search for an air and it takes
you to like, be official of like
issues on resolved page. Like,
oh no,
Dan: I can't. I was deep into
that yesterday. It doesn't
matter. Yeah. Anyway, uh,
computers are doing that. I hate
them.
Bekah: Also. I have to go
Dan: to leave at three, not
three 30. Uh,
Kirk: the week
Bekah: I have children, Bekah
needs to go clean up the Creek
in
my.
Dan: She needs to go clean up
smokey
Kirk: bear
Bekah: birthday
Dan: week. Um, Kirk, I just want
to say a happy Kirk day to us
all.
Bekah: We're glad to have you
thank you for joining us and the
entire world.
Kirk: I am. I'm happy to provide
me as a catalyst for the pool.
People here, Kirk day is weird,
but the people who like it are
great on this,
Dan: we didn't plan any of this
at all. So I appreciate you. If
you know, Dan
Bekah: was like push to have an
agenda. And I was like,
Dan: we did get a lot of stuff
done today. It was
Bekah: a, but most importantly,
we saw Kirk on Kirk day and
changed our profile pictures.
Kirk: Nick Taylor's profile
picture is sideways. We noticed
that
Bekah: it all makes sense,
Kirk: Don road.
Bekah: Well, that seems like a
great way to end.
Dan: That's a good one. Thank
you everybody for hanging out
and I'm
happy, corrected and see you
Thursday.
Kirk: No, don't do another one
no more Kirk days. Yeah, every
single collective. It's fun. All
right, bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can
hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening and
we'll
see you next week!