Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season six episode one of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah
Dan: we're back.
Bekah: Bekah we are back. We are
back featuring members of the
Virtual Coffee community, a
community that is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey.
And
they're here on this podcast,
sharing their stories and what
they've. We are here to share it
with you. Obviously you're with
me today is my cohost. Dan
Dan: Wuddup Bek, how's it going?
Bekah: Do you do that every
season one intro?
Dan: I hope so. Probably not.
Now I will from here on out.
Bekah: you remember that? In
season seven? Hmm.
Dan: but it probably won't be
the only time I say wuddup Bek
either. So, you know, how's it
going?
Bekah: Um, it's going great
because we're launching the new
season of the podcast!
Dan: Um, yes, we are. It was,
um, season five was pretty
awesome.
And season six is also gonna be
Bekah: It is true. It is always
awesome. We are consistent in
one
thing and one thing only, and it
is having awesome people on our
podcast.
Dan: Yes, agreed. Um, so yeah,
so we are starting season six
off
with. An awesome guest of the
name? David Albert. Uh, David is
a director. Um, no, wait, what
is he? I lost it. David is the
Director of Engineering, sorry,
at Northfield IT, um, and one of
the many Canadians we have in
Virtual Coffee and also on the
podcast. um, not the first,
won't be the last. Um, and yeah,
we had
a really great time talking to
David. Yeah,
Bekah: Yeah, David is one of
those conversations that could
have continued on for sure.
Beyond the hour. He has so much
insight into not just like the
technology field, but in working
with other people. And he, I
really appreciated his
thoughtfulness in how he.
Approaches other people and
supporting them.
Dan: absolutely. That, I mean
like that, that's gotta be one
of
the first things I think of.
When I think of David is, is
yeah.
Thoughtfulness. Um, and, and I
don't know, you know, like
thoughtful and empathetic is, is
what, he's one of the, I mean,
he's, he's always on, um, Slack
and he's, I, I dunno, like
everybody loves him. He's always
so great to talk to anytime you,
anytime you're kind of working
through something or have some
existential crisis I feel like
David's one of those, one of
those people that will show up
and, um, You know, like actually
have constructive ways to maybe
work through some, some hard
problems and stuff. It's it's
really, it's really nice having
him around
Bekah: yeah. And, and the, that
empathy that he brings to the
situation is really, um,
Authentic and true, you know, is
somebody might check in and see
how you're doing, but, you know,
if you get a message from David,
he means that. And I think that
goes a long way to supporting
people and helping them feel
comfortable and allowing them
to, you know, grow and, and
learn in
those ways and support them.
Dan: Absolutely. Um, okay. What
is our random question? I, how
do
we start the episode? This
episode?
Bekah: Um,
Dan: Oh, totally.
Bekah: don't but don't we in the
first episode, intro, talk about
the other guests too.
Dan: Uh, I don't know. I haven't
done this for a while.
Bekah: We're excited about this
episode and the rest of the
season. So we're also going to
be talking to Bogden about
navigating tech career paths. We
have quite a bit of career path
episodes this season. So we're
gonna be learning about what it
means to be a demo engineer, a
developer educator, we're gonna
be talking through interviews
and open source contributions.
So I
think this is a pretty well
rounded season to, I don't know,
get you excited about all
things. Am I spinny chair? I've
got a
spin chair this
Dan: you have. Yes. Bekah got a
spinny chair and she has not
stopped spinning. I got
Bekah: It is the best thing. I
just continue to spin.
Dan: yeah. Yeah. It's it's uh,
well, it is what it is. I feel
like you're doing a good job of,
um, like rotating around your
microphone and staying in a good
speaking position
Bekah: Yeah, I'm trying to keep
my head straight on the
Dan: well done. Yeah,
Bekah: my body turns, but my
head does minimal turning.
Dan: yeah. No, it's you, you're
doing a good job.
Bekah: Thanks. That's all I
needed to hear today. but we are
going to start this episode of
the podcast. Like we start every
episode of the podcast and every
Virtual Coffee, say our name,
where we're from, what we do and
answer a random check in
question. So we hope you enjoyed
this episode and the rest of
season six. Today's random
check-in question is if you
could
magically become fluent in any
language, what would it be? My
name is Bekah. I am a technical
community builder from a small
town in Ohio, and I think I
would go with Polish only
because I'm
mostly Polish and I would like
to know more of it. Definitely
not
the most practical, but it's
probably the most meaningful.
Dan: All right, Polish.
Bekah: Yes. See, that was the
most straightforward I've ever
been in an intro.
Dan: Yeah. Um, okay. Hi, I'm
Dan. I do, um, web development
things
in Cleveland and, um, yeah. Uh,
I don't know, languages are
hard.
I, this is a, an attractive
question to me because I I'm bad
at like learning languages. I
took like three years of German
and I struggled with Spanish in
college and I. I took three
German. I don't know. I can
still count to 10, I think, but,
um,
you know, Spanish would be, I
think, I think I'm gonna choose
Spanish. I, you know, it just,
it, I, uh, I like going to
Mexican restaurants. like, you
know, there's a lot of Spanish
speaking people, you know, in
America and, um, although, uh,
Japanese would be cool too. I, I
love like listening to Japanese,
you know? People speaking
Japanese. I like, I just like
the
way it sounds. So that'd be cool
too. And, and it's so different
than English that, you know,
that's one, that's really hard
for me to wrap my head around
ever being able to speak. Uh, so
I'm, I'm kind of tied 50, 50
Spanish and Japanese. That's
gonna be my answer.
David: Well, since Dan said to
you, I'm gonna say to you, uh,
my
name is David Albert, and I'm,
I'm a software developer and
DevOps engineer. uh, in
Winnipeg, Manitoba, and I was
having a hard
time picking just one. So since
Dan set the example, my first
thought was Indonesian because I
spent some time in Indonesia and
I remember just enough
Indonesian to say some things to
Ayu, for
example, in our community. But
I'm no by no means fluent. And
it
would just be so much fun to be
fluent again or more in
Indonesian. But then. Bekah when
you mentioned Polish. I, I
thought Hebrew because that
would connect me with some of my
family
and some of my tradition, so
that I've drifted a little bit
from so
Hebrew and Indonesian
Dan: I like it.
David: will.
Bekah: Yeah, thanks, David.
Normally I, I ask our guests to
choose one thing and then I
choose four or five. So
David: So we turned the tables
today.
Bekah: um, welcome to the
podcast. Thanks so much for
being
here with us today. We always
like to start with the origin
story of our guests. So tell us
a little bit about your origin
story and how that brought you
to where you are.
David: I was thinking about this
question. I love that you start
with the origin story and the
way you frame it as origin, I. I
can
remember using the Logo computer
language to make the little
turtle draw back and forth. I
don't remember a lot about it,
but I remember being really
excited when I discovered loops
and I didn't even know they were
called loops, but I could draw
flowers with not very much. Uh,
code. So that was pretty
exciting. And then I went to,
you know, high school and grew
up and
lots of things happened. Uh, I
went to university and took a
computer science degree. I wound
up taking a computer science
degree and that taught me a lot
of fundamentals about mentals,
about computer architecture,
say, and like hardware
architecture.
There was a computer engineering
course in there too. And also
basics. Data structures and
algorithms. So I feel like I got
a leg up on that before there
was any of the, now all the code
camps and everything, the free
code camps and the flat iron
school and everything that I
hear about all the resources
that are
available today. I didn't have
those back at that time. So, but
I was fortunate enough to be
able to go to this university
program.
And I studied not only computer
science, but also it was kind of
a liberal artsy program. And I
got exposed to all sorts of.
Things that were not technical
in the world. And I got very
distracted and I didn't want
anything to do with technology
and I wanted to go find
something more meaningful to do.
So I went
and I traveled and that's when I
wound up in Indonesia with an
exchange program with, uh,
Canadian, crossroads
international, a cultural
exchange program, designed to
expose people to different
cultures. And as I was
proceeding
with my life, I noticed a common
thread. I would constantly
notice
that people around me that I
cared about friends, family
would
be stressed or unhappy with
technology and they would be
frustrated and they would start
to internalize it like, oh, I'm
not good at this. Or I must not
be very smart because I can't
figure this out. And I would
look at what they were
struggling
with. And I was frustrated. I
got frustrated because it wa I
knew
enough about technology to know.
Didn't have to be that way. And
that what my friends and family
were struggling with was design
decisions that somebody had made
that hadn't really thought about
how they would land on a real
person. And that's really what
prompted me to get back into
technology. Um, and from there
I've done a number of
technology, jobs, technology
related jobs,
uh, web front end. Now we would
call it front end, develop. at
the time I was starting to learn
about front end engineering. And
that was back when I remember
before Firebug was introduced,
like back before Chrome dev
tools. And then Firebug was a
really big deal, Jay Qury and
Firebug changed the way we did
web development back then.
Dan: Yeah, it did.
David: Um, and now, well, from,
from there, I got tired of front
end and I got interested in
backend. So I went and did
backend. I did a lot of C sharp.
I did years and years of C
sharp.
In fact, I found recently a
commit somewhere in GitHub from
16 years ago that I did in C
sharps. I've been writing code
for a long time.
Dan: that's awesome.
David: And from there, I went to
various software developer jobs
and took some project management
training, got involved in the
local Winnipeg, agile community
and found my way into builds and
deploys. And that's what got me
into DevOps. And now here I.
Bekah: That's I was gonna say
great, but.
Dan: Oh, it's great. It is great
also. It's great and awesome.
Um,
no, that, that's a cool that's.
I love having people on. I mean,
I
love having all, I guests it's,
it's always fun for me having
people on who started, uh, like
when you started, when I, you
know, back a long time ago, I, I
logo hadn't thought about for a
long time. I, I definitely did
Logo in like the computer lab
in,
uh, in middle school. Um, What I
was, I had a question for you.
What was it? Oh, it was, um,
okay, so you mentioned like,
right, like learning
fundamentals and learning
computer science
stuff, sort of maybe a, I don't
know what the hard computer
science, uh, I dunno what a good
term is for it, but you know,
the, the kind of stuff that at
least back in the day you
learned
in computer science courses in
college, right. Versus, uh,
today. Where there's so many
different, like places to go so
many different ways to learn so
many different, um, approaches
to
learning even. Uh, and I guess
the thought that I had was, um,
what do you think, like, can you
imagine trying to learn from
scratch now and would you want
to. If you were starting over
right now. Right. But you have
all the stuff available. Would
you rather go that fundamentals
level and learning stuff
probably
in languages that you're never
going to use in, you know, in,
in
practical levels, but you're
getting all the fundamental
stuff
or would you like there's boot
bootstrap, no boot camps, sorry.
Uh, boot camps and everything
like that. That. Will put you
more in a practical place to, to
get, you know, where, where
you're learning some JavaScripts
and learning React and stuff
like
that, even before, you know, um,
maybe some of the more esoteric
pieces of computer science, you
know? Um, and so this is not a,
like, I'm not asking you to
like, place judgment on
anything, but
just like from a personal
personal standpoint, like where,
where do you, like, where would
you land? Like where would you
personally rather, uh, start, if
you could start, if you were
starting from scratch, you know,
now.
David: This is a really good
question, Dan. And it's come up
a
number of times in Virtual
Coffee, because we have a number
of people who are career
changers or, or early career
people in
the, in the community. And
they're constantly wondering
what
do I do next? And what do I
look, um, the way you phrased it
though, for me, if I were to
start now, I, one of the things
I
notice about the technical
landscape today compared to when
I started is it seems to have
exploded in technologies and
frameworks and libraries and
possibilities. And I think it
would, I would lean towards
practical first because I think
that would help me. Learn enough
about one thing to start to
work.
And really once you get into,
once you cross that difficult
barrier of finding your first
job in technology, then you can
get
paid to learn as you work. And,
and then you can, I don't know,
maybe. I think it would be
worthwhile to take some survey
course of the fundamentals, some
high level survey course so that
you introduce the, or you you're
introduced to the words and
phrases, because I find that the
computer science degree helps me
in two ways. One that having
those fundamentals. Often helps
me understand new frameworks,
cuz I kind of understand how
computers work underneath and
all of the languages and
frameworks.
So learning any particular
practical framework gets, I
think
easier with that fundamental
background,
Dan: Yeah.
David: think it's required to
learn how to work in any of
those
things. I just think that it
helps me. The other place I
notice is that it helps me in
searching for things. When I go
to Google sometimes. The terms
and the phrases, I think I'm
drawing from that training back
then. So that's where I think
maybe a survey course without
having to go deep in all those
things, because you, I only
remember the things that I use
and we joke. I mean, we work in,
in DevOps where, uh, cashing is
a
thing, you know, one of the, the
two hard problems in computer
science, right? Yeah. Um, And we
joke about my memory only holds
so much and I expire things for
my mental cash. When I go and
learn something new. Um, you
know, you ask me a question
about
something that I supposedly
studied and I have a cash miss,
and I have to go look it up, but
I do find that things that I
have
learned and then purged often
come back easier or more easily.
That's a long winded way of to
say I would start practical
today
because there's so many
widespread things. I think it
would take a long time to go
from fundamentals to something
practical today. But I think if
you start today with something
practical, you could, but maybe
just a quick survey of you don't
need to understand all the data
structures and algorithms, but
like, if you can name three of
them, cuz you know, they exist,
then you can search up
implementations of them or
details about them when you
need.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: good idea.
Dan: Oh, I think that, I love
that answer. I, you know, and I
think I tend to agree with you.
I per, I mean, also personally,
I,
I got interested in computer
development stuff because of
the.
Like logo, you know, seeing
something happen right away, you
know, like hitting, save, and
then like looking at it and, you
know, whatever. Um, and
sometimes, or writing code on a
chalkboard and stuff like that
is like, uh, was I drifted away
from
it in college? Um, because, um,
I was computer science major to
start as well. And you know, it,
it just got less and less, less
and less like fun, you know, I
dunno, but you're right. Like
the
knowing the like, For instance,
um, the big O notation, right?
Like analyzing how a, how long a
function takes to do a thing.
You
know, I don't think anybody
that's writing rack code for
their job needs to know the
names of all the different, you
know,
or even like, they don't need to
know the, even the phrase big O
right. But knowing that will
help you will help you sort of
think
through and go like, like, uh,
having that in your brain would,
um, In the background and it's
okay if it's expired cash, but
you'll still like, see something
and start like, it's like code
smell, kind of, you know, uh,
it's like a weird phrase, but
like a phrase that makes a lot
of sense to people who have been
doing it for a while is, is
you'll start to get like these
instincts or whatever these like
it's okay. If you don't know the
exact phrase or I don't remember
the exact name of some specific
algorithm or anything like that,
but okay. I know just sort of
almost intuitively that this
thing is going to take like way
longer. Than it should. And I
probably can do it a different,
different way, you know, that,
that sort of thing. I think
that's the sort of thing that
would hit on your idea of the,
um, like doing, doing a high
level, you know, um, survey
course, something like that.
You'll get exposed to some of
that stuff, even if, and you
don't need to know like the down
and dirty details, you know,
David: Even if we take something
that is like computer sciencey,
heavy, like big O notation, it's
very, almost theoretical or a.
An
academic, like it's a very
academic way to approach this
technology thing. Not a very
practical way, but knowing that,
like being able to like knowing
that something called big O
notation exists, being able to
have one sentence about it will
help you identify when it might
be. Um, In like a part of the
problem you're dealing with and
give you enough words to go and
Google the details of how it
intersects with the problem
you're with. And you don't need
to be able to explain it in
detail or,
Dan: Right.
David: you know what I mean? So
just knowing that it's a thing
or
knowing that cashing is a thing
without knowing how cashing
works
or knowing that I Don. The one
that came to mind as you were
talking, is that string conation
is expensive in sea sharp for
whatever reason, because strings
are immutable in C sharp,
they're
treated as immutable objects. So
every time you're joining
strings
together, you're allocating
extra memory and copying
everything
over. So it's a very expensive
operation that detail of C sharp
would never have stuck for me. I
don't think if I didn't know a
little bit of fundamentals about
how memory allocation.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: I think too, once you are
working, you you're coding more
rather than you're learning
those concepts become easier to
understand, because if you're
learning, they, they are kind of
theoretical, right? Because you
have no use to apply them. Or if
you are building a project for a
bootcamp or something, it's a
tiny little project. So it
doesn't exactly. Correlate much,
much of that stuff with what
you're doing. So when you have
that like practical application
and you're learning that like,
oh, okay, I understand where
this would be applied or where I
would
need to reference this idea. And
at least for me, it becomes a
little bit easier once I can see
all right. Th this is where we
need to think about this.
David: This, this goes to my
understanding of how we learn as
humans. Like we learn better
when there's emotion involved.
We
learn better when there's motion
involved, we learn better when
we
have real experience to hang
ideas off of. And that just
makes
intuitive sense to me. That also
is why I say go practical and
learn just enough theory to have
language, to know when you need
to go deeper.
Bekah: So like writing down, I,
you just gave me a new talk idea
and the title has to be like
motion and emotion and it's has
something to do with learning,
because I think both of those
things are, you know, does tie
it to our memory. It does allow
us
to connect with it in a
different way. And I know that
there are
people out there. There were
people when I was learning that
said, well, you have to. Um,
learn how to think higher level
and theoretically, and how to
apply that. And I don't, I mean,
my background, I taught college
English for 10 years and so I, I
can think theoretically, uh,
it's something that I had to do,
but I
don't think that we have to do
that. You know? Um, I, I think
that that's a little bit gate
keep.
David: and, and it also
presupposes that there's only
one
way to learn and only one way to
think. And, and that seems to be
an idea that was stronger years
ago. And now we know better one
of those ideas. Now we recognize
that there's a whole spectrum of
how people think and process
information and learn and, uh,
view and interact with the world
and experience the world.
Bekah: And you have a lot of
experience with this, especially
at Virtual Coffee for our
listeners who aren't in the
slack. We have a co-working room
where anybody can join at any
time. And it's an open zoom room
and sometimes people are there
to
hang out. Sometimes people have
questions and they jump into
pair. And David is one of our,
our top co-working room
attendees, I think. And you've
helped a lot of different people
in the co-working room. So like,
first of all, Thank you. And
second of all, you know, this
all ties into what we've been
talking
about. How do you kind of
approach people who come in and
have questions, because there
are so many different ways of,
you
know, talking through things and
David: Oh, my gosh. Well, thank
you. I love the co-working room
is one of my favorite parts of
co of Virtual Coffee and this
community that you've created.
Um, I never know what's gonna
happen when I go in there, but I
always know it's gonna be
friendly and friendly faces and
in the middle of a pandemic,
certainly when I was locked in
my room, it was a lifesaver to
be
able to dial it like walking
virtually into a room. And meet
friendly people. And, uh, one of
my favorite co-working room
memories is I, you know, often
you go in and there's people who
are not sharing a screen and
they're just talking. Or
sometimes I go in and there's
people who are all on mute and
just enjoying being together.
And other times I, I logged in
once
and Meg had her laptop on her
front porch and she was garden.
I
logged in another time and Orlie
was, uh, making crepes in her
kitchen. Like it was lovely. So
it blew open for me that this
was
really a, a place where people
could connect, which is at the
heart of this community. Um, but
to focus back, you asked about
how do I approach. Pairing or
working with people from lots of
different backgrounds on lots of
different technology? Well, some
of it is cuz I've been doing
this for a long time, so I've
seen a
bunch of things. Um, I, some of
it is that I'm in a job where
I'm
actively working in several
different languages. Um, and I'm
in a job where I'm working to
support developers. So for five
years, that's really been my
role. And even Bekah the other
day you were talking about devel
and I realized some of what I've
been doing falls under that
bucket of really looking for
ways
to help people who are having
problems. And I find there are
some common threads, like a lot
of it is really slowing down my
thought process to take the time
to meet somebody. In their
thought process as best I can to
really try to hear not what I
think the problem is, but try to
hear what someone else thinks
the
problem is, and try to look at
it from their point of view, as
best
I can and try to look with them
at whatever they're looking at.
So I will often say if you're
having trouble, can you share an
error message or can we share a
screen? And I can look at the
same thing you are because
words. Becoming adequate for
talking
about technical things. English
words in particular are so
imprecise sometimes that we can
say the same word and mean
different things. So I often
find it really useful to share,
um, a
screen and pair program and look
at the look at the same thing at
the same time, or to share a
stack trace or a, you know, the,
an error message. Uh, that's
really. I think I've drifted
from
the heart of your question
Bekah: I mean, I think it's
great. I mean, you're really
taking a person-centered
approach to each person that
comes into
that room. And the idea of like
listening and understanding is
something that I, I think a lot
of people struggle, struggle
with
myself included because it's
like, all right, let's just dive
into this. Right. And get going
without like, taking that time
to
understand what's happening with
the other person.
David: I really think that's
important. Um, at some point in
my growth. career. I discovered
the agile manifesto and people
have I've since read lots of
things, you know, positive and
not so positive about the agile
manifesto. And I don't mean to
go
down that rabbit hole, but the
first value statement really
stuck and resonated with me that
we value people and
relationships
over processes and things. That
is kind of a radical idea. if
you, if you take that and
nothing else that we value
people in
relationships over attachment to
any particular way of doing
things and you start there and
you really look to meet the
other
people that you're working with,
no matter what their role is, no
matter what their background is
and realize that we're all part
of a group or a team or a
community that's trying to
accomplish something together. I
think all of the other practices
around software development and
delivery can emerge. If you
start
with who's at the table and you
really make space for everybody
who's at the table. And that
could be a hard thing, cuz we're
not always used to doing that.
There is a lot of gate keep E
like language and habits in
technology. I try to do my part
to break that stuff down.
Bekah: Yeah, I think a lot of
times too, sometimes it's
certainly intentional and other
times it's not, it's, it's just
habits that have built up, uh,
personally or through careers or
with the teams that you have
worked on before. So, you know,
there's a, a need for constantly
evaluating ourselves and how we
approach the people that we are
talking to or working.
David: that. Pairing really well
takes time, takes me time. I
have
to really slow down and let go
of any pressure and really be
present with another person. And
that takes time and energy and
effort. And if I'm under a
deadline to deliver something,
it
can be challenging to make that
time and that pressure, but I
think it is so worth it to.
Balance individual contribution
and individual delivery and
individual speed with all of the
rich benefits you get from
building community as you work
and from building relationships
and sharing knowledge and
building experience and
supporting everybody to grow in
confidence and skill. Um,
there's so many benefits from
actually
working together.
Bekah: Absolutely. And next
month, our monthly challenge,
this will be in June is month of
feedback. And so we read radical
candor. I we've mentioned it so
many times. Uh, it's been a
favorite of ours, but when
you're working with so many
different
people, you are providing a lot
of feedback and that can be hard
sometimes, right? Because that
feedback has to be critical. How
do you approach. Giving honest
feedback, but still supporting
the person that you are
providing the feedback to.
David: That's a great question.
I started reading radical candor
with someone on my team because
you have talked about it so
much.
Um, and it is the, I struggle a
bit with the directness. Of
critical feedback. That's where
I found that book was really
useful
in giving me some examples of
how to be direct without being
confrontational, right. And to
stay heart centered, to stay
person centered and to really
have the other persons to be
committed to the other person. I
find I really practice. The idea
what practice, which means I'm
not always good at it, but I
work
at it. I practice the idea that
everybody is where they're at on
their own personal journey. And
everybody is right where they're
supposed to be in the moment.
And exactly the people that show
up
are the people who are supposed
to be there. And the people who
are on your team are the people
who are supposed to be there.
Like really try to embrace. And
accept and love what's
happening.
I think that's really important,
um, to be more practical though,
I find still I'm noticing a lot
of self-doubt and self-criticism
that happens in technology. And
so one of the things that I
really try to do when I'm
pairing is be encouraging above
all else
to be supportive and
encouraging. Because the biggest
thing that I
believe will help people learn
is to grow that confidence, that
it's okay to make a mistake.
It's okay. Not to know something
that's actually part of the job
and the faster that you are
honest and open about what you
don't know as well as what, you
know, then the faster that
everybody can see how to help
you
and the faster you can learn.
And so I really just try to
always
try to be supportive and patient
and. Guide people towards what
seems to be the next step so
that they can build their
understanding and get stronger
and bigger because that kind of
pairing and feedback and
support. It's not about me in
that moment.
It's really about trying to work
with somebody and support them
to
take, uh, whatever the next step
is for them. And if I'm deciding
what it is, then that's not
right. What I do sometimes
though, is I might point people
in a direction based on the
journey that I've walked. I
might say. You know, have you
thought
about this or let's go look at
that or I'd like, yeah, I do
more
direct coaching sometimes with
people on my team at work where
I
say, I'd like you to learn this,
or I'd like you to learn that,
um, you know, in that context I
feel like there's a framework
and
it's part of my role and
responsibility to be more
directive. But I still try to
partner with people always to
say, There's what you want to
learn and what you're interested
in. And there's what I see as an
opportunity for you. And let's
bring those together and make
out a plan. Um, it
Bekah: that.
David: yeah.
Bekah: I was just gonna say,
acknowledging the person where
they're at on the journey is a
huge part of that. And, and what
your relationship is with that
person, because for sure, we
communicate differently with
people we've been working with
for a while or somebody who's
new on the team or someone we're
meeting for the first time. You
know, all of these things play a
role into, I think, how we
provide feedback and what the
expectations are. Of us, you
know, if I, um, am responding to
a student's paper, there's an
expectation of how I'll respond
to that paper. Versus if
somebody says, Hey, can you give
me
feedback on my blog post? It's
going to be a little bit
different. I'm going to provide
feedback either way, but the
tone
is going to change for sure.
David: But through it, all that
concept of people and
relationships first is really
important. Like. And that's what
I have enjoyed about the part of
radical candor that I've managed
to read so far is that it does
start with that people centered
approach and that, um, valuing
the person that you're giving
feedback to you and valuing the
relationship for what it is not
needing to make it something
that it isn't in whatever
context, but
valuing it for what it is. And.
Valuing that the other person
involved is a human on a
journey. Just like you're a
human on a
journey. And, you know, there
was a time when I didn't know
what I
was doing and people were
gracious with me. So I tried to
return that favor, pay it
forward in that sense.
Dan: and I I'd say another,
another, um, Another piece of
this is, um, you know, when you
talk about meeting people where
they are and things like that,
um, it helps when you know them
already, right. It's easier to
have, uh, connections when you,
well, I was gonna say when you
are connected, I don't know. I
dunno that sentence kind of
broke down in the middle there,
but,
uh, I was thinking about two
things. When, when you were
talking something Bekah and I
worked together. Don't know why
I
brought this up, but Bekah and I
worked together. Um, and it took
us, I dunno. How long do you
think it took us before? I mean,
at least a year or something
before we were really like,
Bekah: I feel like right before
the pandemic hit, we were like
eight months in and we, like, we
finally hit that stride. And
then, and then
Dan: yeah. And, and some of, and
some of that is like, um, Some
of
it is me, you know, so Bekah had
just started in like in dev and
had just kind of gotten outta
bootcamp and stuff. And so some
of it was me like learning how
to do that better, you know,
learning to do all the stuff
that David's just talking about.
Um,
and some of it I think is, um,
is just that connection over
time,
you know, kind of just grows and
grows stronger. Um, and that's
another thing I appreciate about
Virtual Coffee and, and I think
it helps is, um, when you know,
people, you know, it's, it's,
it's a little bit. Um, easier to
do this I guess, and to get
practice at it when you know, a
person. And so, so you don't
have
to maybe necessarily, um, like
I, when I pair with somebody
I've
paired with people, you know,
kind of cold, right. So people,
I
don't know. And, um, for the
first time, and there's always a
bit of like level setting, you
know, and I, and I, I try to be
very, I mean, I, I wanna be very
careful about it and I, you
know,
it's like, you don't wanna
assume that they. That a person
knows
things that they don't know. You
don't not assume that they don't
know anything either. Right. And
so it's that like, it's that,
um,
I, I just, I go level setting
cuz I'm like, and I've now I've
just
started explicit doing it. Like,
I, I wanna be very like clear
that I'm, you know, I, I just
wanna figure out where we are,
you know, where you are, where,
where, like what level I can
talk
at, you know? Um, and it's,
there's no judgment at, you
know,
um, it's just. It's just
somebody who's just learning for
the first
time is gonna have different
questions and different thought
processes than somebody who
maybe is a Ruby expert, but is
just
starting a JavaScript. That
person is gonna have completely
different questions, you know?
Uh, you know, and, and so it's
always, um, I don't know. It's
always kind of interesting to
when you're connecting with
different people. So when you
have a, when you're at work and
you're a team, kind of, you
build
a rapport over, over time.
Right. And, uh, when you. In a
lot of
random internet communities, you
can still be valuable and you
can
still have valuable connections
with people you don't know. Uh,
for sure,
David: Well, this overlaps, I
think, with, uh, with you were
talking about Bekah and that
Deval. Uh, session you gave the
other day, too, that there's a
part of community building and a
part of developer relations that
is going out and reaching out to
people that are not yet a part
of the community and trying to
create an opening connection,
uh, with somebody that you don't
know. Um, Dan, as you were
talking, I'm reminded that one
of
the things that constantly
surprises me still years later,
when I about software
development is how long it takes
to get
started with new people.
Especially with new people. When
I sit down to pair with a new
person, say a new person joins
my
team, or I'm in the co-working
room for the first time with
somebody new. it's not
unreasonable to take one to
three
hours to just set out your
machines to work in this a
compatible way and set up your
language. Like you were talking
about to figure out what level
of detail and abstraction to
speak.
And hear each other and to
develop a common understanding
of
the problem and to work through
build and compile issues in a
new
environment, like all these
things that are not typing that
are not reading and writing code
become really, really important
and take real time when you care
about the relationships of the
people you're working with. And
I'm constantly surprised by, you
know, how little I get D how
little. Progress we make in the
code. When I sit down to pair
with people at work, say for the
first time and how much time it
takes to build that initial
rapport and common ground and
common language and common
environment. And the reason I
keep talking about it here is
cuz
I really want to normalize it
for anybody who's listening. If
you
try pair programming and you sit
down with another human, expect
it to be awkward at first.
Dan: Yeah.
David: will be and that's okay.
That doesn't mean you're doing
it
wrong. And that doesn't mean
you're failing it that's part.
That means it's working. That's
part of figuring out how to work
together with another human. And
it does, it's like any other
muscle or skill. It does get
easier over time. Dan, you spoke
about, you know, you you're
working to get better at how to
ask those questions more
directly. How to figure out and
navigate that awkwardness
faster. I, I, I feel like I can
navigate
it faster now than
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. Um, yeah.
Bekah: You know, coming from the
other perspective, like it's,
it's a two way conversation,
right? And so when you're first
starting out, it can be really
hard to ask those questions. And
if there's anything, I feel like
I've learned over the last
couple
of years, it's ask those
questions, whether or not you
think it's gonna make you sound
ridiculous or incapable, you're
going to learn and grow faster
that way. And so. You know,
having those conversations and
being open about where you are
too, if you're on the other side
of that, that pairing screen is
essential. Do you have any tips
for people who are on that side
of the screen? So opposite of
you David, about like how, how
do you
ask those questions or what can
help make this a successful
session by having these, this
conversation?
David: Well, I like everything
you just said. Bekah all of that
is really important. Asking
questions. The faster you ask a
question, the faster you'll find
out if the person that you're
pairing. Is, you know, how
they're gonna react to you and
the faster you'll find out if
that's gonna work for you and
it's gonna be a pairing session
that you wanna stick with, or if
the person's not gonna treat you
well, not in a place where they
have the skills to treat you
well, and, and you can get out
of
there, right? The faster, it's
all about feedback and
shortening
feedback loops. So that's one
part of it is the faster, you
can
ask questions, the faster you
can say, what, you know, the
faster
you can say, what you don't know
without, you know, with as
little
emotion or. Um, I mean, we're
all emotional people. I don't
mean to
say you have to be abstract, but
there's that thing that we do
sometimes I've done it when I
was learning Indonesia. I. When
I was
almost embarrassed to share what
I knew embarrassed to try to
speak in a new language. And I
think it's very similar with
technology. If you're not
familiar with language or
concepts, it can feel
embarrassing to try, but please
do the faster you try. And the,
the faster you take risks, the
faster you'll find out who will
support you in those risks and,
and how fast you can grow.
Dan: Yeah. And I just wanted to
add that that advice applies not
just to beginners too. It's it
can be embarrassing for me. I
mean, I can feel that
embarrassment, you know, trying
new things and, and, and, um,
some hesitancy and things like
that. So it's great advice I
just did and it applies to
everybody
and we all go through it. You
know what I mean? So,
David: And we go, that's
important that you bring up Dan,
cuz we go through it. Not just
once. It's not just something
you
go through. As you're entering
your technology career, and
that's why it's so important to
get practiced at it because you
will experience that throughout
your career. Cuz we're always
learning and technologies are
always frame, uh, changing new
frameworks, new libraries. You
mentioned earlier, a Java script
or a Java developer who was
learning Ruby, I think. And um,
When I first started learning go
I've program C sharp for years
when I first started learning,
go bang. My head against things
felt
awkward. Didn't know how to ask
questions. Um, I have been known
to rant about type script and
Webpack in Virtual Coffee
threads. And, uh, I kind of
laugh as I do that because
that's me
where I could. I could write C
sharp, cold, probably in, from
memory from just having, like, I
know the syntax so well, cuz
I've
done it so long and I can't for
the life of me, figure out
Webpack or.
Dan: Nobody
David: And I struggle with type
script bindings, and I was
working with JavaScript back
before it was popular. So
Dan: what? Pec David it's okay.
David: it's good to have
community in that. Uh, but yeah,
every, every time you go to
every time I've gone to a new
project
or gone to a new company or
changed jobs, there's that
learning curve. Again, every
time I pair with somebody new
there's
that learning curve. I was just
banging my head this past
weekend
against one of the old advent of
code problems and feeling like I
don't know what I'm doing, you
know, and I've been doing this a
long time. So getting
comfortable with that feeling is
really
valuable.
Dan: Yeah.
David: It's good. Good work to
practice.
Dan: Agreed. Yeah. I'm, I'm
digging into type script for
really the first time over the
last month or two too. So we
have
type script. Tuesdays is my
little plug. Uh for Tuesday,
2:00
PM, uh, Eastern, uh, with Kirk,
um, who is, who's like a, you
know, he's, he's done a lot of,
he is a fan of, you know,
strongly type things. And I have
been, uh, Long time, not fan of
that. So but some of it, some of
it is avoiding it is, is, you
know, you open, I open up, I've
been writing JavaScript for 20
years and I open up a type
script file and I'm like, this
looks.
Nonsense to me. I can't
understand it and I close it,
but
I, and I, and I like I'm instead
of like digging in or asking
questions and making myself, you
know, possibly look like, I
don't
know, everything, I close it and
run away and say, are dumb. It's
dumb. you know, that's what I've
done for the last 10 years or
whatever. And so finally I was
like, okay, let's, let's, let's
dig in. And so, um,
David: Okay. And full on every
time I've ranted about wet bag
or
type script, I'm aware that it's
because I haven't spent the time
to learn it. sometimes it's fun
to put on that grumpy old M hat
and say, yeah, I've been
programming JavaScript since,
before there were types I don't
who needs types, like write your
angle, brackets. I, whatever. No
it's, but none of that undo,
like
I really there's an element of
humility. That's important to
practice in this industry
because there's so much lack of
humility,
abounds, um, arrogance, abounds,
gate, keeping abounds and
anything we can do to be humble
with each other and really
support each other to work
together and to grow together
is,
uh, a net positive.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. And, and I
think a lot of that, um,
arrogance and
gate keeping and some is, is
because the root cause of it is
insecurity. Right. And, and not
wanting to, not wanting to look.
Or look like you don't know
things and have I've fallen in
that drive. I try, like, I
don't, I don't know. Maybe I, I
haven't,
haven't noticed, but I, I don't
usually for me it doesn't, uh,
manifest as gate keeping
hopefully, uh, or things like
that. It just manifests me
avoiding topics. I don't wanna,
I
don't wanna, you know, learn or
don't know or whatever, you
know,
um, and that practicing humility
and practicing, um, admitting
or,
or, you know, being public about
not knowing things, um, It's
been
something I've been personally
working on for the last couple
years and, and it's, and it
feels good once you, once you
turn the
corner, once you realize it,
doesn't actually like, you know,
hurt, uh, to not know literally
everything in the world.
Bekah: What I will say too. One
of the greatest learning.
Answers
I've had over the past couple
years is watching conversations
in slack, between people who I
see as experts in the field
asking each other questions,
right. Like, oh, okay. This is
how you ask that question. Or,
you know, they don't know
everything. And that does help
provide more of an awareness
that
I can ask those questions too.
David: that reminds me. I wanna
go back to that. A part of the
question that you asked Bekah
that we didn't really address,
which is what makes a good
question. And, uh, if you think
about everything we've been
talking about the faster you can
help somebody. Acclimatize to
how to speak to you the faster
you'll
get your question answered. And
so how do you do that? You learn
to add more detail in the
question, which is like your
initial offering to somebody.
When you're asking somebody for
help, the more you can put into
that question to say, I thought
about this. I tried this, um,
here's the command I used.
Here's
the output that I got, like the
more language. That you use
often, it's a better question
because you're giving somebody
more context and the ability to
understand better where you're
at
and what you're really dealing
with. I, I get questions in my
job. Sometimes I get questions
like the integration environment
is down and I look at that and I
say, okay, thank you. The
integration environ. Um, where I
work has probably like 75
microservices or more across
like grouped into several
different
applications. And so integration
is down could mean any number of
things. Are, is that a, is, are
you getting an, an
authentication
error? Is that a, you know, do
you have an HTP status code you
can share? Do you have, can you
tell me what application was
trying to call? What application
can you tell me? What was the
actual response you got? What.
Compared to the expected
response
you got. Can you tell me what
language you're working in? Can
you tell me what version of the
you tell me what libraries and
tools you're using that might be
relevant? You know, all of that
detail is helpful, partly cuz it
teaches the people who might
answer your question, what
language they can use with you
because you're exposing what
language, you know, and it's
also giving people more. Detail
to
hang onto. There are problems
that I can solve. And I have
done
in our Virtual Coffee slack,
where just seeing the error
message reminds me of something
I've already seen. And I can
point somebody without even
needing to be at a computer or
look at their screen. I can at
least offer a few keywords or
say, go try this or go try that.
You know? And sometimes that's
enough to unblock somebody, but
if, if the person who asked the
question didn't include the
actual error message, then. I've
seen also where that can turn
into a thread of 55 messages
long
with people talking past each
other. So as somebody who wants
to ask a question, I don't
expect you to have solved the
problem.
It's not this idea that, you
know, don't come to me with
problems only come to me with
solutions. Like it's not that
business, not at all, but it's
share with me what you've
already
thought about. and share with me
as much detail as you can, about
what you know, and what you
don't know about the problem
that
you're asking. Cause that will
help me learn where you're
struggling and how to speak to
you about it.
Bekah: Yeah. Thank you so much
for being here with us today,
David, this was just fantastic.
I feel like we could have done
three hours worth of this
conversation, but I do
appreciate
your time and, uh, thanks for
helping us to kick off our new
season.
David: Oh, my pleasure.
Dan: Yeah. Thank you, David.
Thank you for listening to this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!