Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 6, Episode 2 of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Hello! How is it going,
Bekah?
Bekah: It is going fabulous.
Dan: That's so much less
satisfying to say than "Waddup,
Bek." [Bekah laughs] I think I'm just gonna
start saying that in every episode [laughs].
Bekah: Fine. It's fine. That's
cool.
Dan: Anyway ... yes. Today we
have another, you know,
awesome, obviously, guest.
Bogdan --
Bekah: The theme- theme for
Season 6 is awesomeness.
Dan: Yes. And really, for all
seasons, honestly.
Bekah: [Singing] Every
[unintelligible].
Dan: But yeah, we have Bogdan Covrig
here. He is a software developer from The
Netherlands, and he ... I don't
know. Yeah, he- he -- it was really
great to have him around [??], he-
he just finished school, like last
year, sometime, right? Or this
year? Last year? I don't know.
Recently. In ... The ...
Nether- ... lands --
Bekah: Time has not exist over
the last two years. So --
Dan: Right? Yeah, yeah. No, I
have no idea. But he talks
about that. He talks about
experience in school, go
through school, and- and then,
you know, his experiences as
developer, and, it was really fun.
Really- really good talking to him.
Bekah: It's always interesting
to think about the journeys that
people take to get them to the
roles that they're in. And so I
think Bogdan is one of the first
people, or one of the few people
that we've talked to who's been
an educator, as in like, in a
university setting, teaching
people about coding.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And to hear what that was like and
what he learned from that experience that
brought him to where he is right now.
Dan: Yeah, totally. I mean, I was
very curious to hear about that.
And I did some computer science
in- in- in school, and in college,
and it was a long time ago. And
... I don't know, I was curious
to see -- hear about -- I'm also
just curious to hear about what it's
like in a classroom right now as
a developer, as, you know, in a-
in a college classroom, as opposed
to bootcamps, and things like
that. And, yeah. And- and also
... I don't know. The idea of
teaching is just like, so beyond
anything I've ever done, like,
you know, teaching at semesters
of worth of classes, you know?
I -- although, I don't know. I was curious
about it and so it was really nice to
hear about it from- from- from
Bogdan.
Bekah: Yeah. And to hear the process
that he went through as he was
trying to figure out like what's
next for him in his career path.
And we start every episode of
this podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. So, we
hope you enjoy this episode.
Today's random check-in question
is, what is your favorite
condiment? My name is Bekah. I'm
a technical community builder,
and my favorite condiment is hot
sauce. Definitely. That goes
on everything.
Dan: That's a good one. Yeah.
All right. Hi, I'm Dan. I do web
development in Cleveland. I-
I don't have a super favorite.
I- I'd say -- so there's this taco
place in ... near where I live,
called ... what -- Bombas.
And they -- so when you
could -- they have this like sauce.
And you can -- when you order like
a taco box to go, you know, like
this, like a family box or
whatever, they'll give you just
like a whole- like a whole thing
of it, a whole like bottle of it.
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: And I -- when we do that, I- I use it for like
the next two weeks and -- on like everything. So I- I
can't really describe it. I think --
it has garlic in it, certainly. I
don't -- it may be some sort of
aioli maybe. I don't- I don't
actually know, and I don't
really wa-
Bekah: Is it spicy? No, it's
not spicy.
Dan: No, it's not- it's not
spicy.
Bekah: Creamy?
Dan: You kn- yeah, it's a little creamy, I guess. Although
saying creamy makes it sound weird [chuckles]. I dunno [laughs].
But- but it's good. And I, like,
I don't wanna know really. I like
the mystery of it, you know what I mean?
It's just like this magical thing that
shows up, and then it goes away,
and then a couple months later
we'll order, you know, those
tacos again, and it'll be back to
my life. I don't wanna have
the mys- like, maybe it's just
some chunky thing that they buy
off -- it probably is [chuckles]
something that I could just buy
at the grocery store, you know?
But I don't wanna know. It was --
Bekah: Is it like mayonnaisy?
Dan: I don't know. It's-
Bekah: Does it need refrigerated?
Dan: -meal [chuckles]. I mean, I put it in
the refrigerator. I don't -- I assume. I
don't- I don't ... I don't know. Why
would you have an open bottle of
some sort of sauce that you
didn't put in the refrigerator?
Bekah: Hot sauce doesn't go in
the refrigerator.
Dan: It doesn't? We keep ours --
Bogdan Covrig: Some do. I feel
like some do, right?
Dan: Yeah. I don't- I don't know. Well,
like Tabasco. Do you put Tabasco in
the --
Bekah: You need it to hive [??] --
No. I don't think it needs to be-
Bogdan: I do [??].
Dan: Really?
Bekah: -there's a lot of vinegar in it
and that doesn't need to be refrigerated.
Dan: Huh. We had these refrigerator
talks before. I- I don't know the
rules. So I just assume
everything goes in because it
seems safer to me [Bogdan chuckles]-
Bekah: Tomatoes do not go in the
refrigerator. They still do not.
Dan: -you know? Right. This is what I'm
saying. I don't -- I- I know -- I- I
don't have the knowledge to argue
with you about it. But I just put
things in the fridge because that
always seems like the safer
option, you know what I mean?
To me.
Bogdan: Do you- do you
put your oil in the fridge?
Dan: No.
Bekah: No.
Bogdan: Yeah. That would be weird.
Dan: No, no. All right. Yeah, that-
that'd be weird. I actually had a
friend ... Emily's
brother actually, like, got in
the habit of keeping his cereal,
like in the fridge. Because he- he
said it- it kept it -- like, it would
not go stale as- as fast, you know?
It would stay fresh longer.
Bekah: How long do you keep
this cereal [chuckles]?
Dan: I don't know. I mean, he's just like liv- living alone,
you know? And like ... I don't know. But like, we went on
vacation altogether at this little
cottage with this tiny fridge, and
the whole fridge was full of cereal
[laughs]. We were like, "No, this is
not like -- this is not a -- this
is not -- we're putting this in the
cabinet." That's where I draw the
line. Cereal, doesn't go in the fridge.
Bekah: That's -- I'm glad [chuckles]
you draw the line there.
Dan: Oil? Yeah. Yeah -- no. I- I
knew -- I know enough not to put
oil in the fridge. Other than
that, I'll put things in the
fridge, and then sometimes Emily
will say, "Hey, that doesn't go in
the fridge, dummy." And I'm like, "Okay
[chuckles]. Fair enough." But this
sauce, I don't wanna know whether
it does or not, you know what I
mean? Cuz I don't wanna know
anything about it. That's my
point. So I'm just putting it
in the fridge.
Bekah: You don't wanna know about
it. That's weird.
Dan: Hey, it's a mystery. No, I like
it. I like -- it tastes [crosstalk]
very good. I feel like if I learn
about it something will -- it'll
become less good [laughs].
Bekah: I don't like the [unintelligible].
Bogdan: Or you'll be- you'll
be disgusted by it.
Bekah: Alright, Bogdan [laughs] --
Dan: But, I mean, that is- that is
a very serious -- that, I mean, that
is an actual possibility too. I don't- I don't want
that to happen either [laughs]. Alright, I'm done.
Bogdan: Okay. Hello, everybody.
I am Bogdan. I'm from
Romania, but I am a software
engineer in The Netherlands. I've
been living here for almost five
years, moved from a tiny city in
Romania to a tiny [chuckles] city
in The Netherlands. And I like it.
And I don't wanna leave. And
I think -- I were talking about
sauces -- sauce or condiments?
Bekah: Well, I consider some
sauce as a condiment, so --
Bogdan: Okay.
Dan: Oh, oh, well, like, pasta
sauces are not condiment, right?
Bogdan: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I get
it.
Bekah: Yeah. Pasta sauce, it
doesn't count --
Bogdan: No, no, no, I get it. I was
just -- yeah. Cuz one of the best
thing that I discovered and
absolutely changed my life, my
friends got me like this jar
of Chipotle pepper or whatever.
I don't know how it works. I
don't know how -- it's- it's just
amazing. Cuz then I put it in absolutely
[chuckles] everything. I mean,
not everything.
Dan: Nice.
Bogdan: Ev- like everything that goes with
like tomato sauce or tomatoes, I just-
Dan: Yeah.
Bogdan: -pour some of those and it's just amazing.
Like the smokey, everything. So, yeah. But
otherwise, it's got -- like, usually
it's got like garlic goes into
everything, and then --
Dan: I mean, garlic's delicious.
Yeah.
Bogdan: Yeah. And smoked paprika
also. Like, if there's something
that needs to be sp- I don't know,
smoked stuff, it's amazing. And
garlic as well. So, yeah.
Dan: I like it. I almost said-
I almost said --
Bekah: I think all those things in
a sauce together would be great.
Dan: Yeah.
Bogdan: I think, yeah. But I
have -- I- I mean, I have to agree,
like, with Dan's friend, like
living alone, like, it just --
there's -- there are no rules. I ... you know?
[Bogdan and Dan Laugh] I do what I want. I put
everything where I want. And also,
I'm the only one that needs to
know where it's placed. So, yeah.
I don't put my --
Bekah: So, do- do you put your Chipotle
condiment in the refrigerator?
Bogdan: I do. But I'm not sure if
I have- have to? I don't think it's
forbidden, right [laughs]? But I just -- I-
I- I was just -- it keeps me sane. Cuz I
had to -- I had a tiny Tabasco
bottles, but like, I feel like the
vinegar goes up, and then I try to
shake it, and it doesn't, and then
it's all-y vinegary, and I don't
like it. So I keep it in the fridge,
just to be sure.
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: That's interesting [crosstalk].
I should try that experiment.
Bogdan: But I dunno. I dunno. But no,
tomatoes don't go into fridge. Like, I'm --
it's just nuts. It's the way it
is, my friends [laughs].
Bekah: Yes -- no, 100% agree
with you.
Bogdan: Yeah.
Bekah: Well, thanks for being
with us here today, Bogdan. And
we like to start every podcast
episode with your origin story.
So, talk to us a little bit about
how you got into tech.
Bogdan: Okay. Thank you for
having me. I just -- I- I mean, I
want to start with, like, I
think it's very unfair how clear
Dan sound- sounds compared to the two of us,
Bekah. Cuz do you -- do -- you don't post it
like this. You don't sound that cool in the
actual [laughs] talk, I see [??]. Like, there's
some mixing going on, right?
Dan: What. Wait. Are you saying --
Bogdan: You s- you sound very cool.
Dan: Oh. No idea.
Bogdan: And I don't. I- I don't
know. But I'm looking at those
things moving on the screen, and
he -- yours are ... bigger [laughs].
Dan: Well, okay. Well, I
might just be talking louder or
having way -- that might be too-
too loud, actually. I wasn't really
looking at it until just now.
This is --
Bekah: I think it looks different
on different screens too.
Dan: That's probably true too.
Bogdan: Ah.
Bekah: Like, mine looks very tiny, like
barely -- so- so, okay. If you're listening --
Dan: Yeah, yours is probably, honestly,
like [chuckles], I mean, and I try
to do this, like I fix this up in
editing later. I try to, right?
Bogdan: Yeah.
Dan: So, this is like sound engineering
stuff that I've been learning on
the fly since we were started
working the podcast [chuckles]. So I
don't, you know, I don't know a
lot about it. But like, the --
trying to get those levels, you
know, to where it's close to the
edges is usually the best. So,
Bekah is like, I -- yeah, like-
like -- what I was saying is you're a
little quiet, still, you know [chuckles]?
Bekah: I'm quiet?
Dan: A little bit. Not a lot.
Bekah: I didn't turn up my sound.
You didn't tell me to.
Dan: Well, I didn't really notice
before. And also, in -- so, for those --
I don't know if we're gonna cut
this or not, but for people
listening, we use Zencastr, and it
doesn't show you these nice level
outputs until you're recording,
which is really obnoxious.
It's hard to tell. So, I
don't know. But, Bogdan, do you
have -- is that the Wave- is that
the Wave:1? Wave:3? [Unintelligible].
Bogdan: You are Wave:3.
Dan: Wave:3?
Bogdan: But no, it was a compliment. We
don't have to go into it. It's also very --
Dan: Oh, no. [Unintelligible]. I- I just
got- I just got the Wave:3, like, last week-
Bogdan: Yeah, I have ... yeah.
It's --
Dan: -and it's like a day getting it set up.
So I can send you some stuff [chuckles].
Bogdan: It's ... no, it's Wave:3,
right? It is.
Dan: It looks like it.
Bogdan: Yeah. It's Wave:3. Yeah. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I like it. It's nice.
Dan: Yeah. I got- I got -- I like it
too. I just got it ... yeah. Two weeks ago.
Or a week and half ago. So ...
I'll send you some stuff.
Bogdan: It- it -- yeah. But is- is
your room, like, prepared for this?
Dan: No. Nope. It's just --
Bogdan: Cuz you sound insanely good. Like,
there's no way mine sounds like this.
Bekah: You sound really good.
Dan: Yours sounds pretty good. I think
one thing is, you probably could
be closer to your mic. That's --
I mean, maybe not. I don't know.
When you're -- it's when you're
moving away -- so, like, if I sit
back here, does that sound- that
sounds like noticeably worse?
More echo-y -- echo thing?
Bogdan: Yeah [Bogdan and Dan laugh].
Bekah: So- so for the listeners,
Dan has scooted his seat back about
four feet.
Dan: All right. Okay, okay. So- so that
was the one thing I- I read about --
so they do like- do like the hang
10 like this, you know, or- or
whatever. And then that's like
distance from your mouth-
Bogdan: Oh, okay. [Unintelligible] move.
Which is [unintelligible].
Dan: -to the microphone should be. Right.
And that's- that's hard. Yeah. It's
hard not to- it's hard not to
move. But like, that gets you
picked up more, but then there's a
bunch of other stuff too, so ... we
don't have to get into it on
that.
Bogdan: Maybe we -- yeah.
Dan: Maybe we do a whole episode
on it sometime [laughs].
Bogdan: Okay. Sorry. I'm sorry.
Bekah: Maybe- maybe a live stream. And
then, the visual will be easier to be seen.
Bogdan: Yeah, screen-ish -- screen the
share -- share the screen [laughs]. Yeah.
Dan: Okay. Anyway, I don't know
what [crosstalk] you were saying, or
you were talking --
Bogdan: Origin story.
Bekah: Origin story.
Dan: Yes [laughs].
Bogdan: Yeah. Yeah, yeah. We were doing
about origin story. Well, yeah. Yeah. It's
very- it's very linear and
r-r-rather boring, but ... yeah. Cuz
I did -- so, in Romania we have high
schools that are very specialized,
and I did one of those with
computer science. So I kind of
knew I wanted. I- I have -- my
family is mainly like, musicians.
A lot of them are trained
musicians, so I didn't wanna do
that cuz I thought it's boring, and
[laughs] fired back to me a few years
later. But yeah, I thought it's
boring. So I went straight to
like this mathematics computer science
high school. So I- I kind of knew
I wanted to do this. I kind of
hated it at the time as well, you
know? The whole C, C++
things that don't make any sense
when you're young and you
just wanna make, what's the
rectangle move on the screen,
right? I don't wanna spend my --
yeah. Anyways. But yeah, I
graduated that, and then I moved to
The Netherlands to do applied
computer science, which was
another [chuckles] surprise. Cuz it
was this program of like computer
science, of course, but like,
electrical engineering as well,
which look -- I could have look it
up and I did look it up. Like, I
kind of knew what the program was,
right? But I did -- I wasn't sure
if this gonna be a lot of -- I
didn't even know what's
electrical engineering and turned out
to be like very ... not cool [laughs].
Like, not- no-not toward the field
itself. This is just for me, like in
university years. It was -- I was
like, yeah. Still, I wanna make
rectangles move. But then I wa- got
super, super, super lucky in my
first year of university, I
think. I got a job — remote
job — in Romania for like one of my
friends' father that had this, like
e-commerce kind of low key
business, where I got into
Node. I did not lie on my
interview, but something made him
think I actually know Node. I-
I did- I did know about Node,
right? I was like [laughs] --
Dan: You've- you've heard of
it. Yeah, yeah.
Bogdan: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Cuz I did -- so
I, like, the -- I remember -- so, the very
first thing I did, like, web development
was, back in high school was like
this pi- p5.js — which is still
around, they're very much
happening — but there was this --
people doing this co-coding
train, they were super into it, and
I did like -- they did, like, the
snake, and I did the snake, and
then I wanted to- to do, like-
like a multiplayer thing or like
a chat room for it, and I- I-
I knew that you can use Node to do
that [laughs]. And that was the only
information I had. And I was
like, "Yeah, you can do like,
WebsSockets, right?" Yeah. But
anyways, they were- they were-
they were very nice to me and
like, they actually hired me, and I
learned a lot about like databases,
and Node, and stuff like
that. And then the second year
of university came in when I was
actually teaching more
programming. And I finally kind of
overlapped the two, and be like,
"Oh, okay, I'm doing this for my
job." I'm learning about this, you know,
we're -- even in school, we learned
a bit like about testing, and CI/CD,
and things like that. I was like,
"Oh, this is actually cool and
useful." So I ... yeah ... tried to
[chuckles] finish school, and then [laughs]
continued, then I got a university job like
teaching Java, which was- which was
bad [laughs]. Look, I have this theory
and [laughs] I hope I never have to-
to get a teaching job again cuz if
I say this. No, I don't. No, it's
not- no, it's not- it's not a hard
day. But it's just like, teaching
programming, it's so easy. Cuz
you just like -- you just say, like,
"I -- I'm- I'm- I'm gonna show
you how to Google." And if they have
questions, you just Google [Dan chuckles]
in front of them, and I -- and- and-
and find out things together. Which
is nice, you know? They also do --
need to know how to Google. But,
yeah. And then I got an
internship at another university,
but for research. And then I
moved here, to another city,
while still studying. I did
my internship, I got a full
contract after, but Corona
happened. So I was staying here
working full-time while
finishing my- my- my bachelor basic
or barely like [chuckles] trying to finish
my- my bachelor. And then I- I --
the- the Maastricht University
research position was absolutely
amazing. Like, it's -- it was
academia, which was kind of new
to me, cuz I- I always knew I wanna
be in -- a developer, right? Or
an engineer. But I was like,
"Okay, we can combine this," right?
I don't know a- a lot about
research, but I [chuckles] know about
development, so we can definitely
overlap. Cuz it was also like a
legal -- kind of legal tech ...
space, where they had a lot of
data where they had a lot of ideas
about tech, but they- they did
the developers. So, yeah, we kind
of combined it very nice. But
things slowly came to an end. And
finally, two months ago I got a
new software engineering job,
to a digital creative internet,
whatever they call it -- agency, in
The Netherlands. So I plan to- to
stay doing Node, basically. Root Node,
React, TypeScript, things like
that. So, yeah, I think, that's-
that's it. This is today [laughs]. Just
recently joined a -- yeah.
Bekah: A cool -- you recently
joined ... I'm sorry. I cut you off.
Bogdan: Yeah, no. That was it. Just
recently, like two months ago, I
think. It was April. So, yeah.
Bekah: So I wanna back up a
little bit and ask some questions
about the schooling that you've
done. So, it sounds like there was
maybe more practical application
than I've seen from universities
in the United States, which
computer science degrees have a
lot of, like, theoretical
content, algorithms, and that kind
of stuff. Is that- is that
accurate statement or were you
doing a lot of that stuff too?
Bogdan: Yeah. We- we were doing that
for sure as well. But yeah, with an
eye on electrical engineering and
kind of like -- so, in- in The
Netherlands, they have this
system of like universities, what
they call universities -- research
universities, which is basically
like a college university in- in- the
US as well, right? Where they, you
know, they teach, you know, like a normal
university [laughs]. And they have these
things ... this like, just wh-wh-what they
call 'hogeschool' or like 'HBO's, where-
where like more professional
schools. In English, they
call them Universities of Applied
Sciences, but it's in- in- in
Dutch doesn't really go -- it's
not ... really -- I think it -- I- I
think it's a university, but
like -- yeah, there's a difference.
Here's like more of a -- like a very-
like a very engineering, like kind
of applied -- hands on experience.
It's also longer. It's four years
instead of three. And you have to
do internships, you have to work
with companies, you have to work
with clients, and things like
that, which is for people
that wanna do, you know, wanna
get straight to- to work and
things like that. Which goes very
well for like, engineering, and
things like that.
Bekah: Yeah. Interesting.
Bogdan: So, it was one of those,
you know? Where you- where you
have like, more like programming,
but like kind of rather like ... the-
the applied part was like more the
electrical part rather than web,
right? Like we didn't- we didn't
learn about web development, but
we did learn about operating systems
or microcontrollers or things that
go into electrical engineering
field.
Dan: Did you have to do assembly?
Bogdan: I think I did not-
Dan: Oh, that's good.
Bogdan: -fortunately. No, but we- we
-- it was- it was insane. Like, I
absolutely -- it- it- it was insane.
And- and- and we did microcontrols, of
course, and all that, like, chip
programming, and things like that,
which I absolutely dreaded and I
couldn't wait to be over.
And although it was interesting,
right? Like, operating systems was
such an interesting thing, but
it's just like the- the- the
whole thing of like patterns,
and ideas, and things you
can have in web development, you --
I couldn't have in- in operating
systems, you know? You- you can't get
too creative [chuckles] about it. Cuz
there are -- especially in
microcontrollers, like, they- they
have this- this huge books and
guides about- about them, and you
have to know things, and you have
to look for things that are just
set, right? Or- or- or, you know, I don't
know enough to- to- to make this [chuckles]
conclusion, but it's still like --
the way I saw it was like, this
is -- I can't- I can't be creative
here, you know? But I
finished it anyways. But,
yeah [laughs].
Dan: Yeah. No, I- I love that. I
love hearing about that, you know?
And you have used this phrase a few
times when you're telling the story
about ... like, I didn't get to
move around boxes or like, you know,
move around boxes [Dan and Bogdan chuckles]. And
like, I- I -- and like, it's -- I know that's like a
funny way of saying it, but I- I
totally connect with that because
that's- that's something that
I personally, like ... I don't
think -- I mean, I never- I never put
it exactly like that, but it's the
same thing of that -- the thing
that drew me to programming was
the -- was that; was moving around
boxes. Or like doing a thing, like,
doing a thing, and then getting to
see it like move or happen or ...
just see it in front of me,
right? And- and while, like
academically, some of the more
like the operating -- the lower
level stuff is, you know, interesting,
maybe [chuckles], you know? I lo-
I totally lost my connection to all
of it. Like, I- I -- like -- and I --
like I said this before, that's-
that's when I switched majors out of
computer sciences was, I was deep
into that- that ... like, section, you
know what I mean? As, you know,
assembling, and I was doing -- I
wasn't ... yeah, I don't know. I don't
think I was -- that semester, had
even done anything where I got to like
hit save or compile and see something
[chuckles] happen, you know what I
mean? And it- and it was just like --
and I lost my interest, you know?
And I think the -- it seems
like you have acknowledged that
in, you know, yourself and use
that as — maybe whether it was
consciously or not — use that as
like a sort of driving force in-
in finding, you know, your path,
and- and like your happiness.
Like, you could have, possibly, and
maybe -- I mean, some people, I guess,
could have forced themselves down the
line of, you know, the electrical
engineering and gotten a job ... I
don't know, soldering things [chuckles] or
something. I dunno [laughs]. But- but-
but, you know, but like you ... I
don't know. It- it's -- I- I just
connect with that. I- I just wanted
to like, kind of highlight that
because it's -- it- it -- finding
what makes you happy in a- in a field
is- is important. Especially com-
field like computer science,
because there are gonna be some
people that ... will get into those
microcontrollers and be totally
hooked, you know? And-
Bogdan: Yeah, of course. Some
find it cool [??], right? Yeah.
Dan: -some people- some people
not, you know? And ... right. Yeah.
No. So, I- I think that's
great.
Bogdan: Yeah, no, for sure. I
mean, I'm not- I'm not- I'm not ...
yeah. It's just like -- also, like,
I remember since I was younger
from high school, like, people
had a thing for Arduinos, which I
think that- I- I think that- I
think that's what -- I think that's
why I thought it's gonna be cool.
Cuz like everybody was like, "Oh
my god. Arduino. Like, you -- we have
to do this," and things like that. And
I'm like, "I do -- okay [chuckles]." I-
I loved it, right? I think it's cool.
Like, Raspberry Pi and things like
that is fun. But ... yeah. Yeah. I
think, I ... yeah. Like,
there where I agree with you.
Like, I need to see immediate
change, and I- I need a reaction
from things I'm doing cuz
otherwise, I feel like I spend the
whole day doing nothing. That's
not super-
Dan: Yeah.
Bogdan: -productive [chuckles].
Bekah: So, when you were doing the
research part of things, was that
more ... data sciencey or what
were you doing there?
Bogdan: Yeah. Kind of. Yeah. We
had a lot of ... yeah. There was-
there- there was data science part,
and again, diving in with little
data science knowledge, cuz I
didn't -- yeah, I didn't study
that. I had ideas. I- I knew
Python, for example. But I got --
I- I- I got very -- I got- I gotten -- [chuckles]
get very lucky to- to find this amazing
person that really, really took
care of everything, like my
mentor, and one of my manager,
bosses, whatever. The person that
I actually got a job through. And
she was super amazing. And she
found all these cool
opportunities, and all these
relations, and connections, and
papers we wrote, and projects we
got in. So, I had the time to- to
learn it on- on the way, right?
Like, I didn't have to worry like,
"Oh, what am I gonna do now?" I'm
always just like, I knew what I
have to do, but I also knew what-
what I have to learn. So there
was amazing. But then we also
did APIs, for example, which was
my previous job as well. And I
think this is one of the things
that ... kind of help them make the
decision to hire me cuz they
were working already on these
APIs. But again, related data,
like, they had -- we had a lot of
data. We needed to serve it to
different sources, to different
other universities, for example,
create some user interfaces, and
stuff like that. So we created
this APIs ... for them.
Which was more engineering, but
then, yeah. The data science part, we
did a lot of machine learning, and
analysis, and NLP for the papers
we were- we were writing. It's very
[chuckles] different and definitely
some- something that I really
enjoy doing, but I- I knew it --
the- the- the whole- the whole way
-- and it was almost three years,
right? I knew the whole time, I
don't wanna do that. I really
much enjoyed it. And I really
much loved working with all these
people, but I- I knew for sure,
it's- it's not something I'm
gonna spend my, you know, my next,
whatever, years doing. So it was like --
Bekah: Was there- was there like
a moment that you realized that,
or it was just kind of like, "I
can do this, but I'm not super
interested in it."?
Bogdan: Yeah ... We-well [laughs], I
kind of learned on the job, right? So I
didn't have a moment to actually
reflect, but it was keep on
coming, keep on coming. I am
talking about moving rectangles
again. This is very serious, so
don't- don't take it too
seriously, but it is. And I -- it's not
that [chuckles]. Seriously. But I ... so,
look. I like ... I like things to-
to- to look good. It's- it's very
silly, but I like the tools that
I use to look very good.
And Jupyter notebooks are not [laughs]. And of course, you
can load it in VSCode, and things like that. But the whole
concept of like staring the
whole day at those notebooks was
something ... it was something
weird for me. I was like, it's not
supposed to be like that. I don't
know if you ever worked wi-with data,
or with people that are doing data
stuff, but those notebooks are
getting extremely messy. I don't
know if it's for everybody or it
was- it was just for us, it was
insanely messy. Like there's -- there-
there's -- there was impossible to, like,
pick up a notebook I wrote, you know,
three weeks ago, and I still
understand it. Like, it was- it was
insane. So I was like, I don't
know for how long I can, like,
guessing my, you know, my- my thoughts
[chuckles], you know? So, of course,
I mean, there's -- there are ways
to do it better. It's not like I
tried everything. It was just like
... the comfort of like working,
and things like that. I think
more. And also, I didn't know,
and I still don't know, and I'm not
at all interested in statistics,
which ... of course we can argue if
that's important or not. But
I felt like I should. Like, we are
talking -- we were always talking
about this models, and probab- probabilities,
and numbers, and constants, and things
like that, that I never had an
idea about, which I was
trying to, but like, it seemed
like I'm really, really, really
like behind all of this. And I
don't have the- the- the passion
to- to learn it.
Bekah: So it's ... oh, it sounds
like you kind of knew what you
wanted to be doing and you did
kind of enjoy that research
aspect of things, but you knew
that was not gonna be like the
place that you -- your ideal job
or what you wanted to be doing. So,
how did you make that decision to
move from that research position
and do something that you would
rather be doing?
Bogdan: So I- I never really knew what I
wanted to do af- i-i-in- in the time --
the -- wh-what -- all I wanted to- to do --
no. All I knew was, so we- we were- we were
doing a lot of programming by the
end of my employment list. So on
the way ... after the last summer
-- so, basically last summer,
cuz I left in February, right? So,
after the last summer, a lot of
other -- not a lot. Like, important
people that I was working close
with -- seniors, left. So I was
kind of around, trying stuff. And
having another -- other people, like
on the same level with me, and
things like that, it's really became
... not, you know ... productive.
And I'm not- and I'm not saying it's a
bad thing. I think it's a- it's a- it's
a great thing for them to kind of
have the- the, you know, this
growing experience, and maybe
growing pains, cuz it was still a
very young lab, right? Kind of
understand th-th-that seniorship
matters, and things like that. And
you need mentorship, and you need
seniors, and things like that. So
there was a thing. So I was- I
was slacking a little bit behind
because I had a- I had a very weird
period after I got COVID.
Even a year after, I was still
very sick and things like that.
So they were very, very nice and
kind to allow me to- to- to work
as- as- as much as I can, which
was [chuckles] not a lot, right?
So I- I- I did the work that I had
to do as- as- as much as I can,
and then when I got a little bit
better, I started looking for
jobs. And I wasn't sure what I
want to do. I- I- I was ... I think
in -- by the end of the year, I
think it was November or whatever,
I've been to web summit in
Lisbon. And I've seen all
these companies, and all these
hot apps, and all these software
engineers doing a lot of cool
things. And I was like, "I wanna
do cool things, but I didn't know
what a cool thing is [chuckles]." But
I just wanted to, you know, I just
wanted to feel like I'm doing
very cool things, which I was
doing at the moment, but in a
different way. Not in an academic
[chuckles] way, right? Yeah. And I
just- I just applied to the startups
that I knew there are in Netherlands,
that kind of met there a bunch to
another companies, and a bunch of agencies.
Cuz I have a f- a friend that is very
much into, like, agencies. He also
has this very tiny agency doing,
like branding and marketing for
people, and things like that.
And he was living with me at the
moment. And -- but he was away,
and I started to apply for jobs,
and randomly told him like, "Hey,
dude. I applied for this creative
agencies -- creative agency in
Amsterdam. What do you think about it?"
And then the flood gets so [??] --
and he showed me, and told me, and sent
me all I could know about [chuckles]
agencies in The Netherlands, which
is very cool. Cuz I wasn't sure
if I wanted to do that, but it
sta- finally started to make sense.
Like, I need- I need something
very dynamic, and I need to move
around. But I also need a
structure which you sometimes,
arguably, don't get in startups
and things like that. So
yeah, like, an agency seemed like
a- like a- like a good place.
But then I realized, ev- all of
that is project dependent or client
dependent, right? Like, you really
need to- to match with- with the
client -- the right clients, and,
yeah, to have the ability to-
to be as flexible as I want to be
and things like that, which of
course they could offer. So it's
going ... well [chuckles]. Yeah.
Still not sure what I wanna do.
I'm just around with [laughs]
programming.
Bekah: Same.
Bogdan: Yeah [laughs].
Dan: Oh man. I- I actually
wanted to swing back to sort of
change topics, but, you were
talking about teaching, I
think when you were doing your
master's, right? And you made a
joke about teaching -- you're
basically teaching people how to
Google. But I- I wa- like, I feel like ...
that's ... that it [clear throat] excuse me.
Maybe that- that's not what you expect
from a professor, but like, that
is like the right way to learn [chuckles]
-- that's what we try to teach
everybody. Not profess- like,
whatever. I don't know what you ...
amateur teach? I- I don't
know [laughs].
Bogdan: No, no, no. For sure.
I know what you mean. Yeah.
Dan: Like the ... you know? But when
I'm trying to help somebody learn,
you know, one of the- one of the, like,
learning how to Google things and
figure things out for yourself is
like one of the biggest skills to
learn when you're becoming a
developer, right? Especially for
the first time. So I just
wondered if you could tell me a
little bit more about like that
experience of teaching in that
structured, you know, in a,
like a structured way as a- as a-
as a ... what- what do you call yourself?
A professor? A- a ... I don't know
what the right term, just --
Bogdan: No. Teaching- teaching-
teaching assistant.
Dan: Teaching assistant. Yeah. So as a TA,
like -- but like, what -- can you just
describe a little bit more about
that from like -- cuz I've watched
and been on both sides of, you
know, learning from sort of
independent online version,
right? But I don't think
we've had anybody on the podcast
who has, like, taught in that --
taught computer science in
this structured way.
Bogdan: Yeah, it was -- it-
it- it --
Dan: I know I might be misremembering this, Bekah,
but ... I'm pretty sure [laughs] -- so I'd like
to hear about it. Could you
just tell me more about that
experience?
Bogdan: No, for sure. But also,
like, they take it with a grain of
salt. Like, I've been a -- I was
a TA. Like, I was still a student,
right? So I also being --
Dan: Sure, sure. So you- so you
weren't doing the lesson plans
and stuff, but-
Bogdan: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Dan: -still you were -- I- I just
would like to hear about it. Cuz it's-
Bogdan: Yeah [laughs].
Dan: -it's like the- the process of learning this
stuff is endlessly fascinating to me and ... you know?
Bogdan: It is. I think it's very
... yeah, I think it's -- I think
education, especially in computer
science is very fascinating
because it's so ... it's so, I don't know.
It's ... yeah. Anyways, [laughs] we'll
get in. Yeah, I think that ac-
actually helped a lot. Like, being
a TA helped a lot because I
don't think people have too many
[chuckles] expectations, I think.
I don't know. They didn't. I had
great students, two times, cuz
there were two periods. And
it was- i-i-it was interesting cuz the --
that- that- that's why I think it's very
fascinating. Like, we had
different people of different,
like, levels, right? Like it happened
-- they were all in the first
year, most probably. Well, I think
it was first year. Yeah. But
some of them had some mathematics
experience, some programming,
some none, and things like that,
but they- they all seemed to- to
kind of like get stuck in the same
kind of places, which I think
it's- it's -- I think it's
interesting. Like, I don't- I
don't know much about [chuckles]
education. But I think it's very
interesting to kind of see how
they deal in different ways
w-with that. And what I used to do
and I thought it was very funny —
not funny in a mean way [laughs] — it's
just funny to- to just observe
it. It's just like, s-see how they
deal with it. And then like, let
them deal with the -- in the way of like
-- I was like, "Oh, yeah. Look, your
colleague did it that way. Why don't
you like ... go around this way," and
things like that, which I think
it was a nice- it was a nice,
like, not bonding experience, but
kind of in a way of like level it
down, especially cuz for some of-
some of -- it was in my ear as well.
Like, for some of us, it was so, so
like intimidating to know that we
had this people in the class that
were, you know, having
experienced in programming and
things like that. I don't know
why. Cuz this is -- it's never a
competition, right? But it was
just weird. It was like, "Oh my god.
They know everything and I don't
know nothing [laughs]," and things like
that. And then, yeah, later it
happened for me to be in that
position and, you know, showing
people -- or students, as a TA, like
to ask those stupid question is
very important, and to
Google everything is very
important. Cuz I also never
understood ... why it was seen so f-
it- it was not seen as like, you
know, frowned upon. It's just
like a thing of like the- the
stigma of like, "Oh, I need to
know things." It's just like, you don't
know Java ... words or whatever, you-
you know how to- to think [laughs], you
know? So, yeah. I think it was very
cul- cultivating for me as well. And
also Googling in front of people
is cool cuz, you know, it's like --
Dan: Yeah, yeah. So --
Bogdan: I, especially -- I'm- I'm good at
Googling. So [all laugh] I think, I- I like to
show off my skills as well.
Dan: Oh, and it is a skill, you know? I
mean, like, way -- a-and i-it's that --
it's about like crafting the
right, you know, like, figure
out what to Google, you know
what I mean, is- is- is hard. And-
and that's like -- that's something
I try to do some- some, you
know, when people ask questions
is if it's something that was an
e-e-easy like ... Google search
for me, I will try to share what
I searched for [chuckles], you know?
Bogdan: Yeah. Sure, sure. Yeah.
Dan: Like- like not -- don't, like, claim that I knew this
off the top of my head, you know, but like, I also wanna
try to, like -- I don't mean to do
that to be like, "You could have
just Googled this," you know- you
know what I mean? Like-
Bogdan: Sure.
Dan: -cuz that's not like -- there's
that- that -- anytime you're using that
'just' word, like the word 'just',
it's probably a bad, like a- like a --
you wanna rethink what you're
thinking because the -- I knew
the right terms to search for, to
find that answer, you know what I
mean? But not everybody does.
And, you know, you -- that's
something you learn over time.
And it's- it's an important
skill. With computer science,
a lot of the answers are out
there ... if you can find them,
you know [chuckles]?
Bogdan: Yeah.
Dan: I've also been trying to do that on-
on our- on our stream sometimes is- is just
Google things. The same thing,
you know? Cuz we're- we're just
like learning at -- you know, Kirk
and I are doing that TypeScript
Tuesdays and so, I'm learn- Kirk
is mostly teaching, I'm mostly
learning [chuckles]. But it's like ...
yeah, we just didn't know something. So we
looked it up and there's no -- I don't
feel bad about that [chuckles] at all,
you know? And- and nor should I, you
know? I- I think that's a great ...
I dunno. That's a great
attitude to have. I- I would
love to see that as a- as a TA,
you know? Cuz I think it's -- it
can be easy to -- when you are ...
when you're teaching or in that
position of like ... I dunno, teaching
something [chuckles]. It could be
easy to like, wanna ... know the
answers or wanna like -- I, like -- seem
like, you know the answers so
that people trust you more or
something like — no, not in like a
nefarious way, but just as a ... as
like a ... I don't know. For me.
This is my personal speaking. It-
it's like I- I can fall into that
trap. And I- and I try not -- like,
I- I- I -- it takes effort to,
sometimes for me, to like, not do that,
you know [chuckles]?
Bogdan: Yeah. [Unintelligible].
Dan: Because I don't, obviously, know
everything and ... I don't know.
Bekah: I think --
Dan: And it's okay, you know?
It's like --
Bekah: So much of it is based on
our education, right? Because
like you're tested, and you're
expected to know information,
right? You're not expected to
look up information and find the
answers. And so then going on
through years of doing that,
there's -- it- it feels like it's
not successful to have to look
something up like, "Oh, you
failed. You should already know
this." But it's -- that's not the
case, especially with this now.
So, you know, it's always how
to find the answer is more
important. And I read a tweet. I
don't know who tweeted it out,
but it was like, the difference
between a junior developer and a
senior developer is they're more
effective. Senior developers are
more effective at Googling. You
just get-
Bogdan: It's true. For sure.
Bekah: -faster, you know more words that you
can use, you can narrow it down more quickly.
And- and I think that that- that's ... a
lot of what it is [chuckles], right? Like
knowing what to look for and what
the approach is because you ha- you
have to figure it out. And tech
moves too quickly to memorize
everything that you're doing. So
kn-knowing how to Google and knowing
that that's what's expected of you,
I -- is really important. It's a --
you are should not be asking for
the answers every time you hit a
roadblock. You should be looking
things up and figuring out how to
do them. And that's Nick and I --
Nick Taylor and I did a Lunch
and Learn ... last week? Where we kind
of talked about like, what do you
do? How do you navigate those
challenges? How do you ask
questions? That kind of thing.
Cuz it's important.
Bogdan: Yeah, it is. I- I- I, yeah.
I think that's great, the- the- the
way you put it. Because I find --
so what I think about is
[unintelligible] [chuckles] I find, with
all due respect and love for my parents,
for example, that call me every
time their phone doesn't work,
right? And I'm thinking about
this. Cuz it's like, look, what
I'm doing is just goo- I don't know
your phone by heart, you know?
You -- they also have Android phone [laughs].
So, I'm like -- no, I'm not saying it is
a weird thing. I just like, I
didn't use an Android for eight
years now. I'm like -- I'm not
gonna- I'm not gonna know what you do-
what you do have to press. I'm just
gonna Google it and things like
that. But then I kind of took
one step back and realized like
what- what happened with me at
least? And I don't know, I'm not
sure for how many other, like, people
Eastern Europeans [chuckles], is that
relatable? Not Eastern
Europeans. Everybody that doesn't
speak natively English, I believe.
Like, we didn't -- I didn't have a
computer for a very long time,
right? And when I had it f-for the
first time, I was young -- still
young, but like, I didn't know
English. But [chuckles] until once I
started to learn English, I realized how
much -- how many things you can
Google, and how many YouTube
videos you can watch. It was insane
[laughs]. It was like the- the
whole world open. And finally,
I started to Google everything.
Like ... even for my mom, like, I
was like, "Hey, do you need this?"
And no, no, no. Yeah. And
then, I think that's a thing.
Like, I think that's where they-
they- they draw the line,
you know? It's just like ...
navigating the internet to- to
finances and things like that. Which
of course, it learn -- i-it's a skill,
right? Like, you have to learn it.
They didn't take the time to
do it, so that's okay. I'm gonna
do it for them [laughs]. But yeah,
like, I think that's- that's-
that's, yeah. That's like, yeah.
How- how you're supposed to- to-
to think about things. Like,
am I supposed to know by phone by
heart? No, of course not. Cuz
it has thousands of menus.
Bekah: Well, it's not necessary, you
know? Like the other thing. We need to --
Bogdan: Exactly. Why would you add --
exactly. Yeah. Why would you adding
all of that if you do it once a year
or whatever [chuckles]? Which happened
to me, by the way, about -- talking
about phone. I'm sorry [laughs]. I was-
I was coming back from a concert
the other week. And it was like a
three hours train ride, and my phone
just froze. And it was- it was not
dead, but it was just like, the
screen was open, but I couldn't
click anything. And I tried to restarted
it the way I know it [chuckles] and
things like that. And it didn't
work. And I s- I didn't have anything
on me. Like, all it was just my
phone and my wallet. So I sit on a
train for three hours doing nothing.
Which was a new experience [laughs], you
know? I never- I never get to do
that. Also in the middle of the
night. But then I got home,
Google it from my laptop, and
there is a second way to restart
your phone, you know? And that
worked actually. And I was like,
"Wow, should I know this? I don't-
I don't think so [laughs]."
Dan: Why didn't you just look it up on
your phone [Dan and Bekah chuckle]?
Bogdan: Yeah, exactly. Why, right?
Yeah [laughs]. Exactly. Yeah.
Dan: Yeah.
Bogdan: Yeah. No, but it was a nice three
hours of ... thinking [unintelligible].
Dan: Wow. So did you like-
Bekah: It was tough.
Dan: -did you like, go into alternate dimensions
or something [all laugh]? You do a zen, you know?
Bogdan: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, it
was weird. I wished- I wished
people would just sit in the
same, like kind of train
compartment with me, and speak
English. Cuz everybody was
speaking Dutch around me. And I
was like, "Please someone speak
English. So --" I just- I just wanted
to hear it. I didn't [laughs]- I didn't
wanna talk with them. I just wanted
to hear so I haven't to like think
about ... it's weird. I never
get to do that.
Bekah: Do you speak Dutch?
Bogdan: No [laughs]. No, I don't. So that's why.
But yeah, I don't -- I never get to- to- to
think [chuckles] on my own. I always
have music playing in a background or
something. It's very weird.
Bekah: Yeah. It's interesting how
much time we occupy our brains
constantly. Like there's a- a need
-- I read this book ... "Bored and
Brilliant" maybe? Somebody
recommended it to me. And it was
really good. Like, your brain
needs time to be able to process
different things, to be creative, to,
you know, like store knowledge that
you have accumulated. And I think
that we don't do that. I mean, I --
like, I'm in the car, I have a
podcast on. I'm going for a run, I
have a podcast on. I'm in my
house, I have four kids. Nobody
[chuckles] ever stops. Like, I feel
like I might be afraid of silence at
this point. Like, what- what will
happen if I spend 10 minutes
being silent? Let alone three
hours. Like --
Bogdan: I- I think I am. But I don't
know. I never re- I never- I never
got the time to actually think
about it. I- I bet I am, right?
Like, I can -- I should be able
to go on a walk and not listen to
music, right? Like, that's- that's
what I was sup- but I can't, and I
think it's weird. Like, I- I
don't know. It's a very weird
thing. And I don't wanna ...
I don't know.
Dan: Yeah. I have the same thing.
I have- I have [unintelligible] --
Bekah: So none of us up meditating
then, we're not [chuckles], like --
Dan: Oh god.
Bogdan: No way. There's no way it's gonna work.
Tr- [chuckles] yeah. Try [unintelligible] --
Dan: I ... yeah. No, I have the -- so
I have the AirPods Pro, and so like
to push play, you- you squeeze the
thing that sticks down, you know?
And the other day I walked outta
my office and I didn't have them
in, but I thought I had them in, and I
squeezed my ear a little [Dan and Bekah laugh]-
a little, and I'm like, "Well,
that was- that was really weird."
Bogdan: Wow.
Dan: I'm just so used to having
them in my ears [laughs].
Bogdan: Wow.
Bekah: Are you --
Bogdan: That's embarrassing [laughs].
Bekah: So now --
Dan: Like, yeah. I need to listen
to my podcast for 30 seconds
while I go get water. Like --
Bogdan: Yeah, exactly [laughs].
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. No, it's
true. Yeah.
Bogdan: I do that. Yeah. Or on the toilet.
Like, I- I got to going to the toilet. I
can't just like ... peeing [??].
That's weird.
Bekah: Yeah. Have to be occupied [laughs].
I will say it's- it's nice weather
here. Like very spring weather,
and my kids like to swing on the
swings, and I like to swing on the
swings, and that is like maybe the
only time that I can just -- I'm
still, like, moving and ... my brother
was telling me ... I can't
remember. I think it was a
neurologist that- that was saying,
"To improve your memory, you
should try thinking in complete
sentences for like 10 minutes a
day," or something. And so [chuckles]
the other day I was like practicing
that as I was swinging on the
swing next to my kid, like, "There
is a tree and the leaves on the tree
are very greenly [chuckles]," I didn't
say it out loud. It was just in my head
[Bogdan laughs], and I'm ike, "This is ridiculous."
I never talk in complete sentences, first
of all. But- but also, it was really
hard. I was like, I was shocked
at how much my mind wondered
while I was trying to stay
focused. It was like, "Wait a
minute." I've just like, "Where --
how did I get to this to-do list
that I'm rattling off in my head
because I was just talking to
myself about tree leaves," you
know?
Bogdan: That's -- that -- like, yeah.
Exactly. The w- the way the brain
just like, worked, when- when you
don't do -- like, my -- so my- my
therapist told me, like, when I
used to have this anxiety things,
like, whatever moments, like, my-
my super plan, which I 100%
thought it- it's working, cuz it
made me feel better, was just
like, if I- if I feel weird, I'll
just like straight up, like put on
something ... something that I
can hear and go for a walk, for
example and things like that. Which
turns out it's not good [laughs].
Cuz, no. Cuz at the end, she
was like, "Why don't you just
like ... sit down, and like, think
about what's happening. Or like,
let your- your- your mind
understand like what's happening,
and why you feel that way, and things
like that." Which ... I'm gonna
give it to her [Bogdan and Bekah laugh], in a ways.
It worked for me. In a- in a very weird way. It's
just like -- but then you start to,
like -- I start to like, you know,
like, as you said, like realize, oh,
that's -- those leaves there, they're
actually very nice [chuckles], you
know, and things like that. Which-
which never happens when- when ...
yeah. I even, yeah. Like I, even
before sleep, I like to- to- to do
this, and to hear something, and
things like that. I had a- I had
a friend coming into my room. And
I was listening to music, and he
was like, "Do you listen music in
your bed?" I was like, "What [laughs]? Of course I do. Why don't you?"
And it [Dan chuckles] turns out not a lot of people do that [chuckles].
Yeah. It's weird. The brain is
weird.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: The brain is weird.
Bekah: I mean, I even -- like, I have
a fan running when I'm sleeping.
Because I can't ... take the silence,
ever. Ugh, sleeping in hotels is
like the- the worst. I hate
sleeping in hotels.
Bogdan: I hate it. Yeah.
Bekah: They're so quiet. Or
they're really noisy. We-
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: -stayed in a hotel this weekend. And there
were people out in the hallway until like, 2:00 AM.
Dan: Ugh.
Bogdan: Oh, no.
Bekah: That wasn't ideal. Cuz ...
well, I couldn't understand what
they were saying because it was a different
language [Bogdan chuckles]. So then it
was like less fine.
Bogdan: I'm staying with Dutch
[Bekah chuckles]. Well, I --
Dan: Were they happy? Were they
happy, or they angry, or --
Bekah: I am --
Dan: Medium?
Bekah: I- I'm not sure. I ...
feel like all of the above. But
at one point there was like, this
wasn't -- this was during the
day. There were two young boys,
like wondering down the hallway.
And you can tell their mom was
the one that came outta the room,
because like, she had a total mom
face on. Those kids were not
supposed to be wondering in the
hallway. And she walked with
like, "You are in big trouble [chuckles]."
It was like maybe my favorite part of
the entire hotel stay. Like, I feel you.
I've been there [Bekah and Bogdan chuckle].
Dan: U-universal- universal language.
[Unintelligible][laughs].
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Bogdan: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah
[laughs].
Yeah. I used to -- I- I- I
used to live on a moderately
crowded city -- street, for Maastricht,
I mean, where there were
a bunch of bars, and cafes, and
things like that. And every
single night, people would ...
fight. But it would fight in Dutch,
which was so frustrating. Cuz I
was so curious. Like, no. Like,
seriously. They f- they- they were
fighting so mm- first of all, so
long. Like, you know, you- you- you scream
at each other for a few seconds [chuckles]
and it go -- but they were
fighting for so long, and every
single night I was so -- that was my main
motivation to learn Dutch [laughs]. Just
to understand what ... what are
they fighting about? What is --
Dan: To understand the drama
[chuckles]?
Bogdan: Yeah. Like, exactly.
Like [chuckles] --
Dan: All of that.
Bogdan: Yeah. But then I moved. So I don't
have that excitement in my life anymore.
Bekah: I feel like I would be tempted
to record it. And then trying and get
it translated [laughs].
Bogdan: Translate it after [laughs]?
Never do that. Maybe I should [chuckles].
I tried that with the doctor's
office a bunch of times
when they have the number
pressing things, but it didn't
work that well.
Bekah: Ugh. That's frustrating.
Bogdan: Robot voices, maybe. I
dunno [chuckles]. Yeah.
Bekah: Okay. So, you've kind
of like, navigated all over this
career path. I feel like you've
done a lot of different things
and have a lot of knowledge.
And it seems like you're on a
path that you're enjoying now. What
advice do you have for anybody
else that's kind of like
navigating where they wanna go? I
especially think like, there's so
many people coming into tech
right now. And I think that
there's this focus on ... you have
to do this one thing. Like, you
have to do wh-whatever program or
whatever self-taught path you
went on, but there are a lot of
different jobs in tech, you know?
So, what advice — like, based on
your journey — would you give to
people who are like doing that
exploration and trying to break
in right now?
Bogdan: So, I mean ... without
adding to the gatekeeping, cuz
you know, everybody -- I feel like,
we all have our ways and things
like that. I'm not gatekeeping
it, but I can- I can talk about
like what worked and -- which is
very tricky as well. Cuz I was- I
was actually talking a few days
ago with someone -- with a person
that also just started — switch
from physics to computer science
and now they got an internship.
And I think it's hard. I --
it's hard for me to be in that
position. And also, I think I ask
a question about this the
other day at Virtual Coffee.
Because I- I still feel like,
everything is so overwhelming
already, and it's so hard to find
ways to do things. Like, me
chipping in with [laughs] things would
add to that. But I mean, it's- it's-
it's very interesting. So
like my- my- my advice in
that regard was -- what I was
thinking at the moment ... based on
my school experience and my jobs
that I had on the way ... is -- and
I'm not sure exactly [chuckles] how valid
it is -- not valid. It's just like, we-
we already have arguments about
this, right? Like, the way -- the
right way to start to- to learn
programming and things like that.
Oh, should you learn ... React,
although you don't know
JavaScript or whatever. But what
I- what I find very interesting
about my- my experience is that I
spent so much time trying to learn
things -- fundamental things, which
of course are very important. I'm
not gonna argue that, will helps us in-
in- in many, many ways to- to do our
day jobs, but I didn't have time
to- to focus, you know, like
profess- not professionally, but
like academically ... on things that
I'm actually using at my job. So,
look. You do need Java- you do-
you do need to know- to know
JavaScript to- to- to work in
React and things like that. But
if you spend too much time on
that, you'll never -- y-y-you'll-
you'll get a little bit later to these
things. And y-y-you might, as I did
it with electrical engineering, I-
I- I missed- I missed the
opportunity to get excited about
it. So I feel like, if we would
spend so much time on learning
the basis of- of JavaScript, and this is not
[chuckles] advocating me -- this is not me
advocating for people not to [laughs] learn
the basics. I'm just saying like, the
division of time is very important.
So, I think ... do- doing --
mainly doing ... I don't know. For
example, frameworks, and then
picking up as a hobby or as a
second thing, learning the
fundamentals that you don't know ...
would accelerate it a little bit
more. In the way of -- cuz at the
end of the day, as- as, you know, as
developers, as engineers, we have
to- to find solutions and to
build things, right? And we're
gonna- we're gonna, eventually,
in wha- in some setups, you- you get paid
[chuckles] to- to use the best tools you
have to build the best things you
can build. And ... how you get
there, like the- the tools you use
to get there, I feel like they're
more important than the things
that I spent a lot of time
learning in, you know, all these
formal setups, which was great.
I'm not [chuckles] denying that. But I
just thinking out loud. I think that
was the things focusing on tools, and
then learning the- the- the basics
and fundamentals as- as we go. Cuz
I think that would help us, you
know, get a little bit more creative
[chuckles]. I think. I dunno. I
dunno if it makes sense [laughs].
But that's what I was thinking about
the other day.
Bekah: No, I think that makes
total sense. And I think that's a
great way to end the episode. So,
I wanna thank you, Bogdan, for
being here with us today. We
really enjoyed having this
conversation with you.
Bogdan: Thank you. Very --
thank you very much-
Dan: Thanks, Bogdan.
Bogdan: -for having me. And it's very --
yeah. Very nice to- to be here. Thank you.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any
of our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!