Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 6, Episode 3
of
the Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of
their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories, and what they've
learned. And we're here to
share it with you.
Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Wuddup, Bek! How's it
going?
Bekah: [Chuckles] It is ...
amazing.
Dan: [Laughs] I'm serious. It-
it- it just gives me so much
energy
coming in like that. I-I- I
can't- I can't- I can't do
anything else anymore.
Bekah: I-it is what it is.
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah. So today we
are continuing our streak
of awesome guests that started
Season 1 Episode 1 [laughs] with
Seth Hall. Seth is a Technical
Product Owner at Uniform. And --
so, one of the questions you
might ask is, what is a
technical
product owner mean? And I'm glad
you asked that because Seth
talked about it. He explained
what that means, and why he's
so happy in that role. It's sort
of a organic transition for him,
from being a, you know, a -- I
was gonna say regular developer,
but that's not- that's not fair.
But, you know, being an
[chuckles] individual
contributor developer to this
new role as a product owner.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: It was really cool to hear
about.
Bekah: Well, and I love, too, he
talked about his transferable
skills as a creative producer.
So his background in filmmaking
and how he brought that over to
what he's doing now, which
for me was
a really interesting exploration
of, you know, overlapping that
creative process with what he's
doing as a technical product
owner.
Dan: Yes. Absolutely. The- the
idea of a producer in, you know,
everybody's heard of a producer
in- in the entertainment
industry, and movies, and TV.
And, of course, there's not
always a lot of
clarity about what a producer
does [chuckles] in -- for a
movie, but-
but the ... oh, man. Now I can't
remember what kind of producer
he said is, the one that does
what he's doing. Do you remember
what it is?
Bekah: Creative producer.
Dan: Creative producer. Okay.
And so a creative producer is a
person who's kind of responsible
for shepherding a -- the- the
project, you know, from
beginning to end, and make a lot
-- make
connections between people, and
doing a lot more than, you
know, maybe a project manager or
something like that role -- kind
of role. And it was really cool.
And I- I- I love the ... I love
that idea. And I lo- [chuckles]
I love, like, placing these-
these
frameworks -- mental frameworks
from other industries on top of
dev stuff, and- and seeing how
we either have a role that's
like
that, and it's just name
something different, or- or
maybe
something, you know, the- the
dev industry can actually use
to be- become
better, you know? And I think --
I feel like creative
producer here is
like one of those- one of those,
like, really cool -- it- it,
likes, I dunno. It seemed like a
very cool idea to me [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. And I love how he
talked about — he used the
phrase
'intimate collaboration', and I
think that that sums up what
really makes somebody good at
that job. But th-that's one of
those
things that -- it's- it's not a
common phrase or a common idea
when you're thinking about what
a technical product owner does,
or a
producer, but that -- those
connections are what really
allow
people to be successful.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. It was-
it was cool. It was very good
talking to Seth.
Bekah: Yeah. And we start this
episode of the podcast like we
start every Virtual Coffee. With
our names, where we're from,
what
we do, and answering a random
check-in question. So we hope
you
enjoy this episode. Today's
random check-in question is,
describe a time you laughed so
hard you thought you would cry
or when you did cry. I'm not
sure if that makes sense. What
was so funny? [Laughs] Did you
ge-
Dan: Did you read that question
before ... just now? What is-
what is happening?
Bekah: I did! When we were
setting up the- the podca- when
scheduling everybody. I put
questions in all of them. So
it's been a minute.
Dan: Okay, okay, okay.
Bekah: [Giggles] My name is
Bekah. I am a technical
community
builder. And laugh so hard ...
that I cried. I feel like these
-- those
moments are great, and I can
remember them happening and who
they happened with, but I cannot
remember why they happened. So,
like, normally, it's with people
I'm very close friends with or
with my brothers -- usually it's
my brothers. And I'm usually
laughing at them, and not with
them [chuckles]. So, I don't
know. I have
to think about that more. But I
guess I'm laughing so -- oh. I'm
trying to think, there was one,
that was recently. I was
laughing
so hard [silence] I don't know.
I have to come back to it.
Sending it over to you, Dan.
Dan: All right. Hello. My name
is Dan. I am from Lakewood,
Ohio, the first suburb west of
Cleveland. I do web development.
And, yeah. I have- I have these-
I have these laughing
issues from time to time.
Honestly, mostly with my family.
I don't- I don't know exactly
why. But, yeah. And my mom
gets it too. So sometimes I'll
just like have to cover my face
and, you know, be laughing a
lot, and probably crying in.
The one time that really ...
comes to mind ... ha- have you
guys seen the -- this, like, the
screaming goat videos?
Seth Hall: Yes.
Dan: Like, they were, like,
popular a while ago. And,
there's -- so there's one that's
like a -- there -- so people
started mixing 'em into songs,
you know? And
the -- and there's like this --
the- the Taylor Swift song,
the ... that's like the ...
[singing] I know you were
trouble. Or how's that song go?
Bekah: [Singing] I know you --
Dan: Some -- there's some -- but
there's --
Bekah: [Singing] You walked in
--
Dan: There's some part of that
hook, and then there's the
screaming goat. And it, like,
just kills me every time. And I
-- we were like playing it on my
phone, you know, with- with
my family
in, like, the living room
[laughs]. And I just like --
I could, like -- I was
laughing for probably, like, 15
minutes [laughs]. Cuz my sister
started -- just every time I'd
calm down, she'd played it
again, you know? That was it.
Bekah: There- there was a --
Dan: [Laughs] I cannot stand
this.
Bekah: I -- it was an Instagram
reel or a
TikTok, that was similar. Where
somebody was going to film
themselves, and while -- before
they got started, they
accidentally
like threw their hip into the
side of a bed, and they-
Dan: Oh, yeah [chuckles]. I saw
that.
Bekah: -screamed out, and then,
everybody remixed it. So they
screamed like, "Ah!" And
so then people are like, "Eh,"
you know, like, staying alive.
"Ah!" it would start with that,
and then somebody would go on?
[Seth laughs] That was really
good.
Dan: All right. Wait. I think I
can- I- I think I can -- oh,
can I change my microphone while
we're recording? That
possible? Might not be possible.
I was gonna play it for
everybody, but ... I don't think
I --
Bekah: Link- link in the show
notes.
Dan: Yep. I'll put the link in
the show notes so that we don't
-- I'll have to listen to me
breaking down again [chuckles].
Probably a good call.
Bekah: I used to laugh so hard
when we started the podcast.
Dan: Yes. That was always fun.
It was fun making that happen.
Seth: It was out of nervousness
maybe? Or out of fun?
Bekah: It was. It was, like,
straight up nerv-
Seth: The red light- red light
syndrome?
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Dan would be like, "Go!"
And I'd start the intro, could
not hold it together. Could not!
It took me -- like, even if I
was recording it by myself, it
took a really long time. Maybe
Season 2 is when I finally
calmed down [chuckles]. Like --
Dan: Yeah.
Seth: Yep, yep.
Dan: Yeah. I- I also, like, the
-- like, times where you are
really not supposed to laugh,
but you're -- like, standing in
front of somebody, whatever, but
you make eye contact with- with
one of your friends or-
Seth: Oh, yes. Sure.
Dan: -you know, somebody who
knows you're trying not to
laugh or whatever, tho- those
are always really fun for me
too [chuckles]. Except when I'm
[unintelligible] --
Seth: That's a good- that's a
good segue into mine. My name
is Seth Hall.
I'm a Technical Product Owner at
Uniform. And for me, laughter
has been a huge part of my life,
just with all my friends. You
know, I think it initially
started as a coping mechanism,
just from my childhood. But I
was always like cracking up in
school, in -- I mean, I remember
one time, my cousin and I were
at a funeral or something.
We were, like, eight years old
at a funeral. And, like,
we had to be separated. We were
laughing so hard. But we, like,
found each other through the
pews, you know, across the whole
church and we're still cracking
up, you know? And so,
laughter has been a great
medicine for me, but it's got me
in trouble a lot. But- but,
yeah. So it's just like such a
healing thing for me. And I- and
I still have great friends that
we just instantly crack up with-
with our inside humor, right? I
mean, no one else think it would
-- no one else would think it
was
funny, but- but, yeah. So I --
I'm like Bekah. I can't think of
a specific time, you know,
another specific time, but it's
always been a constant kinda
thing for me. And- and it --
if I can laugh
with you, then I'm already feel
like a halfway, like, you're my
best friend, you know what I
mean? And then if we can talk
about, like, deep stuff, like,
real authentic stuff, then
we're like, we're best mates. So
... but, yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. There --
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: I -- that reminded me of
a time. I was at church with a
classmate. And one of us, we're
like singing in church, right?
And saying the wrong verse,
right? And it's, like, very
loudly. And then there was like,
no [Seth laughs], no,
coming back-
Seth: Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: -laughing so hard. We
were definitely crying. Somebody
had to get up and leave because
it was just, like, totally
inappropriate-
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: -and disruptive. Which,
like, makes it
even funnier [laughs], in a way?
I feel like- like --
Seth: Would be even funnier.
Yeah. I mean, I- I hate to
even think about what my to- put
my teachers through in school. I
mean ... I just was like --
it- it- it, for me,
like, if I had known comedy was
actually a- a- a career, back in
then -- like, nowadays people-
people, like, "Oh, you gotta
improv, and all
these different YouTube things,"
and, like, people go, "I wanna
be a comedian." They go and they
pursue that. But I never even
knew it was a career, but I
listened to comedy constant-
constantly growing up. And then
the thrill of making people
laugh, which was
what I did a ton of, it just,
like, was like a huge, like,
thrill. I mean, it was great.
And I, like, couldn't get enough
of it. And to the point where I
said it was- it was actually
disrespectful, you know,
now that I look back [chuckles].
But that's- that's part of being
-- part
of growing up, I guess. Being
young, and immature, and stuff.
Bekah: Yeah, always. I always --
if there were a personality
trait that I
could just, like, download into
my brain, it would be
m-making people
laugh. I don't know. That's not
really a personality trait.
Seth: Oh, yeah.
Bekah: But you know what?
[Chuckles] I always would love
to make people laugh. My grandma
was
really great at it. And I always
wish that, like, I had that same
ability because it kind of what
you're saying, Seth, that idea
of you -- if you can laugh
together with somebody, then
you're friends, and then that
does often lead to that
opportunity to dive
deeper into things. Because
there's this almost like built
in trust that happens when you
can-
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: -get into that deep
laughter together.
Seth: That's right. Totally.
Bekah: Well, thanks --
Seth: It's a good question.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah! I what --
now, I'm like, what is the
neurobiology of
laughing together? [Seth laughs]
Thanks for being here with us
today, Seth. We're very-
Seth: My pleasure.
Bekah: -excited to have you on
the podcast.
Seth: Thanks for having me. It
is awesome.
Bekah: Yeah! We always like to
start with origin stories. So
how have you got to this point
in your world -- of your- your
journey of Seth -- being Seth
Hall?
Seth: Yeah, sure. I'll- I'll
give you the- I'll give you the
short version [laughs]. Yeah.
So, for me ... let's just --
I'll just
start with kinda ... how I ended
up in development. Like,
wh-when I was --
I know -- I always liked
creative stuff growing up.
I was always ... I- I grew
up in a single family home. I
had a lot of, like, time to
myself and-
and- and music was a big escape
for me. So when I became an
adult, you know, all I just say
when -- in my 20s, I was like,
"I am gonna
do something different. I'm not
gonna do a typical path that you
take or you're told that you're
supposed to take." So, I
graduate- graduated from
college, and then went and
pursued music. So I played
independent music for, you know,
for a long time. I also
did video production and film
production during all that time.
And then I continued, you know,
did music for about -- pretty
hardcore for 15 years. Then I
just kind of transitioned into
the video, film, and then I
kinda got into digital stuff,
got my
first computer, and was like,
you know, graphic design,
learning how to log into web
apps, and all that kind of
stuff, back in 2006.
And then 2011, in the middle of
my film and video pursuits, I
started making websites. And it
wasn't really planned. It just
kinda happened. And so I started
teaching myself
WordPress and all that- all that
stuff, you know? That kinda
normal story. I got my first
tech job in 2013. During that
job, I wa- I decided I wanna go
get my master's in film
producing. So I went to a film
school here, in North Carolina,
called University of North
Carolina School of the Arts.
And ... that was a great
experience. I loved it. I took
a break from
coding for a while to produce
videos for the school, actually,
in their marketing department. I
made like three or four short
films. But then I got to a point
where I was like, "Okay.
I don't really wanna make videos
anymore cuz I've done that so
much. Filmmaking doesn't pay." I
thought, "Well, maybe I'll
do like a -- go back into
development or maybe I'll --
maybe do something developer
adjacent." So I, like, thought
about being a
Scrum Master, you know? I was
like, "I've worked in Agile."
And so I kinda pursued that a
little bit. And then I realized,
"You know what? I really like
development." So I -- so two
thou- and it -- just, you know,
it's- it's -- a lot of
opportunities, and
it pays well, and it's fun, and
challenging. So back in 2019
December, I jumped back in full
force, and shortly after, I
joined
Virtual Coffee, you know? And-
and so, for all of 2020 and all
of 2021, I basically was doing
front-end development. Multiple
contracts, some of 'em were
toxic. Some of 'em were --
didn't value me. Like, they
weren't great experiences.
But I just kept pursuing, kept
pursuing, kept pursuing. And
then
I found a job at Uniform -- a
job posting at Uniform. I -- it
sounded just like me. It was- it
was working in the Jamstack as
a front-end developer. It wasn't
a ... product. It was,
like, demos. So,
like, our internal team demos
our product with, like, fake
websites, essentially. So I was
like, "Oh, that's great." I
can make --
basically make client websites
without the client, you know?
I can make -- I can be a part of
a product team without being on
the product team, you know? And
so, I got hired as a demo
engineer, and I've been working
for them for about four
months now, maybe five months.
But shortly after I got hired,
it was -- it be-became evident
that ... what they really
needed was someone to 'own'
the demos. Like, product own the
demos, not actually code the
demos. So I transitioned to a
technical product owner where
I'm working with designers, tech
lead for developers,
marketers, sales engineers,
like, I'm working with a lot
of people
to kinda guide all the demo
tracks and demo initiatives we
have. But I'm- I'm -- like, now,
I'm planning roadmaps.
I'm- I'm- I'm basically
producing. Like I- like I did in
film, like, was -- with
film, I used to do camera sound,
editing all the stuff. Then I
moved to producing where I was,
like, hiring those people, and
knew what they were doing, and I
was planning the project. Well,
now, it's- it's -- an
interesting equivalent is I'll
-- I used to
be in the trenches of front-end
as y'all know, cuz we've talked
many times about it. But now
I'm, like, planning that stuff.
So I'm-
I'm not the developer, but I'm a
developer adjacent. So my
initial, you know, thought back
in 2019, where maybe I could do
something developer adjacent,
has like come to fruition, like,
on accident. And I am absolutely
loving it. So- so that's kind of
where and how I ended up here.
You know, to me, development is
very much aligns with my- my
goals in life. It's, like,
it's- it's
creative, it's challenging, it's
fun, it's flexible. It doesn't
rule my life, you know? I get to
go to work in my office, and get
to leave, and be with my family.
So, like, everything I wanted
when I was 20, when I pursued
music and film, I have f-found
that. I
have found autonomy, good pay,
satis- satisfactory work. And
I'm not -- like, it's very
unique too, in- in- in a way.
Even though there's
a lot of developers, it's still
a unique way to make a living.
Cuz most people I talked to
don't do what I do. So it all
-- it fit -- checks
all the boxes for me. So- so,
yeah. That's- that's kind of
my origin story and- and- and --
a professional origin story.
And I'm very happy where I am.
I'm, like, I haven't been
happier in- in the-
in the- in the tech -- in my
tech career than I am now. So --
Bekah: Yeah, I love that. I
wanna backtrack just a second.
And so, you've done a lot of
different things. I love how you
say that this kind of, like,
mimics some of the things that
you were
doing before with producing, and
how those skills lead here. But-
Seth: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -was there, like, a
pivotal moment for you when you
decided that you
were ready to make this
transition? Because, you know, I
think it's sometimes hard to --
you're kind of toying with the
idea or maybe you take on a
little bit of side work, but at
some point, you have to say,
"There's a career transition and
now I'm going to go all in."
Seth: Yeah. So from, like, film
to web was literally wasn't
planned at all. It was- it was
-- I sort of just felt this
call and this draw to
do it. And all of a sudden I had
four clients — four WordPress
clients. And this is, like, had
no experience. So I was
doing all of
the stuff you do to learn
WordPress. And of course, that's
not the best platform to learn
on because it's super confusing.
Bekah: Yes.
Seth: But I mean -- but that's
good. I was in the trenches.
So it was
never a conscious effort. It was
just something that I ended up
doing and I just did it cuz I
liked it. And I worked nights
and weekends cuz I liked it. And
then it started paying. Then I
got my first tech job, you know?
And- and so -- but the
transition between a- a
front-end engineer to a product
owner that was very much ... a
welcome transition. Because as
y'all have
seen or know, like, front-end
development ... parts of it are
... easy? Quote, unquote, easy.
But a lot of it is really
difficult. And
I just found myself --  I was
just was getting tired of the
grind. I was getting tired
of like, not breaking through,
and not, you know, not -- still
not knowing stuff, and still not
knowing how to learn stuff I
don't know. And- and, yeah. I
could, you know, put together a
Jamstack site. I could do some
product feature work and stuff,
but it just got to be ...
exhausting. And my skill sets
are- are very
much relational communicate-
communicative, listening,
validating, planning. I mean,
I'm engineering. The-there's a
-- my -- in my personal life,
I'm, like, producing the biggest
thing I've ever done,
which might come up. But, like,
my mindset and my default is
like to dig in there and
organize a- a big thing. And
that could be a- a-a movie,
that could be -- now it's a
three different demo tracks, you
know? And in- in my life, it's
a, you know, other personal
stuff that I'm ...
producing, essentially. And so-
so, yeah. So it was --
the- the initial
thing wasn't a conscious effort.
It really was outta nowhere. And
I was kinda like, "What?" Like,
"This doesn't make any sense.
I'm trying to pursue film. What-
what do you mean -- what's
going on here?"
But at -- it- it quickly became
something like, "Okay, this is
really good for me." Yeah.
Dan: So you used the word
'producing' a few times there.
And that's a word that you don't
usually hear in the-
the development,
like, aside of things, right?
But you hear it a lot in
entertainment. And- and -- so, I
was just wondering if- if
there -- your
experience with ... you know,
in- in film school and stuff
like that ...
you know, the producer of ik-
I'm not in the entertainment
[laughs]. I- I listen to
some podcasts and stuff, you
know, but like-
Seth: Yeah.
Dan: -if- if there's- if there's
some bit of that you took away,
from the -- from
film school to guide your work
now a-as a- as a sort of
[unintelligible], you know?
Seth: 100%. Totally, totally.
You- you know, in- in-
in software, we'd call it
project management, I guess.
You know?
Dan: Yeah, right. But that's,
like, yeah. That's the -- I
don't feel
like that covers every -- to me,
the- the word 'producer' has-
has a- a bit of a different
connota- I mean, it's close,
you know? It's overlap.
Seth: Yeah.
Dan: But, like, a bit of a
different connotation, I think.
It's a good word to use, but I'd
like to hear what you --
like --
Seth: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. So
I- so I got my ma-
Dan: Wh- what do you think of it
-- what do you think of that?
Seth: Yeah, it's a good
question. I got my master's
in creative producing, which --
so, in film, there's a lot of
different producers. There's,
like, your boots on the ground
producer, there's- there's
associate producers, there's
executive producers who, like,
fund it or make a connection,
and they
get a credit. But then the
creative producer is the one
that, like, comes up with the
idea or, like, options of
script. Bekah, you
know about this. And then they-
they hire the writer. They-
they-
they develop the script. And
then they take the script into
...
raising money or- or making a
pitch deck to raise money. And
then they take that money, and
they go into pre-production, and
then they keep going through
production, and post, and
marketing,
and distribution. So creative
producer is like the unsung
hero,
essentially ... in film. Because
most film, it- it falls on the
director or the star of the
movie. It -- but- but producer
doesn't get much credit. But
without the producer, it
wouldn't even exist. And so ...
all through that process,
really, that- that process
is all about, like ... it's all
about, like, you know, for
example, like,
what are we trying to say? Like,
you know, in a- in a- in a --
who's- who's our audience,
right? Both of those things
can translate to- to
a product in- in software. And
then like, who are the people
I'm working with? How do I
communicate with them ... that
translates to software? And
then- then the nuts and bolts
of it all
which is let's- let's- let's
plan the project and actually
do the work, same thing in
software. And so, it- it -- I
just -- it just seems
like a perfect thing for me
because it's, like, already
what I was good at. And I've
already got all the experience
in it, and it
100% is transferable over to
software. It's just different-
different medium and different
ways to do it. Like, you
don't have editors and, you
know, in software, but you have
QA, you know, Quality and
Assurance or whatever. You don't
have sound audio mixers, but you
have, you know, front-end
developers or backend or
security or whatever. So- so I
learned a ton going to school.
Like, I learned -- I- I took
what I
had already learned in life and
then, like, just applied it to
intimate collaboration and then,
like, different personalities,
and different cultures, and
different ages, and different
genders, and everything.
Like -- cuz when I went to art
school, I was like 20 years
older
than most people. And there was
a ton of people that were just
different than me, but I really
just got to ... res- respect
them, and see what
they were about, and learn how
to be with them, and learn how
to deal with conflict, and- and-
and learn how to persevere on a
giant project that seems never
ending. And that is software
development in many ways. So,
that's kind of what I
transferred over and it feels --
it- it's just same skill
set. Just different application,
essentially.
Dan: I love that. I love that a
lot. And you hit one of our --
Virtual Coffee bingo words,
which is intimate. And I think
you-
Seth: Yes.
Dan: -used the phrase intimate
collaboration, which I love.
And-
and it's -- it paints such a
different picture that -- from
that mindset, paints such a
different picture than ... some
of the software, like, when you
come at it from the software
land, everybody -- all --
software developers, lots of
times, want to ... remove
the human aspects of things,
right? And they build tools to,
like, plug things in or project
management tools or, you know,
everybody has stacks of cards to
-- oh, I'm sorry. Everyone
has stacks of
cards to get through [chuckles].
And --
Bekah: What do you think he was
here [chuckles]?
Dan: I know.
Bekah: You didn't know there was
a guest [chuckles]?
Dan: He's always ... bothering
me [chuckles].
Seth: [Chuckles] Is he, like,
bringing you a drink or
something?
Dan: Special guest. Yeah, I
know. He's -- yeah, yeah. He's-
he's -- he brings me my- my- my
Scotch at the, you know, under
my desk, the end of the day.
Except, it's ... the middle of
the day. Anyway [chuckles], what
was I saying? So, yes. I think
that- I think that's probably
another connection between you
-- the ... your experience
within the entertainment, you
know, i-in
film -- in the film realm is- is
making these connections is such
an important thing. And it's-
it's very important in software
too. But I- I think it gets --
people tend to abstract it away.
People tend to abstract away the
human connection aspect of
anything. And, I feel like work
-- everybody -- all --
we're all
doing, and everybody sort of
naturally does at Virtual
Coffee, whether they are
officially doing it or not.
It's -- and I'm seeing
other people start to swing this
way too. It's -- lots of people
talk about community these days,
and building communities in your
company, and- and things, like,
making connections like that.
And I think we're finding out,
like, it's so important to
foster those sort of intimate
connections. A-and obviously,
you can go probably too far
[laughs] but, like-
Seth: Sure.
Dan: -remembering that all the
people
are people, right? And everybody
that works on a project is --
has their own stake in it. And,
you know, it- it's -- the
project's gonna be better if you
have somebody like that,
have somebody
like you, you know? Fostering
these intimate, you know,
connections and stuff like that.
Seth: Yeah. I mean, that's
exactly right. I mean, and part
of that is like, you know, we --
is giving shouts out to people,
shoutouts to people, whatever
you wanna say. Like,
acknowledging people and- and-
and celebrating them. Now you'd
mentioned community and ... how
it's kind of becoming more
prevalent in software.
And I'm -- to me, that's great.
Cuz that's what it is -- that's
what it's about for me, just in
many ways, is- is friendship,
and authenticity, and, you know
... intimate ... you know,
friendships that
are real. That- that like bring
the joy in -- to life and bring-
bring,
you know, bring things to life.
That's what it is for me. And-
and -- so, you know, part of
that is, like, you know, at
work, I like to do shoutouts to
people, and, like, really just
celebrate people, and- and, you
know, I'm- I'm a super positive,
you know, I don't wanna have any
conflict. If there is conflict,
I'll deal with it. But like --
and
I've had so many jobs where it's
just, like, not like that at
all. And it's so -- makes me so
anxious and nervous, and I
don't- I don't know
how to find my footing, and-
and, like, I just feel like
undervalued and- and- and just
not in the right place. And
so at Uniform,
like, it's the exact opposite.
Like, everybody is super
friendly, super laid back, just
very welcoming. And- and a
community, it's
like -- culturally at Uniform is
it -- the culture at Uniform
is very ...
like, on point. It's great. And
it fits my personality, and
I feel --
and, say, from that, I feel
valued and I feel empowered
to do really
good work, right? I mean, that's
how it works. You- you-
Bekah: Yeah.
Seth: -appreciate people and
you're- you're- you're a nice
pleasant people to be around.
You're gonna wanna work hard and
collaborate together to do
things as opposed to feeling
like you can't -- you're
walking on thin ice or whatever,
you know?
Bekah: I- I love that. And I
think that one of the things
that
you -- one of the words you
used, au- authenticity, is so
important.
Because I think that there are a
number of companies out there
that recognize that community
within the company is good and
can be really useful, but they
come at it from a n-not an
authentic approach. Like, "We're
gonna make this company
a community,"
right? And then there's this
forcefulness, like, "We're gonna
be a community. Now you have to
go to this fun thing that we're
all doing together," right?
Like-
Seth: Yeah. Sure, sure.
Bekah: -no, I don't wanna do
that ... fun
thing all together. There- there
has to be ... that
authenticity there that allows
for vulnerability and openness.
And, you know, I've also seen a
number of leaders in positions
that kind of [silence] I don't
know the right word for this.
They perform authenticity-
Seth: Mm.
Bekah: -so they act in a way
that appears to be
authentic, but, like, the
further --
Seth: Yeah. Whi- which is,
inherently, not authentic.
Yeah [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah! And the further you
get into it, then it- it just
like -- then- then the, like,
suspicious radar goes up. Like,
"Uh, I don't know that you're a
person that I can really trust
and talk to." And then that
creates more of a divide. And
when you have that, when you
don't have somebody who's
authentic or vulnerable or, you
know, even getting back to that,
like, intro question of somebody
that you can laugh with, then
you --
there's this distance. There's
this guard that you can put up
or that you might put up that
makes it harder for you to be
effective at your job or to
communicate with other people,
because there's always this,
like, leeriness about where you
stand in
that, you know, relationship. Or
in that collaboration or- or
whatever it is. So I think that,
you know, having someone
authentic leading a team is so
important in-
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: -forming those bonds that
you need for your company.
Seth: Totally. We just
implemented this thing called
15Five. It's a online web
service that allows for, like,
it manages one on ones, it
manages, like, high fives,
you can give,
you know- you know, internal
high fives. And it- and it
really ...
opens -- it fosters that kind of
community and that kind of
culture. And so that's why my-
my company is series a funded
startups. They're just beginning
to, like, hiring, work on
culture,
and work on all that stuff that
they, in the beginning, you
don't do that cuz you're
building a product to get the
funding. But
now that they have the funding,
all these things are locking
into
place, and that -- it's just
such a relief to- to know that
that's there, and it, like, to
not walk into -- to walk into
work and not
be anxious, and not be nervous,
you know? I'm not dreading,
like,
"How am I gonna make this
JavaScript thing happen
[laughs]?"
You know what I mean? Like, how
am I gonna do this? Like, I
should kn- and then start
beating myself up. "I should
know this
already. I've been doing this
for this long," and- and,
anyway, a-a-and --
and that's just kinda highlight
the importance of the --
of community.
And I will say that, you know,
when I discovered Virtual Coffee
-- I don't even remember how I
discovered it. I think it was
through Drew Clements somehow. I
don't remember --
Bekah: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. I
think that's true.
Seth: I forget. I somehow found
... him, and then found Virtual
Coffee. And it was like a huge
breath of fresh air.
Bekah: He was doing Protege. So,
was it through Protege? I mean
--
Seth: Yeah, it was probably
through that. I was probably
looking thru- for jobs, and I
saw him through Protege, and
then I saw
Virtual Coffee through him. And
then I ended up working on
Protege through that too, which
was interesting. But i-i-it was
such a -- the -- when I
discovered Virtual Coffee, it
was a ... godsend,
essentially. Cuz we were in the
middle of pan- I was in the
middle of the pandemic, right?
We were all in the middle of the
pandemic. I had moved out to the
mountains, which I like my -- I
like being out in the mountains,
but I also like people, you
know?
And I just -- it was -- it
saved- it saved me in many ways.
Cuz it
helped me keep going as a
developer, and it helped me
develop friendships, and- and
it's, you know, and that's,
that's it. That's community,
right? That's what community
does. It- it- it kinda -- it
gives -- it- it- it -- a lot
of things
start to bloom, right? All the
different -- these beautiful
things start blooming from it.
And we can see it every day
on our- on
our Slack team is it -- like,
people are doing this and doing
that. And
there's support here, there's
support there. And then you got
in person meetups, and it just
-- and that's just a beautiful
thing about the Virtual Coffee,
I think. And- and I'm sure you
never even expected that when
you started it, you know?
You ... might-
Bekah: [Chuckles] Nope.
Seth: -have thought something
like- like- like it, but ...
yeah. It just- it just,
all of us coming together to
support each other really makes
the -- makes the indus- makes
our lives better, but it makes
the industry better, I think.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I- I
think that any opportunity that
you have for that close
collaboration with people,
openness with other people can
be ... just a -- I don't know.
I mean,
yeah, you can be more productive
that way, but that's just a
really beautiful part of the
human experience. And I think
that we often don't think about
that, the -- we -- it's
complicated, right? Because we
want our jobs-
Seth: Mm.
Bekah: -to stop. We don't want
them to go on
all the time and to feel like we
can never leave our computers,
but there's something to be said
for finding time to pause and
make meaningful ...
relationships with the people
who are on your team.
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: That- that helps you to
be better, everybody to be
better at
their jobs. But, you know,
ultimately we are not our jobs.
We are human beings.
Seth: Yep.
Bekah: And so, what helps us to
become better at
that or to grow or to become the
people that we want to be? Our
jobs take up a big portion of
our lives. So finding something
that allows you to continue on
that path of being the person
that you want to be, and to be
able-
Seth: Yes.
Bekah: -to do the things that
you wanna do
outside of work is really
important.
Seth: Yep, 100%. That was --
that's
basically what my 20 year old
self was saying to myself
[chuckles]. He was just like,
"Seth, there's gotta be more."
Like, "I- I- I need something
meaningful. I- I need something
that's just not like ... just a
typical middle of the road," you
know? And ... and I'm-
I'm not saying
this for everybody, but it's
pursuing -- I've always pursued
my dreams, and my heart, and-
and- and for good, you know,
for better or
for worse. And -- but it's
gotten me this far, right? It's
gotten me ...
in a career that I love, being
with my family every day, well
paid, well respected, and
creative. And like you said,
it's not my
life. My life is outside of work
... in many ways. So ...
you know?
Yeah, I feel like I won the
lottery, essentially, in some
ways.
But I got -- but I spent a lot
of money on lottery tickets
[all laugh].
And went through a lot to get
here. But --
Bekah: And it's all part of the
journey, right? I mean, I- I
certainly never -- if five and a
half years ago, if you would've
asked me where I expected to be,
it certainly was not here.
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: There- there was a lot
that went into this journey
and a lot of,
like, really hard things to
navigate. But, you know-
Seth: Yes.
Bekah: -I wouldn't take any of
those hard things back because
it shaped me
into the person I am, and I'm-
I'm happy with who I am right
now, probably more than I ever
have been in my life. And-
Seth: For sure. Yep.
Bekah: -you know, all of those
circumstances and all of the
people that I've met, especially
in the last three years, have
been on that journey with me and
allowed me to, you know, kind of
em- embrace this- this Bekah
that ... I am right now.
Seth: Yeah. Yeah. That's a good
place to be.
Bekah: So, okay. So as you're
going through this, you have
mentioned a couple of times. The
-- you had some experiences
with other
companies that weren't so great,
you went through some difficult
interviewing experiences, and
now you're- you're at this
really
great place. But I wonder if you
could give yourself some advice,
looking back now, so when you
were going through these hard
experiences. What would you tell
yourself to kind of give you
that hope that you needed to
make it to this point?
Seth: Yeah. I would just say, I
mean, off the top of my head
that,
like ... rejection's part of the
process, and perseverance is
key,
and just ... it's really hard to
do this. But most of the
time, things
aren't personal ... right? It's
just ... in terms of
interviewing,
it's just, you wanna good fit or
you bomb the interview or
whatever. But to, like, separate
your identity from that, and
separate your ... how you feel
about yourself and stuff, it's
really hard when you need money,
you need a job, and you have a
family and stuff. You're super
stressed about it, and- and then
you gotta go do more interviews
and stuff. But- but yeah,
like, don't be hard on yourself,
like, don't -- just trust -- I
mean, this is a big part of my
life. This is ... trust the
process, right?
Whether that be any films that I
produce or all the day in and
day out of what I'm doing for my
work, or even my family, it's
just like, just do the work
that's ahead of you for the day,
clock out, enjoy your life, go
back the next day, and do the
work that's ahead of you. And
just trust that that's the
process and
you will eventually get
somewhere. And then I also am
a big adver- I'm a big advocate
in advocating for myself
[chuckles], but [cough]
I'm a big believer in ... like,
standing up for yourself,
believing in yourself, knowing
what you want, like, going to
get it. And that's not in, like
a greed, like, you know, a way
of just like, "I wanna do this.
I'm gonna work really hard
to do this thing, whatever that
is." And so, like, believing
yourself, you know, extending
grace to yourself ... 100%
find people -- find your people
who can help you, AKA
Virtual Coffee [chuckles]. So
yeah, I think- I think is off
the top of my
head, those would be some things
I would say to myself. I
would also be ... when you have
a community, you can talk
a- you can
run red flags by people. You can
say, "Hey, is this a red flag?"
Or, you know, and if- if
someone's mistreating you,
stand up for
yourself. I know that's not -- I
know that's easy for me to say,
for who I am, but not everybody
can do that. But -- and I'm just
happened to be comfortable with
... discomfort, I guess
you could
say. So like, if- if someone's
treating me bad, I'm gonna ...
stand up for myself. And try not
to be a jerk about it.
Try not to be
combative, but ... just believe
in myself and- and know what's
right and what's wrong in a
situation. But, I mean, you
guys know it's so hard to --
when you're navigating
interviews. It-
it's like soul sucking. It's-
it's -- it sucks.
Bekah: Yeah. I remember — I
think it was last summer,
actually, at this time — I was
interviewing with two companies
and I had heard people say that
the interview process was soul
crushing. And I was like, "Eh,
there's no way it's soul
crushing." [Seth laughs] And
then I was invited to apply to
two of these
positions and it was still soul
crushing. I'm like-
Seth: Mm.
Bekah: "This is ... the worst."
Seth: I know.
Bekah: "I never want to do this,
ever again."
Seth: Yeah.
Bekah: And it is. I mean, it
just
requires so much ... out of you
in- in a number of
different ways. And-
Seth: Mm.
Bekah: -just kind of is ... I
don't know, puts you through
this furnace. And
how you come out of that, it can
be, you know, you- you
might be very
burnt or, you know, maybe you
come out a diamond. I fe- I
felt like that was really cheesy
[laughs].
Dan: Yeah. That wouldn't -- that
was a little rough [laughs].
Bekah: I don't know. Sorry.
Sorry for the bad- [chuckles]
the bad metaphor. But
the- but the point is, kind of
like what you were saying, Seth,
this idea of you -- don't take
it personally, and think about
it, too, as part of that
journey, right? I like to think
of the hero's
journey, and we're all the hero
in our own story. And- and what
the hero goes through, right?
And the hero -- in- in the
mythological structure of the
hero, first of all, there are
many, many challenges that the
hero has to navigate. And that
defines the trajectory of the
journey. But also the hero never
does it by themselves. There's
always some type of mentor.
There are allies that they have.
There
are resources or training or
different things that enable
them
to continue to move forward. And
in that way, you know, we can
continue to push forward, but
recognizing that we're not on
this journey alone. There are
other people that are there with
us to support us through those
tough times. And when things do
get tough, then- then rather
than, you- you know, pull away
or try
and do it on your own, leaning
on some of those people or
finding
your allies or mentors or
whatever, can be the difference
between being stuck in your
journey and continuing forward.
Seth: Mm. Yeah. That's a great
point.
Bekah: So ... your job, you are
the technical product owner, and
I'm just kind of circling back a
little bit because I have never
heard of anyone being a
technical product owner before.
So just to
kind of get a better sense of
what you're doing, can you talk
us through, like, maybe one of
the projects that you're working
on or the things that you do
find really interesting about
that work?
Seth: Sure. Yeah, I think it's
-- it could be even considered
a product manager, right? Not a
project manager, but a product
manager. So it's- it's an Agile
term, 'product owner'. And it
is basically ... I mean, again,
it's the creative producer of-
of
software or whatever, cuz it's-
it's communicating with all the
stakeholders, figuring out what
you need, figuring out the
direction of the product, what's
the roadmap, what are
the priorities, you know,
breaking all that s- all that
down into tickets, communicating
all that to tech -- to --
communicating all those
needs to developers, right?
That's a special tran-
transition there.
And also, working with multiple
stakeholders. So- so it's very
-- it's- it's a -- it's an Agile
term. It could also be
pro- product
manager ... I guess, maybe PM or
whatever. But the technical side
of it is because I was a
front-end developer. And I was
originally hired to be a
front-end developer in the
trenches
building out Jamstack sites, and
when this transition came, I was
like, "Okay, I can see that." I
was like, "But I still, like,
have all this
technical knowledge." And my
CTO's, the one that said it, he
was like, "We look at you more
like a technical product owner."
And I was
like, "Great. Let's do it," you
know? And what that means is I
just understand what's happening
on the development side, I
understand what it takes to do a
feature or understand what's
happening. I'm just not the one
doing it. And if -- and I -- but
I'm still, like, spinning up,
you know, I'm still doing
front-end stuff
where I'm like, you know, I'm
doing all the repo stuff and
doing the README, and going
through all the steps of the
README, and installing NPM
packages, and all that kind of
stuff. So I'm still in the
technical area. I'm just not a
front-end developer like I used
to be. And, you know, what I
love about it is the different
communi- the different groups
I work
with. Like, I get to hang out
with de- with designers and
talk about UX
and UI. I get to review designs,
I get to offer tweaks and, you
know, and I get to think of it
as a developer. Cuz I know,
"Oh, this
image is huge. We, you know, how
-- let's figure out what
image size
we need," or whatever that comes
up from the developer mindset
when talking to designers. And
then I get to talk to, like,
marketers and that -- that's a
little bit out- outside of my
comfort zone, but I'm a people
person. So I can talk to them
and ask what they need, and
what, you know, like, "What-
what do you-
what do you need to demo?" Like,
"What are you trying to
... what," -- like,
the first thing I did when I got
to this job was I talked to --
like, I had like 20 meetings or
something and, like, in no
time at all.
And I was talking to everybody
about what are the pain points
of- of the current demo -- the
current demo ecosystem. Like,
"You're taking this product
Uniform's platform and you're
demoing it to people. Wh-what-
what are you missing? Like,
what are
they asking for? What do you
wanna see?" And- and what it
ended up being was, like, "Well,
we got like three or four
different
demos that are all doing random
things, and we need all those
features and functionalities in-
into consolidated
redesigned ... redeveloped
demos," you know? So- so I get
to -- and-
and I- I really do look at it
as, like, basically making
client Jamstack
sites. My- my client just
happens to be my- my coworkers-
Bekah: Yeah.
Seth: -right? So they're asking
me for stuff, and I'm saying,
"Well, I- I
can or can't do that this
sprint," or, "Okay, cool. I'll
work that in." And then I'm
going over to tech lead and
saying,
"Hey, we need to do this." And
he goes, "Okay, cool. We'll
-- I'll-
I'll work up the techs of -- the
tech side of that." And we'll-
we'll pass the issues down to
the developers, and then
developers
deliver it to me. And I do user
assurance testing where I'm
like,
"Okay, that's what I wanted.
That's what we- what we need,"
and -- or
I'll say, "Hey, this responsive,
you know, layout is wrong," or,
"Hey, you know, we need to do
this different." And so, I like
the idea -- or I like the -- my-
my job in the sense that I
get to talk
to all these different people,
right? When I was a front-end
developer, it was me, by myself,
banging my head against the
wall,
reading tutorials [chuckles].
And, you know, then I would-
then I would p-ping
Virtual Coffee people and have,
you know, different co-working
sessions and stuff. But most of
the time it was me, by myself.
And so I love that part of it. I
love that I get to ...
understand
these big features, and
understand how to make them
happen, but I
don't have to be the one coding
it. I really like that. And
that's just because it was, like
I said before, it was -- it
could
be super difficult to solve
these technical problems. And I
like
being the one who's guiding it,
encouraging, getting people
stoked, updating our progress,
you know? Knowing what they
accomplished, like, "Man, you
guys did a- a really hard
feature. Good
job," you know? And- and- and
the way I communicate my tickets
to
them, my get up issues to them,
they know that I know that
stuff.
You know what I mean? Cuz I'm
able to be like, "Hey, can you-
can you change this Tailwind
class to so and so, instead of
so and so, because the
whatever," you know? So it's
like I'm getting this --
to be developer adjacent. And
so- so a product owner really
just sees the product from ...
it- it- it takes everything in,
it plans the
whole thing out, and then it,
like, releases stuff out to the
client. And then it takes
feedback, puts that into the
roadmap, and keeps the cycle
going.
Bekah: Yeah. I really love that.
Because, well, for a number of
reasons. But there are so many
people that are coming into tech
right now that it's
oversaturated with people
looking for junior
positions. But what you've done
is you've leveraged all of your
non-technical skills or
non-coding skills, and
transferred
them over into a job that makes
you really good at that job.
And so I think that, you know,
sometimes people are developers,
and- and they move over into
different positions that are
management and-
Seth: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -maybe they're not well
suited for those. They're
really good-
Seth: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -at being a developer.
But also, it's -- that's not the
only job that you can have. If
you've gone to a bootcamp or if
you've taught yourself how to
code or if you have a CS degree,
whatever, you know, there are
these tech adjacent jobs that
require you to have this
knowledge and understanding, but
also, give you space to bring
all of the past history that you
have doing-
Seth: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -production -- producing
stuff, and make you really --
give you the
ability to really excel at what
you're doing. And I think that
-- I'm glad that you're here
talking about that. Because I
think that --
it would be great to have more
people talking about that. And-
Seth: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -getting more people in
positions like you are in
enabling those
intimate collaborations to
happen. So more people feel
supported in tech because we
also hear so many stories at
Virtual
Coffee of people who are in
terrible jobs [chuckles].
Seth: Yes.
Bekah: And this- this -- having
more people doing what you're
doing, I think, helps to create
tech -- create a much more
welcoming tech community.
Seth: Yeah. I-I-I appreciate you
saying that. I mean, like-
li-like I
said, it's -- I mean, really, by
the- by the grace of God,
honestly,
that it even happened. Cuz I
wasn't -- while I was interested
in it and
I was- I was ... I- I could say
that would be cool to do.
I didn't
really plan it. It just kinda
happened. And at first I was
like, "What do you mean I'm not
gonna be coding out this stuff?
I thought you hired me as an
engineer." And it just -- it was
just a classic start-up, "Well,
now we now -- we need this.
And we have
a marketing engineering team,
which handles the website, our
integrations handles demos, so
we want you to just -- we,"
like, what
they said -- this one thing they
said to me, they said, you know,
"The
technical skills you have, a lot
of people have. But not many
people have the other skills you
have." And I was like,
"Awesome."
Like, that's- that's why I
believe in developing those kind
of skills. I call 'em relational
skills. But in- in this -- I
find it a
little bit easier to develop
relational skills than tech
skills sometimes. And I also
find it more natural to have-
have -- to be
organizational. Seeing the big
picture planning. But I happen
to have a tech background. So it
helps me understand how to talk
to designers, and developers,
and stuff. So, yeah. I just feel
like -- I -- like, after all
these years of like wandering
around,
and trying to figure it out, and
like, sacrificing, and not
giving
up, and like, just pushing,
pushing, pushing, I'm- I'm in
the
most comfortable place I've been
in the -- and I'm -- I feel the
happiest I've been in my career.
Maybe ever. And so that's
just such a blessing. I'm very
thankful for that. And I really
don't know how much control I
had over it. I think it just
... I- I
don't know. You could say, you
know, that -- well, if you put
yourself out there, things will
happen or whatever. There's a
lot of philosophies you could --
and beliefs you could say. But
really, to me, it's just- it's
just a natural progression that-
that happened. And I was able to
see what it was, and go,
"Ah, yes. This is it. This is-
this is it. This is it for me."
And I feel
like I'm thriving. And I- and
like I said before, I feel
valued. I feel empowered because
of my company. Because I'm
in- I'm in a more comfort zone.
Where before, in
front-end development,
there were often times I was out
of my comfort zone.
Bekah: Yeah, I love that.
Dan: Yeah. So that -- I mean, I
pretty much just wanna wrap
up here, I
think. I think this seemed like
a good place to stop in general.
I- I mean, I personally really
appreciated hearing your
story. I -- and I- I liked about
hearing about product owners
and,
you know, I- I love this idea of
the producer, like, the creative
producer and-
Seth: Mm.
Dan: -applying it to- to tech. I
think it's- I think it's
a fantastic approach. And-
Seth: Yeah.
Dan: -probably plenty- plenty
of people are doing it and not
using that name, you
know, or not using --
Seth: Exactly. Yeah.
Dan: You know, I- I think that-
that your instincts behind
doing all that is -- are really
spot on. And I think you're
gonna be really valuable.
Seth: Yeah. I appreciate that,
man.
Dan: I- I think it's really
cool. And I think it's a- I
think
it's a very cool skill set and
... I don't know if you wanna
call it
talent or whatever, but like
[chuckles], just a valuable
thing for- for
any company, you know what I
mean? Anybody that's producing
software to have somebody like
that, you know?
Seth: Yeah. Well, I mean, it's
-- it takes so much to do
anything,
right? E-even a basic websites.
It's- it's a lot to wrangle
together and it's a lot to think
about. And it -- so it helps to
have a team of people who have
different ... I guess you could
say skill sets or leanings or
whatever, but -- cuz not
everybody is gonna be, you know,
a great backend developer, but
you're gonna need backend
development. So it's just-
it's just a
part of the team. I- I look it
-- as a team, as a whole. Just-
just like
when I was doing film, like, it
takes a village to make
something.
In- in software, in, you know,
web development is the exact
same
in- in most cases. But there are
some people out there who
can just do
it by themselves and I've always
looked at them in- in amazement.
But I'm a big believer in just
the team, the collaboration,
someone to bounce ideas off of,
you don't feel alone, the burden
is shared, you know? All those
things.
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. Well,
before we wrap up, is
there any last
words of wisdom or any projects
that you wanna talk about?
Seth: Not really on any
projects. I mean, I just -- I
did have a- a little win, this
week. I had my first release
ever in- in- in this role-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Seth: -this kind of role. Like,
I was responsible for the --
everything that comes with the
release. Now, granted it's an
internal, right? I'm- I'm not
running a product, you know,
or you --
we have users. But -- so, it's a
little bit- a little bit less
pressure, maybe, cuz it's
internal, and you got people who
are
forgiving, and you're working to
get it out, and you don't have
users yelling at you on Twitter
or whatever. But ... but no.
It's no- no particular projects.
Just, you know, I- I just --
we've
talked about this a lot in- in
Virtual Coffee, like,
transferable
skills I think are really
important. So anybody can --
I think
there's a lot of things that
people might know or might be
good at they don't realize they
could apply, and- and it-
Bekah: Yes.
Seth: -could be technical, but
it's m- might be mostly
relational, you know?
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Seth: Like -- cuz you gotta
remember that we're -- what
we're doing --
like, people will hire you based
on your -- how you are as a
person ...
more so than your technical
skills. Cuz you can teach techno
--
technical skills, but you can't
teach someone- teach someone to
be nice or have integrity or
have good character, you know?
It's
a thing you -- people setting.
So I don't know where I'm going
with this, but --
Bekah: No, I think that's ...
great advice.
Seth: Just ... keep going
[chuckles]. As an easy- as an
easy,
you know, outro, just keep- keep
going and believe in
yourself. And hopefully, you'll
-- and something will --
something
should pop up.
Bekah: It's so great. Thanks so
much for being here and
sharing your story with us,
Seth.
Dan: Thanks, Seth.
Seth: Thank you so much. It's
been a pleasure. I always love
talking to y'all. So, looking
forward to another time, and
catch y'all online.
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Sounds good. Bye.
Seth: All right. See ya.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for the newsletter, check out
any of our other resources on
our website, virtualcoffee.io.
If you're interested in
sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening,
and we'll
see you next week!