Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
season six, episode four of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And we're here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost. Dan
Dan: Wuddup, Bek? How's it going?
Bekah: It it's going wonderfully.
Dan: Excellent. Um, today we are
talking with Sadie J who is a,
uh, frontend developer with a
federal agency. We talked about
her long experience doing the
interview process and yeah, and
her experience working at a
government agency as well.
Bekah: Yeah, it was really
interesting to hear how she kind
of started in tech. She burnt out
and left tech for a while and
then decided to give it a second
shot and she's back doing it
again. And it sounds like she's
really excited, but also like.
Took those lessons that she
learned from that burnout
experience and brought them with
her. So she doesn't get burnout
again. And I think that's really,
really useful because I see that
happen to a lot of people.
Dan: Yeah, totally. I, it was, it
was interesting hearing her talk
about, um, Her thought process,
you know, when she was
experiencing the burnout stuff
and, um, and just taking a break
like that, uh, you know, and
dealing with it head on, uh, I
think was, was really cool. And I
think there's a lot of valuable
stuff in there.
Bekah: Yep. And we start every
episode of the podcast. Like we
start every Virtual Coffee. We
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do and a random check-in
question. And we hope you enjoy
this episode. Hi, I'm Bekah. I am
a technical community builder
from a small town in Ohio and an
imaginary class that I wish was
offered. I feel like this is hard
because I'm not sure what would
be practical for an imaginary
class and maybe imaginary
classes. Aren't practical. um,
Dan: class teach imaginary things
or is this like a chance to
learn, you know,
Bekah: oh, for sure it can teach
imaginary things. Yeah, I think I
would like to, um, definitely
take a class that watches people
have brain scans. And that's not
an imaginary class. I'm kind of
like neurobiology class. Um, but
there's gotta be some kind of
imaginary aspect to brain scans
and people. really bad at this
question. I was the one that
chose it too. So it just like
makes it worse. Um, I'm just
gonna like look at people's
brains and see what they do.
That's it. It's not imaginary.
It's wishful. That's what I wish
I wish to watch people's brains.
Dan: Less of a class and more of
a profession you wish you had
Bekah: Um, yes, I would love to
be a neurobiologist that would.
Fantastic. What? Okay. Maybe an
imaginary class on like studying
black holes by like actually
physically exploring them cuz
that's not possible. So is that
better?
Dan: I don't know. I don't know
what to do with this question.
Um, hi, I'm Dan. I do computer
development things, uh, in
Cleveland and, um, yeah,
imaginary class. I have no, I
mean, I don't really understand
this question to tell truth I,
uh, I don't know. Um, I guess I'm
gonna go with, uh, um, like
spaceship, flying yeah. but like
not the boring ones that we have
that are reality though, you
know? Or like star
Bekah: Star wars,
Dan: like yeah. Yeah. Like teach
me
Bekah: good imaginary class.
Dan: the Millennium Falcon or
something, you know, that'd be
cool.
Bekah: Yeah,
Dan: long as I actually got to
fly it. All right. That's gonna
be my answer.
Sadie: Okay. Um, hi, I'm Sadie.
Um, I'm from a small town in the
panhandle of Florida. I am a
front end developer for a federal
agency and, uh, an imaginary
class. I think I would take, I
don't know. I, this makes me
think of like when I was in
elementary school and like super
obsessed with like ESP and like
being psychic and things like
that. So I would probably. Some
class that develops like your
psychic abilities.
Bekah: I
Dan: I like
Bekah: that is a good, an, an
excellent answer. You have
definitely won this round of
intro questions.
Dan: Yeah. My first answer was
gonna be like, learn, you know,
learn the Force, you know?
Bekah: Mm,
Dan: then I was thinking about
spaceships would be fun too, so,
and a little more practical. I
was worried that I think that,
uh, canonically. You have to
like, have the, be able to use
the force to learn. Like, it's
not like everybody can learn it,
you know, a bummer to sign up for
that class and they get there and
then find out you can't, can't.
Right,
Bekah: you can watch everybody
else use the force, but you're
stuck.
Dan: right, right. I don't feel
like everybody can use, uh,
everybody could use, uh, or learn
how to fly spaceships.
Bekah: I feel like I want a class
on communicating with aliens, but
I feel like DARPA already has
that or something like it's out
there. We just don't know about
it yet. um, well welcome Sadie.
Thanks for being here with us
today. We're very, very excited
to have you, and we always like
to start off with your tech
origin story. So how did you get
to this point in your tech?
Sadie: Oh, wow. Yeah. That's um,
a good question. I feel like it
was a winding journey for sure.
Um, Like, I, I didn't really grow
up with a desire to be in tech.
Uh, like my household computer
was just the computer that let me
get on cartoon network.com and
play games. like, it wasn't much
past that, but, um, I would say
right after I graduated, um, with
my bachelor's degree in
psychology, I got into drawing
and painting. Like, and this was
just like a random desire that I
had. I was like, ah, I just wanna
learn painting. I'm just gonna
take a class. So I did and like
fell in love. And from that I
wanted to like find a career that
let me combine psychology and
like drawing or visual arts. So I
was like, okay, maybe web design
somehow. Cuz that would also let
me work remotely and give me some
flexibility. So I went to a boot.
Um, I went to skill crush and
signed up for one of their
courses. It was like a web design
course or visual design course.
This was back in like 2017, like
several years ago, but I wanted
to like test out the waters to
see if that was something I would
be interested and like, it, it
seemed good enough. Like, I, I
felt like I could do it. So then
I signed up for my master, my
master's, um, Specializing in web
design and online communication.
And in that program, like we did
both web design and also web
development. And I realized that
like, actually web development
was more my thing and not so much
the web design. Um, so yeah, so
that was like the, really the
kickoff to my tech journey, for
sure. But after I graduated, I,
there was another pivot, like.
Was completely burnt out on tech
and anything tech related. Like I
couldn't bear to think about like
coding. And I remember like I
applied to some internship and
got elite code challenge, but at
the time I didn't know what that
was. So I was like, oh wow. I
just graduated with this degree.
And like, I can't even use it.
Like, I don't know what, like how
to do this thing with JavaScript
that they want me to do. So it
just completely like demoralize
me and. Like crushed my
confidence. So I became a yoga
teacher. I was out in Brooklyn
and doing that like yoga life and
like meeting with cool people.
And then I got into the travel
industry and did that for a year,
but all of that ended around 2020
when I left the job and then the
pandemic started and all that. So
it gave me time to reflect and. I
had to move back home after being
in Brooklyn for a few years. And
I really thought, I was like,
okay, what am I gonna do next?
Cuz like, I don't want to be here
like Florida, which is home for
me. Like I don't wanna be here
forever, but I do wanna take the
time to like make sure that like
I'm going in a direction that I
feel good about and kind of came
to the conclusion that like, I
didn't really give tech a try. I,
I let the burnout like kind of
like take over. I don't know, I
guess like my direction or just
like, I dunno, just had me stop
in my tracks. So I was like, you
know what, I'm gonna give this a
college try, like, I'm a, I'm
gonna do this again. And this
time I'm going to make sure I
have community around me. And
that's how I found. Y'all how I
found virtual. So I restarted my
boot camp, restarted school crush
and did the front end developer
intensive. But this time was very
intentional about joining
community, like being very active
in Virtual Coffee, and I wanted
to do the open source thing. So
it would just so happen that, um,
the kickoff for the October Fest,
um, month was like a week or two
away. So that's when I joined
butcher coffee. I got to sit in
and watch Dan do the, um, like
how to contribute to open source
and yeah. So it, it all just went
from there. Uh, yeah, so I ended
up like contributing to like five
projects and like, I contributed
to a couple of IBM projects. I
got to do a demo day with them
and then, um, side of the job
search or in like February. And
that was another beast of its own
where it took like nine weeks.
and just hundreds of applications
to get this job that I have now.
And yeah. That's how I got here.
Yeah,
Bekah: That's awesome. I love
that story. I. There's just, um,
I like that you have gone through
a lot of different, like
different journeys on this
journey here. Right? Um, you've
done a lot of different things,
but also like coming back from
burnout, I imagine that's gotta
be kind of a hard decision to
make what really kind of pushed
you in that direction. Like,
okay, fine. I'm gonna do this one
more.
Sadie: Right. That's that's a
good question. I think one time
time helped cuz I had graduated
2018 and then I felt like I could
entertain the thought of tech
again, like. Few years later. So
2021. So really it was just time
and space that helped, I would
say for the most part, but also,
I don't know. I know, like I
wanted flexibility in my job and
like where I worked, like that
was also the catalyst of going
into the master's degree program.
So like, I think that thread just
continued and I was like, okay, I
think I could do tech again.
Because I've tried, like also
tried writing on the side a
little bit, but that didn't feel
quite as a fit. So I think just,
I dunno, the reflection and
wanting to like challenge myself
and see something to completion
also helped.
Dan: Can you talk a little bit
about, um, your experience? Uh,
so if I have this right, you did
the bootcamp and then you went to
a master's program after that. So
that's like a lot of school, like
in all together. Can you talk, I
don't think I've actually, we've
talked to anybody who is. Learn
web design stuff or web
development stuff in a master's
program. Um, could you, would you
mind sharing a little bit about
what that was like? Um, and, and
especially like, compared to,
since you did it right after the
bootcamp, maybe, maybe compared
to what, what it was like, um,
you know, the different
approaches and everything.
Sadie: Yeah. So, okay. So I did
the boot. And I, I don't even
know if I completed the course.
Um, like before I did the
master's, like, it was just
enough to be like, okay, this
seems like something I could do.
So I went into my master's
program without any knowledge of
code or anything, but that was
the, um, like the setup for the
degree. Like, you didn't have to
have any prior knowledge. Um, but
I don't know. I don't, I kind of
don't know how. like give more
details, cuz it was it like
college, like you, um, like we
had four classes a semester.
That's what I signed up for. And
like the very first class was
like a web design principles and
like it went into HTML and maybe
a little bit of CSS and I don't
even think we touched JavaScript
that much in that first class.
And then it built up from. Um, we
learned like it was mostly do in
manipulation, cuz it, it wasn't
like a computer science class, so
we didn't learn like algorithms
or data structures or anything
like that. But basically like how
to create websites and like
webpages with an I for design.
Um, we also learn like Adobe
suite and um, social media and
like analytics for websites and
things like. like the capstone
project was to create a WordPress
site for a local company. And our
cohort was divided up into teams.
And that was like, that was the,
the peak, like the end of the
program. But I say all that to
say like, so I did that finished
in 2018 and then went back into
the boot camp 2021. And. I, I
feel like I retained enough
information, but it was enough to
know that like, oh yeah, I
remember learning that in school.
So I felt like what I learned in
the bootcamp and what I learned
in school were comparable, but it
was just that I had more time in
school to learn the things and to
like, kind of like dive into each
thing that was taught, like each
aspect of HTML or CSS or Javas.
whereas the bootcamp was like
basically the same topics, but
just in a more condensed, um,
time space, even though it was
self-paced. So, yeah, it was
really interesting.
Dan: Yeah, I guess it makes
sense.
Bekah: The, so after you did the
master's program, then you went
into the bootcamp. Um, was there
any interview prep that you did
as part of the master's program
or was that, did you do that in
the.
Sadie: No. Yeah, no for the
master's program. Absolutely not.
Um, and I feel like that's why,
like, I was so blindsided by the
lead code challenge, but yeah.
What, um, the, the like real
world, um, aspect of the bootcamp
or not. The bootcamp of the
master's degree was like a
internship. So I did an
internship at, um, American
documentary POV, a media company.
And I'm, I'm smiling because
like, I don't y'all can't see me,
but I'm smiling and I'm laughing
because like, it was an
internship. In the digital team,
but it didn't have anything to do
with like the website or
anything. So I had to like
shoehorn, like, Hey, I need to do
something with WordPress. I need
to do something. But what it
ended up being was more like me
working with the producers and
doing like other cool stuff. But
yeah, no, that was the extent of
like the real world application
for the, um, master's program. So
I was like completely lost when I
was job hunting and. Yeah,
Bekah: I think most people are
completely lost when they're job
hunting. You know, it's just
like, there's not a lot of
preparation and job interviews
are all over the place. So you
just never know what to expect.
And like having to prepare so
much for each one of them makes
it really, really hard. Did you
do interview prep with skill
crush?
Sadie: I did. Yeah. So the front
end developer intensive includes,
um, a job hunting. Coach like a
career coach that helps you, like
prepare your resume and like
prepare your cover letter and get
your like one minute, like, uh,
what's it called? Like a one
minute, like spiel about yourself
and I don't know, just interview,
practice and how to answer
questions. Exactly. Elevator
pitch. Um, yeah, so crush had
that and that really opened my
eyes to like how to be strategic
when job hunting. like, kind of
like understand what to expect
when interviewing in the tech
field and yeah, without that, I,
I really don't think I would've,
uh, or it, it either would've
taken me a lot longer to find my
job or I would've stopped again.
And probably would've said maybe
text, just not for.
Bekah: Yeah. And that's so
unfortunate that there are so
many people trying to break into
tech and are just quitting before
they get there, because the inter
and the interview process is not
reflective of most of the stuff
that you're. To be doing.
Sadie: And like, without that
knowledge of like, oh, like I
actually don't maybe need to know
how to like, do this leak Cody
thing. Like if you don't have
that understanding, then. I feel
like that's what feels like the,
the tutorial loop where like, oh,
I need to know how to do this
weird niche thing. Or like, maybe
I actually don't know enough, so
I need to keep going. Like, I
don't know. It, the interview
process is so like demoralizing
or it can be.
Bekah: That's a really good word
for, I even think like some of
the best interview processes are
still very exhausting and tough
to get through. So why don't you,
can you walk us through what it
was like to prepare for an
interview?
Sadie: Oh, that's a good
question. um, Hmm. That's a good
question. I feel like. What I did
would be to like, look at the job
website and like, look at the
people that I'm interviewing with
and like kind of stock their
Instagram or not Instagram
they're LinkedIn. I dunno why I
said Instagram, but, um, yeah,
stock their LinkedIn a little bit
and try to find like some sort of
commonality that I may have with
them and have the idea to bring
it up, even though like I'm, uh,
really shy and I probably won't
ever bring up like, Hey, Looked
at your LinkedIn. And I noticed
like, I'm not that kind of
person, but just having that like
background behind that person
that I'm gonna be interviewing,
um, helped me feel a little more
confident. Um, I would also try
to gather a few questions. Um,
uh, VC or Jennifer. I don't
remember how to say her last
name, but she has a list of
questions to ask during an
interview. Like to the
interviewer to try and engage
like your fit with the role in
the company. And I would like,
look, go back to that, um, to
that page and like pick out
questions for every single
interview that I had to make sure
that like, okay, this is what I
need to know about this role and
about the company to make sure
that I'm going to fit with them.
So in order to make it a process
of like, I'm also interviewing
the interview, Like, it's not
just me. It's, it's a two way
thing that I need to also be fit
a fit and they need to be a fit
with me.
Dan: Yeah, I think that's, I
think that's really important and
it can get lost sometimes,
especially.
Sadie: Mm-hmm
Dan: I don't know on long
journeys on long, uh, you know,
struggles. Uh, but I, so I was
gonna ask them maybe think, um,
did you run into any, you know,
you said you were doing this for
so long and how many did you say
you did? How many interviews did
you say? I can't remember how
Sadie: at least
Dan: right?
Sadie: it was a lot of interviews
for sure. It was like 250
applications and,
Dan: Wow. And so like, where
were. You don't have to like call
them out or anything, but were
there any times where you were,
you got down the road a little
bit and were like, oh, I don't
know if this is actually a good
fit for me, you know, on your
side
Sadie: Right. That's a good
question. there's been a few
times, I would say. But even when
that happened, I would try to go
into it thinking like, okay, this
is interview practice. Or like,
say I gotta take home or some
like technical test, I would say,
okay, this may be outta my
wheelhouse, but I may, I'm still
going to give X amount of time to
it, just to see what I can learn
from this, like take home or from
this interview. From this
interaction that I can then
hopefully improve the next time I
have an interview.
Dan: I think that's an awesome
attitude. I, you know, I've,
I've, we've had several people
suggest like taking interviews
even when you're not actively
looking, uh, for jobs, uh,
sometimes to do that practice
cuz, and it's just like, you both
were saying it's, it's so hard
and emotionally hard and also
just like intellectually hard.
And um, I feel, I mean,
interviewing is absolutely a
skill that is separate from
everything else. Right. And, uh,
like any skill, I think you can
get better at it with practice.
Um, but I, I love that attitude
that you have. I mean, it's just
like, okay, this might not be
perfect or whatever, but I'm
still gonna go through, and build
up the skills or whatever. Uh,
that's awesome.
Sadie: mm-hmm
Bekah: Yeah, it's really hard.
Even that idea of like practicing
an interview, you know, like
going on practice interviews, I
find to be incredibly.
Overwhelming to. I have to
mentally prepare myself and I'm
trying to like, make that shift
in mindset of, you know, what,
there aren't stakes here. I'm not
being judged. This is practice to
learn something and, and try and
flip it kind of like how you said
where you're interviewing the
company as well. Uh, because
it's, it might not be a good fit.
And I would say like, that's some
of the most advice that I give to
people who are interviewing for
their first job, they're like,
oh, well, what do you think about
this? Like, That's a, that's a
red flag. I wouldn't go through
that. And I think maybe as I
identify what red flags are, I
will say the more I interview,
the more I'm able to identify
what flags are, because I put
myself in situations where I'm
like, this is great. And then I'm
like, this is not great. And I
should have been able to figure
this out before I got into this
position. Um, so at least like
keeping track of that maybe feels
like, all right, this is
progress. I'm learning something.
And. Next time. I'm never, never
gonna interview for anything ever
again. I've just, starting my own
company next because I don't
wanna have to go through that.
But if, if, if in the off chance
I do have to go through it, I, I
really want to approach it with,
uh, I'm interviewing you first.
And, and that kind of like, um,
changes the power dynamic in the
situation. And I think kind of
alleviates some of that stress
that you get going into those
interviews where it's like,
somebody is staring at me right
now. Well, like, Hey, I'm staring
right back at you, buddy. So,
Sadie: Right, right, exactly.
Bekah: so how long did you prep
for your, interviews?
Sadie: Um, that's a good
question. Uh, it would depend.
Like I know when I was first
starting out my job, my job
hunting process, I would be
really diligent about. Okay. I'm
gonna like, make sure I have my
list of questions. Ready. Make
sure I like review the website,
make sure I look at everybody and
all this stuff, but the more I
got like used to interviewing, I
would say the less, I actually
like sat down and prepped for the
interviews. I don't know if I
would recommend or not, but I
don't know. I just, I guess I got
just more comfortable, like being
in that space of, okay, this is
the thing that we're doing. Like
we're both trying to gauge
whether or not we're a fit and
we'll see what happens from
there. So if that makes sense.
Bekah: Yeah, no, I love that. It
shows that you're gaining
confidence as you go forward and
you've done these. So, um, you
know, that, that's more, I think
that, you know, that's also one
of those issues where people who
are continually interviewing are
just pushing themselves so hard
to do this prep over and over and
over. And that also kind of leads
to that situation of like you
talked about like, Burning out in
tech, there's definitely that
burnout in the interview process.
And so sometimes you have to take
a break. And the other part of
that is like, when you're
interviewing so much, you don't
have time to be working on
personal projects or other
things. It's like a full time
job.
Sadie: exactly. Exactly. Yeah.
That was one of the tips that I
got, um, while job hunting and
with the career coach was that
like, you can like stop trying to
keep up with personal projects.
Like this is what you need to be
doing. Like once you secure your
job, then you can start your
personal projects back up and be
like getting paid for it. But
yeah, like the idea was that
like, you could do both, but like
you're probably better off, not
so you can completely focus on
like your time and energy on
interviewing. And then when
you're not interviewing, you can
like be off and like live your
life. So, yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. I like the idea too,
of like giving yourself
permission. You can have
permission. It's okay to not be
working on these personal
projects. And I even think that
it's okay to take a break from
interviewing, you know, I know
that people feel like they're
losing momentum or they're not
ever going to be able to find the
next interview if they're not
doing it all the time, but you
know, if you're burning yourself
out before you start, then you're
gonna start burnt out too. And
that's not where you wanna.
Sadie: very true.
Bekah: So as you were looking for
a job, uh, what was your method
of applying? Were you applying?
Were you reaching out to people
personally? What kind of was the
right direction for you?
Sadie: Oh, that's a great
question. Um, first I started off
just applying. So I, I think I
started off using like LinkedIn
and maybe just LinkedIn at first,
but then I started getting more
plugged into like the different
job sites, like remote and like
different. Job boards cuz I knew
I wanted to be remote. Um, then
the further along I got into my
like application groove, I
started reaching out to hiring
managers on LinkedIn and even
like other engineers that were at
companies that I saw were either
hiring or that I thought would be
interesting to work at. And from
there I would try to make a
connection and be like, Like I'm
looking for engineering roles or
I see that you have, um, like a
software engineer role open, um,
who should I talk to basically?
And so sometimes I wouldn't get a
response, which is fine, but when
I did get a response, it would,
um, usually I would get an
interview and like be able to put
a name to a face and like start a
convers. So that, that was also
another thing that I learned that
I feel like I would probably do
more of would be to actually
reach out to people on LinkedIn
and like have a conversation as
opposed to just applying or even
not even apply. Cuz I found that
like sometimes I would play to a
job and like have the
conversation with the hiring
manager and then. They would say,
okay, maybe you're not so much of
a fit for this role per se, but
we have something coming down the
pipeline that you may be a better
fit for. And it just kind of
opened my eyes of like, oh, like,
wait a minute. Like, I just need
to talk to people like this is, I
feel like I unlocked a key, like,
I didn't know this before, but
yeah. Yeah, I would, yeah, that
was very eye opening.
Dan: So the people you were
reaching out to
Sadie: Mm.
Dan: wait, explain to me again,
like how you were choosing who to
reach out to,
Sadie: So I would okay. Say I
would find a role that was
interesting. So I would then go
into LinkedIn and search the
company name and then like quote,
hiring or manager or director or.
Something like some higher up or
someone that's gonna be in the,
um, like hiring panel or
something. And then I'd pick
someone whose title matched and
then reach out to them. Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So you'd
find a, you'd find a job opening
on a, on a board or something
like that, and then update, you'd
do some homework yeah, that's
really cool. I love that. Uh,
that's a great, um, that's a
great tip. I mean, and I think
that's like a, I mean, Aside from
the sneakiness of it seems like a
really good, you know, like
connecting with people is, uh,
almost always a good thing, you
know what I mean? And, and like,
as long as I assume, you're, I'm
sure you are doing it sort of
respectfully and with some
knowledge, you know, uh, and not
just blasting out the same thing
to everybody's, you know,
whatever, uh, a million different
people. Um, yeah, that's great. I
love, I love that.
Sadie: Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: It, it personalizes it,
right? Because before you're a
name on a sheet of a paper or an
internet form or whatever, but
now there's more, there's a face
to it. There's a voice to who
they're looking at and then
hiring managers or whoever can
make that connection, like, oh,
okay. I know this person, you
know, even if you haven't had an
in depth conversation, there's
something about like, oh, I do,
there is already a connection
there. Makes it you're, you're
already a half, a step above in
front of everybody else in that
pile and that, you know, that can
make the difference, you know? So
is that the job that you're
currently at, did that start with
you reaching out to somebody.
Sadie: no, it's funny. I, I saw
that job in like a. Like an email
list. It's called words of mouth,
I believe. And they post like all
these cool jobs, but, so I saw
that one and then I was about to
reach out to someone when someone
in my bootcamp at school crush
was like, Hey, you should apply
to this job. Like we've been
talking and they think that you
might be a great fit. So I was
like, okay, like, sweet. Like I
just saw this job. So yeah, like
it was again like that community
connection of. Hey, like yeah.
The community connection. Mm-hmm
Dan: That's cool. they had
already heard of you before you
even had nice. Isn't funny, that
the way that works out, lots of
times where you've done so many
applications and stuff, and then
this, this one that actually it's
like came about in some, some
strange connection in some other
way.
Sadie: exactly. Exactly.
Bekah: One of my favorite things
is when people reach out to me
and they're like, Hey, do you
know anybody that would be good
for this job? And then like, can
like, yes, I do. You know, I
think like I'm about to maybe
submit my fifth referral to
somebody somebody at DRA. I just
like. Eventually somebody's gonna
be a good fit and I'm gonna help
them find it, you know?
Sadie: yes. Yeah. You never know,
like, yeah. I, I can only
imagine, or like, even in being
in that position of like someone
having referred. Like the
gratitude, like is immeasurable.
So yeah, you're doing amazing
work. Bekah.
Bekah: Oh, thank you. I, I also
like, well, I just wanna say too,
when people reach out to me from
the community and they're like,
Hey, I wanna apply to this job.
Would you mind like sending a DM
on my behalf? Cuz I know you're
connected with this person. And
most times I do, sometimes there
are people that I'm like, I've
never. Been in a room with you or
had a conversation with you prior
to this point. So I don't feel
comfortable with that. But, um,
if I know somebody, if I've even,
I would say there have been
people that I probably haven't
been in the same breakout room
with, but would still recommend
because I see how they interact
with other people in slack, or
I've heard them talk to other
people on a luncheon during a
luncheon learner, something like
that. And I'm like, yeah, that
person. Is awesome. Like they're
really patient or they're really
knowledgeable or they're really
great at teaching. And so I feel
comfortable being able to pass
that along. And so if somebody is
looking and you do have a
connection to a community member
that has a connection, then, then
it's okay to reach out to them
and ask them for a
recommendation. And I've even had
people in the past. When I was a
teacher say, I need a
recommendation. Do you, I wrote
it already. Would you send this?
So like, alright, I'm gonna
change it up a little bit to put
it in my voice, but I agree with
everything you've said and it
makes it easier on me, so sure.
You know,
Sadie: Yes,
Bekah: I don't think that's
cheating. I think it's just
making it a little bit easier.
And if the person feels
comfortable sending it than they,
Sadie: exactly. And like, you can
say what you wanna hype up about
yourself and then have someone
co-sign that. So yeah,
absolutely.
Bekah: Mm-hmm. Dan, you were
gonna say something and I
interrupted you.
Dan: Yeah. What do you think it
was? Um, it was, oh, no, I was
just gonna talk like harp about
how networking, you know, like
having a network of people that,
you know, and could trust is, is
so important with all this stuff,
you know, cuz it's like that you
found that reference and I've had
people both. Knew they were
hiring and, and asked me, you
know, Hey, are you looking for
like, whatever you look for a job
or the same way as Bekah like, do
you know anybody that would fit
this role? Like we're, we're,
we're looking to hire somebody.
Um, it's the same kind of thing,
you know, and if I, um, I love
being able to help people, but
also, like, I know, like I have
just having a network, you know,
I have this like large safety net
almost, you know, of, if
something fell, fell apart or
whatever, you know, I, I know I
have a bunch of people that I
can. Lean on for helping support
and stuff, uh, in the future. So
I dunno. It's, it's cool. It's
good stuff.
Sadie: Mm-hmm
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I, all of my job all sorry.
So I'm, uh, independent, but all
of my, like clients I've ever
worked for are all word of mouth,
you know, um, like connections of
connections, stuff like that. And
it's always the, you know, and I,
I work, I have, I have a network
of people that do my kind of work
and, um, It's always, this it's
always the, those clients and are
always the ones that are like the
best clients. You know what I
mean? As opposed to like the cold
call ones or like where there's
no connection at all before, and
that's not to say it can never
work obviously, but, um, and
those, those like word of mouth
connections are only come from,
you know, building a, like I hate
using, I don't know the word
network is like, it's got like a
bunch of weird connotations, you
know? Um, cuz there's like a lot
of bad ways to. Do networking,
you know, like I've never like
actively been like, I'm gonna go
network now, you know? Uh, but
that's what you end up with, you
know, at different communities
and, and things that they really
are in network. It's, it's a good
word that has been poisoned by,
uh, I don't know, connotations
other things. Yeah. I don't know.
But, uh, anyway, that's all just
to say, um, I don't know what
it's just to say, other than the
community is important. to the
Virtual Coffee podcast.
Bekah: Well, and community is a
great way to gain experience too,
along with connections, you know,
I know there's a bunch of people
that put Virtual Coffee
experience on their resume. I,
um, actually interviewed for a
job a couple of years ago. And
while I was interviewing, they
were like, oh yeah, somebody else
from Virtual Coffee is
interviewing too. We talked about
in the interview, I still don't
know who that person is. Um, but
I was like, huh, that's really
interesting. I love it though.
You know, it's great. Like
everybody is giving back to the
community in some way. And like,
if, if the, their experience
doing the support that they do at
Virtual Coffee leads to a job, I
love it. I am 100% here for that.
Sadie: Mm.
Bekah: No. Okay. So you've gone
on all these interviews, you've
done all these things. And I, we,
we talked about how tough the
interview scene is in tech, but
are there any like good interview
stories that you have or
experiences that you're like?
Well, I wouldn't mind having that
one again.
Sadie: Right. Yeah. Ooh. I think
one that stood out to me was, I
think it was a two part. Like the
first interview was like me
gathering a whole bunch
questions. The space was set up
that like, this is your time to
ask us any questions that you
have And so I was super excited
about the role on the team. So I
had like a whole list of like 40
questions and put it it's really
embarrassing now, but I really,
I, I put it up on GitHub and
like, Created a repo of questions
and shared it with them. And
they're like, oh, this is so
cool. And like little intimidated
now. Cause you have all these
questions prepared but it worked
out cuz I, I passed to the next
round and that next round was to
present a project that I had been
working on in kinda like talk to
them about like the features or
like why I built it and have a
discussion on like maybe how it
could be improved and things like
that. So I thought, like it was
super, um, collaborative and
like, I don't wanna say low
stakes, but it changed the ni
dynamic, cuz it wasn't like me
getting a take home. And then I
had to get familiar with one of
the directions that they want me
to follow. And then also think of
like, okay, how would I do this?
And like, it's not that, but it
was a project that I had made and
like was excited about and wanted
to talk to other people about. I
had an opportunity to see how
they would collaborate with me on
projects and like how they would
give feedback. And I don't know,
it just felt like a, a more like
big picture view of the
interviewer or of me. And so,
yeah, I would totally do that
again. Like if all interviews
could be like that,
Dan: That's really cool. So they
were, so it was to present some,
just any random project that you
had been working on personally.
Yeah. That's love that idea cause
gives you, yeah, it takes all the
pressure off of the, um, like
learning some unfamiliar thing
and, but you can still see having
to present it like that. Lets
you. Sort of show off how, you
know, much, you know, or what,
like the kinds of things you
think about that your thinking
process is, which is the kind of
stuff that you really wanna know
when you're interviewing anyway,
as like an interviewer you don't
wanna know. I mean, I've
personally like, it's like, okay,
there's like different skill
levels. People might, like,
nobody knows everything. People
might have holes in their
knowledge. But the thing that
you're always looking for is, uh,
is like, uh, the ability to like
think through problems and, you
know, um, sort of. Be able to
constructively like talk about
things, right. And if you're
talking about your own work, then
you don't have to, you know, then
you don't have to have the whole
step of like, learning what it
was and trying to guess what they
were thinking or all Right. You
know, you know what you were
thinking right. Or like maybe,
you know, but maybe you remember
what you were thinking, but I
like, that's a great idea. I
like, I like that. I, uh, I don't
think I'm ever gonna hire
anybody, but I, I always like I
love what I hear about things
like that that are like a little
bit different than everybody, you
know, than, than the usual thing.
Um, and try to take notes of 'em,
but, um, yeah, that's nice.
That's a cool one. Okay. So you
said I'm gonna jump all the way
to the now times you said you
work for a federal agency and you
do front end development. That I
think that's really interesting.
So are there, um, I guess my
question is like, can you, are
you able to talk a little bit
about what that's like, like
working in a government agency,
especially doing front end stuff?
I mean, I. That makes me think of
like, uh, rules and, you know,
oh, you have to like a bunch of
regulations you have to follow or
something like that. And maybe
that's not the case, but like I,
or yeah, or Bekah is gonna gonna
call DARPA and, you know, get the
aliens coming. Uh, but I just
like, would like to hear about
it. I'm just curious.
Sadie: Yeah. That's that's yeah.
Yeah. Um, so I just started in
April, so I'm still trying to
wrap up, like, what can I do and
what can I do? But from my
understanding that all federal
websites need to follow a set of
standards called the us web
design standard. And. something
that's created by, I believe by
18F they are like another, like,
um, kind of like agency, not like
agency, like big agency, but like
they create the standards for
websites across federal agencies
if I understand correctly. But
anyways, the us web design. It's
kind of like, um, kind of like
bootstrap where you put your
classes into the HTML to make
sure that the website is
accessible. So like button sizes
and like screen sizes and media
queries and things like that are
all sort of set by these
standards and you just kind of
drop it into the HTML. Um, yeah,
I'm still trying to learn that,
but yeah, outside of that, like,
I, I. played too much outside of
that. And like tried to really
customize the website per se,
because I inherited this, um,
this website and the properties
for the, for the agency. And so I
don't have the really built out
too much, like by hand. which is,
um, good and bad
Dan: Well, I mean like over time
you'll yeah.
Sadie: yeah, yeah, yeah. It'll
take some time, but yeah, that,
that's what I'm finding most
interesting. Um, it seems like,
uh, Jekyll is very favored and
also, uh, all of, not all, but a
lot of the websites are on
GitHub, so you can actually see
like how these sites are built.
And if you want to like poke
around, like it's all. Yeah.
Dan: Nice. That's cool.
Sadie: Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Dan: Um,
Bekah: using a lot of Jekyll. Is
that what you said?
Sadie: yeah. It's Jekyll yeah.
Bekah: That's
Sadie: yeah.
Bekah: Both of my blogs are using
Jekyll because I'm not really
even sure that's the direction I
went when I first started. And so
I just kept going with it I feel
like Jekyll this is Jekyll
tangent. I love using Jekyll, but
I feel like their documentation
is terrible. And I keep hearing
people that love Jekyll they're
like, but their community is
great. So you can ask lots of
questions and they'll get. But I,
I just want to read it in the
documentation, just explain this
to me, but also I've never like
contributed to their
documentation. So that's also
something I should probably do
instead of complaining about
Sadie: I hear that. Yeah. I feel
that.
Dan: complain once in a while.
Bekah: I'm done my rant. Sorry.
Dan: Oh man. I, I just, that's
very interesting. I mean, I've
done, I've concentrated on the
front end for, you know, my whole
career. And so, but I've never
worked with anything, you know,
that have any external standards
that anybody's looking at in any
of the code. You know what I
mean? Yeah. We try to like be as
like accessible as possible and
you know, all that stuff, but
it's always just me. That's doing
those and enforcing it on myself
or whatever, you know, or, or any
teammates that I'm working with,
but it it's never coming down
from above, you know what I mean?
Um, and so that's, that's like
gotta be in a really interesting
experience, uh, to be in that
role. Um, you know, and that's
awesome that they're, uh, that
they are doing to open source
stuff. That's really cool. Um,
Sadie: Yeah. There's a lot of
open source of projects from the
government.
Dan: That's awesome. Yeah, that,
that makes me like wonder. Yeah,
just now you know, I always just
assume that it's all like locked
down and it's all, uh, whatever,
super custom, you know, DARPA,
DARPA static sites. Uh, but no,
they're just open source season
That's
Sadie: exactly.
Dan: So, yeah, that's cool. Thank
you for sharing about that, that
I find that really interest.
Bekah: What do you like best
about your job?
Sadie: Oh, that's a good
question. I don't know. I feel
like I'm gonna get kind of meta,
but that I am at a federal
agency. um, it feels like it
completes like a cycle or
something because my grandmother
and my grandfather were both in
the army and my uncles were. In
like the army and Marines. My mom
retired military, like retired
air force. And so I grew up in
the military family and always
like, had that like, Ooh, am I
gonna join the military or not?
Or am I gonna be like, a
contractor or something? And I
always felt like, nah, that's not
for me. Nah, that's not, that's
not what I'm gonna do. And I'm
here. Like I'm a contractor now.
So it's just like, oh wow. Like
familiar cycles are, are a thing.
Bekah: That's such a great story.
that.
Sadie: yeah. Yeah. It's so funny.
Yeah. Like, um, yeah. My mom
retired like two months out from
my 18th. So like, it's like the
military and like that connection
is just like a part of my
identity. And like, I feel like
that's something that, like, not
too many people know, it's like,
I like I'm, I'm like looking
around right now. You can't see
this, but like where I am right
now, I grew up actually on the
military base. Like that's
probably like five miles away
from my house. And I don't know,
it was just a lot of like, wow,
like, Like, I've always been
aware of contractors and like,
just that relationship, but just
now being on the other side and
saying like, oh, like, huh, this
is how, this is how it works. And
like, I can also see like how
intense it is to be in the
military and like the, the sort
of like expectations you have to
fulfill that role. Like, like I
came into. this job thinking
like, oh, like now I can't like,
be late for my job. Or I can't
like take, take off work because
that's what I saw my mom, like
having to like, um, I guess
fulfill or like be secure in her
job, but that's, it's not like
that at all. Like, I, I have a
wonderful team that like respects
work life balance and. people
have kids and like, they
understand like, you know,
today's not the day, like just
come back tomorrow and it'll be
okay. Like that sort of thing. So
yeah, it it's a, it's really
deep, but yeah, that's my answer.
Bekah: I like that. I mean,
there's, there's familiarity
there. Right. And then there's
comfort that comes with that. And
when you're talking about taking
on a new job, it's really nice to
be able to have something like
that, where you can feel
comfortable in some aspect of
what you're doing.
Sadie: Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Bekah: Well, we're at just about
time here is, is there any last
piece of advice you have for our
listeners who are prepping for
interviews or leaving boot camps
and about to discover the next
stage of their journey? Uh,
Sadie: Oh, that's uh, okay. I
could say so much, but I hate to
say like something trite, but
like also like one trusted
process and then two, you know,
more than you think. Like, for
example, I didn't know Jack at
all, when I was interviewing for
this job. One, I reached out to
my community. So if you need a
community, find your community,
VC's here, but there's also
others. And then two, like do
what you can explain what you,
what you did and like your
thought processes. And if it's
not the fit, it's not a fit, but
you will find your job and you
can do it.
Dan: All of that. Trust the
process.
Sadie: Mm-hmm
Bekah: Yeah, I love that. Thanks
so much, Sadie, for being here
with us today, we've grabbed all
the links for the stuff that you
dropped, including your, um, blog
post on technical tests,
preparation advice. And we'll put
those in the show notes. And so
thanks for being here.
Sadie: Yay. Thank you. Thank you
all. Thank you.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!