Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and
welcome to Season 6, Episode 5
of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories, and what they've learned.
And we are here to share it with
you here with me. Today is my
cohost, Dan.
Dan Ott: Waddup, Bek? [Bekah
laughs] How is it going today?
Bekah: Just never know- never
know what -- how you're going to
deliver that. It is- is going
amazingly fantastic today.
Dan: That is impressive.
Bekah: Yep.
Dan: That's good. Cuz today we had
an amazingly fantastic guest,
Chad Stewart.
Bekah: Who is also awesome.
Dan: He's a software -- he is
also awesome. Yeah. We -- that's
obvious because he is on our
podcast. So-
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Dan: -like, you know, we just
assumed-
Bekah: Yeah. It was implied.
Dan: -at this point. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: But yeah, he's a --
Chad's a software
engineer from Kingston, Jamaica.
And, yeah, we had a good time
talking to him. And he talked a
lot about his experience with
open source and also his ... I
don't know what you call-
Bekah: Project?
Dan: -he's got a newsletter --
his sort of project. Yeah.
Called Tech
is Hiring. And ... I don't know.
He told us a lot about- a lot
about that and
how- how he got into that. And,
you know, how it works and stuff
is- is very cool.
Bekah: Yeah. I love how
organically it started. You know,
he saw a need for something that
in the wider tech industry. And
then somebody mentioned to him
like, "Hey, what do you think
about doing something more with
this?" And he just went with that.
And I think that's a really great
way to find inspiration and
energy from the things that
you're doing.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. I mean,
it's always good to talk to Chad.
He's- he's very funny. He's- he's
one of our main contributors to
our humor channel [Bekah and Dan
chuckle] in- in- in our Slack.
And yeah, it- it was
fascinating hearing about his-
his experience with all that
stuff. And with, the- the Open
Sauced. That was the other --
that's the big project that he
volunteers with --
contributes with.
And he talked a lot about
how you don't have to be writing
code to contribute to an open
source project. And I -- both
agree with that [chuckles] very
much and- and appreciate the-
the way he talked about his
experiences with that.
Bekah: Yeah. And we start
this episode of podcast like
we start every Virtual Coffee. We
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do, and a random check-in
question. We hope you enjoy this
episode. Our random check-in
question is, if you could have any
animal for a pet, what would it
be?
Chad Stewart: Cheetah.
Bekah: [Chuckles] Not yet.
Chad: [Dan laughs] Oh.
Bekah: And how is it not a
penguin? That's what I wanna
know.
Chad: I like cheetahs. It'd
be cheetah or a peregrine falcon.
Those are my favorite animals.
Dan: Mm.
Bekah: All right. My name is
Bekah. I am a technical community
builder from a small town in
Ohio. And if I could have any
animal for a pet ... I really
like red pandas and ring-tailed
lemurs. So those are on the top
of the list, But a falcon seems
like it would be pretty cool.
I've already got a skinny pig. So
I feel like half of my dreams
have been fulfilled already.
Dan: Yeah, that thing is
horrifying [chuckles].
Bekah: No, cute. It's adorable.
Dan: It's not -- the -- they're
supposed to have fur [laughs].
Bekah: No.
Dan: It's like it has a --
something --
Bekah: It doesn't- it doesn't
have fur.
Dan: Well, I know it doesn't.
Bekah: It's a tiny hippopotamus.
So if you're not-
Dan: [Chuckles] It's not.
Bekah: -familiar with what a
skinny pig
is, it is a hairless Guinea pig
that looks like a tiny hippo.
Super cute. Google it.
Dan: [Laughs] It's- it's --
Bekah: It is so cute, Dan.
Dan: It's really weird.
Bekah: Stop it. Stop hating on
my pet.
Dan: I mean, this is from a
person who likes the hairless
cats too. So [unintelligible].
Bekah: Love hairless cats.
They're amazing.
Dan: They're like the most
horrifying thing in the world.
Bekah: No, they're not. They're
so great. Especially when they're
angry looking, they're just like
great.
Dan: That ... [laughs] I don't
know. Okay. Hi, I'm Dan. I am a
developer of computer
things [laughs]. I live in
Cleveland, Ohio. Yeah. So are we
sticking with real world animals?
Bekah: No. If you want a mini
dragon, you can have one.
Dan: A mini dragon? I was gonna
say the dragon guy from "The
Neverending Story", although he
is like a little --
Chad: Falkor?
Bekah: Falkooor.
Dan: Yeah, Falkor. I was
gonna say, what's the word
for like, when you -- when a
person like a- a being can,
like, talk, and think and stuff?
Bekah: An anthropomorphism?
Dan: No, no, no. Like a- like a
conscious or, you know, like he
has -- he's a
little too much of a human --
not a human, but like a thinking
thing to be, like have a pet --
Bekah: Yeah. He's an
anthropomorphized
[unintelligible] --
Dan: I- I know. But I'm saying,
like- I'm saying, like, since --
Chad: It seems it got a taxpayer
to me. To know [inaudible].
Dan: [Laughs] It's a word --
there's a word, for what I'm
looking for.
And I- I- I can't think of the
word. But what I mean is like,
I would
feel bad keeping him as a pet
because he has like too much of
his own, you know, consciousness.
You know what I mean? Like, he
like talks and he is like his own
thing. So I don't think he'd
wanna be a pet. And that would
make me sad.
Bekah: Well, like what about dogs
that run away all the time? Did
they really wanna be pet? Should
they be free too?
Dan: I mean, I don't know
[chuckles]. I mean, that's a
good question.
Should any pets be pets, you
know? Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: I -- it's one of those
moral conundrums.
Dan: I mean, if you truly love
it, then set it free and it'll-
Bekah: They comes back [laughs]?
Dan: -come back or something?
How does that go [laughs]?
Bekah: If they comes back, it's
yours.
Dan: Alright.
Bekah: And that's how you know.
That is lyrics in a Christina
Aguilera's song.
Dan: Mm.
Bekah: I refrain from singing it
for you.
Dan: Ah, oh, man. All right.
Anyway, that's my answer. I'm-
I'm going -- i-if we have to
stick with real world, I'd say
sloth though.
Sloths are really cool. And, you
know-
Bekah: Oh, yeah.
Dan: -and I'd like -- I'd
totally
like just chill in the backyard
with the sloth. If it's-
Bekah: I was --
Dan: -real world- real world
animal. That's- that's my answer.
Bekah: I was in Costa Rica when I
was like 19 or 20, and that was a
highlight to get -- to see the
three toed and the two toed
sloths.
Dan: [Whispers] Oh, yeah. Nice.
Bekah: Welcome, Chad [chuckles].
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah. Go ahead,
Chad.
Chad: Oh, yeah. So I-I'm Chad
Stewart. I'm a software
engineer in --
cu-currently in Kingston,
Jamaica, mostly do front-end
engineering stuff. Right now
though, hopefully
transitioning to doing more
full-stack stuff. And I guess I
answered this earlier, but it
would be either a cheetah or
peregrine falcon. Those are my
favorite animals. They're fast. I
like fast animals. I don't know.
Yeah. And I like birds
which Bekah might have --
Bekah alluded too earlier
with a different type of bird.
But yeah [chuckles].
Dan: [Chuckles] Did you ever
read -- either of you ever read
"My Side of the Mountain"?
Bekah: Yes.
Chad: I- I did not.
Dan: You read that, Chad? So it's
a -- it's like a- it's like a young
adult book, I think. But it- it's
about a kid who runs away and
goes and lives in the woods, like
with- with nothing, you know? And
teaches himself how to so-sort of
forage, and hunt, and fish or
whatever. And he eventually like
goes and get -- like, steals a
falcon baby from a nest and- and
then, like, raises it and trains
it. And be -- it becomes his,
like, friend and stuff. It's
really cool. Anyway, that- that
sounds cool. It would be- it
would be really cool
to have a falcon as- as a pet.
And like, could just like hang
out with you on your shoulder?
Is that what -- do you think
you'd do shoulder or just do
your arm thing? I dunno if
on arm is possible.
Chad: Depends on the falcon.
I'm, you know, considering the
talents, it would probably not
necessarily rest on your shoulder
and rest in your shoulder, you
know what I mean?
Dan: [Laughs] Right, right.
[Unintelligible] little --
Bekah: Like a very leather
shoulder pad or something.
Dan: Right. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Little contraption for him to
hang out on. Feel like
you'd wanna like, hang, you know?
Keep you -- keep him with you when-
when he's not -- like, when he's
not cruising around.
Bekah: If I am ever famous and I
go to an award show, I'm gonna
come with a falcon on my
shoulder. I just decided it.
Seems like the [unintelligible].
Dan: You're keynoting a conference.
You should do it there.
Bekah: [Laughs] I don't think I
have enough time to train a
falcon.
Dan: Mm.
Bekah: I've got, like, three
weeks.
Dan: That's not enough time.
Bekah: I don't know.
Dan: Well, yeah. This episode
will come out after that anyway.
So, next time you're the
keynote speaker at a conference,
that'll be -- you just put that
in the -- on the plan [laughs].
Bekah: That'll be my thing.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Kirk says my thing is
crying while I give
talks. And that is the thing I
would like to not be doing. I
would rather be the- the Falcon
shoulder person [Bekah and Dan
laugh]. Welcome, Chad. This
is- this is the normal intro for
us. And it is a Friday that
we are recording on. So-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -brains don't work on
Fridays.
Everybody knows that. So
[laughs] you're gonna have to
bear with us today.
But we will -- we'll give you
the mic now. So you don't have to
listen to me talk anymore. We
always love to hear your origin
story. How did you come into tech
and get to this point in your
tech journey?
Chad: Yeah, so, I guess I
give a kind of quick synopsis of-
of what I did. So, I moved to
the United States for some
time. To be honest, to- to go
to art school because I wanted to
be a- a game developer and I -- but
I couldn't draw very well at the
time. So I ended up into another
program, which effectively was
web design. Whatever this -- it
was The Art Institute of Fort
Lauderdale. And it was whatever
they had kinda called web design.
And I did that for some time,
graduated, and then found I
didn't necessarily like web
design directly. Or at least,
what it was
at the time. And so I ended up
going back to another school.
I'm pretty sure the South
Floridians would kind of
know the schools
that I'm talking about. Well,
people know Art Institute. But
for the South Floridians, I went
back to NSU, Nova
Southeastern University, got a- a
software engineering degree from
there. And then did some work,
ended up returning home, and
have been kinda working around
ever since. During the
pandemic, I was unemployed. And
that's how I came across, you
know, Bekah, and Dan, and Virtual
Coffee when they were- when
they were hosting -- well, they're
still hosting [laughs]. They're still
hosting Zoom- Zoom calls. But
that's how I came across them.
And I've mostly been kinda
active on Twitter. So I s- I,
you know, I met- I met Dan and-
a-a-and Bekah during 2020, um,
2020, 2021. I decided to
start an organization called
Tech is Hiring. Te- pretty
much what I do is I retweet job
opportunities as I come across
them on Twitter. And I re- re --
I also retweet people
looking for- for opportunities.
And so I've been doing that for
about -- for- for a little bit
over a year now. And... yeah.
Like -- that's pretty much it.
We- we do have --
we have some presence on
LinkedIn, but mostly still on
Twitter. Have a newsletter,
been doing the newsletter thing.
Haven't missed a week. I'm
actually pretty happy about that.
But have- have been doing a
newsletter for a couple of
months now. I think over six
months now. And yeah, that's
pretty much -- yeah. I'm working
now, you know, thankfully. And
my opportunities are increasing
because of the amount of work
that I've been doing, and people
I've been reaching out to, and so
on and so forth. But yeah.
Yeah, it's pretty much me right
now.
Bekah: That's awesome. And we're
gonna dive into Tech is Hiring a
little bit more. But before we
jump into that, I know that
you've been doing, you know, a
lot of different community things
and some of that's been open
source work. Do you wanna talk
about what you've been doing with
open source and how you've
been a contributor as well?
Chad: Ah, yes. Ah, yes. So, I
recently started open source
doing more open source work.
Funny enough, I started with
the- with the open source
project that I had started with,
which is Open Sauced by
Brian Douglas — at Bdougie
on- on Twitter. And he,
honestly, he approached me to ask
me to- to- to contribute
to his project. And I did.
But I didn't stay initially,
mostly because of just all other
stuff that I kinda had going
on at the time. But he, again,
approached me later- he, again,
approached me later that year —
really late in the year —
mostly because of Tech is Hiring.
And then he, you know, he wants
to brought -- wanted me to- to
come on -- to-to-to
contribute more- more
again, and that's what I've been
kinda doing for the last
couple of months. And, you know,
his- his project is pretty much
about kind of having -- it- it
being a platform of- of people
you know, transitioning into
contributing for open source.
It's in a bit of, I don't
wanna call it limbo, but if the
kind of scope is evolving at this
point. So, you know, we're-
we're all kind of trying to
figure the OT, recently left
GitHub to- to work on- on open
source full time. And so, you
know, as he does that, and he's
putting a lot more like of his
full, you know, effort into it,
he's been- he's been kinda
expanding on that. And I've really
been helping here and there.
So like, for instance, one of the
things that I did — I'm pretty
kind of happy about this — is
that the- the- the onboarding
experience for open source was-
was a little bit disjointed and,
you know, he had managed to- to-
to get some designs, and to
just kinda change the
onboarding experience. And that
was like one of the first major
things that had helped him with,
when I started contrib- contributing
more often. And, you know, been
doing it for -- I've been working
on the project ever since. It --
there's two projects. There's
Open Sauced the- the- the app --
the- the- the regular app. And
then you have Hot Open Sauced,
which is like a-a-a-another --
not a child app, but just that
a-app alongside of it. I
haven't been working with Hot
Open Sauced, but yeah, that's
pretty much what I've been doing.
And, you know, you interact with
the community. You know, you get
to talk to -- you- you- you talk to
people here and there, like --
so, it's kinda interesting because
he has a- he has a Discord, which
I- I interact with a- a few times,
but to be honest, a lot of the
interactions kinda come- come
through his stream. I feel
like a lot of people just kinda
come there. And then there's also
times where he'll have like a
call on his Discord. And, you
know, that's where you- you have
some really interesting
conversations, you know, about
the project and about kinda how
it's evolving. But just generally
about software engineering. I
think that's like in terms of-
of -- in terms of open source,
that's the thing that I kinda
want to -- I- I- I really think
is the most important is, you're
kind of
access to information that you
wouldn't regularly have, or not
even necessarily access. Because
if you've heard these terms,
you've heard a lot of the
technologies and stuff, you
prob- you can Google it. Or,
you know, they're- they're that
open. But, like, the likelihood
of you coming across that as
somebody who's just not in the
know, you know, is very
difficult. And I think that's,
like, the- the key thing that-
that open source has been
helping me with is just coming
across these technologies, and
these people and, you know, just
getting to know them, you know?
Even if it's still more of a
passive la- not passive. But as
a pe- I don't know the person
directly, or I don't know -- I
haven't interacted with the
technology, but just having them
as like in your Rolodex of things
that you could leverage, you
know, is extraordinarily important.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I love
that. And I love Brian Douglas
too. He's pretty awesome. I --
actually, he's gonna be doing
a lunch and learn at Virtual
Coffee, which is super
exciting. We're gonna talk about
open source, and Open Sauced, and
Hacktoberfest. So that'll be coming
up in September. I'm really glad
to have him getting us in
the- in the mind frame of
prepping to do some open source
contribution. Because that's -- I --
the beginning of -- kind of of
the Virtual Coffee origin story
maybe. It's not the first
thing that we did, but it
was the first time I felt like
Virtual Coffee was gonna be an
organization that outlasts the
pandemic. I thought for a
long time that it was like, "Hey,
we're gonna get together." And
everybody's feeling isolated. And
then we did Hacktoberfest, our
first Hacktoberfest initiative.
And everybody was just so excited
about it and contributing. And we
had maintainers, and contributors,
and lots of mentorship, and
support, and it was, you know,
it was fun,
but really gratifying to see
people contributing and learning
and growing through that
experience. And, you know, it can
be- it can be scary to get
involved and do your first
contribution. Even if you've
been in tech, we had a number of
people who have been in tech for
a while, and have never done an
open source contribution. So, you
know, what advice do you have for
folks who are m-maybe a little bit
nervous about entering that open
source experience?
Chad: That's a- that's a
really interesting question.
Hmm. What advice would I give? So,
I would say, find the community,
you know? Like, the -- so, the-
the- the open source projects
that I would definitely look-
look to, are open source
projects that are very much not
just about the- the- the
contributions, but, you know, like
the- the -- whatever you kind of
deliver, whatever you merge, you
know? But significantly more
about the community of people.
And just kind of the culture
around the- the- the open source
project. Like -- that's really
important, you know? Like, there
are a lot of -- there, you know,
people give the advice of- of,
you know, contribute to, like you-
you -- their tools that you use all
the time like React, and so on
and so forth, you know? You want
to contribute to those. And, you
know, some of them are hit and
miss, but a lot of the times
they're so big that they -- they're
really hard to get into, you
know? Like, I- I wanted to -- I, you
know, I heard the- the whole thing.
It's like, "You should- you should
contribute to open source. It's
great." And so, I was just like, "Okay,
I'll contribute to open source,"
you know? "Which- which product then
I'm going to try?" "You wanna try
to contribute to React. There's a
bunch of good first issues there."
And I was just like, "What?" [Chad
and Bekah laugh] You know what I
mean? Like, I couldn't
understand anything that they
were asking. And this was like a
couple of years back. And I, you
know, I tried it a few times and
I was just like, "I'm gonna go do
something else," you know what I
mean? So it's like really
important to kinda have that
community, like have- have those
people being very welcoming, you
know? Having the Discord. Like, a
lot of the- the secondary stuff to
the- to the- to the actual
working code and tools is- is
really important. The second
thing, and I'm- I'm really happy,
I remember this. But the second thing
is that you don't necessarily
have to contribute code, you
know? It's not just about code.
There's a lot of other things
that you can contribute, and that
would be a contra- contribution to
open source. Like, contributing
documentation, you know? Like, I
know Brian have -- for- for open
source, he has a triage team for-
for triaging issues. I believe
that's like ... you know, find you
-- taking -- I'm sorry if I'm -- I-
I- I hope I'm getting this right.
But, like, you- you take it -- when-
when there's issues, you know, you
kinda scope them out so that
there's something that somebody
can easily take on. And I believe
he got that idea from the Node --
from Node. Which Node's, from my
understanding -- no, in fact, for
the longest time, I really wanted
to join the
open source community for Node
because they seemed so welcoming,
you know? They seemed to have all
of this kind of infrastructure in
place for a new person to come in
and really be able to
contribute, you know? Like, I
don't remember exactly everything
that they have now, but like, they
have, you know, they have stuff
on YouTube, they have them week --
they have weekly meetings on
YouTube, you know? Like, they have,
like, this whole community around
joining them. And so -- and -- I'll try
not to- to go into the community thing
again, but like, there are a lot
of things that you can do to contribute,
you know? Like, you can contribute
documentation, like for- for- for
the Node project. Like, I believe
you can do something like just
kinda help managing the
meetings that they have because
they regularly have meetings. But
there are a lot of outside things,
outside of like literally writing
the code that needs to go into
the project that can go- that can
go in there. And people have
literally gotten opportunities from
contributing to open source-
open source projects in these
auxiliary ways, you know? And so,
I would -- so the thing that I
would definitely stress is
community, you know? Like,
community is extraordinarily
important, you know? Having
people to have your back, you
know, when you're contributing is
really important. To be quite
honest, I would say that it's
much more important to- to- to
build and maintain those
relationships than it is to
contribute the code. In my opinion.
But it's much more important
to have those relationships. In
fact, I would say that's the most
important thing about open source.
And that it's not just about
contributing code. You don't need
to contribute code. It's- it's
about you can contribute in- in
your own way. Just reach out. And
there might be things that- that,
you know, that the- the- the
maintainer needs. And, you know,
you may be able to help- help
there. But just -- I guess, to kind
of sum up at the very least the
last part is just be very open
minded on how you- how you'd like
to contribute to the community,
you know? Like, you don't
necessarily have to contribute
something that, you know, gets
merged into a pull request. Well, yeah.
But just be very open minded on
how you'd contribute to the community
-- to- to- to that community
and focus on community, you know?
Even if it's a small community,
just focus on the relationships
that you're building with- with
these people. It's not just
about, you know, you write
something and then merge
requests and then you, you know,
you go off somewhere, you know?
It's about building those
relationships, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Chad: That's- that's what I
would say. Sorry
for cutting you out.
Bekah: No, no, no. I love that. I
love focusing -- especially for
first time contributors on that
interaction on the community
building of things, because
getting into open source can be
really nerve-wracking or seem
really hard to do, but you're
right. If you find that right
community, it makes it a lot
easier for you and you are
building those relationships.
And, you know, if we look at even
some of the larger open source
projects, sometimes- sometimes
there's a need for smaller
contributions or sometimes their
first time contributor issues are
exactly like what you were
talking about. Like, "I have no
idea what you're talking about.
This is not for me." And then
that's okay, you know? There are
other opportunities out there.
And this is one of my pet peeves
where people are like, this is
not in the spirit of Hacktoberfest.
And they wanna say like,
"Oh, you can't make a contribution
that looks like this or that. Just
changes one thing." And I- I
think that maybe that's how you
feel about your project, but that
doesn't necessarily apply to
other people's projects. There
are a lot of projects out there
that are community run, that are
people who are trying to
collaborate, and work together, and
support other people. So there
are lots of different projects.
There's different approaches to
open source contribution. And
finding that community that's
going to support you is going to
help you to make that
contribution.
Chad: Absolutely. Absolutely. I
agree. And I'd like to touch on a
little bit about, you know, there
are a lot of kind of community
run projects. I've been there. So,
[chuckles] this is- this is kind of funny.
I went through -- just looking
up a lot of interview prep stuff.
Cuz to be quite honest, I did a
lot of that within the last -- not
within the last couple of months,
but years prior, I was doing
a lot of interview prep. And there
are so many kind of, you know,
thing -- I don't know if they're
necessarily open source projects,
but they're projects that, you
know, have a GitHub that's, you know,
open to the world. And, you know,
like, as far as I know, it's not
a paid product, you know? I think
it's -- yeah. I don't think it's
a paid product. Like, for
instance, there's- there's the
algorithms, which is something
that I just recently found out
about, which is literally a
project of a bunch of kinda data
structures and algorithms that
you would see in interviews.
And it's like a huge kinda log
of them in different languages.
You know what I mean? And as far
as I know, that's not a paid
product. It's just out there, you
know? And like, I was bookmarking
a bunch of these things. But
there's that- there's that. Like,
there's the- the- the -- what you
call it? The tech interview
handbook, which kind of gives you
like a real -- you know, it's a
great breakdown of how
interviewing is, how you study,
you know? What you -- what people
are- are looking. Funny enough.
The thing that I -- that draw me
to that was, you know, what, you
know, there -- it described like
how people are- are kind of
looking- looking at you, at,
like, big tech interview -- the
point I'm making is all of those
things, when you look at them on
GitHub, they're really just like
marked on files, you know? I
think they are. But
they're- they're not like
anything crazy, you know? You're
not like using Redux to- to
display all of this information,
you know what I mean? But those
projects like that have hundreds of
contributors. And you know, like,
you can contribute to that
project. Say- say for instance,
you've done a massive amount of
interviewing — to- to kind of stay
in context — the ma- massive
amount of interviewing and you
feel like there's an issue here.
Issue with some of the
information here. You could most
definitely reach out or- or- or
apply a change. And I- I mean, even
then, it's like, all of this is
kinda talking about
information, right? So, you know,
say there's like typos or it's
just not as clear, you can
definitely just, you know, clear
up that information or reach out to
whoever. And- and like, that isn't
necessarily code in the se- in- in
the sense that most people think
of open source projects. When
people think of open s- or
contributing to open source
projects, they think about adding
a feature or refactoring. Very
much like code, you know? Very
much like that very particular
use case. When there's -- like I
said, there's a whole breadth of
things that you can- you can- you
can do. And I mean, we're- we're
-- even- even this conversation,
we're kinda talking about the --
at least, the- the way I'm kind of
thinking about it is like, if
you're doing open source, you're
literally on GitHub, you
literally go to the project, and
then it's just like, however,
right? But, you know, if you're --
if the- the open source project
has a community, you know, you
may not necessarily even be on
GitHub, you know? Like, you could
be- you could be a part of their
Discord, and you could be, like,
moderating their Discord, and
something like that, you know?
Like, that's still contr-
contributing, you know what I
mean? So, like, I just -- I guess
I just wanted to- to- to, again,
reemphasize that there's a lot of
things that you can do to
contribute to community, you
know? Like it's, again, it's not
just writing co- I wanna say
JavaScripts of that [Bekah
giggles]. It's not
just writing JavaScript, you know
what I mean? It's just not
writing code. Like, there's a lot
of ways you can- you can
contribute and it's just keeping that
open mind of the- the- the, you know,
the- the needs of the- the- the
maintainer.
Bekah: Yeah.
Chad: That's pretty much it.
Dan: Yeah, I love that. You know,
and- and Virtual Coffee [chuckles] for
example, right? And we have lots
of volunteers that are -- that help
our community. But also like
our- our site is open source. And,
I don't know, like 80% of the
files are just content, you know?
I mean, they're just -- and it -- I
suppose it's code technically or
something [chuckles], you know? But
it's -- like, the- the valuable parts of
it are the- are the words, right?
Are the content, you know? And ...
I- I mean, I love that advice. I
think it's great and very
important to keep in mind. And
also, it's like -- sometimes,
especially when you get into docs
and stuff like that is, sometimes
really hard for maintainers to
keep up to date or to make, you
know, like to catch all the
edge cases and things like that.
Ayu from Virtual Coffee is
really good at this shit. You
know, how many times have you
done, like some install -- followed
the README, right? Done some
install thing, and it didn't work.
And you had to like Google around
and try a couple different things
to get something to work, right?
And then, what I do most of the
time is just, "Okay, cool. I got it
working. I'll just move on," [chuckles]
you know? But how val- how much,
like, it would be a very easy and
valuable contribution to that-
that project to just go back and add
like a- a pull request that just
adds a little note in the README
that says, "Hey, if you run into
this error, try this fix," you
know what I mean? And I
think that's the kind of thing
that a lot of people maybe don't
consider right away. But it --
I don't know. Can be --
Bekah: Kinda like that error that
I have running the Virtual Coffee
site that I still haven't
[chuckles] done anything about?
Dan: Right. Well, that's a whole
different ... yeah, issue -- situation.
Bekah: No, that's a Netlify CLI
issue actually.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. But- but- but it
is the same thing. I mean, like
it's- it's the same thing. Like,
okay. Like, maybe that is something we
need to add. Cuz other people --
most people don't have the Netlify
CLI installed, like, to start and
-- but you already did. And so
there's something going on and
maybe there's some note we need
to add or some parameter to add
to the install steps, you know? I
don't know. I don't know what it
is, but like, even-
Bekah: Yeah [chuckles].
Dan: -just bringing
it up in issue, like, even
honestly, writing an issue is
contributing to an open source.
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: Like, not fixing it, not-
not
knowing the solution, but just
like logging a problem. It can be
a very valuable contribution to
[chuckles] an open source project
because, most likely the maintainer
doesn't know about it, you know?
Our maintainers don't know about
it. Like the -- or they do and
they forgot or [chuckles], you
know, anything. And I- I- I --
yeah, I don't know. I- I think
everything you said is- is right.
And I- I think it's great. I
love that also. I just talk a
little bit more. I love that idea
about helping- helping
maintainers in areas outside of
GitHub even, and how valuable
that can be. I think- I think
that's another thing that people
don't maybe always think about.
But asking maintainers if they
need help outside of writing
code, it can be nice and it
can be nice- nice to, like, have
somebody to reach out- reach out
[chuckles] to you too, you know, sometimes.
Say, "Hey, do you need any help
with this?" Even if- even if
they say no, it's- it's like a
nice ... I don't know. Nice
gesture.
Chad: Yeah --
Bekah: Yeah, I --
Chad: Oh, go ahead, go ahead, go
ahead.
Bekah: Sorry. I- I gave a talk
on ... I think it was called do
you need community? And it was
from the perspective of if
you're maybe getting into code,
or if you are in tech and you
don't have a community, what- what
would be the reasons and the
benefits. And part of that, I
talked about getting involved in
organizations. And sometimes
people say like, "Hey, do you need
any help?" And there's so much
overwhelmed sometimes as a
maintainer that it's like, "Yeah,
but I don't even know where to
start," right? And so being more
specific like, "Hey, do you need
any help? I'm really good at
building chat bots. And I think
this could be really beneficial."
Like, giving that specific thing
or, "Hey, I like to post on social
media. Can I write some tweets
for you?" And you know, you're not
getting a green box for that. And
I know that it can be really hard
to feel like, "Oh, there -- I
haven't accomplished anything,"
but you've supported a community
of people that- that is
supporting other people. So, and
I- I think the -- one of the things
I like too about Virtual Coffee,
our members page just keeps
evolving into something better
and better because we have our
members who have to create a pull
request to get their profile on
our mem- members page. But then
last year, the issue was you can
add your social links. And
we've updated it with all of our
active volunteers. So, you know,
like finding ways to also
support the people who are
supporting your project in other
ways is incredibly important as
well.
Chad: I agree. I agree. And,
I also want to kind of reiterate
that, like, you know, you- you --
for- for the people who are
actually contributing code, they --
a lot of those people do that to
improve their skills, right?
Bekah: Mm.
Chad: To come across problems
that they
generally wouldn't come across or
be more difficult for them to
come across o-on their own, right?
But I think the most important
part of open source as a
contributor is to -- is that
interaction. The interaction with
people, you know what I mean? And
so definitely being -- having
something where it's like, okay,
you reach out to the maintainers.
It's like, "Hey, I can do this,"
you know? Like you were saying,
you know? "I can- I can do tweets,"
and so on and so forth. Like, that
interaction is so valuable. And
the con- that consistency of
interaction is so valuable. Like,
you'd be surprised, you'd be-
you'd be maintaining a project,
and there's just somebody who,
you know, you- you know them- you
know them casually and then they
turn out to be -- well, 50% of the
time, they turn on to be, you
know, your- your next employer
because they're now op- offering
you an opportunity. I- I was
watching a video recently, you
know, I'm just going to be -- I was
watching a video from Open Sauced
recently, where -- I don't
remember who he
was or who Brian was talking to,
but he was talking about how
we had an open source project and
like, it became more and more of a-
of a -- I don't remember exactly
the- the- the circumstances. But
he -- and he started hiring a lot
of people because he had somebody
who was -- he had started hiring --
not a lot of people. He started
hiring from his contributors
because his contributors were
very consistent, they were
excellent, you know, in what the --
in their contributions. And he
just -- he was just like, "Hey, you
want to, you want a full time
job?" And they were like, "Yeah,
sure." And that's how they found
their next opportunitiy, you know?
And so, it's really about those
relationships, you know? As a
contributor. As a- as a
maintainer, you know, like, that's
a -- I don't want to talk about
that too much cuz that's just
not -- I don't have the experience
there. But as a contributor, it's
about building those
relationships. And, like, it's just
a different avenue of- of
building those relationships with
people. And then, you know,
showing that, you know, like -- I
guess going back to- to coding,
showing that, you know, you can
code — that's like one of the big
issues, the big problems with-
with junior developers trying to
get positions — is that ... effectively
they have to prove that they-
they know how to code and they
can just be like, "Hey, look at my
contribution to this open source
project that got, you know, that
got merged and is being used in
the project right now and has my name
on it," you know? "I can code," [laughs] you
know what I mean? Like, so -- like,
it's just, yeah. It's just -- it's
about building those
relationships. Those
relationships will- will
definitely take you far. A-at least
in my- in my opinion, that's like
one of the biggest things for-
for- for --
Dan: Yeah. A-and- and not just proving
you can code, but proving that you have
drive, and can operate on your own,
and things like that as well.
A-and you're interested in it and,
you know, I- I- I think- I think that
sort of ... I don't know. A- a- a
full [chuckles], you know, I don't wanna say
like, all- all the green squares are
green, but like, you know- you
know, a full, like, GitHub profile
where you have a lot of
contributions to some things
can go a really long way. To
showing that, y-you know, even if
you're not, like, write -- like you
said, like, rewriting the React
code base, you know? [Laughs] Like, it-
it doesn't have to be like that,
obviously, e-e-especially when you're
starting out. But just like
connecting with people and- and- and
contributing in -- I don't know. I-
I, yeah. I agree. It's can be a
very valuable tool; open
source contributions.
Bekah: I know a woman who really
wanted to work with a pretty
notable tech organization, but
their interview process was
notoriously hard. And she knew she
would not be able to pass the
interview process. And, you know,
didn't have time to devote hours
and months of her life to studying
for it. And so, she started
contributing to their open source
project. And sure enough, she got
hired without having to go
through that interview process
because she was familiar with the
code base, they knew that her
work was good, and that she could-
could be a part of the team
because of that community
collaboration that she already
had. So, I mean, not everybody's
gonna let you navigate
around the interview process. But
it was really, really great
strategy for, you know, not only
learning more it yourself, but like
you're saying, finding new
avenues to job opportunities.
Chad: Agreed. Agreed. I actually
was, I don't necessarily have a
direct story, but I've definitely
heard of other people who've had
similar experiences, who -- they-
they contributed to- to- to large
open source projects for pretty
well-known companies, and, you
know, no interview processes like,
"We- we see that you co- we see
that you can code. We, you know,
we want you to work on this
thing," you know? So they just
brought them on board, you know?
It wasn't that -- it wasn't a big,
crazy thing, you know? They
didn't have to study for- for-
for months like you said, you
know? Definitely like -- and from
my understanding, that is- that
is not uncommon, you know? Like,
it's not an uncommon circumstance
at all, you know? So, definitely -- I
definitely, again, you know, it's
about those relationships. It's
about, you know, it's about
building those relationships
with- with- with those- with
those people, you know? And even
with other contributors as well,
you know? Like, how- how many
people have- have kind of come-
come to Virtual Coffee and have
become friends with each other
because of kind of their- their-
their meeting at Virtual Coffee
or doing work with vir- Virtual
Coffee, you know what I mean? So
it's definitely about building
those relationships. Again, in my
opinion.
Bekah: Yeah. Well, and I think too,
one of the great things about
contributing to open source is
also learning how to take
feedback. Because oftentimes, you
know, you've got a PR and it's
not going to be perfect. So
you'll be getting some feedback.
Do you have any experience with
that? And, you know, like, has
that helped you develop as a
developer [laughs]?
Chad: It has definitely not
helped me develop as a developer
because that'd -- no, I'm just
[Chad and Bekah laugh]. Yeah,
I've gotten -- I've
definitely gotten feedback.
Like, one of the kinda key
things about just being
coachable, you know? And again,
like, because it's a learning
experience, you know? Like, I
don't wanna say -- well, because
it's a learning experience, you
should really be happy for
feedback, you know?
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Chad: Like, you
don't want somebody to be giving
you feedback where they're like,
"[Mimicking angry tone] Argh,
argh, argh," you know? and
they're just kinda yelling down.
Like, nobody
wants that, you know what I mean?
But if it's like, "Hey, I would
structure it this way." Like, that's
like the key thing about, you
know, contributions, right? Like, ab-
about open source, right? Like, I
don't wanna say it's judgment
free again, you know, it depends
on who's giving you the feedback,
but it's- it's- it's somewhat
non-committal in that sense -- in a
sense, you know? Like, you don't
have to give your contribution.
You absolutely don't have to.
It's not life or death. You know
what I mean? So, a lot of the
times, like, you can give your --
you can give a contribution and
they give you feedback. And that
feedback is just gold. You know
what I mean? It's just like,
there's stuff that they talk
about, that they -- that you didn't
know, or even necessarily they
give you feedback and you push
back on the feedback and say,
"Hey, this is my -- this is the
reason why --," like, all of that-
that interaction is extremely
important. That's what you're
gonna be doing on the job, you
know? Like, code review is going
to happen [laughs]. It, like, well, I
don't wanna say it's going to happen.
There are some companies --
anyways. But, like, the likelihood
of that is so high. Like, that is
just an interaction that you have
to go through, you know? And not
only that, like, the amount of
information that you can get from
somebody saying, you know, "I
don't think is -- this is the
best way of doing it. I think
this is -- a- a
better way is this," is like,
especially when it's -- it can
potentially be difficult or just
hard to- to- to get
information and to be able to
leverage it immediately. Like,
you know, you can go to a
tutorial and you can learn a
bunch of things, but a lot of the
times, if it doesn't apply to
whatever you're doing right now,
you know, it doesn't stick unless
you keep doing it over and over.
But, like, getting that feedback,
you know, on something that
you're working on, and then
leveraging it, and then, you know,
like saying, "Okay, I've applied
it," or, "I don't- I don't
necessarily agree with your
feedback." Like, that is such an
important thing. Even if you
don't agree with it, it might be
something whereas, you know,
might be another tool in your
toolbox. You know what I mean?
So, like, it's- it's kind -- it's still
kind of sticky because, again, you
know, some people are a little
bit more harsh with their
feedback or it's not even
necessarily harsh, but their
feedback doesn't kind of mesh
with how your culturally kind of
built to accept feedback, you
know? But, like, for the most part,
like, all of that stuff can potentially
be gold to you, especially as a-
as a new person, still learning,
you know? If, like, them telling
you, "Hey, I don't think this is
necessarily the best way," you
know? Like, all of that is great stuff,
you know? That stuff that you
can- you can put- you can put
away and then, like, potentially
work on later. Like, even if, say,
your contribution doesn't get
accepted for whatever reason, you
know? Like, that information for
you is really, really good when
you're learning, you know? And it
really just kind of like, I would
say in terms of navigating code-
code -- I don't wanna say -- well,
getting feedback. It really just
kinda understanding the person
and how they're giving feedback.
And if they're giving, like,
feedback that is not particularly
great or is demeaning, you know?
Let's get up and walk away.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Chad: Again, you're not committed,
you know? Like, if they're going
to be that
person, you know, that- that's
not somebody you want to be
associated with, you know, in any
form of kinda long term anything, you
know? But generally, like, you
know, people are very friendly.
Like, people [chuckles] want you
to come back. Like, some people
desperately want you to come
back, you know? It's like, you
know, "I'm working on this by myself
[chuckles]," or, "I'm working on this
with a small group of people, you
know? More people who are working
with me, you know, the better,"
you know what I mean? So it's in
their -- it's -- they're incentivized
to- to- to kinda keep you
coming back, you know what I
mean? That's -- and there's also
like -- and this is a part of -- kind
of the community aspect of- of open
source or a particular open
source project. Like, how to kind
of contribute and like having a-
having a system kind of around
contribution in the sense of, you
know, code style, you know, tools
that you- you- you are using and
stuff like that. Being very
structured in that way, it really
kind of lets people know how to-
how to approach the project. You
know what I mean? So that's also
a good thing to kind of look for.
It does- it doesn't necessarily- it
doesn't necessarily address
feedback directly, you know? But
it kinda addressed what- what
your expectations of the feedback
will- will- will be, you know?
But, yeah. Like, I -- yeah [unintelligible] --
Dan: So, as a- as a contributor
-- like a potential contri-
contributor to a
project, what- what are your
steps? Like, what do you do
before- before you, like, file
a pull request? Like, what do you --
like, I assume you maybe read the
README. What- what else -- what other
kinda steps do you take, like, to
make sure that you're doing what the-
what the maintainers want you
to do, you know?
Chad: To be fair, so, I've mostly
been working with Open Sauced. And
they've had -- they have a very
good, you know, kind of contributors
doc, you know? And so they kind
of put the systems in place so
that you don't necessarily -- so
that you don't mess up, you know,
in a sense, right? So there's
like a lot of kind of guardrails
and hand-holding that the- that
the system will do, you know? But,
like -- again, you know, you can
say, for instance, there isn't
really any contri- any, like, docs
on contributing. Generally, that's
the first place to start, you
know? Docs on contri- just
the- the- the kinda docs on the
infrastructure, right? Like, on
how you contribute. Just start
there, you know? Before- before
anything else. Because a- a- a
good, well-maintained open source
project will at least have docs-
docs to- to- to tell you how to
contribute. If they don't
necessarily have docs, you may,
you know, may reach out to the
maintainer and ask questions. You
may file an issue, ask questions.
By the way, if they don't have con-
docs on contributing, that's a
really good contribution [laughs], you
know? Like -- but it's just really --
just getting clarification, how-
however you can. Like, that
doesn't necessarily mean you
don't -- you can't just work on
the- on the pull request
immediately. But, you know, like,
just getting clarification on how
they kind of want the- the- the pull
request set up. Like, and like I
said. Get that clarification
however you can either they have
docs written or you just reach out
to people di-directly, you know? You
may even kind of go back to- to-
to previous pull requests and-
and take a look at that. But I
would definitely say if they
don't have docs, just reach out
to the maintainer and- and- and start
there. I don't have the most
amount of experience here
because, you know, like my open
source -- the project that I work
with mostly have a lot of these
kind of things in place. But, you
know, just getting that
clarification. Like, that's-
that's the best way I would
submit them. Just get that
clarification first, because it
would kinda- it would kinda suck
where you do all of this work. It
may even take you like a couple
of days. You do all of this work,
and then you make a pull request.
And then they- they- they
deny the pull request for
something simple that you could
have easily sorted out day one,
you know? And, you know, nobody
wants their pull request
rejected, you know what I mean?
So it's like, it- it's just like
at the very least you can just do
those things if you don't -- if
you're not necessarily a hundred
percent clear, you know? That's- that's --
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. And- and I
mean, so you- you said you contribute to
Open Sauced and they've got a
great process. So if you wanna
get started, and you wanna know
what a good project looks like
so you can identify other ones,
then go to Open Sauced and look at
what they have there. Because
that's a good way to start. And I
know, you know, we've got a
pretty thorough contributing
guidelines doc on our Virtual
Coffee site as well. And, you
know, sometimes there's
discussions — not everybody has
discussions enabled — but I really
like discussions for being able
to have community members ask
questions about things and to
learn more. And then also,
discussions allows us to see,
"Okay, yeah. Maybe we're missing
something here or we could add
this. Now, here's an issue." And "Hey,
since you brought it up, do you
want to be the one to make the
pull request for that
project?" So, it is- it is step one
is -- well, maybe it's not step
one. But a good step is
identifying what good projects
look like so you can see them
at other places.
Chad: Definitely agree.
Bekah: Now-
Dan: I'm sorry, I'm kinda --
Bekah: -I'm -- I kinda wanna
pivot a little bit before we end
the podcast episode and talk more
about Tech is Hiring. Because, you
know, all the things that we've
talked about, along with open
source, I think contribute to
this idea of Tech is Hiring, the
idea of community, of connection,
of navigating through a problem
that you identified. So what kind
of started your inspiration for
Tech is Hiring?
Chad: Well, it started really
with my own job search. I- I
don't even know how I came across
this. But I realized that, you
know, you could just make a tweet
and say, "Hey, I'm looking for a
role." And people retweet it. Like,
people are very -- at the very
least in- in- in the tech industry,
or on tech Twitter, people
are very open about, you know, helping
people find new roles. And so,
you know, I was doing that a few
times, like, in my own job search.
And then I think one day I was
retweeting and I was just
realized, you know, if you don't
have a good network and -- yeah, if
you don't have a good network,
you know, l-l-likelihood of you-
you -- the likelihood of your
tweet going viral in a sense it --
that would help you is- is- is
pretty low. And so, you know, my
first thought was like, "Hey, do
we have like a hashtag or
something that we can, you know,
that we can ... like, post our
tweet to? So at the very least,
you know, it's in one centralized
place?" And people were like, "No."
And I was just like, "Okay." And
somebody had reached out and they
were little like, "Oh, so you're
gonna make a hashtag, right?" And
I was like, "I guess I am now."
[laughs]. So I ended up like-
Bekah: Nice.
Chad: -it- it -- yeah [laughs].
I ended up taking like a couple of
days, just kind of trying to come
up with a name. And then, you
know, I just made a quick post
and I was just like, "Hey, this
hashtag, you know, post to it if
you- if you wanted to -- if you
want to- to- to share your tweet."
And, like, I pretty much did
that. And initially, when I- when
I made the first tweet, I didn't --
I obviously didn't expect anybody
to like be jumping, you know, out
to the woodwork to kinda tweet to
it. So I just went out to my way
to go find tweets, you know? So
for people to share, to just kind
of encourage and to build that
kind of backlog, right? Of places --
of- of- of resources and, you
know, it just kind of grew from
there. So like, I started
adding tweets every day, you
know -- every weekday I should say.
I started adding tweets every
day, you know? Just took- took a
couple of minutes all to my day. In
fact, I'm probably gonna do that
right after I get off of this.
But took a couple of minutes
just went through all, you
know, went and looked for- for
people looking for jobs or had
jobs to share. And I would just
ask them if I could add it to
Tech is Hiring. And I've just been
doing that. And, you know, at the
end of last year, I started doing
spaces around- around Tech is
Hiring when- when spaces, you
know, became a feature that was
open to the public. I started
doing that. And there's a --
there's definitely a lot of
people who just kinda like,
there's a lot of -- kind of -- I
don't wanna say there's a lot of
information that people tend to
lack, you know? Like, even --
especially there's a lot of job
changes, right? So they may have
existed in an industry for
periods of time. Maybe years,
decades, right? And they're
transitioning into the tech
industry. And, like, a simple thing
as how to structure your resume
is- is something that they may not
necessarily know. You know what I
mean? And it's actually fairly
difficult. It's not as difficult
now because there's significantly
more resources, but it's fairly
different -- difficult to find out
how to structure your resume in a
good way. And so, you know, I was
just like, you know, that's also
resources that people could have,
you know? Like, people have, you know,
hiring or just kind of job search
or just those kind of
conversations on- on spaces. And
I'll share that, you know, when-
whenever I can. It's like, "Hey,
do mind if I add this to Tech is
Hiring," you know? And I guess
it just kinda evolved from there.
I eventually started a newsletter
to kind of do the same thing,
whereas like I have -- I'll
effectively curate the tweets
that I see. And then I'll just, you know,
take five of the -- five people who are
looking for jobs and then 10 jobs
during that week. And then any
additional, like, an- an additional
information, like, say for
instance, there was like a really
good thread about, you know,
again, let's keep it in context,
talking about resumes, you
know? Like, I'll- I'll- I'll share
that anything that's a part of
the hashtag. So I won't, like, go
searching for stuff. But anything
that's a part of the hashtag, you
know, that got retweeted by -- with
the hashtag, I'll- I'll add that
to the newsletter, and so on and
so forth. And, you know, it's
really just kind of been about --
just trying to be, like, make
it -- make that -- make the whole
thing about either job searching
or transitioning, just job
related stuff, make it easier,
you know? Especially -- so, like
the- the- the thing about Twitter
is like when you go on LinkedIn
or when you apply for a job in
any- in any- in any, I guess,
standard way, right? You- you
upload your- your- your resume
and so on and so forth. It's very
likely that you won't necessarily
get seen by a human for whatever
reason. I'm not even gonna get
into that. But for whatever
reason, you may not necessarily
get seen by a human, you know? Or
-- I don't wanna say that. For
whatever reason, you won't
interact with a human, I should say,
you know? You may get some
automated email saying you were
rejected or you may not even get
to reply at all, right? But, you
know, for Tech is Hiring because
most of the times I'm retweeting
tweets that somebody else made,
you know, a lot of the times that
person — and a lot of the times
it's a person --
legitimate person. That person is
now kind of your- your
interaction, the- the -- your point
of contact for that company. So say,
for instance, let's- let's go
with AWS. A lot of people
actually, when they -- when
they're- when they're sharing
job, they'll say, "Hey," you know,
like, in it's -- in particular cases,
they'll say "I'll- I'll definitely ..."
not -- what's -- not sponsors. The
-- what's the phrase? When they
recommend -- they- they'll
recommend you, you know? And so
you have that, excuse me, you
have that point of contact
with the organization, you know,
and like, for- for- for getting
hired. Like, having somebody
recommend you, you know?
Especially like a big person
recommending you is a huge deal,
you know? And for, like --
especially for- for younger
engineers, they don't necessarily
have that network to have
somebody recommend them for a
job. You know what I mean? And
so, you know, when somebody posts
that, you know, their job is
looking for a- a position and
somebody sees that, they can go
and just reach out to them. They
can send them a DM or they can
send them a reply. And, like, that-
that interaction is significantly
better. That even if you're qual-
I mean, to be fair, if you're
qualified for the job, you're
qualified for the job. But just
having that kind of point of
contact, you know? Maybe it's not
the job for you, but you don't
know that, you know? You're not
gonna know that until you
interview. So you can sit down
and talk with them, you know?
Like, just having that point of
contact is so important, you
know? So, like, that's kind of the
real value of Tech is Hiring
currently is. It's not even
necessarily the resources that
get shared. It's the resources and
the people who actually share
them and your ability to interact
with them, you know? That's
really the- the- the main thing
about Tech is Hiring.
Bekah: That's so great. Thanks
for sharing that with us, Chad.
And thanks so much for being
here with us today. So if you're
listening, please go ahead and
follow Chad on Twitter and follow
Tech is Hiring and make sure to
subscribe to his newsletter.
We'll have links to all of those
things in our show note. And we
will see you next time.
Dan: Thank you, Chad.
Chad: You're welcome.
Dan: Thank you for listening
to this episode of the Virtual
Coffee podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week!