Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello, and welcome to
Season 6, Episode 6 of the
Virtual Coffee podcast. I'm
Bekah. And this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey. And they're here
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've learned
here. And we are here to share it
with you. Here with like host
Dan.
Dan Ott: Hey, Bekah how's it going?
Bekah: fantastic.
Dan: Yes, we are in a silly
mood cuz we just finished
recording with Julia Seidman,
developer, educator. She's
independent consultant and
she's had really long and
interesting career, couple
different roles. And it was a
really good time. It was a very
silly time as well. So, we,
we, we had a good time talking to
Julia as always.
Bekah: Yeah, we did. We had a, a
deep dive into our intro
question. So I think that we have
set the record for longest ever
intro because we explored quite a
few tangents.
Dan: Yes. But we learned some
things along the way. Right?
Bekah: We did some very, very
interesting things about
exploring different technologies
as developer educator, and what
that career path.
Dan: mm-hmm
Bekah: Also about rhodium gotta,
you gotta listen the end of the
episode, though. If you wanna
know about rhodium.
Dan: yeah, no, Julia has a, a
really great, outlook on
pretty much everything. You
know, she talks a lot about how
education is important in her
writing process. And, she has
this, I don't know if it's a
ethos or whatever, but, she
says "embrace the careen over the
career." Right. And I. As another
person who I never thought about
it like that. Exactly. But, I
very much appreciate that that
look in life. I think it's
very healthy one too. So,
yeah, I don't know. It was, it
was a good time and it was fun.
So I, this is I'm horrible at
ending things. It hasn't gotten
better.
Bekah: I think that's probably
my, my job to pick up with. We
start every episode of the
podcast. Like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name where
we're from. What we do and a
random check-in question, and we
hope that you enjoy this episode.
Our intro question today is if
you could have an unlimited
supply of one non-food thing for
the rest of your life, what would
it be? My name is Bekah. I am a
technical community builder at a
it's not what I normally say. I
don't know. Hi I'm Bekah
Dan: It sounded good.
Bekah: but it was like, I don't,
that's just not what I normally
say. And then my brain was like,
what are you doing? This is not
how we do this thing.
Alright,
Dan: That's what my brain does
every time, except that there's
not a normal thing that it's
Bekah: Well that's because you
don't know what you do. you're
very confused about.
Julia Seidman: Same same.
Bekah: Hi, I'm Bekah, I'm a
technical community builder at
DeepGram from a small town in
Ohio and an unlimited supply of
one nod food thing for the rest
of my life. I, this is just,
I don't know where to go with
this. I really like N
notebooks and pens, but that's
two things. So that should it be
like practical and does it just
automatically appear because
like, I, for a long time kept
forgetting to buy light bulbs.
And so we were in the dark all
the time, so, or like triple a
batteries. I don't, I'm just,
Julia: good one.
Bekah: and non food items. All I
Julia: always have
Bekah: food
Julia: always have double A,
never have triple As..
Bekah: Yeah, exactly. Or like
that one time you need a D
battery and like what the, no, I
don't have a D battery. So I
don't,
Julia: You wanna show your kid
what happens when you look a nine
volt and you don't have a mind.
Bekah: Am I supposed to show kid
that
Julia: I feel like it's a right
of passage
Bekah: I don't even understand
what that I've never heard of.
That
Dan: go try it. See what happens.
Bekah: I don't have a nine volt
Dan: no,
Julia: was a science teacher. a
lot questionable things.
Bekah: dry ice is really fun. You
can do. My dad was a pharmacist.
I remember like sometimes he
would bring home dry ice. I like
something shipped in it. I'm
like, this is the coolest thing
ever. I'll just go with dry ice.
I'm gonna have an unlimited
supply of dry ice. I'm that's
what I'm
Dan: Alright, well, you'll
have lots of, well steam or,
well, that's not really steam, is
it? It's?
Julia: It, the, the chemical
process is called sublimation.
Dan: Yeah, but what is the thing
called? The
Julia: it's steam. It's when a
solid
Dan: Okay. It is team. Okay.
Yeah. All right. Cool. Hi, I
am Dan. I do stuff. I I am a
independent, computer person,
developer guy. Yeah, if I'm
Cleveland and, yeah, I think,
time is what I'm going with.
That would be the thing that
Bekah: Oh, that's not fair.
That's
Dan: Listen, it's not food.
That's only, that was the only
rule. All right, fine. Uh
Julia: time is infinite. Dan,
Dan: Hmm. But I don't have an
infant supply of it. See,
Bekah: you want free time. That's
what you're asking for.
Dan: I want more time.
Julia: you wanna look forever?
Dan: No, no, that doesn't
either. Yeah, no, no, no.
alright fine. How about, can
I sell the thing? it,
Julia: Sure.
Dan: can I do, I mean,
Bekah: No drugs. sell
Dan: Can I do money? Nothing
illegal. What is this? You're
putting all these rules in didn't
exist. Gold. One of those
things called. Doubloons. Yep.
That's it. like a pirate and then
I'll sell 'em when I need more
money and, infinite supply.
Yeah. It's the most practical way
to transport gold. Yeah. And,
you know, I could fill up a pool
and go swimming in it.
Scrooge McDuck style. I could
sell them, you know, when I
needed more money for things, I
could probably make jewelry out
of them. Doubloons, you know,
is, you know,
Bekah: Just for reference. We are
recording this a Thursday Eastern
in afternoon. We are not even
like,
Julia: No, one's
Dan: I, I went home for lunch
just before this and, opened
my fridge to get a soda.
Definitely took a hard look at
the beer I chose not to today,
but, I, I, I was like, it's
been that kind of week. I, I, I
took a look at it. So I
decided to but I actually got my
first, like full night sleep last
night in, I don't know, at least
a
Bekah: oh, your brain doesn't
know what to do with itself.
Dan: I know, I know have lots of
energy today, so anyway, me and
my gold doubloons, are gonna, you
know, what we're gonna do.
Bekah: Good luck, Julia. It's.
Julia: Yeah, I have a lot of
thoughts now. My name's Julia
side, I am, I don't know. I
guess I call my lately. I've been
calling myself a developer
educator. I'm kind of mainly
what I do is I work with API
companies to create sample apps
and getting started guides and
tutorials, and generally help
them like improve their developer
experience, with specifically
like with an eye towards
onboarding new developers, but
also like trying to create
content that inspires.
Creativity. So I write code,
and I write about code and
yeah. I, if I had an
unlimited supply of something, so
I was gonna say sunscreen because
I compulsively buy sunscreen,
like in enormous quantities.
Every time I see it, I'm like,
oh, I should probably buy more
sunscreen. But I don't ever
actually remember to use it. And
I'm imagining that if I had an
unlimited supply that just like
materialized, then maybe I would
actually remember to use the
sunblock and I would stop
spending so much money on
sunblock that doesn't get used.
But then I thought. There are
rare earth metals that are much
more valuable per ounce gold. And
if I'm allowed sell the thing and
especially if I could like have
rare earth metals without the
environmental costs of mining
them and like the like child
labor costs of mining them and
all of that, then, then that's
that that'd be really good. So I
think I'm not sure which rare
earth metal I have to do my
research. But yeah, that's
what I'm thinking.
Dan: of another answer,
energy. That'd be my, that was my
one. Yeah. Cause I could sell
that too honestly. But I
could also, you know power, all
Bekah: I was
Dan: all BA my battery things
Bekah: get the day. You're
Dan: oh, personal energy. Oh no,
no, no. I meant like,
Bekah: energy.
Dan: you, yeah, well, you know,
not doesn't have to be
electricity, just energy, you
know, I can convert it into
electricity if I want, I can
convert it into, probably
other things,
Bekah: it make you fast?
Dan: Well, no, probably could
power a thing that fast. You
know, you know, so yeah,
that's, that's it that's gotta be
the real answer. I, I, do wanna
know where these things come
from, you know, cuz because
it's like unlimited supply,
Bekah: unlimited
Dan: well is it not, is it
unlimited supply? I mean, yeah.
Does it mean like you were asking
about this too? Does it just like
one appear when you need it? Or
is it like
Julia: Yeah.
Dan: I mean it's a, know, it has
be like that.
Bekah: Yeah. That's what I was
imagining a closet of
Dan: Yeah. Cool. Yeah. So they
don't yes. Nobody's mining them
or, or, or making this unblock or
whatever
Julia: Yeah.
Dan: yeah,
Julia: As far as I know,
manufacturing, sunblock is not
like
Dan: We need Kirk on this.
Julia: environmentally costly,
but.
Dan: I
Bekah: that should be our last
episode of the season should just
be Kirk questions that we answer.
Dan: Oh man, Kirk, if he was
there for that would just have an
aneurysm, I think by the end of
it.
Bekah: So, if you are
listening and you have not
experienced a Kirk question, when
we do these questions before
every Virtual Coffee, Kirk has
been coming up with some,
some doozies, I, I guess you can
label them where it, leaves a
lot of room for interpretation
and requires you to think outside
of the box, which is a rabbit
hole for most of us.
Julia: Yeah. I hold a little
bit of blame potentially. I don't
know. In that one time in the
co-working room, I pulled out a
copy of, would you rather
questions year olds? And
there have been a few that were
inspired by would you rather for
eight year olds,
Bekah: Is that a book?
Julia: it's a book.
Bekah: Oh, oh,
Dan: Mmm,
Julia: have them for seven year
olds, eight year olds, nine year
olds. I don't what the difference
is, but
Dan: right. I'm writing that
down.
Bekah: kid has a birthday in a
couple weeks. He's about to be
eight and he would love that. So
guess don't, this will come out
after his birthday. So in case he
listens, it will not spoiled.
I think this is the record for
our longest intro ever.
Julia: sorry.
Bekah: no, don't be sorry. It was
all Dan's fault.
Dan: no.
Julia: I even held back on a
about gold doubloons,
Bekah: you have a
Dan: now I,
Julia: not actually about gold
doubloons, it's about gold
krugerrands, which, so it was the
currency in South Africa. Like,
I don't know, historically,
I'm not sure when they stopped
using them, but they are, I guess
they, they were kind of popular
among like people doing like
black market kind of stuff,
pre-internet age. And we had
a super corrupt governor in
Connecticut when I was growing up
named John Roland. And, one
of John Roland had like a couple
of cronies in my hometown and,
one of his. I don't know,
partners in crime was the father
of one of my sister's classmates.
And, he, he was arrested
while my sister was in high
school. And I, in my mind,
they actually caught him in the
act of burying gold krugerrands
in his backyard. I don't know
that they actually caught him in
the act, but for sure, my sister
went to high school with someone
who was, whose father was
arrested and found to have
hundreds of thousands of dollars
of like illegal south African
gold coins buried in his
backyard. So
Dan: that is incredible. that.
This is about. It's so much of a
better story than if you just had
like cash buried in his
Julia: Oh, totally. Well, there
was that guy from Louisiana who
had cash in his freezer. This
guy, way more
Dan: One and a half Yeah. They're
like this quarter, like a little
bit bigger than an American
quarter, I suppose.
Julia: Are you looking it up?
Dan: I'm looking at 'em on
Wikipedia. So by, 1980, they
accounted for more than 90% of
the global coin market. And was
the number one choice for
investors buying gold.
Julia: yeah,
Dan: you go. they're not though
Julia: you know,
Bekah: This is where we need
sound effects for like the more,
you know, is that, how it goes?
Dan: Um,
Bekah: We
Dan: I don't have that one. All I
have is
Bekah: that is
Dan: that's all,
Bekah: not, not what we're not
the I was going for.
Dan: so these are cool, but
yeah, doubloons, I feel like I
need them to be bigger and
thicker, you know,
Bekah: So you
Dan: mean? Why you could wear 'em
you could do, you know, you what
I.
Julia: Like they're a lot more
portable than like a big brick
Dan: Oh, I get it. I mean, I
understand practically, like
these are good for crime and
stuff, you know,
Bekah: These are good for.
Dan: for my thing, you know, this
is why I want, if I have an
unlimited supply, I'd rather
just, you know, know what I mean?
If I change my mind later, I can
just melt 'em down and make
Krugerrands with them. Well, that
was our.
Julia: think.
Bekah: I'm gonna, there's no
segue here. So thanks for coming
on the podcast, Julia, we like to
get started with your origin
story and maybe that's where it
starts with gold coins and
backyards. But give us your,
your story of how you came to
this point in your tech.
Julia: Only. So I, I,
when I was in college, I,
well, so when I was in college,
I double majored in
anthropology and comparative
religion, which is not useful
in any commonly known sense of
the word. But I had a, I had
a, a Dean who I knew pre she
was actually, well anyway, I knew
her pretty well, and we were
talking one time and she said
something about how she had had a
cur, she had decided to embrace
the Korean over the career. And I
just really liked that phrase and
idea, like, and, and I would say
that. That's kind of what I
aspire to is like, I, I can't
plan. I'm no good at committing
to any like long term vision, but
what I am good at is rolling with
the punches and like just kind of
seeing where things go. So,
after college, I bounced around
for a few years, working in as a
professional fundraiser as,
an events coordinator really
briefly as a recruiter. And
then, I spent like about four
years working in finance,
which was just a total, like, I
just stumbled into the job. They
had hired somebody else who went
to the same college and they were
like, Ugh, Let's hire her. Let's
see how it goes. And, I, so I
really liked it in some ways.
really liked that the sort of the
analytical work. I liked that I
was learning a lot because I had
no background in finance. I
did a lot of writing while I was
there. And if I kind of look back
at like, what's the theme, in my,
in my Korean, what I would say is
that I, what I, what I do over
the long arc, I learn about
things. And then I write about
them. So at that phase, I was
learning about finance and
writing about finance
simultaneously. And that was
great for a few years. But
then in 2000, Fall of 2008,
winter of 2009. I don't remember.
I, I don't know if other people
remember this time as acutely as
I do. I live in Seattle, WAMU
collapsed. I worked in finance,
everything else collapsed. We had
people being taken to the ER in
the middle of the work day
because they thought they were
having heart attacks, but it was
actually just panic attacks.
It was such an intensely
stressful time that I was like,
peace. I am, I am out here. I do
not wanna work in this world
anymore. No one is happy. And
so I did, I went back to school
and did something that was
probably as far in the opposite
direction as you could go. And I
became a high school English
teacher. I did that for.
About 10 years. And then just
kind of got exhausted by the, I
don't know, the vagaries of
working in public education.
and it's another story for
another day, but I worked at a
very high pressure in a very high
income, high pressure community.
And, I was really not happy
with like the way that my
students lives were being shaped.
So when my second child was
born, I was like, you know, I'm
gonna take a break and I took a
year off and it felt really good.
And so I took another year off.
And during that second year, I
started learning how to code.
I started kind of more with data
science because of having that
finance background. But along
the way, kind of stumbled my way
through various things. And I did
a bootcamp. I did some
self-taught stuff. I did some
internships. I did a, an kind
of a incubator program. And
then stumbled my way once again,
into this role that I'm in now,
doing developer education. So
once again, I'm learning about
things and then I'm writing about
them. So yeah, that's, that's
my origin story. And I think it's
good because I finally found
something where like, there's
really no limit on how much I can
learn. and I have a ton of
control over who I work with and
when I work and all of that, and
the people that I am teaching
through my work really wanna
learn they are intrinsically
motivated and that's that's cool.
Yeah, so that's me.
Bekah: that makes such a
difference when people are
motivated to learn.
Julia: it's huge. And like you
get that sometimes in K-12
education, right? Like I'm, I
don't know. I'm sure we all had
times in our education where we
were really genuinely motivated
by something, but there's just so
much else going on that. I don't
know. don't love it.
Bekah: Right, Right, That's I
mean, my background's in
education. I taught college
English for 10 years and it was a
lot of core classes, which means
people had to take those classes.
It an option. Most of them did
not wanna be there. Didn't see
the point of it. Weren't
motivated. And like, to the point
of being aggressively unmotivated
and like about things, I'm like,
this is not. why I signed up to
and like the rare occasion, I
would be able to teach,
like a special interest class. I
taught a screenwriting class once
I had eight or 10 students. It
was the best experience. I loved
that because everybody was
excited about being there and
talking about those things.
but those experiences are not as
frequent
Julia: no, no. They're not. Yeah.
And it, I mean, the people who
stick with it and do it for a
long time and I mean, I have
enormous respect, but, I also
don't at all, judge, anyone who
opts out because it can be pretty
demoralizing.
Bekah: Yeah. And I think that, I
don't know if it's a generational
thing or not, but I know my
parents stayed in careers
forever. And a lot of the people
around us, who are in the
same generation, they spent their
entire careers, you know, doing
one thing. But I see more people
now maybe just cuz I'm older
changing careers and, not having
to be stuck doing something that
you're not interested in doing is
really important to me. So I know
like I would talk to somebody
else about a career in tech and I
was like, I don't know if I'll be
here five years or not. She she's
the same thing. Like, yeah. I
don't know if I will either. I
kind of hope I'm not like there
are lots of options out there in
finding, exploring those things
that keep you interested, I think
helps you to, I dunno, be
motivated in all areas of your
life.
Julia: Mm-hmm Yeah. And that's
something like when I kind of
made the transition into tech, I
was pretty explicit in saying
like, it's not that I think I'm
gonna be writing code all day
every day for the rest of my
life. This is a skill, a.
It's a skill and like a
discipline that can feed other
kinds of growth that can enable
me to get involved in, in
different things. And I, I think
initially I thought of it more as
a skill. And now I would say it's
really is more of like a
discipline. Like there's not one
skill that, that anybody learns
except maybe. And, and I think
that this is part of like, what
has helped make me successful in
the time that I've been working
in tech? Maybe the skill is
just learning how to learn.
Like, and I think that that's
like, if I of what I'm good at,
like I'm good at learning about
stuff and that's, I think
probably the most essential.
Skill, otherwise, like, it's not
like you could say like, oh, I
have a skill in writing
JavaScript. Like that's not, I
mean, there is skill, but it
changes. And really the skill is
a, is about like habits of mind.
And, I don't know.
Bekah: I love that. And I think
I, I also always struggle with
people asking me what my career
goals are. And I think that's for
like a lot of this reason, I
don't really have career goals.
Like I'm interested in, you know,
connecting other people. And like
you said, like learning new
things. And so for me, it's not
like, oh, I wanna be a senior
blah, blah, blah, someday. You
know, I just wanna keep doing
things that I'm interested in and
helping to support other people,
you know, feel part of something.
Julia: mm-hmm I mean, I think
it's cool when people. Have those
aspirations to,
Bekah: Yeah. I think that's
totally fine. I just think that
there are so many different
career paths and ways to approach
what you're doing. That like,
acknowledging that I'm interested
in learning or learning new
things. Now that's a really great
place to be.
Julia: mm-hmm ,mm-hmm
Bekah: So let's back up a little
bit and talk about what your
work, what you do for work.
Julia: sure.
Bekah: to give, like more of
a zoomed in idea of what you're
doing daily, or, you know, how
the projects get chosen that
you're working on and talk
through some of the things that
you like about that.
Julia: okay. so I'll just talk
about what I'm working on right
now, cuz I think that's a good
sort of snapshot right now I
have three main projects that I'm
working on three different
clients, three different sort of
types of work. One is
like an API tooling company,
and I am a frequent contributor
to their technical blog. So I
just wrote a three part series on
authentication and authorization
and an authentication best
practices for APIs. So I'm not
writing code when I'm doing that,
but I'm doing a lot of in depth,
technical research, reading code,
reading. You know, reading
documentation from different,
I don't know, different solutions
providers. I did an SME
interview as part of that with a
senior engineer who oversees some
of their security stuff at, at
that, at my client company.
And then writing those articles,
like for a technical audience
writing for API developers to
say, like, here's how to approach
the decision making process. And
that was one of the things that I
try to do as a writer and like
part of why they keep bringing me
back there is that there's a lot
of repetitive content out there.
So if you look up like API
security, best practices, you're
gonna see a lot of articles that
say essentially the same thing.
Anytime you look up anything
to do with GWT, Jos, Jos JSUN web
tokens, the first hits are
the same, like it's, everything
is so SEO optimized, like,
and what I try to do is to take a
point of view. That's a little
bit more about like, okay,
there's a lot of options. There's
not a best option. How do we come
up with a decision making
framework? Like how do you, as a
developer, as a, you know, as a
team lead a product architect,
whatever, how do you approach the
decision making process of like,
what's the best option for me?
So. That's kind of part of
what that series is about, and
I've done things like that on
other aspects of API design for
them. So that's one thing and
that's kind of the least
technical part of what I do.
Then right now I'm working with
two other clients. One, is,
they have a GraphQL API that
coordinates the APIs for like
maybe, I don't know, just
estimating 40 different brands of
I T devices. So like your SL
smart locks or your Phillips hue,
light bulbs, or your eco B
thermostat or whatever, each of
those has its own API and its own
app. And. As a homeowner, you can
use like Google home or whatever,
but let's say that you were like
an apartment building
superintendent and you wanted to
be able to manage all of the
smart devices in your buildings
from one place. Instead of all of
those places, they make an API
that coordinates all of those
things. And, so I, but right
now, most of their documentation
is very like marketing. Oriented.
They it's like, they've been very
focused on just like onboarding
their first few significant
customers. And the, and their
technical onboarding has been
like super intensive, custom,
like hand holding. And I we're,
I'm involved in helping to
transition them away from that,
like creating more standard
documentation for like those
getting started guides. So how to
build a node app that allows you
to control all of your smart
locks, how to build an, you know,
and then eventually like
integrating all of these
different things in there, but
also along the way, explaining,
like, why is this a GraphQL API
instead of rest, why do we insist
on you using. A specific
authentication protocol. And,
and there are technical reasons
that they do all of those things
that have to do with coordinating
between 40 different APIs. So
the content that I'm creating for
them, some of it is just creating
these sample apps and kind of
documenting the nitty gritty of
those apps. And then some of
it is the more in depth
explanations of like the why,
of how it works. And that's
been really cool because I've
gotten to learn a lot about these
different aspects of it. Plus I
think IOT is really interesting.
We have. Everything in our house
is smart, is like a smart device.
And, it frustrates me that
they don't talk to each other
very well it's yeah, I
think it's cool. I just, it's a
really exciting, interesting
project to be working on. And
the engineers who work at this
company are like, they are, they
know their stuff. Like they are
very smart people, creative,
analytical people. So it's been
really neat working with them.
And then my other client that
I'm working on right now working
with right now, this one is like
simultaneously an example of what
I do and really, really, really
do not like about my current
role. So this is a company who
makes a player and engagement.
API for game developers. So, you
know, sending push notifications
and rewards, you know, in game
stuff. And, I'm creating a
lot of the same kind of like
getting started guides.
Because again, like they, their
existing documentation sort of
assumes that you already know
what this thing does and roughly
how to use it. Like maybe you've
already been using a competitor
product and you're just switching
over. And so it's, it's not gonna
be any challenge to, but they're
hoping to expand and, and kind of
make themselves more accessible
to a broader audience of game
developers. So. To do this,
to create the content that they
want. I have had to learn how to
work with game code. And
Bekah: Oh, right.
Julia: I, it's just, it's not all
the same. it's like the
transition from working with a
rest API to a GraphQL API in node
is no big deal. Right. The
transition from working with one
authentication protocol to
another in.net is no big deal,
but changing this entire
framework and way of thinking
about, project architecture
has been really, really difficult
for me. And it's just not easy to
troubleshoot and it's, yeah,
it's been interesting. I mean,
it's cool to be learning and
working on something so radically
different. And I hope
eventually I'll be able to create
some content for them that's
useful and meaningful, but,
it is definitely something where
I'm like, oh, there has gotta be
somebody else out there who's
better qualified to do this. it's
sure not me. But it's kind of
the nature of like, there're just
there, aren't an enormous number
of companies that do what our
company does. And I I'm
technically a freelancer, but I
almost, all my work right now is
through, is through an agency.
And there just aren't that many
agencies that do what we do. And
we had a sales guy for a little
while, while who was. Maybe
overselling our technical
expertise or like overselling the
idea that, you know, developers
could learn anything and you
know, in no time flat yeah.
Yeah. But so that's, that's the
kind of thing, like a I'm I don't
know. Does that answer, is that a
good
Bekah: Yeah, this is great. I
mean, you really broke down a lot
of different things. Do you get
to choose the projects and the
companies that you work with or
does the agency assign you?
Julia: So when I first started
working with them, it was really
just like kind of one off
freelance stuff. And over the
course of a couple years, Well
over the course of a year, you
know, I, I took on a variety of
different projects and at first
they were like pretty targeted to
stuff I already knew and stuff I
had already worked on. And then
gradually they started kind of
pulling me in on more stuff and
saying, Hey, would you be
interested in this? Would you be
interested in this? And
eventually I think that they
realized like, oh, Hey, Julia is
a person who is happy to learn
new stuff, happy to take on
challenging clients. So, I
I'm now like I'm a 10 99, but
I'm, I'm the staff writer at, at
the agency. And I mean, I kind of
get the clients that are too
difficult to give off
freelancers. So like I kinda get
to choose. I was. You know,
at some point they asked me like,
Hey, would you wanna work on this
crypto thing? And I was like, no,
not really. So, I mean, I do get
some input. And that first
client that I was talking about
is one where I did a few pieces
for them. They really liked it. I
was in some meetings with them. I
really liked them. And so I've
gotten, I've been able to say,
Hey, I really like working with
them. Like, I've got ideas. Let
me let, can, you know, can I take
on more of that relationship? But
yeah,
Bekah: So, so with the ideas, do
they come in, does the company
come in with ideas or they have
like a general, do you define.
Julia: do our, our, I have a fly
in here. Our principal
consultant, when, when we
onboard a new client, Does a
process that they call the,
the dis the developer content
action plan. So they do like a
developer content review where
they say like, here are the gaps
in your existing documentation.
This is what developers want to
see. This is, you know, this is,
these are your areas of strength.
And, and they, we have kind of a,
you know, a rubric, and then
they come up with a, an action
plan based on that content gap
analysis. So it's a collaborative
process for sure. And the
longer I've been with the agency,
like the more I've been able to
be involved in that process.
Yeah. So it it's a mix, right?
Sometimes clients have wacky
ideas about what they want.
And then we have some clients
who've been clients for a long
time where we've moved past, like
that content gap. And it's more
like, Hey, we would love to have,
you know, this more kind of off
the wall piece. Like I did a
piece for Algolia around black
Friday last year, that was like
an instant inventory. It was
like, how can you use Algolia to
like, manage your black Friday
sales? And they said, you
know, this is something we think
will like kind of republish every
year leading up to black Friday.
So, you know, it's like that
kind of thing where it's more
like, I don't know,
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. That's fun.
What? Okay, so you've done,
you've really broken down a lot
of the, the stuff that I was
interested in hearing about,
which is great. Like there are
some really fun parts. There are
some parts that are not so fun or
kind of challenging are, there
any, so I would say it sounds
like the part that you like the
most is being able to learn new
things, but it also seems pretty
fun to be able to develop. Those
deeper relationships with the
clients too, that.
Julia: And, I, I really, I
like that. I've been able to
recently kind of develop these
more in depth relationships with
clients. It's a mixed bag
though, because the consultant
client relationship is, as I'm
sure you both know, not always
the easiest relationship to
navigate. And as a contractor
with my agency, like, I'm always
kind of like a little on guard
about like, oh my God, I, I'm not
even an employee of this company.
Exactly. Like if I say the wrong
thing and like upset this client,
like, ah, you know, it's my butt
on the line. And our, our
principal consultant is like an
amazing guy. but it's just not,
it's not the same as like a.
Being part of the same team, like
that manager relationship where
like, like, I don't know, I just,
there's always this like added
level of stress in conversations
with clients where I'm like, oh,
I really hope I don't say the
wrong thing. But I do like it
and I think that like, whatever
the next move is in my career,
I, I wanna have it be
something where I have more
depth,
Bekah: Hmm.
Julia: more depth in my
relationships with people, but
also like more depth in working
with a, a more focused tech
stack, because it does get pretty
exhausting, like just bouncing
from one thing to another and
kind of feeling like. I never
work with any one thing long
enough to really have any
mastery. And like, I know I'm
learning cuz when I come back to
stuff later, like I can achieve
more complex results and I can
work faster and I can
troubleshoot better. But like I
don't ever feel, I, I never
exactly feel competent.
Bekah: Yeah.
Julia: and that's kinda tough
sometimes.
Dan: get that. I mean, like
digging in all the way into
something can feel good. You
know, I was gonna make some joke
about how that's like, just being
a JavaScript in general, where
everything's always new and
changing, you but,
Julia: That's
Dan: then it's.
Julia: an industry wide
phenomenon.
Dan: Right, but still, I mean, I,
you know, I still have been doing
rack for like years, you know,
and it's like, I actually know it
like pretty well. You know what I
mean? And
Julia: Yeah. And it's like, you
know, earlier this spring I was
working on this kind of
complicated.net sequel thing, and
then I'm working in unity and I
have to learn Xcode and how to do
iOS development. And also on the
side, I'm working with GraphQL
and like, it's like, I just, I
mean, I really bounce around a
lot and occasionally they'll be
like, do you know, angular? And
I'm like, oh, that's the GraphQL
client. We're all in agreement.
That the next thing, the next
deliverable is for me to do
something in flutter. And I'm
like, oh, for Christ's sake,
Dan: Yeah, you were, I saw, you
mentioned that on slack. I don't
even know what fluter is really,
what
Julia: it's, it's a
mobile framework, so it's like a,
but it's so,
Dan: apps.
Julia: yeah. But it's,
Dan: I could look it up.
Bekah: it seems like a react
native competitor. Am I
Julia: it's a react native
competitor. It, I can't remember
what the big advantage is.
Overreact native.
Bekah: I've heard a lot of react.
Native people say there's no
advantage.
Dan: well, react native is really
annoying. So if this is
better than, you I've just
started my first react. I just
started digging to react native
for the first time, like a month
or two ago. And I'm I'm phase.
Julia: And the, and the idea is
that like, like react native
it's, it's like device
agnostic. Like it's not like
writing an iOS app or
Dan: Right, right. Wants,
published anywhere kind of thing.
Yeah.
Julia: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I mean, starting from
scratch, I in a, like a big way,
like that is, is hard. You know,
I was, I was just thinking in my
head, I was just like outlining a
blog post about like how I
learned things, you know, from
scratch, you know, and like the
bigger it is, like the it's just
like you were talking about the
game app, right? The like,
the further away from what you're
used to it is the harder it is. I
mean, like, that's an like
obvious statement, but it's like,
it's, it's much more for me. It's
much more exhausting too and
takes longer, but it's also like
harder you know, you know what I
mean? Like it's not just a
simple, oh, it just takes two
days instead of half an hour. If
it's, you know, some package or
whatever, you know,
Julia: Well, it's like, you know,
we
Dan: eh, it's hard
Julia: we're all, all like the
idea that it's hard to estimate
how long things will take is
obviously well known phenomenon.
But when you don't know anything,
Dan: Yeah.
Julia: it's impossible to
estimate.
Dan: Oh, I mean,
Julia: probably roughly estimate
how long it'll take me to like,
write something in flutter,
because I read about it and I was
like, oh, okay. This is not
radically different than anything
I've done before. But with game
development, it's like, oh, GE
like this is, you know, there's
just reams of files that I'm
like, I have no idea what any of
these do.
Dan: Yeah.
Julia: you know, I don't know.
It's just, and yeah, I'm, I'm
a terrible jaw clincher, like I
just all day, every day and. Over
the last few months as I've been
working on this, like these few
particularly difficult projects,
I, I actually went to the dentist
and I was like, you have to help.
I'm going crazy. So that's why I
now sugar free, worth original.
I'm like an 80 year old diabetic.
I suck on sugar free where
there's original all day. Cause
it me punching my teeth.
Bekah: that's interesting. My
dentist me to my chiropractor to
have my jaw adjusted. That is one
of like the most awkward,
uncomfortable adjustments that I
have had. But I am also a jaw
clincher and it was causing my
tooth to grow thickening roots
that were starting to protrude in
my gums.
Julia: yeah, yeah, no, that's
what I like. we don't need to get
into my oral health.
Dan: You mentioned the, you
know, estimating and all that
stuff. And I, I actually, like, I
was been wondering about this
since you talked about it,
especially since you're a
contractor, how, like how it
works, what, like your
arrangement. I mean, you get an
assignment of writing an article
about something that you don't
know about yet. And so like, how
does that, how does that break
down? How does, how does what's
the process of like, cause cuz if
I have a project, you know, maybe
I try to estimate it or something
and there's always unknowns, but
with writing assignments, lot of
times it's, there's other, you
know, it's per pagers. Like
there's like, there's lots of
different ways. And so is it
just. You kind of treat it like a
software project and estimate
hourly and deliver a at the end.
Julia: process, the writing
process doesn't really take me
that much time. So like, if I'm
writing that I already
understand. Really well, or just
like a very simple API where I
just wanna show like very basic,
like here's, here's how to call
it the first time. I know
very well, how long that'll take
me, like the writing process?
Just, it's just, it's like, as, I
don't know, the, so one of the
differences is when I was working
before I kind of got brought in
house as a staff writer, then I
was paid by piece. And it was
a standard rate. And the
pieces that I was getting were
pretty standardized, at the
point that. It started getting
more complex, where it was like,
Hey, stuff's coming back to me
from the client, like asking me
for a lot of revisions that like
were not in scope you know, then
it was like, we have a
conversation about changing how
I'm compensated? Because this is
not, this is not standard now.
I'm paid a, a monthly
retainer and our project manager
sort of, I com I communicate with
her about like where I'm at on
different stuff. And we kind of
scale how, how much I take on
just based on how long things are
taking. So,
Dan: Yeah. Nice.
Julia: yeah. Yeah. It's not,
it's, it's pretty, it's pretty
flexible. They had expectations.
When I came on board as a staff
writer that turned out to be like
really wacky, but everybody
realized it very quickly, like. I
cannot produce 10 articles a
month if I have to learn an
entirely new framework for every
single article.
Bekah: don't know if anybody can
produce 10 articles a month.
Like, that's just a lot of,
Julia: Yeah. I mean, I could do
10, if they're all just like,
Dan: It's stuff you already know,
Julia: yeah. 500 words on,
Dan: Yeah.
Julia: you know,
Dan: No, that's cool.
Julia: why you should have docs
for your API. I'm good. I could
write a lot of those, but,
yeah. It's I don't know. It's
interesting though. I think I was
talking about this with you
recently. Bekah like feeling kind
of like, I do think I'm underpaid
maybe because I think that the
amount that I actually get done.
Is probably on par with somebody
who's a full-time employee.
But I'm paid as a part-time 10 99
employee because I don't have
this sort of like official role
in the organization. The
upside is I have very few
meetings which I love. But
it's also harder to kind of, I, I
don't, it's hard for me to really
like, figure out. What like
what my compensation should be,
because I don't really know how,
like my role compares to somebody
who's in house somewhere.
Although I will say I interviewed
for a role somewhere recently
where they said something like,
oh, our full-time writers, right.
About four articles a month. And
I was like, what? Oh, okay. I
could do that very easily.
but
Dan: Well, no, I mean, that's,
that's, I mean, yeah, it's gotta
be tough, but like the, I, you
know, I was thinking about this
when you were. Talking about the
like actual different articles
you were writing. And you know,
some of the thought processes
you're explaining are complex
things, right. That, that, that
are targeted towards more senior
developers. Right. You're not
writing the, you're not being
asked to write the like, sort of
super, I mean, maybe you are, but
like
Julia: yeah. On.
Dan: of times you're not writing
the super intro basic stuff or
the SEO, you know, fodder stuff.
Right.
Julia: No. Right. And that's
something that we like as a
company like, listen, we're,
we'll like try to make the stuff
that we write reasonably
optimized, SEO wise, but that's
not what we're here for. Like, we
are not here to like, you know,
just create fluff content. Like
we want content that actually
engages developers for the long
term. And there is definitely
like, you have to be
discoverable. And some of
that is like identifying search
terms that just have really low
results volume. So. For example,
just recently, it was like, we
noticed that there's very few
results for the search phrase,
JSON payload. And so we went to
one of our clients and we're
like, can we write something on
this term? Like it's relevant to
you. And like it's relevant to
developers. People are searching
for it. And there's not that much
content. But it's based on
the idea that like, people are
searching for this because they
want information, not like
they're searching for it. And so
like let's, let's create the
fluff. I think so the, the
principal of our, the principal
consultant is, he wrote a
book called developer marketing
does not exist, which I think is
kind of a goofy title. That was a
face of recognition. Bekah do you
know the book?
Bekah: Yes. It's I don't know who
recommended it to me. It's
definitely on my list of books
that I should.
Julia: Yeah. He's and the
idea is basically like, if
developers feel like they're
being marketed to, like, they're
not gonna, nobody wants that.
Like, I wanna know that a product
is gonna actually solve my
problem. I wanna know that like,
if I start using something, I'm
gonna be fully supported in my
journey as a technical user. And
so like, the content that we're
creating is really geared towards
that developer experience of
like, okay, great. You made it to
our website, you signed, you
know, you signed up for your free
trial account. Are you gonna
actually be able to get stuff
done? And are you gonna feel
successful and empowered by the
content that you find here?
Or are you gonna feel like you're
being. You know, told exactly how
to do it. And if you wanna do
anything different, you have
absolutely no idea to make it
work. Yeah. I can't remember
what you said that made me just
that, but
Dan: I was just talking about
the, yeah, I was talking about
how, the content you're
writing is, is, is, talking
about some high level concepts
and, you know,
Julia: oh yeah, yeah,
Dan: it was mostly just mostly
just like you're operating on
like a senior developer level,
you know, and you were talking
about competition before, and
that's what made me start talking
about this, you know, but,
like the,
Julia: then the hard part of the
hard thing for me is like, I
really genuinely love what I do
and that actually makes it harder
for me to like fight for the
compensation
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I hear that.
Julia: with the fact that right
now, like I work from 10 to three
roughly. Sometimes I work a
little in the evenings. Sometimes
I get started a little earlier in
the morning, but like, I really
only work like 20, 25 hours a
week.
Dan: Yeah.
Julia: And I'm, I just, I know
that like taking a full-time job,
like the difference that
additional 10 to 15 hours a week
is just gonna be meetings and
like annoying emails. And like, I
don't like, am I willing to take
less money to not deal with that
stuff? Like, and have the
flexibility, my schedule, like,
yeah.
Dan: I mean, if really, really
wanted or needed more money, you
could pick up more clients too.
Like that's the beauty of being
independent. So you can do,
Julia: I could. And, I do,
you know, I toy it with that but
Dan: or just raise your rates.
You know, it's all, it's all,
good Just send up an email.
That'll be fine.
Julia: yeah, It's true. I have
such anxiety about, I think I
better deliver a couple of
successful projects on these two
nightmare clients. Before I for
Dan: Say now that I am a game
developer, this is my new rate.
Julia: game developers are paid
Dan: Now that I'm a flutter
developer, this is my new rate.
Julia: Developers are like
hideously underpaid,
Dan: Well, now that I'm
Bekah: An angular developer.
Dan: I'll write it for you. To
whom it may concern.
Julia: it's interesting. The
whole game development world is
like its own.
Dan: don't know anything about
it. Yeah. far separated from It
is weird. Like you think about
it, cuz I, you know, I get a lot
of overlap. I mean obviously most
of my overlap is with other web
developers in different
technologies, but even so
there's, I don't know anybody
does game develop it, you know,
it's like, and I know a lot of
developers and
Julia: Yeah. I mean, I've lived
in Seattle for 17 years. Like
I've know people at so many
different tech companies, I know
recruiters all over the place.
And at one point I was, somebody
had expressed an interest in
working for a game company and I
was like, well, I'll reach out.
But like, it was like, you know,
one person was like, well, I, I
know that the VP of HR at wizards
of the coast, but that's about as
close as I can get. I was like,
well, I don't think that's quite
what we're looking for.
Bekah: Well, Julia, this has been
a really great conversation and,
but it is. Time to wrap it
up. So is there any last words of
wisdom you have for our listeners
or, things you want them to,
you think they would benefit from
learning about.
Julia: I don't, I was
talking with David Albert a
couple weeks ago, and we were
talking about the idea that like
was after I gave the lunch and
learn about feedback. We were
talking about the idea that like
giving feedback, being mentor of
some kind formal or informal.
sort of an intrinsic part of your
responsibility in, in the tech
industry. And I, I think it's
a really, it's something I think
about a fair amount that like,
you know, I don't necessarily
have like a huge wealth of
technical experience. I
haven't been in the industry that
long, but I think it's just
really important for everybody to
remember that like you have
valuable experience and knowledge
and skills and insight, and you
know, all of us are always
learning and we should all always
be teaching as well. And
that's not, that's not like to
say that you need to be. You
know, giving formal instruction
on something, but that, like, we
all benefit from people sharing
what they know, sharing their
perspectives. You may not be
an expert in anything, but you're
an expert in being yourself.
Right. you know, and it's like, I
talking with somebody who has a
lot of experience in, in like,
tech support. And I was like,
listen, you may not think of
yourself this way, but you are a
UX expert. Like, you know, more
about actual user experience than
like almost anybody. If you've
worked in tech support for three
years or whatever, like you have
so much hands on knowledge and
insight into how people use
technology. Share that like, but
also like before you can share
it, you have to actually reflect
on it and try to like give it
some framework. And I think
that that's something I've really
been trying to do. Myself is
like, I know that I know things,
how can I put them in a framework
that allows me to share them with
other people? So yeah, we're
all always learning. We also
should all always be teaching and
I think that's, I know. Yeah,
Bekah: I love that. That's so
great. And what a great way to
end this episode. So thanks so
much, Julia, for being with us.
We, we had a great
Julia: absolutely. My
Dan: Julia. Also I looked
that up and the most expensive,
precious metal is rhodium. So if
you are going that direction,
rhodium is gonna be where you're
going. I've never heard of it
Julia: rhodium. Well, I know.
Jewelry is plated,
Dan: That's cause
Julia: but
Dan: cuz it's fancy. I don't, I
don't know.
Bekah: I don't believe you.
Dan: it's used for, oh, it's very
reflective. So it's used in
search lights, mirrors and
jewelry. I think it's mostly just
that it's rare. I don't know.
Anyway, that's it. all I got. All
right. Cool. Well thank you,
Julia. This is great. Well, I had
the tab open from, before and
then I, I forgot about it. I
didn't wanna. Okay. Julia.
Julia: Thank you.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week!