Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season six, episode seven of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey, and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned,
and we are here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan: What Wuddup Bek? How's it
going?
Bekah: It is. It is going well.
How's it going with?
Dan: It's going okay. Um, yeah,
we have a great episode today. We
met with Ryan Con, uh, who has
done a lot of things through his
career. He was a teacher, he's a
developer, and, uh, now Ryan is a
consultant who comes and helps
teams improve their collaboration
and their communication skills.
Bekah: I loved how Ryan talked
about the importance of
empathizing with your teammates.
And treating each person as an
individual human being who makes
up your team. I think that that's
a really great approach in order
to, you know, empower your team
to do what they can do and the
best ways that they can do it.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. I, I mean,
it was, it was, uh, Ryan's, I
mean, Ryan's always great to talk
to you. Um, and yeah, and that,
that, like, that, that
philosophy, I think, uh, I don't
know, lines up a lot with a lot
of the stuff we talk about here
at Virtual Coffee. So, um, it was
nice to hear him talk about it,
and it's nice that he is, uh,
he's doing this, like he's, I was
very interested to hear about his
consultancy, um, and his like,
sort of new journey that he is
doing because, uh, it's a little
bit of a different approach than,
you know, most people, I'm, I'm a
consultant myself, but I just
kind of come in. Do like the
work, right? Or like, you know,
the kind of stuff you, you think
about, right? And this is more,
um, Ryan's gonna come in and help
teams, uh, improve their whole
situation, right? And then leave
you know? And I think that's
really great. I think it's a, I
think it's a very cool thing to
do. Um, and I was excited to hear
about it.
Bekah: It is really something
that I think is undervalued too.
So I think that a lot of teams
experience these problems and
they just end up having a lot of
turnover. Or things like that,
and there's not a huge focus on
what Ryan's doing, but I think
it's something that should be
focused on. It's really needed in
the industry.
Dan: Yeah, I agree.
Bekah: Well, we start every
episode of the podcast, like we
start every virtual coffee. We
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do, and a random check-in
question. We hope you enjoy this
episode. Today's intro question
is if you could remove one task
from your day, what would it be?
My name is Bekah. I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and if I
could remove one task I email or
no meetings, can I remove
meetings? That's kind of like
general, but I would get rid of
most of them.
Dan: So all meetings. All right.
Bekah: Only the only ones I wanna
get rid of. The ones without
agendas. Those ones.
Dan: Sure.
Ryan: one.
Dan: Yeah. Well, this isn't a
meeting, this is, this isn't an
event,
Bekah: Mm-hmm. this is an event.
Dan: Uh, alright. Hi, I'm Dan. I
am in Cleveland. I do website
development. And, um, yeah, I
think the first thing that popped
into my mind was like bedtime
stuff with the kids. I, I don't
mind like the, all the way at the
end reading books and stuff, but
it's all the, you know, bath and
whatever, all that nonsense. But
then I think actually it's
getting them in the car.
Bekah: Oh,
Dan: There's, I, my, you know, I
still a three old and a six year
old, and so they're still all,
both in car seats, you know, and
all that stuff. And doesn't
matter where we're going, what
we're doing, it takes just for
like ever, like I sell them to go
outside cause they can get into
the car by themselves, you know?
And I tell 'em to go outside and
get in the car and I go outside
and they're just like wandering
around in the garage or whatever,
you know, and like, just, just
get in the car. We just need to
go. This is, we don't have to do
this every time. And like playing
with toys while trying to get
them buckled and all this stuff.
So that's gonna be my answer.
Yeah. Putting the kids in the
car, they could just like snap
and they would just be strapp in
the car.
Bekah: with their shoes on too,
right?
Dan: Sure. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Exactly. Yeah.
Bekah: don't know how many times
we've been in the car and a kid
doesn't have shoes. Like my kids
are all. Older. My youngest is
five and a half, but frequently
we end up in the car and like one
kid's like, Oh, I didn't bring
any shoes. Like, Why? What? How
is thing? Like you just always,
You didn't tell me I needed to
put on shoes. You always put on
shoes if you're getting in the
car, like,
Ryan: Um, standard operating
procedure. Okay, well, I'm Ryan.
I am a, uh, developer, experience
consultant and productivity
consultant in New York City. A
little, little town in New York
called New York City. Um, my
daughter is little over one year
old, so getting her in the car is
very easy. We just pick her up
and put her in and she doesn't
have much of a choice about it.
And if she needs shoes, we put
'em on. Um, and yeah, meetings,
Uh, I actually like meetings. I
think that that's when I do my
best work. So I won't say that. I
will say, That is the one thing
that my wife and I have the most
tension about is actually just
doing the dishes. Cause neither
one of us likes to do it. Um, so
I would remove that from my day
in a heartbeat. Uh, just, I mean,
I would want clean dishes. I
wouldn't wanna just not do it and
have dirty dishes, but if the
dishes get clean regardless,
that's what I would pick. Um,
yeah.
Dan: Yeah, I actually, of all the
like household chores that you
have to do all the time dishes
are like one of the easiest ones
for me. Like, know, I, chores are
like a paint, I don't mean easy,
like easy to get myself to do,
you know? Um, I think I can
listen to podcasts and stuff, and
so it's, I don't know.
Ryan: Yeah. It's rather
meditative
Dan: when I'm doing the dishes.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Like if
I'm doing that chore, then, you
know, every. Somebody else is
dealing with the kids
Ryan: Hmm. A little break.
Dan: Oh man. But I don't like
putting the dishes away.
Honestly. That's my,
Ryan: Oh,
Dan: don't mind cleaning them.
It's like putting them away is
the thing that always bumps me.
Ryan: Our dishwasher's actually
broken right now, all the dishes
are done by hand, which is
probably why it's front of mine
for me
Bekah: Our dishwasher was broke
for like over a month and it was,
it was the source of a lot of
tension in the house. Like we
have four kids and then some of
them like take plates in their
rooms and then you've got like
crusty dishes, like, what are you
doing?
Ryan: and my wife does.
Bekah: Well Ryan, we are very
happy to have you here with us
today to talk about. A lot of
different things, but building
better teams I think is gonna be
a great source of our
conversation. But before we get
to that, let's hear your origin
story. So how did you get to this
point in your tech career?
Ryan: Yeah, thanks. I mean, I
always approach this story a
little differently every time I
tell it. Um, I mean, I've always
been interested in computers,
right when I was a kid. I
remember the first kind of
computer programming thing,
computer programming thing that I
did was, there was a video game I
liked to play and it was kind of
like Iron Man mode where like if
you die, you die. And I, I had a
big career in the game and then I
died and I was like, Oh my God. I
was so depressed. Probably the
first time I was ever depressed
in my life that I remember was I
dying in this game. And so I came
in and I, I took the save game
file and I switched around the
bits and made myself alive again,
And so that's where I started
out. I think with the, uh, you
know, I always was interested in
dos and kind of playing video
games, and so I've been talking
to the computer for many years,
is what I call it, through the
terminal. Um, but yeah, I never
considered it as a career. You
know, I had a teacher in high
school who got me into economics.
Um, and so I decided to study
that in college. But, you know,
college didn't really agree with
me for mental health reasons. And
so I dropped out and I was
working actually on a loading
dock. Cause I had a, a cdl, like
a truck license, but I couldn't
find a job driving a truck. So I
got a job loading the trucks. It
was the middle of the, it was in
the middle of the night. It was,
you know, I learned a lot on that
job about hard work. But, you
know, it wasn't really what I
wanted to do long term. And a
friend of mine who I met in
college was like, Hey, do you
wanna be a software engineer? So,
I mean, this is kind of the, the
height of privilege, right? It's
like someone just offers you a
job and you don't have to apply.
And you know, like I, I, I feel
for everybody these days who is
looking for a job as a software
engineer and really kind of has
to look and look and look. You
know, for me it just fell in my
lap even when I wasn't looking
for it. So a lot of privilege.
And, uh, yeah, so, you know, I
started off doing that job. It
was like a government contracting
job. I actually really enjoyed
it. I remember the first problem
I solved, which was putting a
ClickHandler on a button, And,
you know, I, I solved it sort of
the, I put put it in the HTML as
like text, which is, you know,
not how you even did it back then
with J Query and stuff like that.
This was back in 2009. And uh,
yeah, so I didn't even solve it
kind of the right way, but the
elation of having solved a
problem was huge and I kind of
tried to stay close to that
feeling. Um, kind of like, you
know, with switching the bit in
the save game file, just trying
to stay close to that feeling
throughout my career. Um, so I
did that for about four years.
You know, my boss was like, I'm
not gonna pay you anymore than
you're making now. And I was
like, Well, I could make more
money. So I went to another job,
um, a private sector job, cuz the
first job was a government
contracting job. And, You know, I
enjoyed that too. You know, it's,
it was in DC It's not like a big
market. So the company that I
worked for was a little bit, you
know, janky, I would say kinda
like the first one. Um, but I
learned a lot at that job. I
worked with a lot of great
engineers, um, learned a lot
about what I didn't want in a
job. Um, and at the same time, I,
uh, I went to a meetup for
general Assembly and they asked
me, Someone just came up and
said, Hey, do you wanna be a
teacher? And I immediately said,
yes. Um, it's something I hadn't
really thought about, but I was
always on Stack overflow, just
kind of answering questions and,
and so it just was an immediate
yes for me. Like I just kind of,
it blurred outta my mouth, you
know, like joy without me even
thinking about it. And, uh, yeah,
so I, I did some teaching, a
general assembly, and that was
sort of the end of my programming
career, even though it lasted for
another seven years or something.
Um, Actually, I don't know how
long, but it lasted for a long
time after that, uh, even though
I decide, I decided at that point
that I wanted to solve human
problems, um, in software and not
so much solve the, the
programming problems, but I kept
grinding at it for many years.
Moved to New York. Uh, it's
continued to teach at a company
called Thankful. Um, just worked
at Squarespace first and then
Dropbox, and then eventually
just, you know, kind of burnt out
on development. Uh, cuz again, I,
I kind of had already found
something in my calling a little
bit, uh, in something else
related. And so now I work as a
consultant. Um, and I guess we
can talk about that, but yeah,
it's, you know, what I'm trying
to do is help teams be more
knowledgeable and more
productive, uh, and. Deliver kind
of on a promise of quality, you
know, and, and, and timelines.
Uh, so that's what I'm trying to
do as a consultant. But that was
sort of an evolution from
teaching, uh, you know, from
teaching and, and solving human
problems. So that kind of brings
me to where I'm at today. And
then, you know, of course I'm in
vc, which is a wonderful
community. Um, and that's been a
source of great joy for me. Uh,
and you'll make other communities
that I'm in, but this is kind of
the main one that I, I appreciate
the most. So yeah, that's kind of
where I'm at.
Dan: We're the, we're the best
one, obviously, so
Ryan: Well, the most welcoming
right the most welcoming tech
community. I've started to get
the invite, so I'm really happy
about that. I hope we can
continue to expand at a, at a
measured rate, uh, with, you
know, people who are aligned with
the vision.
Dan: Yeah. That's been so fun to
have new people back, you know,
coming back in. It's been, it's
really
Ryan: Yeah. I invited ahead.
Dan: ahead. I was just gonna say
thank you for that story, but.
Ryan: Yeah. Okay. Sure. Yeah.
Yeah. It's, it's, uh, it's a
story that, um, has other parts
to it. Of course, it's hard to
kind of like capture a, the
multidimensional nature of human
beings in a, in a short blurb.
But yeah, happy to talk more
about it as we go forward.
Bekah: there a moment in when you
were teaching that you really
felt, this is what I wanna be
doing, Or do you think the whole
experience just kind of led you
down this path?
Ryan: Well, there was a moment
when I was like, This is not what
I want to do. Right in the
beginning. You know, I taught
htm, I taught a front end course,
a general assembly, and you know,
I taught HTML and it was great. I
was like, Oh my God, I'm such a
good teacher. People love me. I'm
getting great reviews. Like this
is what I want to do. And then we
got into JavaScript And to be
fair, there was no curriculum,
you know what I mean? Like this,
they just opened this office and
General Assembly was rather, I
don't know how young it was, but
it seemed. Pretty startupy. And
so there was no curriculum, so I
had to make it up as I went. And
you know, I didn't do a good job
at that initially. It's very
tough to teach JavaScript. And
so, um, I got all these bad
reviews. People love me still cuz
I'm like a nice person, but they
were like, he's a nice person but
he's not a good teacher. Um, and
so that was sort of a lesson for
me. It's like, okay, prepare. How
do you actually, you know, teach
really hard material to pe to a
variety of people? So I learned a
lot from that. But you know, the
initial kind of, you know, I
wouldn't say high, but the
initial sort of like, um, joy of
teaching was that first kind of
semester part of it, the first
half of the course. And I really
enjoyed that. And that kind of
carried me through even the tough
time of like, you know, not doing
well. Um, but I also realized
from that, that I wanted to do
individualized mentorship more
than I wanted to do. Teaching in
general, you know, and I still
kind of struggle whether I wanna
do conference talks or cuz I do
like what I can do in
conversation rather than what I
do in kind of multiplexing, if
you will, to a bunch of people.
Um, so yeah, I think teaching is
great. I do enjoy kind of getting
up in front of people actually in
the, the kind of nervousness of
that. And, but I do enjoy the
individualized mentorship better
and that's kind of where I, I
think I shine is pair programming
and, you know, conversations. So,
Dan: Yeah, that's, that's really
cool. I was, I was, I think
that's actually the answer, but I
was gonna ask, um, you know, you
talked when you were talking
about, um, before you were
teaching, um, that feeling,
right, the feeling fixing the
game or, uh, adding the
ClickHandler, right? You were
talking about staying close to
that feeling, which I, which is,
I turn a phrase that I love and
also something that I've sort of
un, you know, unintentionally or
intentionally sometimes try to
do, uh, throughout my career. But
my, my question was going to be
like, how do you stay close to
that feeling when you're not,
when you're. Solving technical
computer problems anymore. Right.
How, like what, Like what are
ways that you can, that you do
stay close to that? Because I, I
imagine you do, but it's just a
little bit different. And so I
was wondering if you talk a
little bit about like how you,
um, or if you've thought about
that at all, how you stay close
to that Um,
Ryan: I think it all the time
actually.
Dan: Yeah.
Ryan: Um, well, for me it's the
concept, you know, uh, there's a
Buddhist teacher named Suzuki
Roshi who had a great phrase,
which is in the beginner's mind,
there are many possibilities, and
the experts mind. There are a
few. Um, and so I, I just
remember the beginner's mind. I
try to remember that. I don't
know, basically anything, you
know what I mean? Like you've had
experience with things, you've
seen some problems, but every
problem you solve is totally new.
Um, it's, you know, it's like,
it's some new combination, some
new context, some new, uh,
outcome you're trying to achieve.
Some new technologies. So I try
to stay close to beginner's mind
as much as I can by reminding
myself that I don't know, and,
uh, going from that sort of area
of possibility rather than sort
of the preconceived notions. And
so in my current work, I try to
work with companies that. Want to
hire junior developers. Um, I
think that's sort of the, I'd
rather work with companies that
are trying to integrate juniors
rather than companies that are
obsessed with, you know,
seniority. Um, and the reason for
that is that helps me stay close
to beginner's mind by working
with beginners. Um, you see the
kind of endless possibilities in
their mind. Um, as they create
sort of quote unquote bad code,
it's like, that's actually
creative code. It's creative
problem solving. It's not like
they're just wrote writing down
something they already know.
They're really trying to solve a
problem from a standpoint of
possibilities. And so, yeah, I
think working with beginners, Is
how I stay close to that feeling.
In addition to kind of
cultivating it in my own mind, I
try to experience it through the
minds of actual, you know, you
know, beginners. Um, so yeah, I
think that's, that's kind of the
answer is I, I try to stay close
to that feeling and then that
allows me that excitement when
other people solve problems when
it clicks for other people.
That's where like it clicks for
me too. You know, It's like I, I
don't know that I could do it. I
mean, I, you know, if I'm solving
a problem myself, some sort of,
you know, big scope problem as
you get when you're more
experienced, there's clicks for,
you know, it clicks for me too.
And I get that, that feeling of
like, Oh, it works, you know,
there's no errors. Or, you know,
the type script compiler says, Go
ahead. Um, you know, that's,
that's good stuff. But I do love
feeling it click or seeing it
click beginners and kind of
experiencing that joy. Um,
second.
Dan: That's awesome. That's very
cool. Like being able to stay
close that feeling right by
sharing it with other people. You
know, I before I ask this
question. Yeah, yeah. Totally.
Totally. You know, and you had,
you had started talking about um,
how you like doing more one on
one, you know, pairing stuff like
that, um, with people, and I
imagine that's, it becomes a lot
easier to do that right. To.
Share in the experience when you,
when it's a more intimate, you
know, learning situation, right?
With one, you know, one on one
sort of thing, instead of like
teaching a class, for instance.
Um, to,
Ryan: Also I've found that.
Exactly. And also I've found
that, I mean this is an a d d
trait, but like if you tell me to
go off and do something, if I'm
not interested in it, I'm not
gonna do it And so like that's
why freelancing
Dan: about that.
Ryan: Yeah, exactly. So, you
know, it's, it's tough for me to
kind of do programming on my own.
And I've found that like if
someone else holds the focus,
like pair programming or. If, if
it's something I can do in the
context of a meeting, you know,
like I just kind of go in, I do
the meeting, I come out, I go
back to my life. Like that is
actually where I do my best work,
is something I can do in
conversation, in, in, in
collaboration where someone else
holds the focus. I can do the
best work. But, so that's sort of
a another thing about knowing
myself, right? It's like knowing
where I work best and not trying
to like fit into someone else's
life as a, as a software
developer, you know? So, and also
trying, it took me a long time to
kind of. Release myself from the
view I had of being a software
developer, cuz it was such a part
of my identity. Um, and so it's,
it's tough like to say, like, you
know, to give that up to say, you
know, I don't wanna be a software
developer so much anymore, as
much as I wanna help other
software developers. Like that's
a, it was a mind bending thing,
you know? Cause I was so used to
seeing, you know, to to telling
people I was a software engineer.
I still do sometimes cause it's
much easier than explaining what
I try to do. You know, if I don't
really wanna have the
conversation, if it's just.
Somebody doesn't know the
difference anyway. Uh, I'll just
say, Oh, I'm a software engineer,
but it's still true. I do a lot
of engineering on my own, but
yeah, pair programming, things I
can do in conversation is where I
really shine.
Bekah: So when you're working
with teams, how do you kind of
transfer that same energy to
teaching within a team, or what
do you think the role is and how
that's translated from your
experience to what you're doing
now?
Ryan: Well, I mean, first you
have to know the team, right? You
have to kind of know what their
individual problems are. You have
to talk to them. Um, and so, you
know, I, I start with like an
audit where I go in and kind of
identify the pain points for
people so that way when I go pair
with people, I know them and I
know the kind of what they're
working on. I know where they're
struggling. Um, so yeah, I think
that, uh, yeah, knowing, knowing
people, knowing the people on the
team is kind of the most
important thing. And being
personal, um, you know, I don't,
I'm not writing a book, right.
I'm not writing a book on how to
solve all the problems. If I was
doing that, I mean, that would be
great too. But it's like I'm
really creating an
individualized. Plan for people
and companies as well. You know,
there's a plan for the team.
There's also a plan for
individual pe, individual people
for how to improve, how to, um,
to do better. Uh, so yeah, I
think I've actually forgot what
the, what the feeling was you
were asking about, but I think
that's sort of maybe an answer. I
mean, if you, if you have a
follow up, I mean, maybe I can
get back on track, but that was
the first thing that came to
mind.
Bekah: Yeah. Well, I mean, it's a
hard balance transitioning from
doing like one on one mentorship
and teaching to going inside of a
team. And I think that idea of
getting to know people is super
important because I, I think that
you can be way more effective as
a teacher if you do know the
people in front of you. Um,
because like I, I think. So much
of the time we depersonalize what
we're doing or we abstract these
concepts out and try to apply
them rather than like recognizing
like there's a dynamic group of
people in front of us and this
approach is not going to work
unless you have an understanding
of who those human beings are.
And I think that's, You know,
having those conversations and
the, like we do in Virtual Coffee
and the breakout rooms makes a
big difference. And there there
can be a real balance of like
trying to have that personal
experience and having empathy and
then also teaching in that
situation. So do you have any
strategies for being able to
balance those?
Ryan: Well, you know, I, I think
there's, I have sort of a view on
learning. I mean, I have a lot of
soundbites, right, that I say
over and over again. But, um, you
know, my view on learning is
that, And knowledge is that it's,
there's nobody has the same
knowledge. We all think that
like, Oh, I learned react, you
know, react like we know the same
thing, right? But actually, you
know, the way we really learn is
by connecting to our experience.
We have all these analogies that
are personal, that we use to kind
of identify and understand
problems, understand solutions,
understand technologies, and so
it's really like a 3D space where
nobody really overlaps. It's like
you have this sort of bubble of
knowledge in the, in the problem.
And it's very multidimensional.
It doesn't overlap with other
people. It's centered around you.
Um, and so I think when you're
working with a team, it's like
you have to kinda understand that
a team is a collection of
individuals who have common
goals. It's not like a unit, um,
like you know, in the military or
something where everybody just
sort of like follows an, I mean,
I don't know, I never in the
military, but you know, it's like
that software team is very much
like individual people tackling
problems individually. And I
think that the other thing.
Trying to break that cycle and
improve kind of pairing and
knowledge sharing between the
team. Because a lot of times, I
mean, teams, these teams I've
been on, it's like you come in
and people are individually
working on problems, your
individual productivity,
everybody's trying to burn down
their sprint points. And you
know, there's not like a lot of,
you know, some people will come
up and ask a question
occasionally, but there's not.
Teams working together. And so I
think the, the ultimate thing is
I don't wanna be there long term,
you know, I'm not there to like
be the teacher forever. I, my, my
goal is to change the team
dynamic to make everybody a
teacher, you know, make everybody
sort of a learner and everybody a
mentor. You know, not obviously
people have different capacities
and interests in it, but you
know, just improving their
ability to do it in their own
way. Um, I think is kind of, I
think that answers your question.
I always get off on these
tangents, but I think that's sort
of how I approach. The team
dynamic is really trying to make
myself irrelevant. make myself
not necessary in the long term.
Cuz again, I wanna work in
limited engagements. It's again,
an a, d, D thing. I'm not trying
to make a year contract with
somebody where I'm just like
constantly grinding with them.
It's like, no, I wanna make them
better in a short term, in an
impactful way. Like do the, do
the judo move where you just sort
of like come in and flip things
around and leave, you know, Um,
that's kind of my ultimate. Is
not to, not to be, to make people
dependent on you, to make people
self-sufficient
Bekah: I think that's great and I
think that one of the biggest
things that I see or hear in the
industry is it kind of takes a
breaking point to bring somebody
in to rectify communication and
team. Um, I don't know what the
right word is. Uh, what would
you, what did you say?
Ryan: Uh, Dynamics.
Bekah: dynamics. You know, people
wait until there's a problem and
I feel like bringing someone in
very early on can reduce
miscommunications, burn out. Um,
Problems that you see because you
haven't spent that time
developing communication. And I
don't know if this is
particularly a startup issue, but
like the whole move fast and
break things, I feel like there's
a lot lost in how we communicate
within teams and cross team
communication. So like what? What
is your ideal situation to come
in? Would you like to come in
from the beginning or do you like
to come in and kind of like blow
people's minds by fixing their
problem?
Ryan: That's a good way to put
it. Yeah, I mean, a lot of the
things I offer are
counterintuitive, right? Um, like
slowing down, like, you know, not
going, moving fast and breaking
things, but instead, you know,
allowing people the time and the,
the ability to talk to each other
first, you know, and second,
create quality. Um, but I will
say that there's the ideal
situation there is sort of a size
of the company that makes sense.
I think that one thing people
kind of. Discount is that the
best practices for a very small
company are different than the
best practices for a large
company. You know, if you're like
a small company and you're trying
to scale, you know you wanna get
started first. You wanna create
an mvp, you wanna, And so the
best practices for doing that are
not necessarily focused on
quality as much as they are
vetting and validating your idea
and validating that it has a
market and validating that people
want to use it. And that maybe
creates incentives that are. and
if you're like a series a company
where you have maybe 10, 20
people and you have some
investment and you have some
ability to take risks to improve
quality, right? So I think the
ideal situation is a little
larger company. Um, also larger
companies have the ability to
onboard juniors more. I think
that, you know, it, it's tough
when you're a small company to
have maybe one developer. Who you
know is a junior developer. I
think it's probably great from a
standpoint to that junior
developer, they learned so much.
I've been in that situation where
I'm the only front end developer
or something, and I was kind of
junior and I learned a lot, you
know, so I think it's great for
the person, but for the company,
maybe it's like they wanna move
faster, they wanna, they wanna
break things, but like they don't
wanna things to be broken
constantly. Um, so yeah, you
know, I think that the best
practices are different and the
ideal situation is maybe a
slightly larger company where
there is a team. The team is sort
of established. There's
investment and ability to take
risks. Um, I would love to work
with, you know, smaller companies
and work from the beginning.
Right. But that also is maybe
they may, may be a little more
dependent on me, right? They
actually may wanna hire me as
like a senior developer, and
that's not really what I'm trying
to do. I want to come in and like
have a team that I can work with
and kind of affect, especially a
junior team. Um, so yeah, I think
that I would love to be there
from the beginning and help them
build quality, but I'd rather be
there when they are ready to
build. Um, ready to, to have
those counterintuitive solutions.
Like, hey, you know, slow down.
Don't when there's a, when
there's tech debt, solve it right
away. Have everybody work on it.
You know, things like this, which
are sort of like, not the
incentives you usually have, you
know? Cuz the main thing is
they've been trying things, like
you said, there's a problem
right. The CTO is talking to the
ceo and the CEO is like, Hey,
you're not delivering on these
business needs. Your team is
making a qu product that lacks in
quality in our users notice, and
you know, what's the problem that
you're, you can't affect these
things. That's kind of the, the
issue that I would come in and
sort of solve is like when that
exists, and I think it exists in
a lot of teams at different
times. Um, but yeah, that's what
I would say. It's like there is
an ideal size and an ideal
problem to come in and solve and,
and not, companies are not really
ready for counterintuitive
solutions when they're,
everything's working fine. I
think they don't want to come in
and like change things. They're
like, Oh, everything's working
fine. But when there's a problem
it's like, try something
different. Try a different tact,
because that's how you're gonna
find a solution.
Dan: know, we talked, Ryan had me
on his Twitter space. What was
that last week? This week? I
don't know.
Ryan: Um, the past
Dan: Recently, And,
Ryan: not future,
Dan: one of the things we talked
about was a lot was, um, was the
idea of technical debt. On teams.
Right. And, and that's like one
of the, one of the, maybe one of
the problems that you are hoping
to be able to help solve. Right.
With, with these teams. Could you
talk a little bit about what,
what technical debt is, you know,
like what, what it means to you
when somebody says technical debt
and what, and then, and then also
like, you know, how, how that can
like negatively affect, um, a
team, you know, maybe even
without them knowing about.
Ryan: Well, I think there's
actually, it's important to say
there's actually lots of
different kinds of debt. That are
different than just, I mean, a
lot of people when they say
technical debt, they think of
some developer experience problem
where it's like there's something
counterintuitive code. Um, some
feature, but you know, Excuse me.
There's actually multiple
different kinds of debt. There's
quality debt. Which is where
you're building things kind of
let lack quality and you just
leave it that way. I did this
funny tweet where I had a bridge
that I built in like poly bridge.
I dunno if you know this game,
but it has these gaps in the
bridge and like the truck goes
across it and the bridge flexes
around and I'm like, this is kind
of how we built products. We
leave these gaps and we say, Oh,
the, the truck can get across the
bridge without the, the whole
thing being built, therefore it's
done. And um, so I think that's
sort of a quality problem, right?
So that's quality debt. There's
knowledge. Which is where the,
the, the product doesn't teach
people how to use it, how to
develop on it rather. Um, and I
think that the ultimate sort of
product is one that teaches the
developers how to, how to, how to
create. Changes in it, right? How
to extend it, how to modify it to
maintain it. If the product isn't
teaching people that, that's
knowledge debt, right? That's
sort of, And the team isn't
sharing the knowledge too, right?
But, so it's kind of a
combination of sort of like
automated solutions and just
plain old interfacing with other
people face to face or you know,
remotely or even asynchronously,
right? Cause there's lots of
different ways teams operate
these days. So that's knowledge
debt. There's tactical debt,
which is, you know, what we
talked about, sort of like.
Developer facing problems in the
code that make it hard to develop
that, make it hard to implement
quality, hard to share knowledge.
Um, and then there's, there's one
other one that I, I can't think
of right now, but yeah, it's,
there's, that's what I would say.
There's lot, there's other
different kinds of debt. Um,
quality debt, knowledge, debt,
technical debt. Well, you know,
I'll think of it. Um, it's just
funny. I should know it cuz it's
kind of something, I dunno if
it's something I came up with,
but it's something I talk about a
lot. But there's different kinds
of, um, Oh, innovation debt.
That's it. So innovation debt is
like, Is, um, things you wanna do
but you haven't done cuz you
can't do it for some reason. You
know, like, you wanna build this
feature, you wanna implement this
big change, refactor the product,
but everything else is holding
you back. Right. So that's sort
of like there's a debt in the, in
the innovation you're trying to
do. So yeah, I think breaking it
down in different, into different
kinds of debt, not just focusing
on calling it technical debt sort
of opens you up. To really affect
the problems that are holding you
back, to affect the things that
are preventing you from
delivering on that promise, like
I said, and quality right, and
promise of timelines. Yeah.
Bekah: I love how you break that
down. I think that that really
helps to better understand what,
what problems that you're facing,
um, and also to be able to
explain it to other people,
especially if you have junior
members who are, are just coming
into the industry and trying to
understand exactly what you mean
by technical debt. I think. It
also can help people to better
identify their problems by
looking at it in that way. Um, so
I, I think that this kind of
touches on this idea of knowledge
sharing and how you do that in
teams. So, um, can you first
define knowledge sharing for us?
And then maybe talk about where
to start with that.
Ryan: Yeah, I mean, I think it's,
uh, you know, we have this
problem of droughts these days.
Because of, you know, global
warming and there's places that
have water, there's places that
don't have water, and how do you
irrigate? You know, how do you
get water from one place to
another so that everybody can
drink, everybody can grow crops.
Right? And that's sort of what I
see knowledge sharing as is.
There's people that have the
context, have the understanding,
and there's people that need that
understanding, that need that
context to affect their work. And
it's like, how do you get the
water from one place to another?
And, uh, there's lots of
different ways to do it, right?
There's, you know, documentation.
Cause the thing is, there's
asynchronous and synchronous
knowledge sharing, right?
Synchronous knowledge sharing is
what we're doing right now. We're
having a conversation in real
time. I'm telling you, you're
asking me questions. I'm telling
you. Something logical. I
wouldn't call it an answer,
right? Cuz there's lots of
different answers. But I'm
telling you personal answers
about like how I think about
problems. So that's like
synchronous knowledge sharing.
And I think that if you can do
that, that's kind of the best way
to do it. Yes, it costs two
people's time. Um, which is kind
of where people get caught up is
like, Oh, there's a big cost. You
know, like pairing, there's a big
cost with meetings, you know, Um,
or one on ones ideal. Um, but you
know, of course there's a cost,
but it's like there's a huge
benefit. It's not like two times,
two people is two times work, you
know, and two times cost. It's
like, maybe it's two times cost,
but it's like there's a
multiplication effect that
happens when people share
knowledge, both in terms of the,
our ability to execute and also
their ability to build quality,
right? Cuz they know the edge
cases, they know sort of the
context they need to create best
practices within the product. And
then there's asynchronous
knowledge sharing, which is
around. It could be Slack, right?
It could just be that's async
sort of knowledge sharing.
There's also documentation,
right? I have a lot of ideas on
documentation and kind of how to
affect it and make it sort of,
uh, useful for people. But yeah,
that's what I would say. That's
sort of knowledge sharing in a
nutshell. It's like how do you
irrigate this knowledge between
different areas, the people that
have it, the people that need it,
and, uh, doing it synchronously
and asynchronously and sort of
like being aware of the
difference between.
Dan: I love that metaphor. No, it
makes, it makes a ton of sense.
I, you know, uh,
Ryan: I have a lot of water based
metaphors for programming.
Dan: water-based metaphors, All
right. I I'm, a big fan of, I'm a
big fan of, uh, of Data's
Bekah: be a water bender.
Ryan: No, I would be Bruce Lee.
Like, you know, if you put water
in a cup, it becomes the cup. You
put water in a bottle, it becomes
the bottle. That's sort of my
thinking of water is that it's
like, it's flexible and I like, I
like that idea. It's a flexible.
Dan: nevermind. I was just I was
gonna take this metaphor too far.
Ryan: No, well, you know, mean,
it's great metaphor, so
Dan: Oh, I was trying to figure
out what, what, like Twitter
would be if you're, you know,
sharing if knowledge is, is
Ryan: Twitter is a rainstorm.
Dan: is a rainstorm or is like
you like your Twitter account,
not you, but like a person's
Twitter account is like you
standing there with a scorecard.
right.
Ryan: You're just, it's a fire
You're
Dan: That's right.
Ryan: a, Into a chasm.
Dan: Right, right. Yeah. Maybe it
hits
Ryan: And sometimes it splashes
back at you, but that's, you
know,
Dan: right?
Ryan: that's about it. I don't
know. That's a good question.
Dan: I, I like, No, I mean, but,
but going back to like what you
were saying before, the, the,
that metaphor of the, especially
the, uh, you started this with
the, uh, concept of droughts.
Right. And, um, and I think, I
feel like that is a really
powerful part of this metaphor
is. You have these droughts,
Right? And of knowledge and, and
yeah. Yeah. And the, the lake of
knowledge, like you have the lake
sounds, This is
Ryan: A drought, nothing grows,
what I mean? Nothing is
Dan: Right, right, right. Yeah.
And
Ryan: People are, you know,
Dan: I think
Ryan: thirsty.
Dan: yes, I think that's a great
way of thinking about it. Uh,
it's,
Ryan: Kim Kardashian is like
watering her lawn at 200,000
gallons. You know, It's like, no,
nobody else has the water. I
don't know
Dan: Right. So that means she's
the senior developer who doesn't
talk to anybody
Ryan: exactly. I there are those
people right there
Dan: absolutely. You know, and,
Ryan: knowledge Dragons,
Dan: and talked about, Yeah, we,
we, we talked about, uh, or you
talked about, um, you know, Some
of this work being easier with
larger teams or whatever, things
like that. Um, I feel like this
happens a lot more often with
smaller teams. Uh, maybe not more
often, but it is a harder solve
problem to solve, right? With a
smaller team. Um, especially like
long term. So I'm just talking
about myself here, So just like
talk about, but like, I've been
working on some of these, some of
these products for, um, like
your. Uh, I don't know. I've been
working on one client for over 10
years. Right. And I have a ton of
knowledge just in my head about
it. And, you know, I try to do
docs and stuff, but it's like
small team, right? So that means
mostly me, you know, And then
sometimes, like Bekah worked with
me for a while and, and, and, um,
I have somebody else working with
me now, you know, and it's.
There's all these, there's all,
there's like deserts right? Of,
of, of, of not knowledge, right?
I, you know, there's places where
I've like, this is gonna be
confusing, so I'm gonna like,
write things down. But there's
other places where, you know,
either, well, for a million
different reasons, there's, you
know, nothing, right? And, um, I
guess I don't really have a point
other than it's hard. It's our
problem. It can be a very hard
problem to solve for teams all
size.
Ryan: you know what? I would say
again, counterintuitive
solutions, right? Um, My way of
keeping, my way of saying keep
docs up to date is don't try You
know, speaking of the water
metaphor, it's a point in time
thing. There's, Well, go ahead.
What were you gonna
Dan: talk more. No, I was gonna
say, talk more about this. That
is, never heard somebody say that
before, so I wanna hear what you
Ryan: Well, I think there's some
documentation that needs to be
sort of evergreen, right? Like
onboarding documentation. It sort
of needs to be evergreen. Read
means need to be evergreen. But I
think architectural documentation
with like diagrams and like how
things work, I think it's, it's
so tough to kind of keep that up
to date because it's such a big
sort of problem. You know, like
how does the whole thing work?
It's different from onboarding,
which is like, how do you start
the thing you don't know. But,
um, architectural, Go ahead.
Dan: Oh, I was just saying
totally. I was just
Ryan: Oh yeah, exactly. Documenta
or, you know, architectural
documentation is so tough to kind
of like take the whole product
and put it, boil it down into a
little residue of knowledge. And
so I think, you know, I really
like the idea of architectural
decision records. Which is, I see
it like a blog. You know, you're
keeping a blog of like all the
changes you're making in the
product and it's point in time.
You don't update it. It's just
like, this is the decision we
made. And then if you, you, I
think if you reference those in
the code, right, you know, you
have some anchor comments or
something that like link to these
different architectural records
and you know, the architectural
records supersede each other.
They amend each other, they have
linkages, sort of like hyper
text, right? It's like they're
all linked together. So it is
very much like a blog that you're
keeping of the decisions you make
throughout the development of the
product. And you're not trying to
like go in and create sort of an
omnibus like book that's
constantly has new additions.
You're creating blog posts that
sort of like, you know, do the
point in time thing. And that's
much easier to. Approach,
especially as a small team,
because you don't, you're not
like constantly going back and
trying to create evergreen, you
know, an evergreen documentation.
You're just writing these blog
posts and leaving it, you know,
as you go, as little breadcrumbs
for someone to say, Oh, this is
how the product evolved. Also,
you have sort of knowledge about
how the product used to be. Which
I think is also very important
because sometimes you wanna go
back you know, sometimes you
wanna learn from the past, you
wanna learn from like how things
were done initially. And also
it's just like, it explains
things in a way that maybe, uh,
just a present sort of evergreen
documentation wouldn't cuz you
say like, Oh, this is why that
was done. There's so many times
when we go into a code base and
go, Oh my God, this is horrible.
I was just done this way. And the
truth is always a reason. There's
always a reason. I always try to
tell people that when they're
like, Oh, I got this legacy code
base, and it's like, it's the
worst. Like I can't believe it.
Who are these bad developers?
It's like, you know, they were
you just in the past working with
problems, know, they're not like
bad developers. It's just they're
working on deadlines, they're
working on the context is
different and so like, I think
knowing that having empathy for
those original sort of the
ancestors of the code base is
sort of like important. And just,
that's kind of something you get
from a decision record that you
wouldn't get from, you know, like
explanation of what, how things
are. And also it kind of, it
shows sort of alternate solutions
that you might consider in the
future. The decision record. If
you, if you look at the, the,
the, you know, the way they're
written, it sometimes talks about
alternate paths that could have
been taken in the decision that
was made, and that could be
useful in the future. You might
say, Oh, you know, that's
actually a way we could go with
this based on the current
context. Let's go refactor. And
it's also in the code. There's
context, you know, it's like, um,
and I think documentation and
code is really the way to go, um,
for all things. Cuz I think it's
like when you separate it from
the code, you lose the context
of, um, you lose context. And I
think that's important to
understanding how things work.
But yeah, that's kind of my
thinking again, counterintuitive
solutions. It's like, try
something different. There's a
thing called like o bleak
strategies where it's like, it's
like you just have a card, you
pull it out and it says like,
Dance around in a circle and like
that's how you like cultivate
your creativity. I think like
thinking differently and trying
different things than you would
normally do or are normally done
in the industry is sort of an if,
even if it doesn't work, it tells
you something about how it might
work. You know, it's an
experiment that you're testing
hypothesis and maybe it doesn't
work, but like you learn
something new in the process. So
I was a dog Yeah, that's what I,
that's what I think.
Dan: I love that I, this
architectural decision records,
um, I was just looking it up. Uh,
I found a couple, I kind of found
a couple blog
Ryan: It's like adr GitHub dot. I
owe
Dan: that's what I, Yeah, that's,
that's what I'm on right now. Um,
and I, I like that concept a lot.
I like to, you know, it's, it
becomes, and I, you know, I have,
I have spoken about this before,
but I have ADHD too, right? And
it's like, um, the, the idea of
like, Oh, okay, I need docs.
Right. This is like the thing
that pops in my head, right?
Like, there's nothing here. I
need docs. But then like what are
like, it's just such a huge thing
to try to Like you said, it's
like writing a book almost, and
you know that like, I mean, and
then when you start thinking
about it, you know it's going to
be out of date immediately and oh
my gosh. So now it's like huge
chunk of work to begin with. And
then also huge annoying chunk of
works, like chunks of work, uh,
to keep it up to date. And it
just seems impossible in my head
sometimes, you know?
Ryan: Well, you know, when I
worked at Dropbox, just to be the
things wild, we had librarians,
technical librarians who li I
mean literal
Dan: like that
Bekah: I wanna be a technical
librarian. didn't know that was a
thing.
Ryan: can connect if you want.
Dan: uh, that sounds awesome. I
mean, like, that's the kind of
thing you, you the, once your
company grows in size, like, you
know, you can start having people
that have jobs of, you know,
specific jobs. Right. And smaller
teams, you have to do everything
right. Um, and that's, that's a
very cool I wonder
Ryan: you get, that's a big
Dan: if there's like a
consulting. Technical librarians
that can consult
Ryan: Well, there are technical
writer
Bekah: what I wanna do. I wanna
Dan: Yeah. I mean like
Bekah: librarian.
Dan: Right, right, right. So,
Bekah: you put the books back in
the right order,
Dan: Yeah, because like,
Bekah: miscategorized.
Dan: Right. And then keeping it
up to date, like if you have
somebody that is not a full-time
employee, Right. But somebody
who's like, all right, the first,
uh, run through would be. big
project. Right. But like after
that, it's like maintenance
stuff. Maybe a couple hours,
whatever, a week or a month, you
know, whatever it is. But like
that man. Alright. I have to
think this.
Ryan: No, I, I agree. It's, it's,
uh, it's a, it's a huge task and
so like having specialized people
is really valuable, but, you
know, also, but they're, they
don't necessarily have the
context, so they're just sort of,
Organizing, making sure things
are formatted correctly, making
sure things are linked correctly.
But you know, the knowledge has
to come sort of ultimately from
the people who are on the you
know?
Dan: But, but if somebody's like,
and that this is like, you know,
speaking of something that I've
done that is not well documented,
whatever, but somebody asks me a
question about it, then I'm like,
can talk about it for a while.
You know what I mean? But then,
and you mentioned like, like
those async, you know, learning
channels and stuff like that.
That's this kind of thing. And
then, but then it gets buried in
a slack, you know, thread
somewhere and disappears cuz
don't pay for slack you know, and
all that stuff. Right? And so,
um, Man, I, I like the idea of
having somebody, an outside
person plus like, if you see
somebody do, I'm sorry I'm
talking about this so much, but
I'm excited about it now, But if
you, if like, if me as, as like
the whatever lead developer on a
project and you have an outside
person that comes and gets
something going or adds an
addition, you'll be able to like,
I would be able to like see if
it's wrong or needs some like,
not wrong, but, you know, need
some like tweaks or whatever. And
that's an easier job than,
Ryan: Well, there's a value
Dan: the, starting from the
beginning. Right.
Ryan: It's a value to an external
perspective. That's what I always
say about myself is like, you
know, you've tried things, you
have a context about how things
work. I can come in as with an
external perspective and provide
additional value that you
otherwise wouldn't get. You know,
it's kind of like, uh, I'm trying
to think of an explanation. It's
cross pollination, you know what
I mean? It's like you're getting
sort of information or genetic
information from an external
source, and that creates a. Sort
of, you know, better result if
you just kind of like, I don't
wanna get into like genetics, but
it's like, you know, you don't
wanna just breed the same genes
over and over again. It creates
sort of problems. And so it's
like you need that external
information, external
perspective. And, you know, I
think every company needs that.
And that's kind of what you get
when you hire people, right?
You're hiring someone, they come
in with their own sort of
knowledge and abilities and, uh,
but you know, if you can just,
you can also hire a consultant,
you know, and, and they can
provide the same sort of thing on
a more temporary sort. Basis and
less, you know, ultimately less
cost. Right. You know, than
hiring somebody. But, uh, over,
over, you know, if they come in
for three months and you cost
this much, hiring someone for a
year and maybe not having them do
the same work is, you know, a
different, different calculus.
But yeah, external perspectives
very valuable.
Dan: I love that. You've given me
a lot to think about I mean,
I'll, I'll Every time we, every
time
Ryan: have talk about it some
more. Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. I always, I always end
up coming away with a, with a lot
of stuff to think about all of.
Ryan: Yeah. Well, that's the
point, right? Is like, that's
the, I have the external
perspective and you're learning
from it, and I'm learning from
yours. That's sort of the, the
ultimate idea, right? Is like we
learn from each other. That's why
we have conversations. It's not
to like, I'm not like telling you
stuff. I wanna listen you.
Bekah: that's so important. Um,
that idea of listening, cuz it's
hard to do and so much of the
time we spend listening to
respond to other people rather
than. Just listening to
understand people, and I think
that's, it's a hard thing to do,
but it's a good habit to work on
in, in any situation, but
especially if you're on a team of
diverse people or I, I think too,
Ryan: Well, hopefully you are
Yeah. I think that listening it
requires empathy, right? But it,
it's more than that. I think it,
because empathy comes from
letting go of yourself.
Bekah: mm-hmm.
Ryan: If you come into a
listening situation without
compassion, which is literally
just like not putting yourself in
the other person's shoes, but
just not even, just not even
really imagining, you know what I
mean? You just kind of let go of
your own preconceived notions and
listen to the person, and then
when they're done, you come out
of it and try to integrate it.
Then you can come up with some
advice. But if you're sitting
there in your head sort of
calculating like, Oh, this is my
answer. This is my answer, this
is how I think about it, this is
how you know. Then you're not
really listening. You're like, I
don't know what it is, but you're
not listening. You know?
Listening is really like letting
go of yourself for a moment
completely as much as possible,
and just being present with the
other person. And really like
trying to, That's how empathy
comes, is not from like relating
it to your experience, your own
sort of hurts and desires and you
know, suffering or whatever you
wanna put it, you know, in the
Buddhist sense I would say. But
yeah, you know, it's really just
kind of listening and being there
for the other person and then
after they're done you come back
and you go, wow, you know, I
really learn from that
perspective, you know, cuz it's
ultimately listening is learning,
right? And the way you learn is
not by, is by integrating, but
first sort of, you know,
transporting yourself to. Another
way of being, another
perspective.
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. Well,
Ryan, it's about time for us to
wrap up. Is there one tip that
you can leave our listeners with
to help them get started and this
idea of build. Better teams
through, um, empathy and
listening.
Ryan: Wow. That's a good
question. Um, I think it's being,
you know, compassion is very
important. There's a big push
these days for compassionate
coding, for compassionate teams.
And you know, I've been on some
teams as well that just don't,
there's some lack of disconnected
compassion, you know, And so
being gentle with each other,
being empathetic, as you said, is
such an important skill and such
an important you. Component of
being a team. That listing aspect
of really kind of letting go of
yourself and connecting with
another person is, you know, and
then, and then sharing knowledge,
you know, is like, that's, that's
the, the basis of sharing
knowledge is connecting with the
other person's experience. You're
just talking at them and saying,
Read the docs. You know, like
that's not how you connect with a
person and connect because
ultimately knowledge, as I said,
is like about connecting. Some
sort of theory to your personal
experience. You know, that's how
you transfer knowledge is, I tell
you, this is my experience. Or
you tell me first. I think you
have to ask questions first. You
know, ask questions first and
listen, and you say, This is my
experience. Then I go, Oh, you
know, based on what I think, this
is how I might connect with what
you said, This is how I might
connect with you as a person.
See, I don't know if that makes
sense to your question, but
that's what I would say is being
gentle, being compassionate
first. Not trying to just kind of
grind people, you know, cuz
that's really how you lose your
team. It's how you lose kind of
the knowledge that people have
when they leave is you burn them
out and you're not being
compassionate. And I think it's
so tough on a corporate level to
be compassionate cuz there's the
profit, motive, and business
needs and all this stuff. But if
you can really kind of let that
go and say, Look, we're gonna
care about our people first, that
will reap the rewards you.
That'll reap the rewards more
than like, you know, burning
people out for a business end,
you know what I mean? Like,
there's more to life. You're a
person too. The CEO's a person,
you know, they don't want to,
they wanna go golfing or
whatever. They don't wanna like,
you know, just be burning
themselves out and, you know, to
like, to, to, to make money. I
think ultimately maybe they do,
but that's sort of my opinion, is
like, you wanna build a great
team, be compassionate and play
golf, I guess, you know, let them
play golf. I don't know whether
they were, they. I play disc
golf, but, you know, let people
be themselves. And I think
that's, you also have to accept
that people don't work the same
hours, People don't have the same
accommodations. Like that's
where, that's where compassion
comes in is like understanding
the diversity of people and
trying to make them productive
and not trying to put them on a
clock. And like, like where, you
know, in the Henry Ford factory,
um, it's creative work. You
really need to kind of disconnect
from that idea of like, you know,
hours and time and productivity.
Bekah: was a great way to end the
episode. Thank you so much, Ryan.
Dan: Thanks, Ryan. Thanks for.
Ryan: Of course. It's so
wonderful to talk to you both the
two people I really respect and
have great connection with and
it's so nice to be able to spend
time with you and you know, I
guess record it, but just to
spend you is really
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah, Agreed. All right. Um,
yeah, we'll talk to you later.
Bekah: Thank you
Ryan: Oh, you talk to me now,
Dan: and also later,
Ryan: and also later. Yeah. Love
you
Dan: right. Bye Ryan. Thank you
for listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel. If you
have questions or comments you
can hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
virtual coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!