Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello and
welcome to Season 6, Episode 8
of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey, and they're
here, on this podcast sharing
their stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with you. Here with me today
is my cohost, Dan.
Dan Ott: Wuddup, Bek? How's it
going?
Bekah: It is -- it's going
alright. How's it going with
you?
Dan: Yeah. It's going great. We
just finished recording with
Shelley McHardy. She's a front-end
developer at Rightpoint. Shelley
transitioned from being a
high school chemistry teacher to
her current role a couple
years ago, I think, around when
Covid started. Which is when a
lot of, I think, transitions
happened. And, so yeah, she
shared with us her journey, you
know, learning about coding,
and doing some -- a bootcamp
and Collab Lab. And then we
talked a lot about the interview
process as well.
Bekah: Yeah. She had a lot of
really great points about how to
navigate that interview process
and shared really candidly about
how hard it could be. And I
really appreciated that she was
open with that. Cuz I think
that, you know, we talk about how
great it is to get into tech, and
we don't talk enough about how
difficult it is. And sharing
these stories can really help to
empower other people as they go
through that journey as well.
Dan: Yeah, I agree. I- I like hearing
about these- these journeys and-
and you s- you start -- we've
talked to a few people who've had
these sort of long and kind of
hard interview processes. And
you start to hear some of the
same -- si- similar, you know,
similar
things happening across- across
all of the interview process. And
so it was- it was interesting to
hear her thoughts about that. And
we talked a little bit at the
end about just -- about the
[laughs] the- the- the state
of this -- the interview process
in- in the tech world, you know?
And- and maybe how- how we can
try to improve it a little bit
down the line.
Bekah: Yeah. If you have any
ideas for that, leave us a
comment.
Dan: [Chuckles] Leave us a
comment on ... twit- Twitter?
Bekah: Well, Twitter would be a
good place to it. [Dan laughs]
Or- or on the- the podcast
episode.
Dan: Oh, yeah.
Bekah: Wherever they're
listening.
Dan: Oh, like a review?
Bekah: Well, you can leave a
review with a comment about-
Dan: Yeah. But you-
Bekah: -how to improve --
Dan: -have to do a review?
Bekah: Well, we also what --
like reviews. We love reviews.
Dan: [Laughs] Well, definitely
give us reviews.
Bekah: If you're listening, give
us a review.
Dan: And then, af- yeah. In your
review, tell us how to fix the
interview process as well
[chuckles].
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Dan: Yep. We'll- we'll read
those. For sure.
Bekah: And hit us up on Twitter,
VirtualCoffeeIO [chuckles].
Dan: Yeah. I'll -- also, other
places, I'm sure [chuckles].
Bekah: Lots of places. We're-
we're around.
Dan: Yeah [chuckles]. Listen to
the end of the episode for all
of the different
places that we've listed, that
you can contact us at [laughs].
Bekah: But if you wanna hear the
rest of this episode, you should
definitely listen. And we're gonna
start this episode of the podcast
like we start every other Virtual
Coffee Podcast episode, and how
we start every Virtual Coffee. We
introduce ourselves with our
name, where we're from, what we
do, and a random check-in
question. So, we hope you enjoy
this episode.
Dan: That was a great segue.
Bekah: [Bekah and Dan chuckle]
It's my- my one and only talent.
Dan: [Chuckles] You do. You are
very good at segue.
Bekah: Today's random check-in
question is, what was your least
favorite food as a child? Do you
still hate it or do you love it
now? My name is Bekah. I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio. And I think
that I liked a lot of food, but I
did refuse to eat any red meat
or pork, other than bacon,
for like from the time I was 11
until the time I was 21. So --
I- I didn't hate it. I just
didn't want to eat it. I do eat
it now, but it is also not my
favorite. I- I enjoy chicken and
fish, still. A lot. So that's
it. I'm boring.
Dan: [Laughs] Alright. Well, hi,
I'm Dan. I do web development in
Cleveland, Ohio. And yeah, I
don't know if I ever had like a
least favorite food. But the one
that popped into my mind, a food
that I did not like, and now I
like, was green beans.
Like I -- and I think part of
that was, I am pretty sure that
growing up, we weren't eating, like,
fresh green beans, you know? They
were -- you know what I mean? They
were like canned or whatever.
Some sort of things --
Bekah: Did you eat green bean
casserole, though? I love green
bean casserole.
Dan: I probably avoided it
because I just didn't like green
beans [laughs]. You know what I mean?
Like, there's just- there's just
that thing. But, now, like,
especially like a -- like crispy --
like a -- not crispy, but-
Shelley McHardy: Fresh.
Dan: -crunchy? I don't know.
Whatever.
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: But fresh green beans, you know? Like, not ov- like --
especially if they're not-
Bekah: Al dente green beans?
Dan: -overcooked thing. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Exactly. They
got a little crunch to 'em. And
-- I'm- I'm big fan these days.
Shelley: Hi, I'm Shelley. I am a
front-end developer in Atlanta,
Georgia. And I'm gonna have to go
with spinach. And again, just
like your canned green beans,
Dan, my mom used to do
disgusting things to spinach.
And it was not-
Dan: Yeah? [Laughs]
Shelley: -not edible.
Dan: Yeah.
Shelley: Like, just- just awful.
She told a story, I don't
remember it
anymore, but she's -- she still
does vividly. That she -- the
dog would
eat anything. And so she mixed
up a bunch of cooked spinach
with dog food and said, "If the
dog eats it, you guys have to
eat it."
And we said, "Deal." The dog
picked around the cooked spinach
and- [Dan laughs] and just
ate all the kibble, and we never
had to eat cooked spinach again.
Dan: Oh, that's hilarious.
Shelley: Which I love now. I
mean, like saag paneer and
stuff, if it's cooked well. Not
just smoosh.
Dan: Right. Right.
Shelley: So that's --
Dan: Yeah. It's like the
spinach --
Bekah: Somebody at Virtual
Coffee -- sorry.
Dan: Go ahead.
Bekah: Somebody at Virtual
Coffee — I think on Tuesday —
was talking about how they used
to eat canned spinach with a
little bit of salt on it. I was
like, "Ugh."
Shelley: Oh, no.
Dan: Yeah, that's -- yeah. No,
no. That's the kind of thing
that, like, the -- maybe
previous generation or whatever
was, you know, would eat.
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: Or like, I- I just
remember the Popeye, you know-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -cartoon. And he -- there
was always a can. And it just
came out in like a mush, you
know? Like -- and he would just
like slurp it down. And that's-
that's what I think of when I
think of it. Yeah. That, like,
spinach- spinach-
Bekah: That's how I used to eat
it when I was a kid.
Dan: -from back in the day.
Yeah. Yeah.
Bekah: My grandma used to say.
She was like, "If you eat this
can, you'll be really strong."
And I was like, "Okay then."
Like, "I wanna be strong
[laughs]."
Shelley: And my brother and I
were like, "I don't care. I'll
be weak." [All laugh]
Bekah: It's what I should have
done. I was a little bit
gullible, I think [laughs].
Well, thanks for being here with
us today, Shelley. We're really
excited to have you on the
podcast. We start-
Shelley: Excited to be here.
Bekah: -every episode of the
podcast [chuckles] -- all
right. Like, my eyes started
watering. And now I'm like
crying. I'm not crying for any
reason. It's just happening.
Shelley: [Chuckles] You're so
happy that I'm here.
Bekah: [Chuckles] That's it. I
was just so happy. It is an
involuntary physical
response to how happy I am to
hear your origin story. So
go ahead and- and kick us off
with how you got to this place
in your career.
Shelley: My orange -- origin
story. Now I have to decide if
I'm the hero or the villain,
okay?
Bekah: [Laughs] You can be both.
Shelley: Nah, I'm a good guy
[Bekah laughs]. Always. Let's
see. In my past life, I
was a high school chemistry
teacher. And even that was a ...
unplanned event. I actually
wanted to be Indiana Jones. A
hundred percent. I was an
anthropology made [??].
Bekah: I love that.
Shelley: Yeah. I wasn't gonna --
the- the worst thing about
anthropology -- so I have to say
that I'm really grateful that I
discovered other paths because I
can't stand hot. And I can't
stand beating down sun. So, you
know. And every- every movie has
prepared you to dig up dinosaurs,
you know, in the desert heat. So
it's good that it didn't work
out. I took chemistry,
accidentally, because I had
to take a lab science to
transfer to — the four year
university I wanted to go to. I
went -- I started at community
college. And so I'm like, "Okay,
I'm gonna take this bone head
chemistry class." And -- for
morons. I think it was called
that. And I completely loved it.
And I don't know why I missed
out in high school, but I did.
And then I took another one and
I realized that the teacher made
all the difference.
Bekah: Yes.
Shelley: And the environment of,
'You can make
mistakes. This is hard. That's
okay. You're not dumb.' And I
thrived and changed everything.
So I became that teacher and I
loved it. And I thought that I
would grow old teaching
chemistry, you know, and
doing fireballs in my lab as a
80 year old woman. But public
education is not all it's
cracked up to be. And I do
not wanna turn this into a
conversation about that, so we'll
just put that one aside. I
tried a lot of special programs,
a lot of special things. I did
some amazing stuff. I met
incredible kids. I loved it.
I missed it every day. But it --
I wasn't gonna grow old doing
it. So, at co- right at the
beginning of Covid, about six or
eight months in, I decided that
this -- or I should say, my
mental health
and physical health decided that
I wasn't gonna keep doing it. And
so I took a leave of absence and
thought, you know, "I'm just
gonna get better, I'm gonna take
a break, and then figure out
where to go
back." And for fun, because I'm
this kind of nerd, got an edX
course. I think, every --
"Python for everybody" or --
something-
something one of those little 10
hour courses. Not a- not a legit
anything. And it reminding back
my computer programming classes
in college.
And I was like, "I used to love
this. Why have I, like, stepped
away?" I mean, did a lot of tech
stuff in- in the classroom, but
not programming. And I found
bootcamps. It completely changed
the search algorithms on all
social media. And that's all I
saw. And I hadn't even known what
they were. So I did some research
and I found one at Georgia Tech
that sounded amazing for my
learning style. It was virtual,
which was required. There was no
way I was going into a classroom
at that point. This was early
2021. And I -- it was virtual,
it was live classes with an
instructor, and their whole thing
was that they broke out into
breakout rooms so you could
practice. So they teach for 10 or
15 minutes, and ask questions, and
then they send you in a group of
three or four people. And it was
just this cycle for three hours
at a time, you know, three times
a week. And it really worked for
me as far as the way I learn and
the way I work. Yeah, so I
did that. Went to my first
virtual conference last summer,
heard about
Virtual Coffee, found you all,
new home, new family. Yeah,
took about a little over a year
to get my first job.
Bekah: What conference was that?
If you don't mind me asking.
Shelley: Refactr.tech.
Bekah: Oh, cool.
Shelley: Yeah, so I don't know if
you know it. It's a little local
Atlanta one. Yeah. And it was
virtual that year cuz everything
was -- in fact I'm not going
this year cuz this year it's
completely back in person. I'm
kind of -- I think virtual
conferences were the best thing
that came outta Covid, and
there's still some hybrid ones.
But now people are going back a
hundred percent in person and
I'm just not wired for that
anymore. Or at least not yet.
Wait for this new vaccine to
show us how good it is
[chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. Do you think that
if Covid hadn't hit, you would
still be teaching?
Shelley: Oh, that's a good
question. I would not still
be teaching in the same place
because I was definitely unhappy
there with the way things were
changing. I think I am still
teaching. That's the funny
thing. As soon as I got outta
bootcamp, they reached out and
said, "Do you wanna be a TA?" So
I was a TA for my bootcamp, the
following cohort. I've start --
I've started volunteering for
Virtual Coffee, for Lunch and
Learn.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Shelley: I've become the
coordinator at Collab Lab for
the Career Lab, for little two
week-
Bekah: Yeah, awesome.
Shelley: -extension stuff
they do. So, I
will always be a teacher. That's
just -- that's how I'm wired. I
think that's what I like about
software development and tech,
and how much -- not -- maybe not
everywhere, but at least the
places that I've gotten involved
with, how much teaching is just
sort of part of how it's done.
I doubt at this point I'd
still be in a classroom teaching
chemistry. Yeah. That's- that's-
that's passed, I think,
unfortunately. Or maybe I'll go
back to it. Who knows? Or maybe
I'll go back and teach computer
science. That could be fun
[chuckles].
Dan: I like that. Yeah. Or you
could -- yeah. Maybe you could
do ... well, I don't know what-
what you call it, but like,
[chuckles] I'm sure there's
teaching positions that aren't,
you know, like, aren't the
whole full-time thing, right?
And-
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: -like, cuz -- just come in
and teach a class or something,
you know?
Shelley: Ooh. Or summer coding-
Dan: Well, yeah. There you go.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Shelley: -programs for girls,
and stuff like that would --
that's definitely in my future,
without a doubt [chuckles].
Dan: Yeah, that'd be awesome. I would -- that -- I just really
loved how you said that. Cuz
the- the teaching- the
teaching aspect of- of this,
like,
development -- and you're right.
Like, not everybody does it. Not
everybody wants to do it a-and
that's perfectly fine. But it is
one of those things that when
you find the right, like, places
in the right communities, you
know, there -- that -- that's
almost always one of the parts
of our -- of like, the
communities that feel good, at
least to me, right?
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: Is- is people, like-
Dan: -being willing to teach.
Even -- especially if it's not
like a- a position or
something, like an official
thing, right? But just people
sharing knowledge, you know?
It's- it's cool. It's --
Shelley: Yeah. It's a -- it's an
amazing thing. That's my two- my
two big communities, Virtual
Coffee and Collab Lab. It's just
that. It's constantly sharing
information, asking questions,
you know, pairing up on all
sorts of things. It's amazing. I
don't think the rest of the world
is like that. I don't know.
I'm sure-
Dan: Yeah. It doesn't --
Shelley: -people answer
questions, but it's not- it's
not part of it. It's not
built-in.
Dan: Right. I- I- I mean, I think
I agree with you. I mean, I don't
have any experience with other
careers. But like, the, you know,
my- my wife is -- she's had a
few different jobs over the last
however many years. And- and,
you know, she does data science
stuff
and it's- it's like programming
adjacent, you know, certainly.
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Dan: And like, she did
[chuckles] -- her current job,
actually, is on GitHub now.
Like,
they are like sharing- sharing
... I don't know what it is.
But sequel schemes maybe or
something. I'm- I'm not sure
[laughs] what they're doing,
you know? But- but it is that --
but it's still -- but there's
not like that expectation
and that -- I don't know. It's
still not the same, you know? It
isn't, like, just the way she
talks about it and the way that,
like, they're all like, work, you
know? It's very different than a
lot- a lot of software
organizations that --
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: It's- it's a weird thing.
I- I think that a lot of other
industries or whatever could-
could learn a lot from- from
that.
Shelley: Definitely. There's
some overlap with teaching and
teachers. There was a new
trend. It was probably -- it's
probably called something
different today, and 20 years
ago it was called something
different. But when I learned it,
it was called PLCs, Professional
Learning Communities. And it was
a set of protocols and mindsets
where you came together and
shared your work, shared your
blockers. I mean, it- it really
has a lot of overlaps with ...
the way that the tech space and
engineering talks about things
now. Retrospectives, you
know? All- all of those little
parts, there's a lot of overlap
with how teachers collaborated.
Dan: What was that called? What
was the --
Shelley: PLC.
Dan: PLC.
Shelley: Professional Learning
Communities, I think? You know
it, Bekah. I don't know if you-
Bekah: I've definitely heard of
that before.
Shelley: -you've ever heard them
before.
Yeah. I'm sure they call it
something different now,
cuz that's kind of how the
education industry works is, you
know, put a new label on it every
10 years. I guess a lot of-
Bekah: [Laughs] Rebrand.
Shelley: -industries were like
that. Yeah. Rebrand it. Call it
something
new. It's everybody's favorite
thing. It was really funny when
I was first started teaching.
That's what veterans would tea-
tell me. Of like, "Yeah, we've
seen it all. There's nothing
new." And I was gung ho, and
like, "No, no. This is new. I
love this. This is brand new.
You've never seen anything like
it before." And then
I turned into that person of
like, "Yeah, yeah, we've seen it
all before [laughs]." But yeah,
that's the greatest thing about
my new job, is the first time --
that it started out as a
training thing where everybody
comes in and then they train for
-- not everybody, but this one
program I started called
Jumpstart. It was eight weeks of
training. And it just got you
used to a lot of different
things and
then you got assigned to a team.
So now you're thrown in, you're
the new one. And the first
time I paired with someone or
shadowed someone, I was kind of
terrified. I was like, "They're
gonna think I know stuff and I
don't know anything [laughs]."
And it
was beautiful. He was talking
about what was going on. He
asked like, "Have you seen this
before? Are you familiar with
this?" I mean,
it was just -- and he's just a
developer. He's- he's not a
teacher. He wasn't taught how to
deliver new content, how to make
things feel risk-free, you know?
He doesn't have the pedagogy that
a teacher has. He was just a
natural and it was amazing. And
then I paired with somebody
else. And it was kind of the same
thing. Everybody I've worked with
on my team. I'm very lucky, has
sort of been that way. It's like
learning is part of their, like,
whole culture. And it's real.
It's not just, you know, we say
we do this and then you're left
on your own. So I've been lucky.
Bekah: I love that. I think
that's-
Shelley: Yeah.
Bekah: -so important to have
that culture,
that it -- that everybody
is on the same page rather than,
I think some places say like,
"We have a learning culture,"
and then they force people to-
to teach when they don't want
to. Or-
Shelley: Mm-hmm [chuckles].
Bekah: -they're like, "In
addition to all of these other
tasks that totally
fill your day, you also have to
teach now. And we're not going
to support you in knowing how to
really do that effectively." And
then you see so many negative
situations that come out of that,
you know, people feeling not
confident with their own skills,
thinking that, you know, I'm not
ready for this job or this
career, or whatever. But really
it's an issue with the culture
that's not supporting them.
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: I wanna backtrack --
Shelley: And it's not authentic.
Yeah. Go ahead.
Bekah: Yeah, sorry. I just
wanted to backtrack to Collab Lab
because you mentioned it and I
think they're doing great stuff.
And for our listeners who aren't
familiar with Collab Lab, can you
just give kind of an overview of
what it is and what you did at
-- where- where were you in your
journey from bootcamp to first
job working with Collab Lab?
Shelley: Mm-hmm. Oh, I'd love to
tell the world about Collab Lab.
So it is ... it's an in between.
It's post-bootcamp, but it's not
really an apprenticeship or an
internship. The program was built
by Andrew and Stacy — and
probably a couple other people
I'm forgetting — a few years
ago. Because they realized that
bootcamps were the thing that's
-- this is -- they grew huge,
that's where a-
a lot of new engineers were
coming from. And we don't wanna
talk hours about bootcamps, but
they've got a lot of positives.
You learn a lot of stuff, you're
exposed to a lot of stuff, you
build some skills, but they don't
teach you how to work as an
engineer. And I guess you could
probably say that about
undergraduate programs too. You
don't learn how to work on a
team, you don't, you know, learn
how to deal with that kind of
stuff. So Collab Lab's goal is
to give you a more real-world
experience of getting a full
story of a project that you're
supposed to build, a team of
developers — so it's a group of
four developers, and the tickets
are all already done for you,
and the acceptance criteria. And
you kind of have to figure it
out. So it's not all perfect, at
least sanitized, like- like your
homework assignments in
bootcamp. And you have a little
bit of freedom to, you know,
make mistakes and go your own
path. You're- you're not --
you're -- it's not dictated
exactly what techniques you're
supposed to use.
It's React, it's Firebase, the
rest is up to you.
Do whatever you want. Whatever
packages you think you're gonna
need, whatever path you're gonna
take. And you build ... it was a
shopping app. I think it still
is. And you have mentors
assigned. So you get 3 mentors,
which is an amazing
ratio of, like, professional
support to newbies. So it's 4
developers and 3 mentors. And
we did it in weeklong sprints.
So you decide your tickets, we
worked in pairs — it's all about
pair programming. And so we
paired up, and we changed partners
each week, and we went through our
ticket. And we're supposed to
spend about four or five hours a
week. And then, we'd have a
retro at the end of each week.
Oh, we also have an office hours.
I forgot about office hours. So
you have a chance to- to meet
with the -- your mentor and just
talk about problems or whatever.
And it's all communication over
Slack. I mean, the support is
unreal. I know I'm kind of like
just bouncing all over the place
instead of just presenting. But I
get filled with a lot of emotion
when I think about [laughs] this
program and I can't stay on
track. So
then at the end of the week, we
have the retro, you demo the
little piece that you built.
And then, we also had some, I
think there were a couple little
workshop-y type things on stuff.
Like, we had one workshop on
accessibility cuz that's not
covered well in bootcamp.
They basically try and fill all
these little holes. And to give
you some real experience and
confidence. And so that's an
8-week program, and they do
four cohorts a year. And then at
the end of the eight weeks,
you've got a project, you've got
an amazing project to put on
your portfolio that's not
like everybody else's, you know,
Pomodoro timer and sho- I was
gonna say shopping list. To-do list.
That's it. The infamous to-do
list that everybody's built.
So you have a, you know, more
unique fun project and a lot more
to talk about. And then the last
two weeks, if you're interested,
is Career Lab.
And that's the part that I've
gotten involved with. Because
that changed everything for me.
You spend a week doing
similar type things. You have
some tasks, you meet with a
couple of men -- volunteer mentors
to update your LinkedIn is
the first week. And the second
week is interviewing, which
nothing they do in bootcamp
prepares you for interviewing.
So, you get to watch mock
interviews. You get a bunch of
practice interview questions.
They pair you up with another
collabie — that's what we're
called — so that you can sort
of practice your answers. And
then you do two practice
interviews — a behavioral and a
tech interview. There's even a
tech project that you build and
then go into the interview to
present what you did. So it's
much more realistic. And tech
interviews were- were my- my
killer thing. I had several of
them before, and after, and during
Collab Lab. And that's where I
tanked. My brain would shut
down. I could- could not -- I
couldn't code anymore. It's like
I knew nothing. Like, and- and it
was just awful experience. And
so I kept doing it because
everyone told me that's
what it was gonna be like. And
I kept pushing through.
But I never got better at them.
There were a couple of good ones
because the interviewers treated
it like pair programming. But
mostly, it was some dude sitting
back in dead silence watching me
burn [laughs]. And I just don't
respond well to that. So when we
went through Career Lab, they
kind of showed us how to tell our
story, how to lead the interview a
little bit, to say the things we
wanted to say, where to take
chances, you know, stuff like
that. And I had an interview
about three or four weeks after, I
think, the Career Lab with my
current employer. And I just --
I channeled the whole thing. I'm
just like, "I'm going to do this,
this way." And it was phenomenal.
It was like magic. I- I- I
felt great. I did fantastic.
Every question he asked, I
understood and could answer. I
felt- I felt really, really good.
And I had a couple other good
interviews too. So I ended up
getting two offers.
Bekah: Yeay!
Shelley: Yeah. And so I got to
choose. That was the
craziest thing after a year of,
you know, fingernail biting, I
got two offers in a week and got
to pick the one that I liked
the best.
Bekah: That's really awesome and
we were chatting a little bit
before we started recording
about the difference between
interviewing and preparing for a
job in tech versus other careers
and how it is so different. Can
you talk a little bit more about
that?
Shelley: Sure. The biggest
difference is how many rounds of
interviews, I think. Because I've
had a lot of teaching interviews.
Before I was a teacher, I had all
kinds of weird jobs all over the
place in different industries.
And it was typically one
interview, possibly a second.
But I feel like I've been -- every
job I've gotten, I think was one
interview, you know? They- they
saw your resume, they chatted
with you on the phone for a few
minutes, you sat fast to --
face to face for half an hour,
an hour. And maybe
you didn't get the offer right
then, you know? Maybe they slept
on it? But you didn't get called
in again, and again, and again.
You don't have to perform ... hm.
Perform. That's the right word.
Bekah: That's the right word.
Yeah.
Shelley: You don't have to
perform live. And it's funny
cuz I'm a teacher. I'm used to
performing live. That's what I
do. But in something I'm an
expert in-
Bekah: Yep.
Shelley: -you know? Give me-
give me an interview for a
teaching job today. I'm gonna --
I haven't done it in two years,
but I guarantee I'll knock
everyone else out of the water.
But I'm a newbie. I'm a beginner.
I'm a novice. I love it. I love
it when something works. I think
JavaScript is loads of fun.
But I don't know it like that.
So you ask me something live and
I choke. So, so many rounds of
that is- is traumatizing. I
don't know any other word for
it. Like, the first couple
rounds are fine, and the
behavioral interviews, I always
did fine.
Bekah: Yeah.
Shelley: But as soon as it
started getting technical, it's
like, "I don't know this well
enough to be tested." And it's
a test.
Bekah: Yeah.
Shelley: Really a test.
Bekah: That's a good point. I
think there was one role I
interviewed for where I went
through six interviews
[chuckles]. And then
didn't get the job. I was like,
"Oh, wow. That- that was really,
really intense." But- but
you're right. I've never had
that anywhere else. I think,
tops, I've had three interviews
for something and the last was
probably more of a compensation
interview. You know-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -talking through that
kind of stuff. But
the process is -- and it seems
pretty standard that you just
continually go through these
rounds and it does get really
intense and stressful. And I
remember somebody on Twitter,
early in my career, calling it
soul crushing. And I thought,
"Well, it can't be that bad."
Shelley: Yeah, it's pretty
intense. Yeah [laughs].
Bekah: And- and then what I had
to -- I'm like, "Oh, yeah. Yeah,
it is. It is that bad." Like
[laughs] ... it's really
exhausting.
Shelley: Yeah.
Bekah: And it's -- especially,
I, you know, mentioning that you
had different kinds of
interviews. Like, where some
people would just sit back and,
like, stare at you. And-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -you know, how -- I don't
know how they expect people to
perform in that
situation when you're already
nervous. I think that you should
be doing your best to support the
person on the other side of the
screen so you can see how they
perform at their best, you know?
Because you're- you're not going
to be in that situation most
days where it's awful and
somebody is really putting the
pressure on you.
Shelley: Someone described it to
me as hazing, and that clicked.
So, and- and there are -- it- it
-- I had both experiences. There
were definitely people who were
interviewing so that I could show
my best. Definitely. And then
we would just reach a point where
I'd, you know, maxed out my
knowledge and me, personally,
didn't handle that well.
Bekah: Mm.
Shelley: And some people told me
that that's
part of it too. Like, how do you
respond when you don't know what
to do? And even then, it's so
artificial because it's like, if
I don't know what to do, I'm
gonna send you a message, call
you, whatever, and go, "Hey, I
can't figure this out." But you
don't feel comfortable doing
that with a complete stranger
when a job is on the line.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Shelley: So, yeah. I definitely
have likened it to PTSD and all
[chuckles] sorts of traumatic
stuff. When I finally signed the
contract, and it was official
and done, and I wasn't gonna
start for
about five weeks, that's another
thing. That's really different
in tech too, that you might not
start for weeks and weeks because
they just have their onboarding
schedule or whatever. I
collapsed. I just stopped doing
anything. And I gave myself
permission to. I was like, "This
was the craziest ride ever."
And it's funny. Everyone's like,
"Oh, it's a full-time job to get
a job." It's maybe not full-time.
But the stress and the psychic
energy involved is
exhausting as working 40 or 60
hours a week. There's no- no
doubt about it. And there's a
lot of when it rains, it pores.
I had one week where I was
juggling ... I think five or six
applications all in different
places. Like, one
was make the perfect, you know,
cover letter all the way to this
is the final tech interview and
you're gonna present something
that you've built over the
course of a week. Like, just --
it was nuts. So yeah, that is
kind of like a full time job
[laughs].
Bekah: Well, I always try and
encourage people to take time off
in between jobs and starting
their new job.
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: And a lot of it's for
that reason.
Because it's- it's important to
get kind of healthy
habits set up, especially if
you're working from home.
Finding that space to be able to
navigate in between your job and
your home life can be really
challenging. But because that
interviewing stress can be so
intense, it -- it's good to
breathe before you jump right
in. And it sounds like you had a
pretty good onboarding
experience with your 8-week --
I ca-
Shelley: Yeah.
Bekah: -Jumpstart?
Shelley: Jumpstart. Yep.
Bekah: That sounds really great,
rather than- than just being
thrown into, "All right. Here's
some work. Now do it!" [Laughs]
You know? Where it can be-
Shelley: Mm-hmm. Figure it out.
Bekah: -equally stressful because
you don't know how to communicate
or what the process for things
is. And it sounds like Jumpstart
helped to establish good paths
of communication.
Shelley: Yeah, it's a- it's an
amazing program. And it is a
program. It's something that
Rightpoint — that's my company —
developed like three or four
years ago. So they've had, you
know, about eight cohorts at this
point. And they've found that
it's just a really good way to
bring in new engineers, you know,
junior level that don't know
anything. So we're all either
bootcamp grads, or recent grads,
or were a couple of computer
science grads too. Most of us
had jobs in other industries. So
that part of the skill set we
had. We just hadn't worked,
you know, on an engineering
team, and, you know, Agile
development, and all of
that, and sprints. So we got to
learn that, and shadow people
all over the company, and work
through training stuff. And also
had assignments and, you know,
we were cohort. It was a really
great way to do it. And so it
felt kind of like school, but on
the job. And then when we got
put on a team, we're still
consider, you know, novices.
So I've been doing new training
cuz you know, there's things that
my team uses that other teams
don't use. I've been learning
about Optimizely and will
probably be the- the person on
the team that knows the most in
a couple of months because I got
that- that task of learn
Optimizely so that we can start
using it on our project.
So that's been fun and ... it's
just- just been great. Actually
you've caught me the really,
really good week. I have to brag
for a minute.
Bekah: Do it!
Shelley: I haven't sh- I
haven't shared this in tech
spaces yet. Today's Thursday. So
on Tuesday, I put in my first
PR as a professional engineer.
Bekah: Yeay!
Shelley: And it has, it's only
gotten-
Dan: Nice.
Shelley: -reviewed and approved
once. It's not merged yet, so
that's what I'm
waiting, for the merge, before I
make the official announcement.
But I am so excited because it
was something that I wrote all
by myself. They wanted -- and it
-- they've -- that's- that's
part of it too. This is part of
the learning thing. They don't
just throw you
at the codebase and say, "Figure
it out." The first task I was
given was there's something that
they do manually, every time,
that's tedious copying and
pasting of translations. Cuz
we're a global company, so every
time we launch a site, it's the
same site for a different country
or language. Everything has
to be translated. Every single
button, every single everything,
description has to have a new
translation. And we're not gonna
build a whole new site for it.
So they just do this manually.
They send a CSV to a translation
team, they get the 800
translations,
and then somebody copies and
paste them into a file. And so
they're like, "We need to
automate this. Shelley, do it."
[Laughs] I'm just
like, "Are you kidding? I don't
know the codebase. I don't know
anything. You want me to do
this? Okay, cool." So I built a
CLI. And I'm so proud of it, and
it works, and I might be demoing
it this morning. Yeah. So. And-
and it was not that big a deal.
Dan: Awesome.
Shelley: Anyone else would look
at it would be like, "Oh, that's
cute." [Laughs]
Bekah: No, that's a big deal.
Shelley: Yeah, it's mine
[laughs].
Bekah: And then, uh, have a big
impact, I think, on the
processes there and making
people's lives easier. So-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -I think that's really,
really-
Shelley: Yeah.
Bekah: -important.
Shelley: Yeah. Other people will
use it, maybe, once a month for
the next six months, and then
it'll go away. But that's okay
[chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. So, okay. So
you've been through this whole
process. And I think that you've
shared a lot of really great
information and I appreciate you
sharing your story. So what
advice would you give to somebody
who is maybe towards the end of
their bootcamp and thinking about
what the next step should be.
Shelley: It's- it's -- I think
it's really an individual thing.
So I
think the best advice I could
give is asking yourself what
exactly you want and what's
important to you. Because
where you're at in life's gonna
make a difference. I've had this
conversation actually with
someone at The Collab Lab of,
you know, what next? If you are
young and you don't have kids or
responsibilities, you know,
you're in a very different place
in your career no matter what
field you're in. But definitely
in tech, you know, you could
sign up with one of those two
year contract programs where
they train you, and hire you
out, and you make crap money,
but get great experience.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Shelley: But you have to live
someplace weird or you don't
get a good enough salary. And
you're stuck for two years. I'm
not at that place in my life. I
got a
little paranoid towards the end
of- [chuckles] of this journey.
It took seven
months after bootcamp to get my
job. So somewhere around the
five or six month mark was like,
"Maybe I am gonna sign up.
Maybe- maybe that is what I'm
gonna do." But something in me
all along said, "You need to
find the place that fits you.
And being assigned a contract
for a client wasn't gonna
achieve that." Even if
I didn't care about the money,
even if I didn't care about the
flexibility, I wasn't gonna get
to pick where I went. And I
realized that was critically
important. And honestly, the- the
interview process taught me that
too. I met some amazing people
and I met some horrible people.
Like, "Okay, yeah, you made me
cry and I don't wanna work for
you," you know? Like, thank you
for that. You took a half an
hour after the crying to go,
"Okay, wait. Thanks for that. I
don't wanna work for you." So,
for me -- so, if a person is
like me, interviewing the
company, finding
that spot, really doing your
research of who they say they
are, and then, once you get into
the interview process, if
they're gonna force you to do
five interviews, force them to
do five interviews.
Bekah: Hm.
Shelley: Ask them the questions.
Really dig into who
they are and what they're about.
Because for me, that was what
was I decided was most important.
I needed to find a place where
the people ... felt right, you
know? The product would be nice
too, you know? I ended up in
e-commerce. That's not a thing I
ever would've predicted
[chuckles] at all. I'm all about
education, and
nonprofit, and, you know,
whatever. And I love these
people. I mean, they're- they're
amazing. And they're -- it's --
it just so happens that commerce
is their thing. So now commerce
is my thing until the next thing
comes around. But ... also
f-finding people, I guess that's
it too. This is could be really
isolating. It's amazing that we
can do this all virtually.
But that also means that you're
all by yourself. So you have to
find communities, you have to
find other people that are in
the same boat as you. That's why
Collab Lab was so good. Cuz
it's filled with people that are
looking for their first role, or
just found their first role, or
are there to support people
finding their first role. Like,
that's the entire focus. And
in a really loving, supportive,
fun way. Not a, you know,
commercial way, the way the- the
career services in bootcamp are,
where they're just, "We're gonna
get you a job, so apply to 800
things." But honestly, that
works for some people too, you
know? The- the numbers
game of applying to every single
thing and hoping something
sticks. I got turned off of
that really, really quick. So I
just got really picky and
choosy. I had my schedule. I
gotta find one
or two things, three things a
week that really mean something
and apply to them. Oh, and
cover letters. Cover letters,
cover letters, cover letters. I
don't care what anyone says,
they make a difference.
Bekah: I love cover letters.
Shelley: And if they don't make
a difference, then you don't
need to work there [chuckles].
Dan: [Chuckles] That- that adv-
that advice about getting picky
about things, you know, you're
not the first person on the
podcast to have that
advice. A-and I think it's --
it- it makes a lot of sense to
me, you know? I -- you can get
the -- like numbers game
approach, you know, can make
some sort of logic sense, you
know? I mean, like, I- I can
understand the logic behind it.
But the -- everyone that we've
talked to that has gone through
like a- a long and especially,
like, a hard journey like that,
I think comes out on the
other side. Like, they finally
-- like, some people, like, were
thro- throwing out thousands of
interviews and then eventually
started getting picky, you know?
And- and some people started that
way to start. But it seems like
the people that are happy with
their roles, you know, it --
after the awful journey of the
interview process, you know?
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Dan: The people that have found,
like, the people --
that -- the companies that they
liked, have all been -- they've
all said this similar things of,
you know, find- find companies
that, like, either the people or
the- the product or whatever are
meaningful and do the research
and all that stuff.
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Dan: And- and, yeah. Yeah,
narrow your scope.
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: I think that's great. I
mean, I think that's a great
advice.
Shelley: I mean, it's- it's
tough. It's big risk because,
you know, it's really expensive
to be unemployed. And if, god
forbid,
you're actually working a job
while trying to find a job, I- I
couldn't even imagine that. I
was very, very, very lucky that,
you know, my wife had health
insurance, and I had savings, so
I could work a part-time TA job
and do just fine for seven
months. And I know not everyone
can do that. And it might take
more than seven months. I think I
also got really lucky. But
yeah, I'm really- I'm really,
really glad that I was picky,
that I kept telling myself
that's- that's what I needed to
do. And there was always a
little voice going, "You're
being stupid.
Just get a job," you know? "This
is- this is- this is not real.
You're not gonna be able to
find the right job this way."
And then it works. So, [laughs]
not very scientific, but I'm
gonna say, "Yes, do it that
way."
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I think, you know, that-
that point that you made about
having support behind you is
really important. Especially
to new folks who are coming into
tech. Because I think that
there's often these promises
that tech is this goldmine, and
you're gonna
find a great job, and a great
career, and- and it will, you
know, help you with your life
situation. So, we see so many
career changers and then,
they're doing this thing where
they do have seven months and
they can't find a job. And so-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -they're -- I think it's
really important that we talk
openly about, like, it's
hard, first of all. You're
going to have to go through this
really rigorous interview
process, and then after that,
you might not get a job. So you
need to plan on taking, I would
say at least six months-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -to look for a job. And
then, also, I think that it can
really impact relationships with
the people who are close to you,
you know? Because-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -they're supporting you
as you're going
through this situation. And I've
seen relationships break up
because the partner says, "Oh,
yeah. I am totally supportive
and I am here for you." But
without really understanding how
stressful this situation can be.
And, "Hey, I'm really sorry, but
I'm gonna have to put in four
more hours tonight because I've
gotta get this take home test
done-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -so I can go to this job interview." And
I know, you know, my husband,
Jesse, was a career transitioner
before I was into tech. And at
the time, I didn't understand
it, you know? He was like going
to work, and then coming home,
and like, "Oh, I've gotta do
FreeCodeCamp and all this
stuff." An I'm like, "Dude,
I've been with the kids all
day." Like [laughs] --
Shelley: Yeah [laughs].
Bekah: And then, once I came
into tech, it- it all made
a lot more sense. Like, "Uh-oh.
Now I understand this."
But I wasn't prepared for that
in terms of like being a
supportive partner and knowing
where that would get us as a
family. And I'm like, "This is a
long-term investment, but it's-
it's gonna be hard."
Shelley: Yeah. My wife said
something. It was a couple weeks
after I got the job, before I
started. And, you know, one of
those heartfelt moments, and she
was like, "You're incredibly
strong." And I'm like, "What are
you talking about?" [Laughs]
I was like, "I cry so much," you
know, or whatever. And she's
like, "The last seven months,
you worked so hard, and it was
so uncomfortable, and so
painful, and
so traumatic, and so emotional,
and- and just, you know, all of
these things." And she goes,
"Besides the fact you shocked
everything and learned this new
thing. Like, you put it all out
there." And I was like, "Oh,
gosh, you're right [laughs].
I guess I am."
Yeah, I don't think anyone can
get just how hard it is. And
I'm sure lots of career
transitions are tough. But
yeah, this- this particular one
comes with a huge amount of hype
and fanfare. And the slog is not
something, you know, you're
necessarily prepared for. Oh,
and the rejection. Holly
goodness. I've never been
rejected for so many things
[laughs].
Bekah: It's worse than high
school. Like [laughs] --
Shelley: Yeah. Like [laughs], I
mean, I- I get it. I get it.
Totally, you
know? You're gonna, "I'm not the
perfect fit. I don't have a
problem with that." But there's
something about that third or
fourth interview, and you're
like, "Oh, I've gotta have it
now." No. That's- that's still
the beginning of the process
[laughs]. Because there were a
lot of times where I made to the
third or fourth step and then,
didn't go further. So --
Bekah: Yeah.
Shelley: Oh, it's the worst
thing.
Bekah: I was invited to apply
for two positions a while
back. And I didn't get either of
those positions. And they also
had really long interview
processes. And I was talking to
a- a ... partner who owns a
consultancy afterwards, and just
saying, "This was really tough."
He was like, "Yeah, it's really-
it's really mind blowing that
you didn't get either of those."
[Laughs] "Yeah, it is!" Like
[laughs] -- they're like, "Well,
it came down between you and one
other person. I'm like, "Well,
that's great." Like -- but
[laughs] --
Shelley: Oh yeah, I got one of
those. Actually, it was really
-- I got the form letter email
that said it came down to one
other person and he actually,
the -- put a PS at the end. And
I could read between the lines,
he wanted me with somebody else
or-
Bekah: Yeah.
Shelley: -whatever wanted the
other person. So, it was really-
Dan: Yeah.
Shelley: -clear. And he said
something
like, "If you ever need
mentorship, reach out." I mean-
Bekah: That's [unintelligible].
Shelley: -and again, it was that
reminder of- of just how good
parts of this industry and
community are.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Shelley: Like, that mentorships
built-in. It's not
always- not always perfectly.
But that- that was like a- a
totally normal thing for him to
offer. And from my perspective
coming in, that's so generous
that this is a person you
interviewed. You- you spent an
hour and a half with them, you
know? And you're offering to
have coffee, meet up with them,
and help them in their career.
Like-
Bekah: Yeah.
Shelley: -that's just crazy. But
also, wonderful.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, it's -- it --
that -- so, thinking about it
from the
other side, like I- I -- well, I
haven't hired a lot of people.
But again, my wife [laughs] has
gone through the hiring process
of- of
fair number of times over the
last year or two. And she's had
those same struggles. Like, she
really want -- loves a person
and then, you know,
somebody else, whatever. And-
and it's- it's hard on them.
And it like, it's hard on
everybody. Like, the whole
process is just hard, you know?
Like -- a-and that doesn't --
I don't think probably
make it easier to feel like to-
to- to accept the rejections,
you know? But it's just like,
this whole process is just a
nightmare, you know [laughs]?
Like --
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I don't know what we could
do to
fix it. But like, it is. It is
so hard. It's so, like,
emotionally fraught, you know?
I- I don't --
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: I don't know. I don't
really have a- [laughs]
a suggestion to fix it, but it
... it's really is.
Bekah: I feel like part of this,
like, what we're doing right now
is making a way to fix it,
right? Having open conversations
about these things. Talking about
the problems, talking about our
experiences to help other people
through the situation is- is a
start to making an improvement
with how the industry does
things.
Dan: At least prepare people for
it [chuckles], you know?
Shelley: Yeah. Well, and
acknowledge the people that do
it better. The interviewers that
do it-
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: Yes.
Shelley: -better.
Dan: Yes.
Shelley: They need to get that
feedback too.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
Shelley: So that more- more do
that. Yeah.
Dan: Yeah. Like the- the dude
that -- the dude that would sit
and watch you and glare at you,
right? When you're doing your
interview. Like,
it- it's such a- it's such a --
I mean, it's bad just like as a
person, you know? I mean, it's
obviously just like not a nice
thing to do. But it's also,
like, it's a bad advertisement
for their- for their employer,
you know? And-
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: -I don't know. And that is
like -- that actually is a
problem in tech is that lots of
people in the hiring process are
not -- they're not, like, HR
people. They're not-
Shelley: Mm-hmm.
Dan: -like, people that are
doing hiring. At smaller- at
smaller places it can -- in tech
is like a lot of small shops,
right?
Shelley: Yeah.
Dan: And so, you just have
developers, like, just get told,
"Hey, run this interview." You
know what I mean? [Laughs] And
that is with no training,
you know, or anything like that,
probably. And that's a
problem too. I don't know.
There's problems everywhere.
Shelley: Yeah. Yeah. But let's
start fixing 'em [chuckles].
Dan: Yeah. Alright.
Bekah: Alright, Shelley. Thank
you for spending time with us
today. Do you have any last bits
of wisdom or any wins you wanna
share before we go?
Shelley: Oh, just that I think
I'm about to go do a demo. So
that's my- my- my win.
Bekah: Yeay.
Shelley: I'll -- I've done a lot
of demos,
but they've all been, you know,
mock demos. This will be the
first time I share something
that I've built. so I'm really
excited about that.
Dan: That's awesome.
Shelley: And ... yeah. I think
Virtual Coffee's probably
responsible for a lot of it.
That's how I found ...
Collab Lab. Cuz Ayu talked about
it. I'm like, "What is this
thing you're talking about?" And
I think it was, like, the day
before the deadline for the-
Dan: Nice.
Shelley: -cohort. And that I
signed up for it.
Yeah. So it all comes around.
Bekah: Awesome.
Shelley: That's my advice. Meet people-
Bekah: Yeay.
Shelley: -talk to people. Come
to Virtual Coffee [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah. Alright.
Dan: I think that's a good
advice.
Bekah: Thanks so much, Shelley.
Shelley: Thank you.
Dan: Thanks, Shelley.
Shelley: Bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week!