Bekah: Hello and welcome to
Season 6, Episode 9 of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. We are
live because this is our season
finale and we are very excited to
be here with you. Virtual Coffee
is a group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey,
and they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned. But really it's
the last episode of the season.
And so it is the three of us
sharing our stories and what
we've learned. So, we'll do
an intro question in a second,
but do you want to, does
anybody wanna give us an intro
question? Hey, Deborah-Kaye!
Kirk: Do you want to use the
one from VC? Oh, that might be a
spoiler for when this was done,
but like today Oh, I didn't hear
dance cause he wasn't in my room
and I don't think he could make
it. So the question is, do
you like sour? And if you do,
what is your favorite sour food?
And Bekah is already making faces
so.
Bekah: name's Bekah. I'm a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and sour is
the worst. Like I am pretty open
about different tastes, but I
draw the line at sour it. If I
drink like any kind of sour beer,
I immediately have heartburn and
sour just makes your face go
like, and that means it's bad, so
hard. Pass on sour. I will take
bitter all day long.
Dan: Alright. Hi, I am Dan. I
do computer things in Cleveland
and I don't judge. Foods
based on facial expressions, You
know, in general, I, I, I
like, I like some sour things.
You know, I, I definitely like a
little bit of sour in a lot of
things, you know? I, like, we had
tacos the night, squeeze the line
lime on top of the chicken,
really, really good. It doesn't
make like the whole taco taste
sour, you know what I mean? But
it's just like that
Bekah: Well, I like citrus that
doesn't really count as sour.
Dan: I, Okay. I mean, like, it's,
it's just like a little touch of
it, you know what I mean? That's,
that's what I mean. But I don't
like, like I, I, I was saying
this in, in the room, I, you
know, I'll eat like a, like a
sour patch kids, you know, for
instance, which is like, sort of
sour. It's mostly sugar anyway,
but like, definitely my last
choice of, of, from the
Halloween bucket that my kids
always have full of candy somehow
all year round, so yeah,
that's, that's my answer. I'm
ambivalent. Citrus, I'm a
huge fan of, and I think sour is
part of the citrus thing, you
know? So I can't just say I don't
like
Bekah: because I love citrus.
Dan: Fair enough. What up, Kirk?
Kirk: I have, I have a lot you've
been saying. So, Okay. So first
of all, first of all, my name is
Kirk. Let's just get outta the
way. That's not, that's
irrelevant at the moment. In
our room, immediately we get the
discussion of does citrus count?
And I said, yes, because. I'm
gonna say this thing that I hate,
I don't want to yuck anyone's
yum. Which now also feels like a
sour
Dan: Didn't, Didn't we make a
rule that you weren't allowed to
say that anymore?
Kirk: That was so long ago. You
know? But
Dan: to be one of the worst
phrases in the entire world.
Kirk: but also like everything
you said about why you don't
like, like I, I want sour things
like once a. And when I eat, I do
make the faces of like a baby
when they're given. Like I do all
of, I can't help it. And then
everyone around me just laughs at
my face. Like I just fully lean
into that. You know, it's like
those old lemon drop candies.
Like I just, I do it and then,
you know, like my soul just like
shutters and then it's great.
But it's like pepper, right? Like
we're not supposed to eat.
Pepper, Right? Like peppers want,
like birds. Birds can't. Birds
don't care about capsaicin. So
plants made spicy so that mammals
wouldn't eat the food. Birds lead
the food cuz birds travel farther
and distribute the seeds farther,
Like. When they poop. But like
humans or mammals we're just
like, Hey, this like hurts. But
I'm kind of into it and that's
why we're already doing stuff
that we're not supposed to be
doing. Right. Like sours supposed
to be like, this is probably not
meant to be consumed, as is
bitter. But here we are. So just
lean into it. It's bad because
it's good. It's bad cuz it's
good. Put it on a t-shirt. That's
my intro.
Bekah: I've never heard anyone
say it that way. And also I will
do what I want with this stream
because I have the power. If
you're listening, I discovered
that I can change the way things
look, and this is going to be
fun.
Kirk: This is what?
Dan: Mm. That's great.
Bekah: So welcome everybody to
this live podcast. Thanks for
all those who are joining us
live. If you have a question or
if you have a topic that you want
to hear us talk about, go ahead
and put that in the chat and
we'll do an excellent job of
keeping up with it at all times,
Dan: We promise
Bekah: All right, why don't we
get started with what's going on
now at Virtual Coffee? So, so Dan
is in his pumpkin jacket, so I
think it's appropriate if he
starts this conversation,
Dan: Hello, my name is Daniel t
Pumpkins. Yes, I've, I've
started referring to this as my,
my pumpkin regalia. I don't know
if I'm using that correctly, but,
Oh, we lost Kirk. He'll be back.
Oh, there he is. I don't know
where he went, but he's back.
Hello. So,
Kirk: internet has been
Dan: all right, well, hopefully
we don't lose you for good.
You're back for now. What is,
oh, what is going on in Virtual
Coffee right now? It's
Hacktoberfest. And so we've
mentioned this a couple times on,
I don't know if we've mentioned
it recently on the pod. We've
been talking about it a lot in
Virtual Coffee. So
Hacktoberfest is a month long
sort of celebration of open
source, right? And, it.
Originally it's, I mean,
originally and still is run by a
company called Digital Ocean, and
they do a monthly thing every
year. And, the object is
really, so for, contributors
to submit four, poll requests
in the month of October and have
them accepted, you know,
hopefully. And, if you can
hit that goal, then they, you
know, celebrate you and usually
send some swagger or something
like that as well. And, they
do a really good job of doing
this and providing a lot of
resources for contributors and a
lot of resources for, open
source maintainers and things
like that. And so we, couple
years ago decided to,
piggyback on that and basically
help our idea two years, three
years ago, was to help our
members get, you know, get the,
the Hacktoberfest
accomplished, you know, And
so that was, yeah, that was three
years ago. We did this the first
time in Virtual Coffee and we had
a lot of fun. And last year we
had, a huge number of people.
Join us and contribute a whole
bunch of awesome things to open
source projects. And, we're
doing it again. And so we have
add Virtual Coffee. We have a
Hacktoberfest, you know, room
where we have been chatting and
sharing lots of like, open issues
and, you know, providing help
and support for people. And we
have the Hack Hector Coworking
room, which is a special version
of our coworking room. You
know, for people who are
Hacktoberfestering and, yes,
that's the word. And, what
else's going on? Heto
Bekah: it's just "festing".
You're just "festing"
Hacktoberfesting.
Dan: I'm Hacktoberfestering. And
that's, Listen, who has the
jacket? Okay. me, And so I make
the rules and I, you know,
all decisions come through this
jacket.
Kirk: When you invited me to this
podcast, I thought I was coming
up here as a creative consultant.
So to hear this now was really,
uh,
Dan: Well, you know, what are you
gonna do,
Kirk: executive producer.
Dan: And so we're halfway, almost
halfway through October, and, you
know, we've had, I know a lot of
our members have been doing some
contributions. We have our
traditional issue on the Virtual
Coffee site that people can
complete to, you know, get one,
one of their poll requests in
to start us off. We have some
videos on our site for some of
our Hacktoberfest, things
that we've done so far this
month. And, yeah. Did I miss
anything about current event?
Bekah: Julia put in the chat. Dan
makes the rules. Bekah controls
the settings, and Kirk is an
unwitting victim. Again,
Dan: Sorry, not sorry. Yeah,
that's the,
Kirk: No, No. That captures our
dynamic pretty well. Julie is
right. She's insightful.
Bekah: don't know. I feel like
I'm gonna push back a little bit
against Dan makes the rules.
Dan: I mean, you can push back
all you want, but still I have
the jacket and so what are you
gonna do?
Bekah: I, this is, this is how my
criminal story starts. I will
come and take the jacket, if
that's where the power is. I will
acquire the jacket.
Kirk: Before you came on the
stream back, I was saying like
Dan in that jacket. I dunno if
anybody remembers like the
Bekah: Yes.
Kirk: It's, you know, Stanley, I
kiss. It's a similar sort of, you
know, there's this garment in
beauty of chaos and then he knows
he's not supposed to put it on,
but he does. Then he becomes this
entity, you know, And then we
just all have to deal with it
until the jacket comes. It's like
the Hulk, but for Hacktoberfest,
The Hulk Tober
Dan: I feel like Hulk
Bekah: Hulktoberfestering?
Dan: Loses clothes as he turns
into Hulk though, you know? So
Kirk: That's true.
Bekah: So the anti Hulk.
Dan: No, I'm not anti hok. I
love Hulk. Also shout she,
She-Hulk has been really awesome
too. So,
Bekah: That's exactly right. Tom
Cudd
Dan: Yes, Tom Cudd. And, yes.
So, Oh, Tom, I saw that you
followed us. Twitch, I think, I
think I get emails for some
reason every time somebody
follows us. So if you haven't
followed us on Twitch, please do.
If you haven't followed our
podcast, you can find the
link on our site, Virtual
Coffee.io and follow us on
Twitter too. Oh, slash podcast.
Yeah, there's links, but yes
slash podcast if you wanna go
right there. We have a bunch
of people in the chat that we've
actually talked to on the Virtual
Coffee podcast, so that's kind of
exciting.
Bekah: Yeah. And some of our
maintainers are here as well. And
contributors for Hacktoberfest.
So how's everyone's Hacktoberfest
going? Kirk, are you
Hacktoberfesting?
Kirk: I am Hacktoberfesting
in the way, and maybe this is
really relevant. I guess you've
had three Hacktoberfests before.
I had one where I was a
maintainer and that was super
cool. And I have one where I was
just a contributor and that was
also super cool. And this time I
feel like most of what I'm doing
has been mentoring and that has
also been super cool. So I'm
really, you know, I'm doing all
the things. I'm the real, I'm
getting the full experience just
spread across three years and
that's like totally okay. Right.
Which I feel like has been the
real. It's always sort of the
theme of Hacktoberfest, but
especially this time, you know,
like people are like, What do I
do? Or How come like it's, you
can do whatever you're
comfortable with or whatever you
want. Or like, if you do wanna
get outside of your comfort zone,
you know, like there's a
difference between stepping
outside your boundaries or
pushing your boundaries and like
jumping far away from it. Don't,
don't do that, but you know, if
you can find a little way to move
it, then I think it's been really
good. It's been really. I'm
Bekah: like I take the opposite
approach where I'm very resistant
to doing many of the things in
Hacktoberfest and then like two
days before I suddenly decide I'm
going to do all of the things,
Let's start new projects, let's
resurrect projects I haven't
worked on in a year. Let's
mentor, let's contribute. I'm not
really sure why, but I can't help
it. I just, I, I can't not do the
things cuz they're just, they
look so exciting.
Dan: Yeah, and I like, I, I'm
kind of with that too. One of the
things is, one of the things I
like about this is that it,
well, helps me, you know, having
like a date that a thing needs to
be done by or whatever helps me
do it. And that includes like
making a bunch of issues for the
re for the Virtual Coffee site
for instance. You know, I, I, I
know in my head a bunch of things
that need to be done and we can
use for an help on, it always
takes time and a little bit of
like, mental energy to write
those issues and, and so
sometimes they just, like, I
just, they get put on the back
burner. But since we had
Hacktoberfest coming up, it
was a really good time to, you
know, put some effort into doing
that and, and creating those
issues. And it's been really
awesome having people, having
people, contribute back to
the site, you know? And we,
we always have some contributors
throughout the year. But it,
it's, I dunno, it's been,
it's been fun having a bunch of
different people and all that,
like, shook kind of goes to show
like creating, create the issues
and probably people will come and
help out, you know, as a
maintainer, you know what I mean?
It's, it's like, One of those
things where, we now have a
bunch, I mean, there, there's
the, the member issue that
everybody, all of our Virtual
Coffee members are welcome to
like do, but the features and
stuff, it's, it's, you know, they
need to have the, the, the
options to work on, to do the
work, you know? And so it's been
really fun, kind of doing
back and forth with people and,
and getting some new stuff going.
So I've been enjoying that a lot.
Bekah: Tom says, It sounds like
we're learning from the current
Virtual Coffee book club start
finishing, which I wanted to get,
but I couldn't get in an audio
book format and I knew if I
ordered a hard copy, it would sit
with all the piles of hard copies
of books that I have yet to read.
Dan: Yeah. I need to
Kirk: have it in, That's the,
that's the only way I could
figure out how to read. But I did
find an audiobook format and it
is really good
Dan: Nice.
Bekah: I see. I don't have
Audible or understand how to use
Audible, so I don't audible
things.
Dan: What
Kirk: Bekah.
Dan: call
Bekah: Audible. Well cuz you have
to like sign up for Audible,
Right. And then you pay money for
Audible and then you have to pay
money for the books too, right?
Dan: Yeah. You get one free,
month, pretty sure. And then
you can
Kirk: Yeah, like your book token,
and you can like, Hey, here's
this token. Give a book. And if
you don't use your token for the
month, like stack up. And if you
want more, more. than the token,
then you,
Bekah: pay for them.
Dan: Yeah. But you pay for
tokens. So all books cost the
same amount. It's one token
Anyway, this is our audible
corner
Bekah: We are not sponsored by
Audible. We won't
Kirk: If you'd like
Bekah: I'll never be sponsored by
Audible
Dan: My gosh,
Kirk: any of the podcast
sponsors, you know, if you, if
you sell mattresses or shaving
stuff, or
Bekah: Therapy. That's on all of
my True Crime podcasts.
Kirk: dog, if you're listening,
if you're listening, Datadog.
Listen, we're we are, we are
ready. Yeah, no, but, the
book just to say like, I've been,
the, the process of making, and
we talk about this a lot, like
the process of making or ready
for contributions is a dance like
it's non. Evergreen chat out
to Nick Taylor. I love Nick
Taylor's been super active in
Theto channel and he in year and
have their project that they've
been working on, but I also
really appreciate how like as
soon as Nick sort of like spots
something's wrong, I feel like
he's like, Yeah, I should just
turn this into an issue. And he
just like, does it. And I feel
like part of, I probably. Make
things more than they need to. In
my head, I feel like I need to
craft like the perfect issue
every time. And I feel like he's
willing to just, Well, I'll get
it up there. If I need to fix it,
I'll fix it later. But it's
there. And it's like, yeah, you
can grab this if you want.
And it may end up being that he
was, the maintainer might end up
doing this thing, but it's like
you gave people a chance, like
try It I don't know. That
sort of ties into one of the
aspects of having an open source
repo is like that willingness to
let go. Like I have to let other
people sort of like be a part of
this thing and they don't think
like me and like I can put stuff
in an issue, but at the end of
the day, like they're the ones
figuring it out. And you sort of
have to be okay with that. And I
think, if you're somebody who
has, I wouldn't. Issues is weird.
If you have difficulties of sort
of like letting go of certain
things, like making it open
source is a great way to realize
like, Oh, I can't pour this cuz
I'll like, I'll stress myself
out. You sort have to kind of set
a tree and let it be a community
thing, an organic thing. And I, I
really like seeing like the
virtual I website. Like I really
say, Oh yeah, a bunch of people
have like helped make this what
it is and it's really cool.
Dan: It is really cool
Bekah: I think, you know, the
idea of letting it go and putting
it out there is a really good
one. Because I think too, like
sometimes as a maintainer or
somebody who's been working on a
project, you might get stuck on
an idea and somebody might come
along. They might have a better
idea or they might have a
different approach. And I think
that one of the fun things is
like keeping an open mind about
how, how people will understand
the project and taking their
feedback and building in a
process to have that feedback
because it's not. Just about
helping and supporting
contributors. I think it's about
learning as a maintainer too, and
that's been one of my favorite
parts. I actually think that my
favorite part of Hacktoberfest
for the last three years has been
being a maintainer and being able
to interact with others and the
all of our contributors, to learn
from them and to hear what they
have to say about things. And
that was an experience the first
year. I know that I didn't, I
didn't realize how much I would
learn from being a maintainer.
Kirk: Yeah. Um. I think that's a
great way to phrase it. Maybe
like entice people if you're
considering like, Oh, like a lot
of people with the framing is
like, Oh, I don't know enough to
be a maintainer. Right? I'm like,
But if you have an idea and you
wanna see it to a fruition, the
best way to learn about it might
be to like invite other people to
help you. And you just, just get
that for free. Like you get, get.
And you get, people are gonna
teach you stuff and you get to
finish the thing you wanted to
work on. Like, it's all, it's all
upsides here. And it's weird
where people work on my project
like, Hey, thanks for letting me
work on this. I'm like, You just,
I didn't know how to do that.
That's why I made the issue, you
know, this is great. Now I do and
it's done. I wish I could do this
for every aspect of my life. Like
my choice and other obligations,
you know, it's like, or it just
all the times where it's like, I
don't know how to do this thing
and like doing it by myself feels
like a real struggle. And we
talk sometimes on the slack about
like, neurodiversity and just
like people having different mode
and the things we have to do
sometimes just to figure things
out. And yeah, sometimes the
answer is, Oh, I just, I just
need some help on. An open
source feels a lot like that. I
wanna do this thing. I need some
help, and then they help me.
Bekah, no one noticed that your
camera went on, I promise, except
Bekah: It left for a while. This
keeps happening. I did a live
stream before this and I couldn't
give my camera to work, and then
midway in the middle of a
sentence, Mike, I just totally
disconnected. It was, it was
awesome.
Dan: Alright.
Kirk: It started, we had this, we
were talking about like old tech
and then we, it just became like
weird UIs and then just like all
the weird quirks of technology
that we have to deal with. And
then I'm like, Okay, cool. Now
that we've just been dunking on
technology for the last 10
minutes, everyone here who works
in this industry can get back to
talking about it. Sometimes,
but I guess, I don't know. It's
because we like the stuff that we
also notice the stuff and we talk
about it.
Bekah: I always, love it when
people in the wild. Make a
comment to me about technology.
They're like, Oh, technology, You
know? I'm like, Oh, yeah, I know.
Dan: Yeah, no, I, I said in the,
in the chat when we were talking
during that discussion, there's
nobody that hates computers more
than developers. like, like it
took my my wife a while to
really. And that, you know, but
now she's like, you know, she'll
have like her, her grandma ask if
I could like help her. I mean,
I'm fine to help her, but like,
she's like, Oh, he, he does
computer stuff. He loves
computers. And she's like, No,
he, he hates computers. I'm like,
I'm like, I really do.
Bekah: I had a friend ask me to
help with her printer, and I was
like, Oh, no, I don't. I don't do
printers. I, I, when my printer
doesn't work, I just buy a new
one, because that's easier than
trying to fix existing printers.
Dan: I worked it at, college.
And you know, so the job is
mostly just like going around to
professor's offices and fixing
their stuff and Yeah, we had a
rule like printers, you only
spend like five minutes trying to
fix whatever it is, and then you
throw it out and by and like give
them a new one. It's like
they're, they're always just
like, printers are nightmare.
They always have been. They still
are. They, I don't know why they
still are, but they definitely
are.
Bekah: I don't understand. I can
buy a printer and it works like
perfectly for 30 days and then it
like hits that mark and it just
dies. It doesn't do any of the
things that it did before. I feel
like it's making a decision to
not work.
Kirk: If you're willing to
indulge in conspiracy theories,
there's a perfectly valid
explanation,
Bekah: I am always here for the
conspiracy theories.
Kirk: But I was gonna say
this conversation, and it feels
like similar ones we've been
having for a while. Just about
like, and we said how vast this
like tech is as a word means, I
don't even know what it means.
Like it's just, there's so much
and it, it's weird because we say
things like software developer
and like those are two words.
Yes. I don't know what those
mean. And they have very little
to do with what my job is.
And then like words like full
stack or front end or backend,
it's like that's still so
incredibly vague as to be almost
ultimately useless. Like it
doesn't, I don't know what you do
when you say that at all. I could
guess and I would probably be
Dan: Yeah, we, we actually spent
our entire hour today Virtual
Coffee, talking about that exact
thing. Mostly cuz I said in my
intro that I don't like the word
full stack. And when I was
talking about myself, you know,
and like, I don't feel like it's
very descriptive for what I do.
And then that started a whole, a
whole thing but
Bekah: instead of saying full
stack, you just say you do things
with computers.
Dan: Yeah. At
Bekah: much, much better.
Dan: at yeah. Yeah, at
coffee. I ended up with, I do
Type E. Type E. So that's
Kirk: Like explain it like I'm
five the subreddit. It's like
what a computer format, like I do
type type, and then you just see
what. Recently I've been saying,
I've been like very specific.
It's like, Oh, I write JavaScript
sometimes in type script,
sometimes in Python, sometimes
and SQL sometimes. And sometimes
I'm clicking buttons in, and
that's that's what I do right
now. That will probably change
for six months or something.
Bekah: I was, at the hospital
with one of my kids. They had to
get a test, and the hospital
intake person asked, she was
like, Well, what do you do? And
in my mind what, what she really
wanted was just like a job title
so she could put it down on the
form. Right. And I was like, but
she said, What do you do? And so
I was panicked because I'm like,
how do I explain what I do? I do
things with the computer and code
and community and education and,
and I like went on this long
tangent about what I did. I was
like, Oh, my title, it's
technical community. It was like,
really, really, I, I don't
think that she was ready for that
at five 30 in the morning on a
Saturday.
Dan: Yeah, it's, yeah, I can, I
can feel that whole thing
happening every time.
Somebody asks me and or every
time I have to do an intro
Virtual Coffee, it's like, I'm
like, Well, do I do the half hour
discussion version or do I just
say I do computer things? Yeah.
Jesse was saying, Yeah, if
the, if you talk to somebody in
that are in tech, then you'd be
more, more descriptive. And if
it's somebody that doesn't know
anything, you say, I build
websites and apps, and that's,
that's mostly what I do too.
Yeah. So
Bekah: I don't do any. I don't do
that though,
Dan: Well, right now, I mean, you
know, Yeah. It's, it's a little.
but you have a job title right?
That you
Bekah: Yeah, that does make it
much difference. Well, she didn't
ask me my job title. She said,
What do you do? Which to me is
like, now I have to tell a story
of the thing that I do.
Kirk: Like, who are you like as a
person? And yeah, I will write it
in this form. There's a section
for it.
Bekah: what It felt like she
wanted my bio
Dan: So, uh
Kirk: Yeah. I mean,
Dan: Go ahead, Kirk.
Kirk: well, Dan, like you, and
then if I think of like how Bekah
would describe it role, if I
think of how it, there's the
overlap, like there's overlaps,
but I don't, I make an app for
people who. Apps and websites,
you know, so like, it's a very,
it's very similar, but I don't
know, just, Oh yeah, it's, I've
been trying to like sneak the
word meta into like, all aspects
of my life cuz it just feels
cooler if you can like, oh, like
a meta way.
Dan: Sponsored beta.
Kirk: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I mean, If they're tired of react
and they want something else
that's like super cool, just
saying, give a whole
Dan: Next time we, next time we
talk, Kirk's gonna show up with
like the NASCAR outfit and the
hat, you know, and the, like the
jersey and stuff. Except it's all
just gonna say me over place.
Kirk: I cannot describe to you
how foreign the entire concept of
NASCAR is to every aspect of. But
it looks cool. But yeah, but
just to say, I. Hacktoberfest
also, I feel like did that in a
big way of sometimes, especially
online spaces, you feel, what's
that word? It feels like everyone
around you sort of like doing the
same thing or you get that
feeling like everyone's doing the
same thing and then you start
comparing yourself to everyone
else cuz you're like, Ah,
everyone knows about like, React.
What I know about reactor, like
everyone knows about kit's, like
why? I know about kit. Like these
things. There's certain things
that we just talk about more and
you start like comparing yourself
to other people. Oh, everyone
knows about aws. Why aws? And
Hacktoberfest was like a real
like good reminder that there's a
lot going on here. You can only
know like 1% of 1%, like the very
thin slice. You probably like
what you have more in common of
people is what you don't know
than what you know. So when it
comes to open source, like you're
going to feel like a beginner in
some things and you're going
better in other things, and like
that's everyone's doing that all
at the same time and you really
shouldn't. really shouldn't like
compare yourself to others. They
have a whole life of experiences
that have led to like where they
are and what they feel good at.
And if you actually ask them,
they probably feel like you. They
probably, I also do not know what
I'm doing and I also feel like
everybody else online knows more
than me. And I also feel. You
know, I'm just, How did Julia's
daughter describe it as staring
at the screen for a couple
minutes and hitting control, said
75 times. That is how I feel all
that time, that is my job.
But yeah, hack to profess is a
really good reminder of that in a
way that doesn't feel like
destructive, but like feels
really healthy. You know, like
we're all trying to figure it.
It's like, it's like for one,
Everyone tries to figure
something out and like we all
accept that we're trying to
figure it out, and that's great.
Dan: Yeah, totally. And like the.
This is just, we talk about this
every, every time we talk about
Hacktoberfest, but like there's a
lot of, I don't know, there's
a lot of like social things that
go around with contrary to open
source, projects too. And
that, that, like, that is
something that causes anxiety for
me, you know? Especially,
especially when I hadn't really
done much contra, you know, open
source contributing before I
worked as a developer for a long
time before I ever, you know, did
any open source stuff. And that's
one of the things that we try to
push here too, like with our,
with our thing is not just like,
oh, writing code or whatever, but
how to, how to like, engage in a
community, an open source
community, whether it's a big one
or a small one. And you know, how
to, how to navigate that without
feeling, I mean, I suppose you're
always gonna feel nervous the
first time you do something, but
hopefully we can, you know, help
you kind of get, go along and,
and, and do it. And so
that's, that's one of our other.
One of, one of the other things
that we, we try to like
concentrate on is, is just,
helping people kind of start that
journey. You know? Cause once,
once you get a couple under your
belt, it becomes like, it opens
your eyes to all the things you
can do, and everything else
becomes a little more possible.
If, if you've done it a couple
times, you know, maybe in a
controlled environment like
adverse coffee.
Bekah: Well, it's nice too that
we have maintainers who are
members because they might be
maintaining a project for fun,
for Hacktoberfest to help people
get in, or they might be
maintaining a larger project for
work. But I think that when you
see other people who you know in
those larger projects, let's say,
and you have some experience
doing the things that we do at
Virtual Coffee, then it helps to
like create that path to being
able to take on things that maybe
you would've been too scared of
before, or, you know, to go
outside of Virtual Coffee to do
the things. And I think that, you
know, decreasing those barriers
to entry, providing support and
mentorship and that community
excitement around things goes a
long way to improving the
experience of everybody who's
involved in open source contribu.
Kirk: Yeah, it reminds me not to
get to mad enough, but, I've
been like re binging. I've been
binging like all the episodes of
the podcast and I, was listening
to one with Julia. Is one, as
I told, it's, it's the most
chaotic episode. It's just like
the first 20 minutes is so off
the rails. It's balloon Dan,
which is my, one of my favorite
Dans. You know, but you all
were talking about like teaching
and concept of teaching what
feels good about teaching, Right?
And like the, that moment where
you helped somebody else. Truly
gain insight. Right? Not just
like you told them something,
they're like, Yeah, okay. But
like, you like explain something
or you show them something or you
help them and they like, they
like say like, I get it in like
this real moment of like pride
and joy and just like
self-validation. That feels
really good. You know? That feels
like a. It almost like, I almost
wanna say it's like an almost
fundamental human experience.
Like you feel it like when you're
with your kids or with family or
like, you know, like young people
where it's like, I helped you
figure out a thing and I can like
watch that happen. So I feel
like Hector Profess also has a
lot of those moments where like,
you're on either side of it, but
it's like, we both did this and
now there's like a real.
Something just got like better,
you know, like, this person
learned something, like I helped
them. I love that feeling,
you know, like, I would, I'd do
that all day or I wanna do that
all day. So that, I think
that's like my, I love, like
it's, it's a real. A lot of like
Hector Effects for me is like
really like vicarious. Like I
can't always like jump into
stuff, but if I'm just hanging
out the Slack it like, Hey, this
person helped this person figure
this out. They're like, Hey, I
didn't know get stuff. Someone
helped me. This is like, I could
just, I'm just, This is like.
This is my television. I don't
know. This is like my, I can't
think of like a thing that I like
more than just like watching
people go, Oh, I figured this
thing out. And then like the
double up like, Oh, someone else
helped me figure this thing out.
That feels, that feels like
all of it really. And like
everything we do from, you know,
the. The podcast or like the
videos or even having like the,
the one big pairing thing or
doing stuff together or like the
website, it gets all, seemed like
we're all funneling towards
making that moment like super
achievable for people. Right?
Cause like that's the thing where
you go like, Oh, actually I'm not
like worse than everybody else.
Oh, actually I think I do like
this, this work and this field
that I've chosen to do. You know,
I do feel like I belong in this
space. Like it's those moments to
make this. we talked about a
little bit in VC today of like,
you know, so much, so much
for a lot of people of the
developer experience, especially
when it get, it's like just
developing alone, just like
figuring it out by yourself. It's
just like you, you're online and
it's all by yourself, and there's
nothing like wrong with that, but
it also feels really good when
you can do stuff with other
people. And I feel like sometimes
that's the difference between,
yeah, I want to keep going at
this, or, Yeah, I don't, It's not
like you couldn't have done it or
you're not capable, but. Things
are better sometimes if there's
other people to work on. Like
it's just, I'm trying to think of
what if football, not saying
soccer can't make me, which is
like a one on one sport, same 90
minutes, same field, but just one
person. And that's kind of how it
feels when you're working on a
problem by yourself. Sometimes.
Just like, this is so much I
can't finish. But if like 10
other people, then it feels. The
football that is not, not soccer
for Olympics football.
Dan: I, like that analogy. I do,
I'm getting distracted cause
like Bekah seems like she really
has something to say, or is,
maybe there's an animal loose in
her room. I'm not sure. But,
if you're listening to this
later, Bekah is just like
losing her mind. While Kirk
is talking,
Bekah: It's, I'm, I'm struggling
because I'm really tired and I
didn't get a cup of coffee before
this. And like, I'm, I'm
definitely into this conversation
and I'm just having a hard time
with, dealing with the
physical symptoms of tiredness.
sorry. sorry. I might go get a
cup of coffee.
Dan: Oh man.
Bekah: well also, this is, I had
a meeting today and then I live
streamed and this is the second
livestream. And I, I am sorry
that I, this is the third, third
person people interaction that
I've done of the day because you
got, they had me at my best in
the first meeting. Now I'm
whatever this two o'clock back.
Kirk: Dan, she give her the
jacket she needs
Dan: Hmm. Pass
Kirk: You have Maybe think about
it for more than two seconds,
Dan: Pass.
Bekah: Tom Cud has given me
permission to go get coffee, so
that's what I'm going to do so
you can talk and I will mute and
go get my coffee and then I will
be fine.
Dan: Okay. This is. That's fine.
Kirk: Ooh, Julia Hollywood. So
Julie just mentioned Hollywood
Squares in a chat and. I feel
like I've spent the last two
years not seeing the parallels
between every Zoom meeting and
Hollywood squares, and it's weird
that there hasn't been like more
of an intersection between those
two concepts, but we can explore
that at another time.
Dan: Alright, well, Bekah is
gone. So, Kirk would,
Kirk: I'm back
Dan: no, you're, you're, you're
Kirk. Should we just talk about
type script? type script.
Tuesday's takeover
Kirk: We're just,
Dan: Uh,
Kirk: I mean, we can talk
about script in the, in the frame
of reference of October. Sort of
like a manifestation of
everything we've been talking
about. Right. You and I have been
sort of learning how to use
TypeScript together in a code
base, and we've been working on
it. Bekah really
Dan: Yeah. Kinda a wild Jesse
sighting
Kirk: This reminds me there was a
time, See, I feel like in the
early days of Virtual Coffee eons
ago, I feel like we did not go
one VC meeting without Bekah
being like, Ashton Kucher punked
by at least one of her kids. And
there was a day where you locked
your door, you're like, I've
locked the door. They can't come
in. And then they opened the
window and you could just hear
the sounds of children spilling
in through the windows.
Bekah: my, my bedroom has doors
to it, but they don't go
anywhere. They open up and
there's like a railing there, so
you can't get through. And so
they climbed up the house. They
pushed like a play set and
climbed a story up, opened the
door and came into the bedroom
because I locked them out.
Kirk: It's called Manifesting
your
Bekah: Yesterday I had a meeting
and my six year old came in to
tell me during the meeting that
my eight year old was twerking at
her.
Dan: Oh God, That is amazing.
that the new, Is that the new? My
sister's staring at me. For the
modern day.
Bekah: I It must be. It must be.
Yeah. I hate when people to at me
too. Um.
Kirk: With me is fine, but acne
is unaccept.
Bekah: I, So I'll take you on a
tangent. I might have told this
story before, but never on a
recording. When I was in college,
I went to Prague for spring break
with like the business group, and
we went to this dance club and
this guy was tickling my armpit
while I was dancing. And I was
like, Is this some kinda thing
that do in Prague? And I don't
know who was at Virtual Coffee
when I told the story. And
they're like, This is, that is
definitely not something that,
that they do in Prague. That guy
was just really weird. Now you
all know about it too.
Kirk: I'm just, I don't know what
I thought you were gonna say, but
that that wasn't it particularly
marked. It wasn't
Bekah: I I don't even know how to
respond to that. I still don't
know. And this is like many years
later. How do you respond to
someone tickling your armpit on
the dance floor? Go ahead and
throw that in the chat.
Kirk: that's an interest
question. Maybe when he was
six and his was eight, they
Dan: That's a good question. Were
you twerking at him in
Bekah: I was most assuredly not
twerking at him.
Dan: I mean yeah, there's
different kind. I mean, there,
there's like twerking at somebody
where you want them to dance with
you and there's twerking at
somebody where you're trying to
bother them. Right. And so
Bekah: don't, I don't know how to
twerk. Okay.
Dan: Well, obviously you have
somebody in your house that could
teach you, so
Kirk: it feels like you're saying
that of like, Like the, the sort
of like father kid moment. Well,
there's different types,
Dan: That's right.
Kirk: ofac,
Dan: Right?
Kirk: there's.
Dan: Yeah. Invitingly, right.
That's when you tickle their own
bits.
Bekah: You should just never
tickle someone's armpits. I'm a
firm believer in not tickling
armpits,
Dan: Uh,
Bekah: hopefully nobody is
tickling your proverbial armpits
on your Hacktoberfest repository.
Dan: there she is. The master of.
Kirk: But also like your real,
like not, it doesn't, you know,
metaphorically or not? Probably,
probably. No, I don't think you
need to like put it in a code
conduct, but. Maybe after that
guy went to that, that dance
place in Prague, they put it on
their code of. con on the door.
Like, you know, no like must wear
shirt, no armpit, tickling, you
know, Don't, Proverbial is an
excellent band name. Tom. You are
right. I, think when we
decided to do this, this one
live. Thoroughly did not
anticipate the fact that we would
have to talk while reading chat,
and as everyone here knows, that
is very difficult for us.
Dan: I, I mean, yeah, I, I,
you know, there's been a couple
comments in the, in the chat
about Yes, you shouldn't just,
just in general life rule, don't
take a strangers aren't bits, you
know, you want them. Any armpit,
tickling to be consensual. All
right, hold on. There's a
delivery person walking in right
now,
Kirk: That's perfect.
Dan: That was really well timed.
cool, well, got my package
delivered. Well, hopefully he
walked out with the knowledge,
you know, the wisdom to not
tickle the people's armpits that,
haven't given prior consent.
Bekah: Can we need, Listen, we
need a sticker in the Virtual
Coffee store, that that talks
about that.
Dan: If somebody makes that
sticker, I will put it on the
store. I promise.
Bekah: need a structured YOLO
sticker. We're about to run a
contest or something to get those
in there. Ooh. Make an issue for
arm tickling. I really enjoy
derailing the conversation.
Dan: Yes. No, Kirk, Kirk
said, yes. Imagining the
delivery person walking in,
seeing my jacket and talking
about arm tickling, in a
stream. Yeah, no, I imagine
that that gentleman will be
sharing that story when he gets
back from a shift.
Kirk: I'm gonna say, so I mean,
you're probably like, you don't
even place on like the weirdest
events that have happened while
he's delivering things. Right?
Like so, you know, I always like
to remind myself of that
sometimes whenever I'm like, Oh,
was that. Weird or awkward. I'm
like, it doesn't even rank on the
things happening in the world.
Bekah got armpit-tickled in real
life in.
Bekah: Real armpit tickled.
Dan: uh,
Bekah: I used my segue and then
nobody followed up.
Kirk: It, it didn't take, you
know, like some, when you have
like a lighter and you do the
first flick and like, it just
does like the,
Bekah: hard to have two armpit
tickling segues though.
Kirk: anyone can do it. It's,
Dan: I have faith
Bekah: speaking of armpit
tickling, what have been your
uncomfortable moments in your
Hacktoberfest history.
Kirk: Oh.
Dan: you know, actually that's a,
that's, Hey, Bekah, that's a
really good question and, a
wonderful segue. Thank you.
This is actually something I was
gonna talk about, before you
left to get a cup of coffee in
the middle of our stream,
was, was, Okay. Well, that's
fair. Is, you said
uncomfortable moments, eh, And
there, there are some like, so.
We were talking about, the
positive sides of, you know,
becoming a maintainer and, and,
and open sourcing your project
and doing that things. And just
from a, from a maintainer
standpoint, there are like, you
know, it, it can be hard too, you
know, it can be, like
difficult to navigate sometimes.
And again, here's like, the
social issues are more of problem
than like the technology or code
parts of it. You know what I
mean? Is how to, navigate
some of that stuff. And, and
like, as a person who is not
always the best, I don't know,
like I I, I, I don't know
my reactions to things are, you
know, you know, usually sometimes
like my erections come out, like,
you know, you have a gut reaction
to something and then you like
realize that, oh, okay, let's,
you know, think about this for a
little bit. And, you know, it
took me a while to figure out
that I needed to pause before I,
you know, before I let any gut
reactions like come through or
whatever and think through some
things and, you know, help
communicate with that. But
it's like, I think the biggest
part of that is, is
communication. All right. I'm
sorry, I glanced at the chat in
us. Just like Bekah, you are the
one that was trying to segue us
back over here and, I feel
like, you know, you're not,
you're not
Bekah: I didn't say anything. It
was
Dan: yes, you were giggling and
chatting and you know,
it's just sometimes hard to, hard
to concentrate. But, you
know, I don't really have any
idea what I was saying.
Bekah: Responding to people
in communication and taking a
step back before going with your
gut feeling, See?
Dan: yes, exactly. So anyway,
communication skills important,
but it is a very good place
to practice those and get better.
I've be, I have become a much
better, I mean, certainly a much
better open source maintainer,
since the first time I did it
was when we started this thing
three years ago. And. You
know, over the last three years
have have like learned a ton, you
know, and I'm, I feel much better
about doing it now than I looking
back, than I did. You know, I
felt confident about it going
into it in the first place. But
that's where you, you just like,
it's just one of those things
where the only way to really get
good at it is to do it. And
that's why, that, that's just why
I'm, I'm always like behind Kirk,
like what Kirk was saying was,
you know, it's a great time to,
like, this is a great time to do
it because we have, like, all of
our resources are pointing
towards that. I mean, not our,
like researchers on our site, but
all of Virtual Coffee right now
is doing Hacktoberfest stuff, you
know what I mean? And we have a
ton of, support for
maintainers and stuff as well.
And those, those that's,
that support exists all, all year
round. You know, if you're
thinking about open source
project, doesn't have to be right
now, obviously. But it's a
good time to do it and you'll
have. Probably have instantly
have people that wanna contribute
if you have a project that's open
source during heta profess.
so I dunno, that's, that's my
little bit is, you
Bekah: My goal this year is to
Dan: in and do it.
Bekah: the momentum beyond
Hacktoberfest, right? Like, to
continue to do open source
projects and to work with other
people at Virtual Coffee or, you
know, outside of our community
and keep moving these things that
I'm really excited about forward.
And I think that, you know,
hopefully we can build some of
that accountab some of that
accountability into Virtual
Coffee for other maintainers who
want that support and
contributors beyond Virtual
Coffees, VCHI Virtual Coffee
Hacktoberfest Initiative.
and, and just keep going with it
because I think it is a really
great way to learn more about how
to contribute, how to be a
maintain. To work on that
communication because
communication can be really hard.
And so, you know, this is, this
is the start of it, and we're
gonna keep going.
Kirk: We call VCHI VCHI also
because it's. It's a reference to
the word chai as like another
coffee tie.
Bekah: Yep.
Dan: I don't.
Bekah: Mm-hmm. That's exactly
what were thinking.
Kirk: Great. That's a great idea.
We were super smart for thinking
about that. But also yes, to
everything that, that you said,
like sustain. I don't know. I, I
think I spend a lot of time
thinking about like
sustainability. In many ways
I feel like a lot of the things
in my life, like I can get this
like big burst of energy and do a
flurry of activity and then, but
then all that energy like goes
away and then I'm like, Oh no,
what do I do now? That thing I
used to do, all this stuff is
gone. And you know, like that
sort of. A lot of the stuff we've
been talking about in this
community just in general and
reading like about like having to
not rely on like inspiration
slash motivation and how to like
turn things into processes and
routines that either like provide
you what you need to make things
sustained or like just lowering
the barrier on yourself for what
you have to put into things to
get like the outcomes that you
want. So Yeah, I feel like that's
a really. I don't know. That
feels like a really good goal and
I should probably do the same
thing. Yeah. And you know, if
we also, if Segway wants to
sponsor, I don't, do they still
make those
Bekah: Yeah, I saw people like
riding around them in a segue
pack in Pittsburgh.
Kirk: collective.
Bekah: flock,
Kirk: A herd
Bekah: of.
Kirk: It's like when Dan was in
that, that group of his, when
he was a kid, The kids of. Bad
town, I know that's their name,
Dan: Yeah, that's it. What did
you say it was?
Kirk: I've been, Every time I
mention, I think this is like the
fifth time, and every time I try
and say a new name, it's like
Benedict, like you can't say his
real name. You have to say like
Bumblebee pumpkin patch. Like
you, there's no, Why would you,
you know, like the whole point.
Anyway, it's fine. Dan was? in a
scooter
Dan: It was not a scooter gang at
that point. I'm going to, I'm not
gonna, Yes. End that. I've, I
don't ride scooters. I am not
interested in that. It's a
mountain bike gang called the
Sugar Hill Pumpkin patch Crew. I
dunno, trying to remember what
you said. But we were
awesome. So, you know, what are
you gonna do? Yes. Rebecca says
mountain bike for the win. Yes.
Kirk: No, maybe Bekah was right
about getting more coffee. I saw
MTV and I was like, Major
trifecta baseball. I could not
put that together. Okay, now
the chat's, just talking about
bikes, and Jesse
Dan: Jesse, how dare you.
Kirk: so just low
Dan: Jesse says, Bikes are just
low tech scooters. Right? And I
did that say, how dare you, sir.
Kirk: I are just overly
engineered, unicycles, you know,
like
Bekah: Yeah. It's interesting how
bikes are so much like open
source contributions, right? Like
you gotta learn how to get on the
bike, learn how to ride the bike,
and how to maintain momentum. And
that's what we're trying to do
here. come on. It wasn't too bad.
Dan: I wish I had, I wish I had
my soundboard here. Yes, I
would've air horned that one.
That one was awesome.
Kirk: Just Bekah segues. We would
like a very specific sound.
Dan: just like a
Kirk: I wonder.
Dan: sound or something, you
know?
Bekah: I'm here
Kirk: Is it. possible to do like
an entire presentation of like
only segue, I guess you can't be
only segue, right? Because like a
segue is like a conjunction. So
like you, you need things
Dan: But you could write an
awesome segue between each slide
or something if you're doing a
talk, if that's what we're
talking about, you know,
Bekah: I think you, I, I would
argue that you only need to start
with one thing and then the
entire rest of the presentation
could be rolling. Segues
Kirk: Right, because a segue can
segue from one segue to another
Dan: of rolling segues,
Kirk: functional
Dan: functional programming.
yeah, I segues. Make me think of
the, white and nerdy weird L
music video, which is amazing if
Bekah: my eight year old listens
to that like every single day.
Julia,
Kirk: That's where you tour.
Bekah: great. Julia's got some
really good extensions here. It's
easy to buy a bike, but you need
someone to help you learn how to
maintain it. Absolutely right.
It's easier to keep up the
routine maintenance and get the
most out of your bike investment
if you have other cyclists around
to mentor you and ride with you.
This is great. There's an entire
blog post right here in the chat.
Somebody just needs to put it
together.
Kirk: And then you can tie in
that phrase to tech people say
sometimes like shedding and it
all.
Dan: We're bike shedding, we're
bike shedding the sway.
Kirk: Yeah,
Bekah: I don't know what
Dan: just like, dog fooding
and,
Kirk: See, I specifically didn't
say that
Dan: Shotgun foot, foot
gunning, cat treating. And,
Kirk: No, no. But my is the real
thing. It's a real phrase that
people actually say. It is far
more tolerable than, than
Dan: curious to know why it's
bike shed and not like some other
kind of shed. So bike shedding,
for those of you who don't know,
is in computer. When, when you're
talking about it with
development, it's like spending
all of your time and resources on
this thing that's sitting on the
side instead of your house,
right? Like, so, like in the
metaphor, your house is like the
actual app or whatever you're
working on, and the bike shed is
just this like little thing on
the side and you're, you know,
you're making your bike shed
really fancy, but not working on
your house. Like that's the,
that's the, I don't use the term,
but that's what the term means.
But like, why bike shed and
not, you know, but like, is a
bike shed a thing? Do people
have, I suppose they probably do
somewhere. I dunno, But like,
yeah, I'm just saying of all the
things to choose for that
metaphor, why a bike shed is my
question.
Bekah: Because
Dan: Speaking of bike, shes,
Bekah: a bike gang
Dan: Oh yeah. Yak, shaving. I
don't remember what that one
means.
Bekah: use that out loud. That's,
This
Dan: Oh, is, is that, am I,
am I getting code of conducted
All, All,
Kirk: I. My next high tour first
project will be a bot that just
takes like random MO and then one
of these things and just puts it
together and then just makes up
some sort of nonsense
definitions. It's like these are
All the tech terms. I put them
all in this bot, you know?
Dan: I love that
Kirk: What was that one you said
earlier? Cat feeding.
Dan: cat treating. I think she
said
Bekah: Yes, that's what I said.
Kirk: We, that'll be my next
project. I feel like we can,
slowly but surely, I feel like we
have managed to talk a little bit
about OSS and open source. And I
feel like for those of you
listening and watching, if you
take anything away from this, it
is that, we really enjoy this
time. And in many ways
Hacktoberfest is the thing that
like. Really solidified a lot of
parts of Virtual Coffee. It was
how the maintainers sort of like
became the maintainers. It
was how we like normalized a ton
of things. It was how we like set
the direction for a ton of
things. It was how I think a lot
of us made the decision to. This
wasn't like, this was like, Oh,
this is VC is like a thing that
we wanna keep doing and like, it,
it exists as like a space that
can do a lot of good, you know,
in addition to like the personal
good was doing for us, but just
like, just like a really good
thing to be like kept and
maintained. So we, we care about
it a lot and we're really excited
that it's still happening. We're
still sort of feeling the way we
felt about it at the beginning,
because at the end of the
day, Hacktoberfest really isn't
about the like individual
projects we're working on. It's
about the collaboration with
other people. And the reason I
managed to get through of that is
explicitly did not read whatever
posted.
Dan: I'm proud of you. It's
impressive.
Bekah: You did an excellent job,
Kirk. You did a much better job
than Dan and I normally do on the
podcast wrapping things up. So I
think it's probably a good time
to wrap up and think about what
Kirk said.
Dan: I always think about what
Kirk said. I spend most of my
Kirk: I never think about
Dan: about what Kirk says.
Yes, I know. I mean, I just also
like to add, I mean, thank you to
everybody that, it's here
today, and thank you to everybody
who's been contributing to
Hacktoberfest and listen to our
podcast and hanging out in
Virtual Coffee. Like Kirk
said, this is like, I mean, this
is my favorite time of the year,
for, for Virtual Coffee
stuff. The Hacktoberfest stuff is
really exciting for me. I love
open source stuff in general. I'm
gonna say stuff a few more times
in this sentence, and then
I'll wrap it up. But I don't
know, it's, it's just a good time
and, yeah, has, has a special
place in my heart too, because
the reasons Kirk said,
sort of the genesis of a lot of
the things that are actually
happening in Virtual Coffee now.
And it's,
Bekah: the podcast.
Dan: a good, including the
podcast and the website itself
didn't exist. We, I made it so
that we could have that issue,
to have people add themselves
as members. And so, like a
lot of stuff, a lot of stuff came
out from, from, from
Hacktoberfest. V1. V1. So
Bekah: we are grateful for
everyone here and for this
Hacktoberfest season.
Dan: Alright, well then I think
with that we'll wrap up.
Thank you again everybody for
coming. Follow us on, you
know, the, all the things we're
VirtualCoffeeIO, you know, most
places. So if you haven't yet,
you know, follow, subscribe,
whatever you do in whatever app
that exist in the world. And here
I am, I am at the end of my
sentence and I don't know how to
wrap up. So somebody finish this
thing and then I'll hit end
Bekah: Thanks for being here,
friends.
Kirk: Bye.
Dan: everybody. Thank you for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel. If you
have questions or comments, you
can hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website virtualcoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee, you can find out
more information on our website
at virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and we'll
see you next week!