Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello and
welcome to Season 6 of the
Virtual Coffee podcast.
We are live and in person
at Kansas City Developers
Conference. This should be our
50th- 50th episode of the
podcast, but we had some
technical difficulties and-
Dan Ott: This is the 49th.
Bekah: This is the 49th. But
we're
gonna pretend like it's very
special-
Dan: I mean --
Bekah: -and that it is the 50th.
Dan Ott: Sure. Yeah.
Well, if we publish it-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -after, then it will --
Bekah: So this is definitely
the 50th episode of the Virtual
Coffee podcast [laughs]. And --
Dan: Here with me today --
Bekah: [Laughs] Here with me
today is my cohost, Dan.
Dan: Wwwuddup, Bek? How's it
going?
Bekah: Hey, it's going --
Dan: Yeah?
Bekah: It's going good.
Done with my talk, and I'm
very happy to --
Dan: She did great.
Bekah: I -- it [crosstalk]
wasn't my best [crosstalk]
performance.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. No, it was
good.
Bekah: No.
Dan: I saw it. You didn't-
Bekah: It happened.
Dan: -you didn't see it.
Bekah: It was okay.
Dan: You can't --
Bekah: So people got up and left
during my talk and then
I -- it was very thrown off.
Dan: I feel like they just --
Bekah: And I said something that
was funny and nobody laughed.
Dan: I laughed.
Bekah: And then I was
like, "Oh. I'm not really
funny [chuckles]."
Dan: Yeah. Bekah did a
great job at her at talk.
Todd, we-
Bekah: I did an okay talk.
Dan: -another Virtual Coffee
member, Todd, I saw his talk
right before yours.
That was also really good.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: But Tom Cudd is-
Bekah: Tom is --
Dan: -to- tomorrow, I think.
Bekah: Tomorrow.
Dan: Who else?
Bekah: Chris DeMars.
Dan: Chris is now, I think,
actually [chuckles].
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Sorry, Chris.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. This has been good.
We got up and got to do
in-person coffee this morning,
which was a lot of fun.
And now we're gonna be answering
some of the questions that
you all submitted. And I think-
Dan: Yeah!
Bekah: -we'll do it soon.
Dan: Yeah! We
were supposed to do this live.
But ... there's no wifi here.
That's good. So we're recording.
We're gonna publish it.
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: In a little bit.
Bekah: Yeah. So --
Dan: Some time.
Bekah: Alright.
Dan: Alright.
Bekah: Ready to get started
with some questions?
Dan: I guess so.
Bekah: So, so we've got some
anonymous questions.
I've only viewed one of them
and the others we
have not viewed at all.
So we'll see what those are.
And we have some that are
not anonymous and we'll
go through those as well.
Dan: Okay. Sounds good.
Bekah: The- the first question
is an anonymous one. And it is,
what time do you go to sleep?
Dan: Hmm.
I try to go to sleep like
10-ish most days, you know?
Bekah: Yeah, I feel like
that's also what I go for.
Last night, we said we
would go to sleep at 11.
Dan: Well, you said that. I
never promised anything.
Bekah: Okay. Well, I said, Dan,
I'll meet you from 10 to 11-
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -and then we stayed up
later.
Dan:  Yep. Well, we had
catching
up to do and my plane
got delayed to infinity.
And so, I finally made it.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And Bekah --
Bekah: And then somebody
challenged
my ability to weight lift.
And ... then I- I had to take
care of that.
Dan: Well, he wasn't
challenging your ability.
He was challenging, like,
your form, which is, I
think even more-
Bekah: Yeah!
Dan: -ridiculous. He was
like [inaudible] --
Bekah: He was like, "Is this --
how do you -- show me how
you..." How dare you? First
of all [chuckles] --
Dan: [Laughs] I just don't
think he knew who
he was talking to, you know?
Bekah: No.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. Don't challenge
my weightlift form.
Don't mansplain my
deadlift.
Dan: Especially not at 11.45
a night at a- at a- at a bar.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah.
It all ended peacefully though.
I am happy to report. I did --
Dan: Yep. She deadlifted that
guy. And then, you know,
threw him into the street? I
don't know [laughs].
Bekah: Uh-huh. Yep, exactly.
That's exactly what I did.
I did not.
I was very kind to him.
Maybe. I can't promise. Okay.
All right. Alright.
Let me -- let's go with the
anonymous questions first.
Dan: Wait. Who? Wait. Was that
first one anonymous?
Bekah: That was an anonymous one.
Dan: It was in your notebook?
Bekah: Yeah, because I
wrote it down before, okay?
Dan: Oh, you looked and-
Bekah: Cuz I was-
Dan: -wrote it down. Okay.
Bekah: -afraid it was gonna
disappear. I never used this
anonymous app thing before.
And so I wasn't sure,
like, I opened it, now,
is this like Snapchat?
And it goes away after
50 seconds or something?
I'm not sure how Snapchat works.
Dan: Yeah. Technology. I have
no idea.
Bekah: All right. So I hope that
these are all ... appropriate.
Well, that one says Netflix
and chill, so --
Dan: Well, hey.
Bekah: That's --
Dan: Just --
Bekah: There we go.
Dan: Nope.
Bekah: Please give me pickup
lines that always work [laughs].
Dan: Well, that's not a
question. So --
Bekah: That's a demand. We
don't-
Dan: They failed- they
failed the --
Bekah: We don't negotiate.
Dan: I mean, just read
the instructions, people.
[Bekah chuckles] It's not hard.
We were looking for
questions, not demands.
Bekah: All right. Here we go.
What extra work goes
into landing a full-time
international remote role
as a first role out of
webdev bootcamp, with no
prior developer experience?
That's a really good question.
I feel like this is
something that we talk a
lot about at Virtual Coffee.
Maybe not so much the landing
an international remote
role, because that's a
little bit more challenging.
Not all companies can work
internationally. So you really
need to narrow it down to
see what companies allow for
international remote work.
Dan: Right. Yeah.
And- and- and those points
you're gonna have to start
looking and see if the companies
have, like, supported visa stuff
and, you know, lawyers to
help you, things like that.
There's a lot of like ... laws
and rules and things that
can come into play, I think,
with international stuff, right?
Bekah: Yeah, for sure.
Dan: But if you set that-
that part of it aside
a little bit, right?
What kind of stuff can we
do, coming out of bootcamp,
to, like, land your first job?
Bekah: Yeah. I was just talking
to someone about this recently.
She's gonna be learning how
to code in a couple of months.
She's a- a mom of a couple of
kids. And I- I think that once
you're getting close to applying
for jobs, working with other
people and building projects
together is something that
can really help you stand
apart-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -because there's a lot
of people coming out of
bootcamps right now. But a lot
of them
have experience where they've
just worked on their own stuff.
They haven't worked
collaboratively,
they don't communicate
aloud with other developers.
And when you're going into those
interviews, you're going to have
to communicate aloud about code.
And that can be, I know
for me, that was a really
hard learning curve.
I was not good at speaking
code words out loud.
Dan: Speaking code
words out loud. Yeah.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Dan: I mean, that's a silly way
to say that.
But like, I think that --
Bekah: So I told you I wasn't
good at it.
Dan: I- I mean, I
totally agree with that.
I- I mean, I- I'm always a
proponent of like building things,
you know, as a way to learn.
And I think, yeah, I think
building something with
other people is also very
important ... skill to like --
start to -- it-
it doesn't always like --
isn't always taught, right?
It isn't always
taught in a classroom.
I- I know that, like, lots of
bootcamps do have collaborative
projects. It's part of their
curriculum. But it's a
little different, I suppose,
when it's not a school-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -project or, you
know, bootcamp, whatever --
a classroom situation.
But yeah, like, learning --
that- that's like one of the --
especially if you're hiring a
junior role like that, where
you're gonna be interviewing --
where you're expecting to
hire somebody ... at that
level. Those sorts of
skills are something they
can set you as -- like, far
apart from- from other
people from -- in the same
boat, right?
You know, so, they all -- like
the- the- the, like, breadth
of technical skills at that
level will be, like, pretty
tight. And so, ways to- ways
to, like, set yourself apart.
I think communication skills
is like a huge one, right?
I mean, if I- if I have -- if
I'm interviewing with somebody,
and they can- they can sort
of speak well and have
some, like ... I mean, speak
well about- about code. Like
you were saying, use code
words. Like, whatever. All of
that- that sort
of thing are- are used to, like,
talking out loud or explaining
some processes, or even just
explaining how a thing works
that you built, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Even if it's a thing
that's --
for bootcamp. Maybe lots of
times -- well, I've never been
to do
bootcamp, so I- I don't know.
But like, you would turn in
the assignment. I don't know.
Do you do like presentations,
after you finish?
Bekah: We did.
So for each of our -- we
had like a series of
projects that we had to do.
And so, after each one, we had
to walk through the code. And
then for the last one, they
asked us questions. And we had
to add on a feature depending
on what the interviewer
felt would work for the
application that you created.
Dan: Okay.
Bekah: So there was live coding
that was involved in that.
Dan: Nice. That's cool.
Bekah: Yeah.
And I feel like you
can get somebody who
is experienced in the industry
to do the same thing with you.
So if you have-
Dan: Sure.
Bekah: -a project
that you're using as a portfolio
project, then what you can do
is say like, "Hey, would you
mind walking through this with
me? Suggest, like, what I can
do?" Do a code review with
somebody, just so you get an
understanding of like whether
or not your code is written
well. I think that you'll always
be able to improve on your code.
But when you're doing it
in isolation and you're
often just trying to see,
like, does this work-
Dan: Right.
Bekah: -you know, there's more
that goes
into coding than does this work.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Is it- is it written
well or efficiently?
Dan: Yeah.
Oh, I- I think that's great.
And- and I think, another path
to practice that sort of
thing is open source as well.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And another thing that we
talk about a lot, in Virtual
Coffee, at -- in this podcast,
is it's another great way
to practice those skills
and prac- you know, see
what works and- and-
and join other code bases.
And like, that's another skill
that is- is ... sometimes
maybe a harder one learn -- not
harder one to learn, but maybe
not an obvious one to learn-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -is like how to dig into
... an unfamiliar code base,
right?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And there's like --
[chuckles] there's-
there's some things that you
can do to make it easier, but
in general, it's very much just
practice.
It will, you know, like if
you practice it, it will --
you'll get better at it. And
so, there's a million, billion
projects [chuckles] out there
on GitHub that all are looking
for help. And ... you know, I
don't know. Jump in.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I -- we have a lot of
episodes where we've talked
about, like, all- all the
reasons why it's a good idea to
do it. And like, also like, the
... things to do to- to get over
some anxiety you might -- may
have about- about doing that
as a- as a junior developer.
Like, just jump in or,
[chuckles] you know, do some
peer -- pull requests on just
documentation or whatever,
just to get your feet wet.
Like, that kind of thing.
There's like -- a
lot of stuff like that. So --
Bekah: Yeah.
And I think, also, it's a
pretty easy ask to say like,
"Hey, I really wanna get
started in open source, I'm
a little nervous about this.
Is there anybody out
there that would be up for
mentoring me through it
if I'm struggling?"
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And then that way, you
know, you can pair up with
someone, you can work on those
communication skills, and then
you don't have to feel nervous
about what you're doing.
You have that support.
Dan: Agreed. And ... absolutely
agreed. And, like, join Virtual
Coffee [chuckles], you know
what I mean? It's -- there's a
lot of people
that are always down to help
with that sort of thing.
And it's good.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: All right.
Before we go on, I'm getting
really nervous that I forgot to
hit record or it didn't work.
So I'm just gonna go look
at-
Bekah: Yep. Go check it
[laughs].
Dan: -really quick.
Yeah. No, we're good.
Bekah: We're good. We're good.
We've been recording. Per-
excellent.
Dan: We're good. Everything
is okay.
Bekah: Cuz I was gonna make
you do the whole thing over.
Dan: Yeah, that would be
[inaudible].
Bekah: Okay. So, let's see.
Did we -- so your first role --
and- and along with landing
your first role, I think
always finding community,
finding people. And remembering
that, like, your network is
not just the people you
know, it's the network of the
people you know. So-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -making connections that
are not transactional, and like,
"Hey, I want to know
you so I can get a job," right?
Like, get to know people and
be their friends, be kind, don't
criticize their deadlift form,
[Dan laughs] and then you-
you'll have a better shot at
finding a job.
Dan: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Probably- probably just
in general, not giving an,
you know, giving advice to
people who didn't ask for
it, you know? Especially
people you don't know.
Bekah: I mean,
like, generally speaking, I
like it when people give me
advice. I know that that's
like kind of controversial,
cuz a lot of people are
like, "Don't give me advice.
I didn't ask for it."
But I- I don't know.
I like to hear what
other people have to say.
And I often ask for advice a lot.
I guess that's another bit of
advice is ask- ask for advice
because not everybody's just
gonna give it to you. Also,
sometimes advice is bad.
People get bad advice.
Dan: That's not true.
Bekah: Like, also his deadlift
stance [Dan chuckles] yesterday.
I'll get over that
in a couple of weeks.
Dan: Yeah, right?
Bekah: I'm --
Dan: I'm personally shocked
that the drunk guy at the
bar last night didn't have
perfect deadlift form
[chuckles].
Bekah: All right. Let's
go to the next one.
Dan: Okay. Next question.
Bekah: I don't know what
that says. And, what happened?
Oh, no.
Dan: I- I don't know.
Bekah: It might not let me
answer.
Wait a minute.
I don't wanna do that.
[Chuckles] How does a computer
get drunk?
Dan: Well,
do you know the answer?
Bekah: No.
Dan: Screenshots.
Bekah: [Chuckles] Did you
submit that question?
Dan: I- I did. I did. That
was me.
[All laugh] This is a good one,
right?
Bekah: Who was the last dude
you texted?
Dan: Jesus Christ, people.
Bekah: Let's see.
Probably Dan. Probably
you. You were the- the last
one I texted.
Dan: Yes. I don't know. I mean
... are- are you asking me?
Cuz I don't know-
Bekah: I don't know.
Dan: I don't know who you
texted.
Bekah: I- I didn't --
Dan: You did text me recently.
Bekah: I did recently text
you. About this conference.
Who was the last dude you texted?
Dan: Mm ... I dunno. My --
one of my friends? One of
my friends
just took his dog out in the
canoe for the first time.
And so he was sharing
pictures of that. And I said,
"That's cool."
Bekah: Nice.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: That was excellent.
So- so there- there you have it.
We did really well.
Those anonymous
questions were fantastic.
Thank you all for doing such
a good job of sending them [all
chuckle]. We do have a handful
of non-anonymous questions.
Un-anonymous, unanimous
question.
Dan: Unanimous?
Bekah: Mm-hmm. I think that's
the right word.
Dan: Un-anonymous, I think.
Bekah: Un-anonymous.
I wrote one of 'em down.
Dan: Oh.
Bekah: So I wouldn't forget.
Okay. This one comes from Meg.
Dan: Is this notebook from
like, 1920 or something?
Bekah: Listen, I keep
buying these notebooks.
They sell them at T.J. Maxx
in a pack of three.
This one says the right stuff.
I like these notebooks.
Dan: Look at the inside though.
Show them the inside.
Bekah: What's wrong
with the inside?
Dan: It looks like it's,
you know, paper from ... the
civil war or something
[laughs].
Bekah: [Chuckles] Is that what
civil war paper looked like?
Dan: I don't know. But,
probably.
Bekah: I think you're wrong.
And a liar.
Dan: Oh, I and ... here we go.
Bekah: All right.
This one's from Meg.
Is there anything you
would've done differently
when it comes to Virtual
Coffee's setup, organization,
time commitment, et cetera.
You go first.
Dan: I mean, that's a really
good question. But, like, it's
hard to have an answer for
it because everything
that, like, has happened has
been so organic, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And you- you, like, you
think about, like, all the
things that
we have going on right now,
like, everything that's
in play and- and, like, yeah.
Like, I can think of a
lot of things that could
be better or, you know,
right now, or whatever.
But ... I think if we had
started from scratch in, like --
we're like, "Let's try to build
this community, but like
start..." you know, I- I don't
know. Who
knows what we would've done.
You know what I mean?
And it probably, I don't
know. It's a good chance
it wouldn't have worked
maybe. You know what I mean?
Like-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Like, I'd like to think it
would've, but the- the --
one of the beauties of the- of
the community -- of the Virtual
Coffee community is- is the
sort of organic, like, nature
of how all that starting it.
And of course, all that was,
like, around you [chuckles].
But, like,
it's -- and it's, like, one of
the reasons why Virtual Coffee
is sort of different and-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -successful. I've -- I
feel it. As opposed, to, like
... I'm trying to think
of an example, but, you know,
I suppose there's people who
are like, "I'm gonna start
a community," or something.
And sometimes they're cool,
and sometimes they're not, but
you never know what it's --
like, you never know what's
gonna happen un- until it
happens. With- with, like,
groups of people, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: So, I don't know ... I
mean, I could think
of, I don't know.
I could think of like a lot
of -- like little instant, like
instances of times that like,
okay, I wish I made a
di-different decision there,
you know, but
that's- that's less like ...
that's more just like I make
mistakes,
not- not so much like, you
know, tactical, like, planning
stuff, you know what I mean?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I dunno. What about you?
Bekah: Well, I think it's nice
because- because of like the
authenticity and the organic
evolution of Virtual Coffee,
that we have more freedom
to make mistakes almost, right?
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Because we know that
the people who are coming
to Virtual Coffee are okay
with that. Because they know
that we're human beings, and
we, like, we do get things
wrong sometimes. I, for sure,
have gotten things wrong on a
number of things at Virtual
Coffee. And, you know, you-
you try and get 'em right.
The next time, you learn
your lesson, you apologize
when you need to.
And I- I think a lot about
what I would do differently,
but I actually think it's
kind of a strength that we
had no idea what we were
doing in the beginning.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Because, you know,
now that I'm community building
professionally, I'm, like,
diving into things like
metrics, and planning.
And a lot of different, like,
processes and procedures that I
wouldn't have considered before.
And I think that sometimes it
actually makes me less creative
with what the community will
look like, because I see
what everybody else is doing.
And it feels like these are
the things that you should
be doing if you're building
a community, because this
is what the experts say.
And I'm like -- sometimes
I get caught in it, like
thinking about Virtual Coffee.
And I'm like, "No," you know,
"This is -- that's not true
to who we are as a community."
Dan: Right.
Bekah: But I'm, like,
trying to think too [silence]
what I would do differently.
I- I think I would find more
ways early on to allow people
to support the efforts of
Virtual Coffee, to provide
more autonomy for members
to do their own things.
Like, I'm really enjoying
seeing the coffee table groups
grow, and the different
things that we're doing.
Ray is doing the Virtual
Coffee speech club now.
And, like, I love that. That's
one of my favorite things.
But, like, finding more ways
to empower people to do that.
Like, honestly, I wish that
I had more time in the day
because I think that we have
so many great people at Virtual
Coffee that are willing to
provide support for-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -a lot of different
things and finding ...
more ways to empower them to do
that is one of those things that
I still wish that I could do
better.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. I mean, that's
... that's a hard problem.
And, you know, I- I know of --
both from my experience and
from, like, talking to other
people, it's very hard to find
people that are willing to,
like, put time and effort into
something like a volunteer
thing like that, you know?
And I think that just
goes ... to show how awesome
Virtual Coffee is. That we
have all these people that are
doing this stuff, you know?
And the- the to- coffee table
groups, all -- almost all of
them started before we, like --
just on their own, you know?
Right?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Like, before we had
anything around them.
Like, we are
building stuff to support them
now because they exist already,
you know? As opposed to, like,
we had some idea for coffee
table groups, and then we're
trying to find people to- to
do them or something like that,
right? And that's, you know, it
just goes back to the,
you know, the organic
nature of- of Virtual Coffee.
And ... if we were planning
this -- I mean, you could
see like special interest
groups being a thing to plan
[chuckles], you know, if
you're trying to plan a group
ahead of time, or a community.
But, I don't know.
It's- it's hard to imagine,
like, trying to do all this
stuff a-ahead of time, or
whatever, you know what I mean?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Also, that's not
usually how my brain works
that well anyway. I- I mean
[chuckles] the- the way that
things have
gone is what, you know, is
obviously, like, it's more how
my brain works anyway, you
know? Kind of like-
Bekah: Same.
Dan: -along with
things and trying to make things
better, but, I don't know.
It's ... well, it is what it
is. I don't know.
Bekah: Yeah. I mean, I ...
I'm, like, super proud of
us for early on getting
a lot of documentation in
place because that-
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: -has helped to provide
a better space for people.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I- I would
like- I would like to do
a better job of onboarding
new community members.
Dan: Yep.
Bekah: And I feel like that-
that from the beginning. So I
feel like a lot of the, like,
would you do differently is --
are still things that, like, I
would like to do more of, now?
Dan: Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Bekah: Especially now that
we have
new members coming in. It's
so great to see new faces
at Virtual Coffee again.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: That's been a- a
really bright side of
the last couple of weeks.
But I just wanna make sure
that everybody's taken care of.
Dan: Yep. Yeah, I agree.
And that's like, you know, so
there's, like, technology stuff
that I- I just wanna change now.
It's- it's not even- it's not
even like, "Oh, I wish we
had done this differently." It's
just ... well, now we need it.
Like, now we need things.
Like, there's things
we need, you know? So
let's change them. The- the
new member thing, especially.
It's especially cuz it's built,
like, originally around Slack [chuckles], you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And that's ... that
sounds --
Bekah: That, maybe, is
something I would change.
Dan: I don't know. Yeah. I
mean, like, maybe. But, like,
it was really before Discord,
like, took off- like, took off
for people outside of gaming,
you know?
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Dan: And ... I don't know.
That -- there's any better
option and it, like, created the
community, honestly. Like, it
-- like, you know what I mean?
It's -- I mean, the, Zooms and
the- and the Slack, it's like,
it's what was -- it was the
whole thing for first ...
however long. I don't know.
I dunno. Whatever. However
many months or whatever it
was, you know? So- so yeah.
Yeah. There's things that, like,
I'd like to see improved and
stuff. But it's -- I don't look
at them as- as, you know,
regrets or whatever, if that
makes sense.
Bekah: Yeah. Let me ... okay.
So the next question is, what's
the hardest part ...
of community?
Dan: Of, like, run- running a
community?
Bekah: Just of community.
So you can take it as you- as
you ... see fit.
Dan: I don't know, man.
I -- like, alright.
So, for me, part of -- as a
member of communities is- is
just like ...
it- it takes, like, emotional
energy for me to engage with
things, engage with people,
and do things or whatever.
And so sometimes I find
myself like just falling
out of communities or- or
just like not -- whatever.
And it- it even happens in
Virtual Coffee sometimes.
I mean, you and I ... I mean,
we talk all the
time, like, doing management
side. But, like, I- I'll
miss, like, coffees for weeks
because it's like ... 8.50
in the morning, you know?
And- and it's not -- I'm
not tired or anything.
It's just like, I need- I
needed a certain amount of -- a
store of energy to be able to
like, talk to people, you know?
Especially people I don't know.
And I love it. But,
like, sometimes it's-
sometimes it's hard. And so ...
I -- although that will say --
I will say, like, every time
that I've felt that
way, but then still gone,
I've been very glad that I went-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -you know what I mean?
Like, it's- it's one of
those, like, "Catch-22" where
my brain is, like, fooling
me about it, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: But, like, overcoming that,
that's -- that can be hard.
And then another thing
for me is, my memory's
really bad, especially
with like names and stuff,
and, like -- a-and so, you know,
remembering people that I met
or like that I'm supposed to
know or let- you know,
I'll- I'll --
I sensibly do know, but have
forgotten who they are or what
their name is or, you know,
that happens to me, like, a lot.
And it's much easier
online because you can kinda
like, look -- try to Google
them or something [chuckles],
you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Harder in person.
Like, it's more- more
embarrassing for me in person.
So it's -- that's my other-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -struggle. What about you?
Bekah: Well ... I guess the-
the thing that I never
would've thought
about, before this community,
was last year, when Mike passed
away. That was, like, obviously
a really hard experience.
He was an active
community member.
Like, everybody loved him.
But then, like,
making decisions-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -about that-
Dan: Yep.
Bekah: -and having to tell
people over and over was --
Dan: Yeah?
Bekah: I- I -- like, something
that you can't ever be
prepared for.
And so, like, experiencing the
losses of community members
and with community members.
And, like, trying to leave
space for people to experience
grief in different ways-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -is just ... I- I don't
know. I felt like, I was
stretched beyond my limits of
human being. Like, I-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -went through -- and-
and, you know, it was hard
with Mike, but like
there have been other losses
in the communities, right?
Like, there have been
miscarriages, there
have been jobs lost,
there have been relationships
that are no longer.
And when people, like, confide
in you, and talk to you about
that, it's just ... one of
those --
it is definitely the hardest-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -emotional labor that-
that
I have ever had to put in
anywhere. It- [chuckles]
it's like a "Catch-22" though,
right? Like-
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: -you have to ...
experience ...
like, the- the full humanness
to really be close and
supportive to the-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -the people around you.
So like, would I love to
not ever have to experience
any of those things?
Dan: Sure.
Bekah: Yeah. But I think it's
the -- a key part
of understanding the
people in front of us
to be there through it. So --
Dan: Yeah. No, I- I- I mean, I
totally agree. And that's like,
it was- it was incredibly hard.
A- and ... but I just -- I was,
like, while you were talking
just now, I was just, like,
thinking of how ... thankful
I am that, like, Virtual
Coffee is- is what it is.
And, like, it's a place where
people can come to, like, share
... this- this horrible thing --
like, the heavy feelings or-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -you know, it's -- it
obviously is
hard. But I think, like, my --
I guess my point is just
like ... that it's worth it.
Like [laughs]-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -I guess it- it's my
point.
You know what I mean?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Like, the -- like, it is
like,
it- it- it's ... yeah. It's
that. It's- it's just -- it's
hard, but like, it's also like
-- it's what makes Virtual
Coffee, like, what it is, you
know? I mean, the -- that's-
that's sort of, like,
connection. The, you know, the-
the intimate connection, right?
Is- is -- I started noticing it
even before ... maybe right
around, like, our- our,
like, original
Hacktoberfest time, you know?
Like, when we all started like
really doing that, but like,
just the -- I this is gonna,
like, sound --
it might sound like silly. But,
like, the fact that like, people
would just, like, throw around
the heart emoji, you know?
And like ... just to people, you
know? Like, not- not your best
friends or not -- but just like
people, like, in the community,
you know, made me feel good.
I don't- I don't know why.
Like -- and- and- and to be able
to also -- like, also start
throwing around the heart
emoji, or whatever, you
know? Like, I -- it's like a --
it's like kind of a silly
way to say it. But, like, to-
to both share ... you
know, I guess sharing it, right?
Like, both -- like, two ways,
right? You know what I mean?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: There's like --
there's- there's good
feelings coming ... both ways,
and I -- from everybody
in the community. And, like,
I dunno. This -- it's good.
Bekah: Yeah. I think when you
can eg- share
your losses openly like that,
then you celebrate your wins.
Dan: Right.
Bekah: You know, just as
strongly in the other direction.
So it- it is definitely one of
the hardest, but one of the
most rewarding to be able to
know that there are people
out there that trust you to
share that information, that
you know, that if you're
going to be going through
something hard, that there
are gonna be people there too.
And I know that my empathy and
understanding of other people
has definitely, I feel like-
like "The Grinch", right?
Like [chuckles]-
Dan: Yeah [laughs].
Bekah: I was a little bit of
"The Grinch"
before Virtual Coffee [laughs].
Dan: [Inaudible] Two- two --
three- three sizes. It's --
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: No, that's a great call.
And that's a good point.
Like, I mean, I have learned
so much just about like ...
yeah. Expressing myself and
talking to --
connecting with people and ...
yeah. My ... I was gonna say,
like, my- my, like, emotional
literacy, I feel like has
exploded over the last few
years. It- it reminds me of s-
... I forget what we were
talking about, but I was
talking with somebody and I
was- I was like -- they were
like -- this was earlier in
pandemic when things were
like, still like a lot
more shut down, you know?
And they were talking about
how they hadn't, like, they
hadn't, like, meeting new people
or they haven't talked, you
know, like all this stuff.
And I'm like, I've actually,
like, made more friends.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I mean, it is because of
Virtual
Coffee -- or once Virtual
Coffee started, but like, made
more friends, new friends in
that time, in the last three
years than I had in the last
10 years before that [chuckles]
I think,
you know? Like, put together.
And like- and like good
friends. Not-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -you know,
not just like random Twitter
followers or something,
you know- you know what I mean?
Like ... and- and, yeah. I
mean, that's all- that's all
Virtual Coffee, you know? It's-
it's just like, you know, it's
good stuff.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. And
it's great. Like, we get to
meet up some of us.
Dan: I know.
Well, this is [inaudible] --
Bekah: Which is really, really
nice.
Dan: Yeah.
This is the second time that
Bekah and I have met in person.
Cuz -- and when- when did we
meet? When did- when did we,
like, start working together?
Is 2019 [??] ... June [??] --
Bekah: July of two thousand --
Dan: 18?
Bekah: 18.
Bekah: I think.
Dan: Okay. Yeah. So --
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Two times every ... four
-- what year is it now?
Bekah: 22.
Dan: 22? So it ... two times
every three years s-see each
other in person?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Right?
Bekah: Yeah. And we're
in Kansas City. So --
Dan: We're in Kansas
city right now. Make sense.
Bekah: We live like two hours
from each other, like [laughs]
... but --
Dan: This is the only place
that would take us really. So --
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I guess that's
understandable.
All right.
Let's see what other questions.
Dan: [Inaudible] time over
ahead [??].
Bekah: We still got-
Dan: Oh, we got-
Bekah: -some time.
Dan: -twenty minutes-ish
before hours up. I dunno.
Bekah: Um ... oh, okay.
Dan: I suppose we should have
said something on Slack about
how we are going live.
Bekah: I did.
Dan: Oh, good job.
Bekah: Don't worry.
Dan: Did you do
it on Twitter too?
Bekah: I didn't
on Twitter though. Sorry.
Can't cover all the spaces.
Uh-oh. What did you do? Did it
pause it?
Dan: I don't- I don't know if
it did for that
moment, but it is going again.
So ... we're in good shape.
The recording [inaudible]
several technical issues.
We've been recording for
like half an hour.
Bekah:  You need to sit -- be
in -- closer to your mic.
Cuz I can't hear you.
Dan: Has it -- that been true
the full time? Or just now,
since I got up?
Bekah: It was like, just
since you got up.
Dan: Okay, good.
Bekah: All right.
Where are the questions?
Dan: I don't know.
Bekah: There was another one.
And --
Dan: Oh, Ayu
had a question that was --
I know it was a trap.
Bekah: It was a trap?
Dan: Yeah. For me.
Bekah: It was a trap for you?
Okay, wait. Let me --
Dan: I think it was on Twitter.
Bekah: Twitter. Thanks,
Barrett Blake, for saying
the Virtual Coffee
podcast is a must listen.
Dan: Yes. Thank you.
Bekah: We love it.
Dan: [Chuckles] We love it.
Bekah: Um ... why can't I find
it? Okay.
Maybe it's the history of how
Virtual Coffee was found.
Oh yes.
Dan: Yes. See?
Bekah: Go ahead.
Dan: What? I didn't found it.
Bekah: Well, you fired me,
and --
Dan: See? Ayu is just -- [Bekah
laughs] this is, like --
this is it. Every- every time.
Starts like that. I didn't
fire you. Yeah.
You heard it here, folks
[chuckles].
Bekah: Dan said, "I will no
longer pay you to do work."
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: So you all are welcome
to define that as you see
fit. We should have them
vote for their favorite Virtual
Coffee host and see who wins.
Dan: That doesn't sound very fun
for me [chuckles].
Bekah: [Laughs] I mean, you mi-
you're probably a lot
of people's favorites.
Dan: Hmm ... I doubt it.
It'll probably be like,
just one of our guests would
win [chuckles].
Bekah: One of our gue- Kirk.
Dan: Yeah. It's gonna be Kirk!
Bekah: Kirk is gonna be the
one that win.
Dan: It would be -- he would
get my vote, honestly.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah.
I vote for Kirk too.
Everybody vote for Kirk.
Dan: All right. It is decided.
[Chuckles] K-kirk is favorite.
Oh, I mean, sh-should we,
like, finish the story if
people haven't heard this?
Bekah: [Laughs] I guess so.
Okay. So, Dan and I
work together.
Dan: Yes. And then the shutdown
happened and all of my clients
stopped giving me work.
And so I had to stop
giving Bekah work. And then
something happened. I dunno.
Bekah: Yeah.
Well the- the day that I
went and picked up my kids'
schoolwork, cuz they said,
"Oh, you're going home --
they're going home
for three weeks," which they
never went back that year.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Dan was like, "Hey,
wanna catch up?"
[Laughs] And I was like,
"Oh, no."
And it was, "Oh, no."
So I -- when Dan hired me right
outta bootcamp, I hadn't had --
we didn't do an interview.
Like, we just have a
conversation.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And so, I was now
interviewing for the first time,
really ever, with four kids at
home that were trying to
be doing school at home.
And it was just miserable.
Like, the interview
process is soul crushing.
And I just found myself --
I was like crying all
the time, every night.
I'm like, "This is awful."
And so, I finally like,
remembered ... like, everything
I had gone through in trauma.
And I was like, "I
know you shouldn't be alone
and isolated in your feelings.
Does anybody wanna meet
up for a virtual coffee?"
And then people did.
So I was doing it, like, one
day a week. And then, it
was at East Coast time.
And then people were like,
"What about West Coast time?"
So then I added -- I was like
doing double sessions at
one point. Like, Fridays,
I was doing in the morning,
taking a break for an
hour or two, and then
doing in the afternoon.
And it was- it was not,
like, I'm an introvert.
I- I- I say I'm an introvert.
But I -- like, by that, I was
like, I don't -- I enjoyed
it, but I didn't, like, wanna
people anymore for like
the rest of the weekend.
That was just-
Dan: Yeah, yeah.
Bekah: -too intense. But
then, we just kept going. And,
like, people were like, "Hey,
why don't you have a Slack?" And
so, I think Brian, initially, is
-- he was like, "Here's a
Slack." I'm like [chuckles],
"Okay." [Dan chuckles] And then
he was like,
"Let's do lunch and learns."
Okay. Then we did a newsletter,
and then I've always
wanted a podcast.
And Cameron, I think,
was like, "When are we
gonna do the podcast?"
And you were like,
"Let's do a podcast."
So we just-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -kept going with it.
Dan: Yep.
Bekah: And Dan- Dan did
hire me back for a while.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: So --
Dan: As soon as I was able to,
I [inaudible]
Bekah: [Giggles] He only fired
me for a little bit.
Dan: Oh my god.
I didn't fire you. That's
not the right word.
You're using the
word incorrectly. I feel like,
Bekah: Oh. What
is the definition?
Dan: I feel like, if you're
gonna fire somebody, it has to
be for, like, a reason. Like ...
it's -- laid off is maybe what
-- other -- like, probably
doesn't really apply to
contractors, but like,
that's closer to what it is,
right? Laid off means the company
has to stop, you know,
can't pay you anymore.
Bekah: However you wanna justify
it in your head, Dan.
Dan: Oh, god. Whatever. [Bekah
chuckles] You better watch or
you're gonna get fired
again, cuz --
Bekah: You can't fire me
[chuckles]. I don't work for
you anymore.
Dan: I definitely can, and
I will.
Bekah: You can't fire
me if I don't work for you.
Dan: You can't tell me --
don't tell me my truth, okay.
Bekah: [All laugh] All right.
You go ahead, and you try and
fire me, and see how that goes.
Are you- are you firing me
as part of the pod- as your
podcast co-host?
Dan: No. I don't think a
lot of people tune into
the "Just Dan" podcast.
Dan talks to himself podcast.
Bekah: I would tune into
Dan: Yeah, but you
just heckle me. So --
Bekah: Yeah. I would
probably heckle you.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Well, tomorrow, when I
speak at PubConf, you're
allowed to heckle me though.
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: Please ... heckle ...
me.
Dan: I ... yes, I will.
Bekah: All right.
Dan: I -- are you glad or sad
that I didn't say -- yell
"Wuddup, Bek" at the
beginning of your talk
this morning? I- I thought
about it.
Bekah: [Laughs] I- I- I think
I'm glad that you did not
do that.
Dan: Okay. All right.
I made the right choice.
Bekah: I was already
super nervous.
Dan: Well, that's why --
Bekah: And then I --
Dan: That's- that's why I
didn't do it, you know?
I didn't wanna --
Bekah: Would've been very --
I'm not really sure how -- what
would have happened.
Dan: Yeah. I- I just, like, well,
I mean, I
figured you would just break
into a laughing thing where you
couldn't stop laughing and which
would've been entertaining for
me, but probably not for you.
Bekah: No.
Dan: I -- that's the way I made
the right choice.
Bekah: And then I would've
just hid in a hole.
Dan: I just wanted you to
know, I --
Bekah: I would've just like
stood behind-
Dan: I ... considered it.
Bekah: -the screen and then --
Dan: I considered it and
then chose not to, you know?
Bekah: Thank you.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And thanks for being
there.
Dan: Yeah. I feel like 10 years
ago, me would've done it.
And then -- I mean, and then
realized it was a bad idea,
after, you know? But like-
like ... wouldn't have put
it together beforehand,
you know? That that was a bad
idea?
Bekah: I feel like the --
my brothers definitely
would have done that [chuckles].
Dan: That's what I'm saying.
Yeah.
Bekah: All right. We have
more questions.
Dan: I'm learning. We do?
Bekah: What does community
mean to you [laughs]?
Dan: Community? I don't know.
Bekah: I think community
is a group- a group of
people that have some
shared sense of belonging.
And there can be different
degrees of that, right?
Like, you- you all might, like,
to go hiking. And that can be a
sense of community. Or it can be
people that are ... you know, I
love true crime podcasts.
So -- and actually my favorite
podcasters, true crime
podcasters, live in Kansas city.
Dan: Whoa.
Bekah: So I like the thought
about trying to get them to
come, like, "Can you come be
part of our live podcast?" But
I wasn't sure how we were gonna
talk about murder and Virtual
Coffee at the same time.
Although I have some --
no. I'm not gonna take
you down that tangent.
Dan: Oh, no.
Bekah: Sorry [chuckles].
So, yeah. So, some sense
of belonging. And then there's
different degrees and ... ways
of ... expressing that sense
of belonging.
Dan: Yeah. I think that's
great. Yeah.
And the other word that I would
use is connection, right?
It is, like-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -belonging and connection.
And maybe those -- maybe
you can't feel belonging
without connection. I don't know
[chuckles]. But like, you
know, the- the -- that's the
other side of it is- is the --
is connecting with people,
right? Like, okay.
So, like, I'm a Guardians
fan, you know? And ... I
don't know. We were talking
about this last night,
which- which is why it's
in my head. But like, you
know, your regional sports
team, lots of times, you're
a fan of or whatever. And it --
the -- you, like, some- some
sense of belonging from that,
right? It's like-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -a ... whatever. You have
the hat or whatever, you know?
Bekah: Yeah. And
when I was in the airport,
there was somebody wearing WVU
tennis shoes in front of me.
And, like, I graduated from WVU.
I taught there and it
was like, "Oh," like, "That
guy's my friend."
[Chuckles] I don't know that
guy.
Dan: Right. Right. Right. And
you might connect, like, yeah.
And that like creates
a connect- you know?
And it creates a connection.
I mean, you were the
only one. Cuz you didn't
probably say --
Bekah: Yeah. No. I would thought
about saying, "Let's go,
Mountaineers," but then I got a
little embarrassed. So I didn't.
Dan: That's probably the right
call. So [laughs] --
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah.
Dan: My mom does stuff like
that, you know? I would like --
the -- like, with- with the
Ohio state people, you know?
Bekah: Yeah!
Dan: It's not -- it's never fun
for me anyway [Bekah laughs].
[Chuckles] But ... yeah, I mean
that- that's it. Like, right.
The belonging is a great --
like, I think that's a great,
I think
that's like the- the- the real
key, you know? And then, yeah.
And then that sense of
connection is a-also of --
Bekah: I was getting off
the escalator here, earlier.
And some guy was waving, and I
thought he was waving at me.
And then I, like, waved back
wholehartedly at him [laughs],
he was, like, was actually
waving at the guy behind me.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Then I didn't feel like
I belonged.
I felt very embarrassed
for myself [laughs].
Dan: You- you were not in his
community of- of waving people.
Bekah: I- I was not- not part
of that.
Dan: I -- it happens to me like
once a year [Bekah laughs] I'd
say. It's really bad, you
know? Like, just like that?
Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: There's a lot of people
here. So, it's- it's easy to --
Bekah: Yeah. I hope he forgets
my face. Let's see here. Okay.
Here's another question.
Dan: [Chuckles] I hope he
forgets my face.
Bekah: At in-person events,
what are some techniques or
tactics you use for starting
a conversation with a stranger?
I- I am, like, terrified of
talking with strangers. And I'm
on booth duty while I'm here,
for work at DeepGram.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And I guess it
almost makes it a little
bit easier, cuz I'm like,
"I'm deep- part of DeepGram.
We're a speech to text API
company." So at least, like, I
can do the spiel. But
sometimes I don't -- I told
a woman I liked her glasses
[chuckles].
Dan: What's wrong with that?
Bekah: No. That's how I
get to talk to people.
Dan: Oh, sure. Yeah. Oh, yeah,
yeah.
Bekah: Give them a compliment.
Dan: Sure. Yeah, yeah.
But I would say only
compliment, yeah, clothes
and- and stuff, right? Like --
Bekah: Yeah. You have to be
careful what you compliment.
Dan: Especially -- I mean,
especially if you're not a
wom- if you're not a woman.
Bekah: Yeah. Don't be like --
Dan: It's just like, don't --
Bekah: You have really nice
eyes.
Dan: [Chuckles] No, yeah.
Bekah: That will get creepy.
Dan: That's ... yeah. Yeah, no.
I don't have
any good strategies cuz I'm
really bad at it [laughs] also.
I'd say, one- one strategy --
Bekah: You talk to
people at the table --
lunch table.
Dan: Sure. Sort of.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I mean, they were talking
to me [laughs]. Alright. What I
was gonna say was, if you go
with a friend, you know?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: It's much easier to
actually
talk to other people if you ha-
already have somebody
that you're, like, with -- you
do know, because, like, we
sat -- Bekah and I sat next to
each other at the lunch table
and then, like, other people
just sat down, you know?
And we weren't ...
like ... I don't know.
And then they -- we just, like,
started chat, you know?
And- and that's cool. It's ...
again, also hard for me
[chuckles]. I'm not- I'm not
good at it.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: I -- they're -- here, at
this conference, they're doing,
like, a Bingo thing where
they're trying to get you to
go to all the speaker table --
or the sponsor booths, that you
can see some of them is behind
us. And -- so you have like
this little card, and you get
little stamps, you know, and
if you get 'em all, you get
entered in something. Raffle
for ... I don't know what.
Bekah: Yeah, I don't know.
Dan: But, anyway, so
now I'm going to all these
booths that I don't have any
interest [chuckles] in going
to and trying
to, like, make conversations.
Like, I feel bad just
being, like, stamp my thing,
okay, bye, you know?
And so, I'm always like, "So,
what do you guys do [laughs]?"
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah, we got a lot
of that in our booth.
Dan: I'm like- I'm like --
Bekah: It's okay.
You don't have to talk to
me if you don't want to.
Dan: Yeah. Well, one of the
people was like, "Have you heard
of us?" I'm like, "No,
[inaudible] I haven't." I --
Bekah: That's awkward.
Dan: And like, also, I'm not
looking for a job. And that's
one of the, like, a lot of
these people are here to hire.
Which makes a lot of sense.
But like ... I probably
wouldn't -- I don't know if
this is a common thing to,
like, get your thing stamped
at every booth thing.
But like, I imagine that a lot
of these booths are used to
the people that come up are
the people that are looking for
jobs. Because that's the reason
they're- they're here, you know?
And I'm like, "No, I don't."
They're like, "Whoa, we have
some positions available in
front-end." And I'm like, "Yeah,
I'm good," [laughs] you know?
Like, I don't know what to say.
I don't -- I'm like, I don't
have the ... I dunno. I could
feel like a lot of people are
just good at ... saying things
in ways that make sense to
people [chuckles]? I dunno.
Bekah: My dad, like, loves
talking to strangers.
I talked to a stranger in the
airport and I texted him like,
"Dad, you'll be so proud of me.
This- this guy used
to live in Pittsburgh, now
he lives in Atlanta, and
he's been there for 10
years, and I had that whole
conversation all by myself."
Dan: That's impressive, yeah.
Bekah: And he was like,
"Isn't that amazing?"
And I was like, "No, Dad. [Dan
laughs] It's not. I don't wanna
do that all the time."
I mean, the guy was really
nice, and- and I would've had
of more conversation with him,
but --
Dan: No, I- I didn't --
Bekah: I think, like,
getting involved too. Like, if
you're a speaker, then people
will talk to you?
So, that's a good way to do it?
Dan: Yeah. I mean like, yeah.
And that's -- I'd say, the
other times that I've
had fun at conferences,
I've been with the speakers.
Not because I was a speaker
necessarily, but like,
I just either knew the
organizers or whatever.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: And like -- or just, there-
there was one event in Florida
that I went to, where they just
had their after party, whatever.
And all -- of course, all the
speakers were there, and I- I
just kinda, like, tagged along,
[chuckles], you know? And
ended up at a smaller thing.
And that's like, for me, I-
I always -- I do much better
in smaller, like, settings,
you know? Like, smaller
groups of people or whatever.
And so ... yeah. I'd- I'd say
... to go back to the
original question, right?
Your strategies for
this sort of thing.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: My main strategy is bring-
bring your friend.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah.
It is really good.
Last year, at KCDC, James Quick
was here. And I just like,
followed him around, like,
everywhere. With --
Dan: Yeah. That's what I- that's
what I told Bekah, I was gonna
do to Bekah. Except that she's
just sitting in this
booth the whole time [chuckles].
And that's less fun.
Bekah: Not the whole time.
Dan: No, not the whole time.
Bekah: Some of the time
I'm not.
Dan: Obviously right now-
Bekah: And now I'm podcasting.
Dan: -you're sitting right here-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -which is cool.
Bekah: I gotta go back to
the booth after this though.
Dan: Right. Yes. Yep.
Bekah: But then tomorrow, I'm
free in the afternoon.
Dan: Yeah. What was that?
Bekah: Yeah.
So, I would say bringing
your friend is nice. And it --
or it doesn't even have to be
like a 'friend' friend. Just
put it out there on Twitter
or whatever, social media,
like, "Hey, is anybody going?
Want to meet up?"
Dan: Yeah. Yep.
That's another
good strategy as well.
Yeah, I did the same thing-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -with Rizl. I was trying
to get
her to come find us as lunch.
Cuz she was-
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: -she was at your talk,
and I didn't know that.
And I probably
missed her, but anyway --
Bekah: It- it is hard when
you're by yourself.
I- I mean-
Dan: Yeah. I --
Bekah: I've been to
conferences that were
terrible experiences.
Because like, there one -- I
can't remember which one it
was. Within the last year.
Like, I would go sit down at
the lunch table, and people
would just like [laughs] stand
up and walk away. And then I'd
just be sitting there by
myself.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: I'm like, "Oh ... all
right.
I'm just gonna
continue to sit here-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -by myself."
Dan: Yeah, yeah. No. I -- when
I'm -- when I-
I've -- I think I've only gone
to one, like, big conference
by myself. And I just turned
into like a bold [??] person.
Like, I honestly, like, put my
headphones on, I'd read my book,
like, or something, you know?
Put my, like, op- open my
computer. I- I'm not good at it.
That's why it's nice
to have a friend, you know?
Bekah: The other thing would
be, you can talk
to speakers, you know?
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: So if you are there
by yourself,
then go up to the speaker
and-
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: -talk or, like, what
-- our-
our badges say if we're
speakers or- or not,
and what company ... oh, mine
doesn't say what
company I'm with.
Maybe cuz I'm a speaker.
I'm not really sure. Does
yours?
Dan: No.
Bekah: No. Yours says attendee.
Dan: I'm an attendee --
Bekah: Well, you can just go up
to him and be like, "So, I see
you're an attendee too
[laughs]."
Dan: [Laughs] Yeah.
That's the kind of thing
that I imagine saying.
And then, you know,
realize it's a bad idea,
and then, you know --
Bekah: Jokes are a good way.
Just go up to somebody random
and tell them a joke.
I think that's a good idea.
Dan: I -- my- my-
father-in-law is the same
way I think i-is your Dad but --
and he'll do the same thing.
He'll do drop a joke or
like, just random, you know,
thing, or make a comment.
And like -- one time, he- one
time, he was -- this is on --
we were on vacation, heard a
lady talking to her friend
at the grocery store. And was
like, she was telling some --
it wasn't like a personal --
it was a personal story,
but not like a- not like
a, you know, private story.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: But like -- and then saw
her at some other
store, like, later, and he was
like, "Hey, how about that thingy
thing?" You know?
Bekah: Oh, that's creepy!
[Laughs]
Dan: Oh, yeah, I know. I'm
like, "That's a horrible act."
And he's like, "Yeah.
And she- she acted kind
of weird about it." [All laugh]
I'm like, "Yeah, no kidding,
man." So, don't do that.
Bekah: No.
Dan: Yeah. I mean --
Bekah: That's why I
bolt my door shut-
Dan: Right [laughs].
Bekah: -in the hotel. And stack
up furniture against the door.
Dan: And he's not creepy.
That's the- that's the
thing, you know? He's
just like ... he thought it
would be funny, you know?
And ... it wasn't.
Bekah: That's not.
Dan: He didn't keep following
her. So --
Bekah: [Laughs] Start again,
a year later and brought
it up again?
Dan: Right.
Showed up at her house.
Anyway ... sorry, Phil. [Bekah
laughs] That was -- I love you.
Dan: Do we have
any more questions?
Bekah: Okay.
Travis followed up, "But I
always like slapping language
and framework stickers on
things, but they seem better
for keeping the conversation
going than starting it." Yeah.
That can be a good way to do it.
Dan: What?
Bekah: Like, language or
framework stickers? Like, talking
about those things that you do?
Like, as a conversation starter.
Like, if my water bottle had
a-
Dan: Oh --
Bekah: -React sticker on it --
Dan: Talk to me about --
Bekah: "Oh, you know React too.
Hey."
Dan: Yeah, yeah. Okay, okay.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: That's cool.
Yeah. I -- yeah.
That's a good idea.
I was -- [chuckles] I started
talking about Tailwind to one of
the sponsor booths that I was
having random conversations
with, and I- I -- pretty sure
I bored them cuz I just, like,
saw their eyes crossing
[laughs]. Not bored them, but,
like, I went off on a
Tailwind tangent. And they
were not interested in
that content [laughs].
Bekah: You can also go up
to each of the booths and
practice a different accent.
Dan: Ooh.
Bekah: So, try the
same conversation-
Dan: [With thick accent] Oh,
yeah.
Bekah: in a different
accent every time [laughs].
Dan: How- how many accents?
What ac- what accent do you got?
What's your --
Bekah: Oh, I don't do -- I
can't do any accents.
Dan: [With accent] You can't
do any accents?
Bekah: No.
Dan: [With accent] You can't
do a German accent?
Bekah: No!
Dan: What about --
Bekah: Ambrose is really good.
He's been practicing his British
accent.
Dan: At the, "[With accent] Get
to the chopper," you know?
"[With accent] We need to do
the -- we need to add the
React to the Remix. Now!
Bekah!" [Laughs]
Bekah: I'm not-
I'm not gonna try.
I'm not even. I was
thinking about it.
Like, "I think I can do that."
I can't do that.
Dan: Every time
I think I can speak
in a British accent,
it does not go well.
I- I feel like I need
to get warmed up on a British
accent.
Bekah: I like mixed British
and Australian-
Dan: Well- well, I'm not
saying --
Bekah: -but I hear that that
is not uncommon.
Like, my coworker, my teammate
is ... he is from England.
Dan: Uh-huh.
Bekah: And he said, whenever
he's in
the US, people either think
he's from Australia or England.
They're not usually really sure.
And he asked the -- one of
the people when we were
together, she was like,
"Oh, that accent." He was like,
"Where do you think I'm from?"
And she was like, "It's
either British or Australian."
[Dan laughs] I was like,
"Yep."
Dan: Yeah. I had -- when I --
when -- I went to
Scotlands, like, a long
time ago ... before kids.
So, more than six years
ago [chuckles], I don't know.
I don't know how much more --
but -- no, I really
practiced it when I was there.
I had -- I felt like I had a
pretty good Scottish -- go --
oh, no. It's pass the thing.
I think- I think it keeps
recording. I think it's just
a screensaver.
I think it keeps recording
when it does that but
I didn't wanna risk it.
Anyway ... yeah, I had a good
Scottish accent going for
a while.
Learned some good words here.
Have you heard the
word 'shuggled'?
Bekah: What?
Dan: Shuggled. Shuggled
is like ... shaken, you know?
Bekah: Oh.
Dan: Like- like shooken up,
you know? As a bus driver was
driving over some bumpy stuff
and then -- and- and she was
like -- something about, "Sorry
to keep you all shuggled,"
or something. [Laughs]
It was- it was really fun.
I like accents.
I'm not, like, good at
practicing them, but ...
that's a good idea.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: All right.
Bekah: Practice your accents.
Dan: I feel like the German
one is my go-to.
Bekah: That's a good one.
Dan: It's like a ... quirky
German. Do you know it?
Bekah: Quirky German? [laughs]
Dan: Yeah.
Not like a serious German.
There's like serious German.
And there's like, you
know ... fun, silly German.
It's like Hans and Franz, you
know, from "Saturday Night
Live".
Bekah: Mm-mm.
Dan: Bekah.
Bekah: "Saturday Night Live"
is on too late.
Dan: I mean, it's from when we
were like kids. So it's not like
nothing very much live --
Bekah: I only know
the cheerleaders.
Dan: The cheerleaders?
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Like [inaudible] --
Bekah: [Soft cheering] Tacos.
Burritos. What's coming outta
your speedos. [Dan laughs]
There's Bobby Fisher. Where is
he? I don't know.
I don't know.
Dan: Oh, yeah, yeah. I remember
that one. That's a good one.
Bekah: That's -- those -- and
get off the shed.
I used to like that.
That was Chris Farley, I think?
Dan: I don't know that one,
But anyway, we've gone-
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: -way off the beaten path
here [laughs]. Thanks, Travis.
I'm blaming with Travis for
that one.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Alright. Is that the
last-
Bekah: I think I -- we're-
Dan: -question?
Bekah: -that -- we've covered
everything.
Dan: Okay. Alright.
I was kind of ... expecting
some of our friends to stop
by and say hi, but nobody did.
Bekah: Well, it's also really
hard to hear.
Dan: Well, sure. But I thought
they would coming --
Bekah: And I know
that they're at talk -- number
of them are at talks. So --
Dan: Yeah. Alright, cool.
Well, this was ... fun.
Bekah: This was an
excellent in-person-
Dan: I hope that the --
Bekah: -podcast experience.
Dan: Yes. It was excellent.
I'm sorry that we weren't
able to live stream it. But ...
well, if you listen to this --
Bekah: We did our best.
Dan: If you listened to this,
then I've already published it.
So I don't need to talk about
when I'm gonna publish it.
Bekah: Yes.
Dan: Cool. Cool, cool.
Co-cool, cool, cool.
Bekah: All right. And we'll be
back next week with another
podcast [laughs].
Dan: I don't -- I'm -- yeah.
I'm having some technical issues
with Descript and trying to get
that last -- trying to get
Bogdan's out. So --
Bekah:  Yeah. So if anybody
works at Descript --
Dan: Yep. Hopefully, we'll get
that sorted out soon.
Bekah: Oh, actually I know
someone that works at Descript.
Dan: Excellent.
Bekah: All right.
Dan: [Laughs] Have them call
me.
Bekah: As usual,
we're very good at concluding
our podcast episode.
Dan: Yes. This is been the
Virtual Coffee podcast --
Bekah: Live edition.
Dan: Live ... edition
Bekah: Live from-
Dan: Live from --
Bekah: -Kansas City.
Dan: Beautiful Kansas City.
And ... I've seen about two
square feet of it [laughs]
because the hotel is right next
to the conference center, but
it's been cool so far. So --
Bekah: Love Kansas city.
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: It's a good place.
Dan: We'll be back ... [whisper]
tomorrow? No. Wednesday? I'll be
back Wednesday night. So --
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: Is that when you're going
back? Wednesday early?
or Thurs- or Tuesday?
Bekah: I leave on Wednesday.
Dan: Yeah. Alright, cool.
Well --
Bekah: All right.
Dan: Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you [laughs].
Bekah: Bye.
Dan: Bye. Thank you for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by
Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot Weigel.
If you have questions
or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us
at podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show
notes, sign up for the
newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website, virtualcoffee.io.
If you're interested in
sponsoring Virtual Coffee,
you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to
our podcast and be sure
to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening, and
we'll see you next week!