Bekah: Hello and welcome back to
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I am
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey, and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
Here with me today is my co-host,
Dan
Dan: What up, Bek? How's it
going? We're back!
Bekah: We are back. We are back
for this brand new season of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast season
seven.
Dan: Season seven. Can you
believe it? I think we're, uh, I
don't know when we're supposed to
come out with this, but we took a
little break, but I'm really
excited to get, get going again.
It, it, we've recorded a couple
already and, uh, it's been really
nice and really fun. I, I missed
it, so I'm, I'm happy to be back.
Bekah: Well, I'm really excited
to be back too. We have some
awesome guests this season. Some
new friends, some friends who
have been around for a while.
What are we talking about this
season, Dan?
Dan: We're talking about becoming
a founder. We're talking about
like some technical writing
stuff. We have, uh, already had a
couple discussions about neuro
neurodiversity in tech, uh, which
is obviously you've, if you're a
long time listener, you know,
that's kind of a, kind of a good
topic for us to talk about. What
else are we talking about? This,
this season? We got a
Bekah: Career transitions. We're
always fan of career transitions.
Lots of new origin stories.
Dan: Origin stories are almost
the best. I mean, all really, all
of it is the best part, but I, I
love hearing people's origin
stories so much. And I'd say at
least like 50, 60% of our guests
say, oh, I just have a boring
origin story, you know? And then
they like, tell us and it's never
boring, And it's always, it's
always. Very, I dunno, unique and
interesting. I, I, I find them
endlessly fascinating.
Bekah: Yeah, I think it doesn't
matter what your origin story is,
even if it, you have taken like a
quote unquote traditional route
into tech. I always enjoy hearing
how people got here and what
they've done to, you know, oh,
they with technology as a child,
or they hated technology as a
child. I don't know. It's just
fun to see the different paths
that lead people to where they
are today.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely. And
honestly, I don't even know these
days what you, what even is a
traditional path into tech, you
know? Uh, everything has changed
so much. I mean, maybe co maybe
college and computer science and
stuff, or, but like that's I've
dug in on the, the people that
have gone through like college.
College. I. I've, I've, I mean, I
always find it very fascinating.
So yeah, our first guest this
season is, uh, is Jörn Bernhardt,
and he is from Germany and he's
been a member for a while. He,
uh, Virtual Coffee and, um, he's
really great guy. I, I, I've
always enjoyed hanging out with
him. He's come on to TypeScript
Tuesdays a few times. Um, and he
recently actually just started a
new Coffee Table group in Virtual
Coffee that's doing CSS battles
on Fridays.
Bekah: have to announce it at
Virtual Coffee every Tuesday, and
it has a really hard title. What
Dan: Oh yeah. Uh, he, he likes
alliteration. He's a big fan of
that. So,
Bekah: Yeah, it is Front End
Friday Folks Fighting
CSSBattle.dev.
Dan: Yeah. Uh, that was like the
fourth one he sent to me. He sent
me a bunch of titles, so he
worked really hard on that one.
Um, so. We had a really great
time talking to Jörn, um, on the
podcast. He has a, again, a, a
really interesting story and he's
had a very interesting career
too, um, which I enjoyed hearing
about. He's a two-time founder
and he does a lot of work with
governments, which that's like a
whole world that I know nothing
about. Um, and it was really cool
hearing Jörn how he's working
with government stuff and still
doing his own thing cuz he is
independent. He is not an
employee of a government, but his
company, does contracting with,
uh, with governments and I dunno,
I found that, I found that very
interesting. It was a good time
talking to Jörn and I know you
all are gonna enjoy it.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast, like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. Today's
question is, what's your favorite
science fiction story? My name is
Bekah. I am a technical community
builder from a small town in
Ohio, and my favorite science
fiction story is Kindred by
Octavia Butler, which is now a
mini-series. And I haven't seen
it because it's my favorite book
and I'm too nervous to watch it
because if they don't do it
right, I'm gonna be really angry.
Dan: what happens in Kindred? I
feel like I've read that.
Bekah: So it is a slave narrative
time travel story.
Dan: Are there more than, is it a
series of books?
Bekah: no, but you know what
Parable of the Sower, I think is
by Octavia Butler, and we did
that for Virtual Coffee Book Club
a long time ago.
Dan: Okay. I definitely read that
one.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: That's cool. Octavia Butler
is dope.
Bekah: Yeah.
Dan: cool. Hi, I am Dan. I live
in Cleveland. I do things on
computers, and uh, um, yeah, I
don't know. I mean, the first
thing that pops in my mind is
Star Wars. Um, there are some.
People will, might argue that
it's not sci-fi cuz of reasons,
you know, so I understand that.
Uh, if I had to pick a second
one, um, I don't know, because my
mind usually goes blank for these
kinds of questions. Um, I think
the, I I would say if, if we had
to, like, if we're gonna be
strict with the science fiction,
you know, whatever. Um, the
Expanse series was amazing, very,
very long, but very, very, very
good. Um, so
Bekah: That's a TV show too,
right?
Dan: Yeah, they made a TV show of
it. I, I watched a little bit of
it, it was fine. Um, I don't
know, I don't know if they've
finished the whole thing or, or
not. I, my Emily was not that
interested in it and so we just,
you know, I don't watch a lot of
TV by myself, so it just kind of
fell off the wayside. But the
books are, are, are so good. Um,
so that would be, uh, yeah,
that'd be my answer. Star Wars
First Expanse second.
Jörn: Okay. Hi, I'm Jörn. I, uh,
work at compose.us and, um, I
work as a web developer and doing
all sorts of stuff because I'm
also the founder of that company.
And, uh, At another company
before. And yeah, always web
related programming stuff. Um, my
favorite science fiction movie, I
think I have to copy Dan because
I, I don't really know. Um, like
I, I love watching, um, science
fiction and fantasy movies and,
um, like everything there, but
Star Wars was also the first
thing on my mind because, it was
the, uh, childhood experience, I
guess.
Dan: Yeah,
Jörn: Yeah.
Dan: exactly.
Bekah: Well, that's awesome.
Welcome Jörn. We are happy to
have you here with us and we
always like to get started with
your origin story and we're gonna
do things slightly different this
season. Um, we're gonna start
with one word. that describes
your tech journey. And then, then
I'm gonna have you tell us a
little bit more about how you got
to where you are. So what's your
one word?
Jörn: Um, well, it's, uh, I, I
guess dream job. There's just
technically two words, but yeah,
I, I have to admit that, um, I
actually always wanted to be a,
um, like with programming and,
um, my, my really first dream job
wasn't like policemen or,
astronaut or something, but it
was actually video game tester
because I played video games like
Alley Cat as a, as a
three-year-old. So I wanted to,
to, um, play these games all the
time. And then I figured out
really, really fast that I wanted
to create my own game, so video
game programmer, so I could test
them and create them. that's way
more awesome. So my whole life
was more like, okay, how do I
program, how does that work? And
somehow out of that I got way
more interested into programming
itself, what you can do with it.
And uh, it led me to a lot of
different things. And now I'm
trying to create nice experiences
for people and, uh, yeah,
especially on the web cause. Have
like the biggest audience, I
guess.
Bekah: what was your learning
experience like?
Jörn: So, um, yeah, it, it wasn't
really nice because nobody really
could help me with, uh,
programming. So my parents, well,
they had the computer obviously,
but, um, they didn't program
themselves. And, um, my, my uncle
gave me like a big box of. Of
floppy disks and I tested all of
them out and tried things like,
okay, how does this work? How
does that work? Got a manual for
MS. Dos so I could write my own
text adventure. That was like my
very first thing that I did. And
the text adventure worked by use
CD into different folders where
you then could read like the next
part of the story, which was.
Weird. I think at that time as a,
as a boy, and, um, later, I, I
had in school, um, some vet
development, well, not really
course, but there, there was an
art teacher who, um, created like
a website and, um, made me look
into that and how that works.
Then we used Macromedia, um,
director, which is like the
predecessor of Flash, I think.
And um, there we created things
like, uh, little games for, uh,
CD ROM for the school that they,
that they put out there, um,
which was refund to, to work on
these kind of things. I then got
a manual for C. So I could
actually create a real program
for the first time in my life,
but I couldn't do it because I
didn't understand what is a
compiler, what does all of that
mean? Because the book was
completely in English that I got
from a parent, from a, uh, from a
friend. and, um, well, he just
gave me the book here. If you
know English, you can do it If
you don't, well that's it. That's
all the help I can give you. And,
uh, yeah, so it took me quite a
while to, to actually get into,
uh, into deeper programming. And
that worked only because we got
internet when I was a teenager at
some point. And then we got, um,
like I could create some, some.
Chats and stuff like that, like
guest books and things like this
in Pearl went to a php, all the
web related stuff, they
maintained a browser game for
like these, these idle. um,
browser games where you say like,
okay, I'm, I'm clicking here to
build something, and then you
have to come back in two hours
until it's done And uh, yeah, it
was actually a really nice
fantasy game. We had a good
community about like, uh, 1000
people were playing that. And,
um, then, um, yeah, we, we also,
we still, um, Know each other.
Like there is still some groups
of people who are talking about
this. We were sharing like, uh,
like holiday, um, vacations
together, like we had, we had a
small, uh, small group of friends
basically established from that.
Um, yeah, then studying and uh,
there I really learned
programming. And got into, like,
I, I wanted to create games for,
um, inside of planes actually,
like, so that the first class
customer can play a poker game
against someone in economy class.
Bekah: That's
Jörn: And, uh, we, we saw that
there, there was basically these,
um, um, these, these. Uh, how do
you call it? Uh, in inside the,
the plane, um, inside the
aircraft. Um, they, they wanted
to create like a network and have
everything on the network, like
videos and, and all of that,
obviously. And you should be able
to do not only video or streaming
entertainment, but actually
interactive entertainment. Then
we want to get in. So, um, we,
that means, uh, me and a friend
who I met in university. So we
founded a company and tried to
get involved into that and, uh,
yeah, it somehow didn't work out
for the planes, but we created
other multiplayer games with
HTML5 at a time where it was. and
Roy two was like the latest
thing. So it was really hard to
get a performance HTML five game
out there, And yeah, we created
different things like this, but
somehow all of that was more
like, okay, we could do the
technical stuff. but it was, uh,
hard for us, for us to sell
actually. So we, um, we ended up
doing more and more projects and,
uh, got enough and good money
from doing more and more
projects, and that's how I ended
up like in an agency kind of
business. And yeah, at some point
I decided, rid of that, um, and
want to go back into some, some
kind of product business. And,
um, we or I, I decided to, to
quit the. that company, it's
still running, so they are still
doing something. But, uh, without
me, they are, I think around 15
people still. So I was working
out for them, but I wanted to do
something new and, um, I wanted
to help more like the, the, in
the government sector, like we
have seen that there is so
little. New things, innovative
things, it's um, not really user
friendly. Every time you have to
interact with the government,
with a town hall, whatever, then
it's always, uh, a little bit
hard. And we decided we want to
make this better. So we started
to create little programs that,
um, should help. like the
citizens and the people who are
working in a city, um, to, to
like, um, yeah, have, have more,
um, or a better view, a better
overview of the city and can, can
do better things basically. Yeah.
So that's my, where, where I
ended up now.
Bekah: That's pretty awesome. So
you've been a founder. Pretty
early on in your career, it
seemed like that was the path
that made most sense for you. Do
you, was that like a decision
that you made or did it just
always seem like a natural fit
for you?
Jörn: Um, so I, I actually didn't
know that there is this career
path of, um, founding a company
until, uh, during my studies
like. um, when I was, um, so I
studied quite a long time. So the
first thing that I did was, uh,
studying in one city at the
university. And we had like a
math professor who was really,
really bad. Um, I. So, so I
always say like, he, he was
talking faster than Eminem reps
and, um, he was saying things
like, okay, this is, this is so
easy. You can read it in the
script. And then you read their
script and then you saw like the,
the proof of that is trivial, but
no answer to your questions
basically. So it was really hard
to follow and, um, I, I just
didn't manage it so, then I was a
little bit depressed, like, okay,
what should I do now because I
can't get my computer science
degree? That's what I thought.
So, um, I got an internship with
Luhan Systems in Toronto. So I
worked on something for, Air
Canada with them and uh, was
basically a software tester.
During that time, I could create
scripts and um, yeah. Accelerated
our testing processes, like quite
a bit like, was like, uh, a two
week long process of checking two
different lock files with a
couple of gigabytes. Um, and, um,
creating an Excel file out of
that. So you could basically see
what, what were the differences.
and that improved the testing
process from like these two weeks
of manual looking at these lock
files into a 20 minute process.
So it was really great and
everybody liked that and they
wanted to actually hire me. And I
said, well, if I do that now, I'm
probably not getting, um,
anywhere like there, there will
be a fixed point where I can't.
over it. So if, if I stay at that
company and, um, so I thought,
okay, I'll try that with a
computer science degree again, in
a different, uh, kind of
university, uh, uni, university
of Applied Sciences, and I could
actually do that there. But we
had this one term, um, well one
semester where we had to, um,
basically. in a company as an
intern, and I already had this
experience, so I didn't really
want to do the same thing again
or something like that. And I
was, uh, still maintaining that
browser game and I wanted to get
this to a next level. So I, um, I
said, okay, what do I have to do
in order to get this into, into
something that I can work on
this. and, um, basically still
tell you my professors, um, that
I'm doing like an internship
during that semester. And, um, I
had to incorporate, uh, well in
general it's called fine. I'm not
sure how it's, how it's called in
English. Um, it's, it's not a
real company. It's more like a,
um, Like a club, sports club or
something. Um, but just for that
game. So we incorporated that and
then I could basically get there
as an intern and, uh, work on
that stuff. And, uh, yeah, I, I
did that this one semester. They
said everything's fine. Great.
Cool.
Dan: So you were an intern at
your own, at your own company.
Jörn: Yeah, basically
Dan: That's awesome.
Jörn: But in order to know how to
incorporate, um, I had to ask
someone at the university who was
doing like these, um, like
helping people to found their own
companies and. Well, I talked to
him. I don't want to own my own
company. Like I think that's way
too involved. I just want to do
that small little thing. So he
told me what to do there, but I
was in this newsletter now and he
wouldn't let me go. Like he was
always pushing me into like, you
are the kind of person that is a
founder and you should just
accept it, that you are. You're
doing things all the time and you
want to. Things your own way. So
you are actually that kind of
personality to do that. And I,
um, well, it didn't occur to me
until, well, he told me like
multiple times and I have seen
that buildings things from the
ground up is really fun and I
really like it. But yeah, it's,
it's also very involved so. Work
late and long and all of that. So
yeah, I don't know, but it's,
it's fun still. So,
Bekah: what do you think some of
the biggest challenges have been
in founding your own companies?
Jörn: um, How to, how to say, I
think bureaucracy is, uh,
something that I really hate. I
know that it's necessary, but I
really, um, hate if you have to
read through like this, this, uh,
lawyer language, um, that that's
very, um, energy draining. Um, I
think many people have struggled
with finding other people, and I
think that somehow works out for
me. Um, like I, I wouldn't found
my own company just by myself.
Like I, I need other people. Um,
and I, I need other people who
have different interests so that
we can share the workload
basically, and, um, try to, um,
to, to get better at everything
basically. And, uh, yeah, but
really the, the hardest, hardest
is probably just the. all, all
around it. Like the, all the
lawyer stuff, Texas and all of
the things that is not about
building the product, doing
something around the, the product
or, or whatever you do, actually.
Dan: So do you try to find a
founder or a partner, whatever,
that can do that stuff and not
much of the building stuff or
like what, like what, what, you
know, how, how do you, or do you
try to like learn that stuff, you
know, anyway, you know what I
mean?
Jörn: so, uh, the, the person
that I told you about who, um,
who gave me that, Hey, you should
phone your own company. Um, he,
uh, this, this counselor,
basically, he said that, um, he
started with economics and now he
thinks like, Bad idea to, um,
just do the business
administration and then try to
get into tech, for example, to
build your own stuff. He would
very much like it, way more to,
um, study computer science, do
something like this so that he
can build something. Because all
the stuff that he learned, he
said that's something that you
can get on your, um, in, in your
head anyways. And. Actually, you
don't, you don't get around this
at all. Like you, you can't just
say like, okay, someone else is
doing that for me. Like all the,
all that part because in the end
you will still be personally
responsible for whatever you are
doing or not doing, basically.
So, um, I think it's more like I.
Always looked into, into people
who can help me more with the
things that I'm not that good at.
Um, but just for taxes and things
like this, I think we, um, or
everyone that I, that I worked
with, was more on, on the
agreement that, uh, we let that
do like a tax, uh, consultancy,
for example, help us with this.
then, um, yeah, all, all of these
things we try to outsource
basically
Dan: Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Jörn: but yeah, it's, it's
costly, but I think, um, it's way
better to have a better and, um,
bigger, um, product then, um, try
to save some little money there.
Bekah: Yeah, there was a podcast
that I listened to a couple of
years ago and it was talking
about, um, I can't remember how
they framed it, but it was kind
of relationships and so they
examined different relationships,
uh, and it, there were people who
were married, there were people
who were co-founders. There were
people who were on teams
together, but they were saying
like, all of those relationships
kind. you, you function within
similar roles, right? And like
complementarity was a really big
part of that. And I think that,
you know, that's important in
that founder journey and, or you
know, whatever journey you are
working with other people or
teams of people. But then as part
of that, like being able to
recognize like this is. Something
that, that we should outsource to
someone else. It makes more sense
long term to be able to make that
decision and maybe spend that
extra money rather than, uh,
spending that time trying to do
it ourselves. I think that's a
really, it can be a hard decision
to make, but a really smart one.
Jörn: Yeah. I, I, I guess so.
Like I, I think. One, one thing
that I, that I learned also was,
um, okay, if you, if you have
shares at a company and like, if
you can sell that company for,
let, let's pretend like, uh, 1000
euros, then you will get your
shares from that if you get
someone else. Like you, you have
100%, you get 1000 euros for it.
Basically, if you have 50%
shares, you get, uh, 500, uh,
euros from it if someone else has
50. But if the other 50% give you
like an extra boost so you can
sell it for 10,000, you will end
up with 5,000 euros instead of
1000 euros. So it's a way better
deal. So, um, if you, if you can
find people who can, um, make
your company better, um, in, in
that regard, um, it will, it will
help you in the long run as well.
So I think it always makes sense
to, to focus on the things that.
work out well and try to improve
the company itself instead of,
um, trying to like save a little
bit here or there instead. But
yeah, you can't always, um, say,
okay, I'm not going to save on
that or no.
Bekah: Yeah. What is the size of
your company? Right.
Jörn: Um, so we are six people
right now. and, um, but well to
working students and, uh, the
rest, full-time, um, two founders
basically. And, uh, yeah, we are
looking to, um, well just, get
the projects done that we
currently have for our, uh, our
current thing. But then, uh, try.
to focus on products again. So I
don't think that we are going to,
to, um, look for investment
money. So, um, we kind of like
this bootstrapping mode cause you
are actually forced to always,
um, create value and, um, if, if
you have this investment money
where you can say, okay. we are
all safe now. Then you probably
lose a little bit of this energy
of, okay, well I have to, I have
to create, well, you know,
because I need that money and I
only get that money from
customers and not from somewhere
So, um, it kind of makes sense, I
think. It's may, maybe later. It
could make sense if you, if you
have a real product where you
want to get a really big
marketing budget or something,
um, or try to expand in a
different area where you don't
have really any connection to
yet. Um, but yeah, I, I think
the, the bootstrapping thing, uh,
just makes sense cuz you have to
work more.
Dan: So the plan would be to
kind. When you've moved over back
over to products, would you kind
of keep some contracts or, you
know, still do some contract work
to keep paying the bills? Or are
you guys kind of just saving up
enough that you can focus
entirely the entire company on,
product, product work,
Jörn: It's a, it's a good
question,
Dan: if it's a, if it's a secret
plan, you don't, you don't have
to, you don't have to, you know,
reveal
Jörn: No, no, no. Um, it's, it's
definitely, uh, definitely we
will, um, keep on doing, um,
projects, um, just because we, we
won't be able to, um, completely
lose that. I guess I, I think we
will have, after this project
right now, we should have enough
runway to. I have a few months of
focus work on the product, but
still, I don't think that you can
create a product that fast with
that much, um, monthly recurring
revenue, so fast and easy that,
um, you can sustain a company
for, for a long time, like, or
right away basically. I think
it's, it's really hard to, to
get. But the, uh, a good lesson
that you can learn from this, uh,
y Combinator startup school kind
of thing. They, they always say
like, okay, the, the biggest
issue for startups or the, the
biggest thing that you need to do
is, or concentrate on, is to not
die. Just don't die as a company.
And so many things work out. I
think if you, if you do something
and you find out, okay, that is
not financially sustainable, you
have to stop it, otherwise you,
you will die and yeah.
Dan: Yeah, I think, I think
that's really cool. I, it reminds
me of, uh, and I mean lots of
people have done it, but, um, 37
Signals are, I, I guess they just
changed their name to Basecamp.
But, you know, the Basecamp folks
did the same thing. You know,
they, they did it, they started
out just purely as a client
company. And then, um, well, I
think they made Basecamp because,
for internal use, honestly. And
then they decided, you know, and
then they were like, Hey, we
should, we should probably, we
should just make this a full on
product. But, um, I, I, I. No, I
appreciate that approach a lot.
You know, and I think that's a
smart way, I like the way you
said it cuz there's, there's a
lot of trade-offs of taking
investment money. Um, and you
hear about some of them, you
know, I mean, we, you relinquish
some control and all that stuff.
But the, what you said about the
energy, I, I think I, I really
appreciated that how, how you get
this big influx of money and you
lose all that urgency and the,
and the, you know, kind of
day-to-day stuff. I think that's,
it makes a lot of sense to me
anyway.
Jörn: Well, sometimes I think it,
it would be great if you
Dan: Well, sure,
Jörn: have that right like it can
stress you out quite a bit. But
yeah, I, I don't know. Like, um,
once you have a big, um, client
contract for example, and you,
you got it and you know that you
will be like, for the rest of the
year you are totally booked,
whatever, and it works out for
your company. As a whole, then
that's so, like, that's you who
has done this, right? So it's way
more powerful than having someone
else do that for you. And yeah,
I, I think it energizes you a lot
more to, to get there.
Bekah: You are a fully remote
company, right?
Jörn: Yes, I, the first company
wasn't fully remote. Um, this one
now is, and I kind of like it.
Um, but we are doing that only
with, um, in inside of Germany.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Jörn: Because of, as I said
before, the we are outsourcing
everything to tax consultancy,
for example. And they told us if
you want to have other people
from other countries, that will
cost you a lot more. And we
thought like, okay, well there
are enough people living in
Germany who can help us for now.
But yeah, I, I think also I made
the experience with, uh,
different time zones. It can be a
little bit tricky also in the, in
the current, um, well the, the
current industry that we are in,
like public administrations, it's
uh, basically always only German.
So we, um, we need people who can
speak and understand German in
this regard. and, um, yeah,
that's, that's basically what we
are, uh, working with right now.
So it's, uh, it would be hard to,
to change this, but it's, it's
not from the table, so I would
definitely say okay, if we find
someone really good for a task
that we really need help with,
then um, we are definitely open
for anything there. But yeah.
Bekah: And when you founded the
company, it was a couple years
prior to the pandemic. Right. And
then, Moved into the pandemic,
and I know I talked to a lot of
founders who really found that
time to be challenging or maybe
that was where they ended their
business. Um, what was that
experience like for you?
Jörn: Okay, so, um, the, the
start of the pandemic is still,
uh, really. Um, tough time for me
because like, it happened a lot
of stuff like was the, like the,
the week where there was the
first lockdown in Germany the
week before we got our daughter.
So my, my first child. and, um,
it was a Thursday and on Monday
there was the lockdown. So my
wife got out of the hospital on,
on Monday with the child. Um, it
was lockdown day and the day
before our daughter was born, her
father died. So there was really,
uh, a weird situation like it's
three very. Uh, hardcore things
that, that happen at the same
time. So I really didn't have to,
um, I, I didn't, or I couldn't
really think of lots of, um,
stuff around that, right. So I'm,
I wasn't, um, I wasn't really
thinking too much about, okay,
how. How is, uh, this going to,
to change anything because we
were still like, okay, our
company is, is working. We still
have our clients. Um, we had
issues then with, um, like some,
some projects that we were really
thinking that, um, that they
will, um, come, didn't come.
Basically like a lot of other
client companies were. Mainly
saying, okay. Um, we are not
going to do that anymore. We were
already, um, well we, we already
said before the pandemic hits
that we want to, uh, focus more
on these public administrations,
but we still did client work for
private companies, so basically
building web applications for,
for bigger companies there. So,
um, We try to, to get into, into
different things that, uh, worked
during the pandemic. Like there,
there were a couple of
applications that tried to help
with the pandemic for, for
example. So we, um, made contract
work for them and um, yeah, had
different things like this, but.
I don't know. We just focused on
do not die the whole time. So in,
in all the senses, So Kit do not
die. My wife don't die to
depression or something. Company
don't die because we all need
money. And um, yeah, so.
Bekah: That's really intense,
that That's a lot. Um, hoping
things that are feeling better
now, maybe hopeful.
Jörn: Yeah. Yeah, definitely. No,
it's, uh, it, it's been, uh, two
years now. So I think, um, we
are, we're getting, we are
getting somewhere again. Also,
I'm very optimistic, like I'm ex
extremely optimistic all the
time, so I always thought of this
like, this will going to be hard
and, or this is hard, but it will
end at some point in time. So I
just have to, to get through this
and then at some point it will
get better and it will feel it
once it's there. So, um, I think
that helps a lot. And, uh, yeah,
I don't know, my, my best man
told me, um, that he, he finds it
interesting how I can get from,
from these experiences and just
get back up and say, and say
like, okay, well then let's do it
differently, if it doesn't work
out that way, basically. But, uh,
never, never, uh, give up and try
to like, I, I don't know. What,
what should you do? He would say
like, okay, it doesn't work out.
Okay, well then find something
else. I guess So you have to,
anyways.
Dan: I feel like that, uh,
attitude is, Seems like really,
really important for a founder,
for a good founder, you know, um,
being able, uh, you know,
everything that I've read and the
people that I follow that do
this, you know, talk about like
how failure is part of this
process, you know, and, and, and
a lot of, uh, y you can't always
count on everything working out
exactly right. You know, and so
being able to pick yourself up
and say, okay, let's try
something different and not just
quit, you know, like, not rage
quit or, or keep trying to pound
in the same. That's not working,
you know, other people, I mean,
I've, I've seen that happen too.
You know what I mean? And I
think, uh, I think that seems
like a really good and healthy,
uh, attitude for, for somebody
that's wants to do, you know, you
know, this sort of thing. I think
that's cool.
Jörn: I think it helps. Yes. But
yeah, I, I also believe that the,
the team itself, um, needs to,
needs to be something, right?
Like the, the team needs to be
good. I don't think that one
person alone can, can do. like
really big things you always need
a team for, for that. Even if
it's like, okay, people are
saying something in a meeting and
then this one person can connect
all these ideas and say, okay,
our ideas know this. You know,
like if, if you don't have the
team around you who are talking.
Really good things or creating
impulses that you can use, then
you won't get there. We will, I,
I don't think that you, that you
can actually create something
great if you, if you're just for
yourself alone without these
external impulses there. And, uh,
yeah, if you want to create
something quick, then you
probably also need a couple of
other people who can help you
with.
Dan: Since you're our, uh, fully
remote, um, team, like what are
some ways that you foster that
sort of. That's sort of like idea
making and, you know,
communication and things like
that. Like do you do daily
standups? Do you, do you know,
what kind of stuff do you do,
Jörn: we, we do and we do it
especially because like, I have
to get up at some point in the
morning so it's, it's more like
this, uh, trying, um, trying to
get me out of bed more or more in
the morning because of, um, I'm,
I'm a very, like you have seen me
in the co-working room around
like 3:00 AM. during the week
sometimes. And this is not, uh,
not really the, the way that it,
uh, should work. And I'm
definitely not like the, the, uh,
role model for how you should
work. I guess. It's, it's more
this, uh, and try to, to have
everybody be healthy and, and do
their things that. that work out
for them. But for me, sometimes
it just works out best if I work
late in the night, but then maybe
the next day I sleep a couple of
hours during the day. Doesn't,
doesn't really matter that much
there. So, um, as long as the, as
long as the work that I do is
still, uh, working out. And, um,
yeah. As you, as you said to, to
create these impulses. Yeah,
definitely. We have, uh, our
dailies and, um, we, we have
meetings to, to talk about things
like this. Um, like where we,
where we do this, we also, um,
Had workshops where we just
gathered together. Um, so we
still have some rooms to, to go
some if, if we want to or need
to. I mean, right now we are
focusing more on the client
projects, but while the client
being a bigger public
administration right now, so, um,
we are just trying to, to do our
best work there, but it doesn't
really. Like this creative
impulses there
Dan: Yeah, sure.
Jörn: right now, So when, when
you, when you just have to like,
okay, do that work. And we, we
know that it's going, it's going
to, to pay, pay our bills,
basically. But um, yeah, once we,
once we have this, We will
definitely have another meeting
and another more strategic
approach towards our products.
Again, so always or that, depends
on what our current, uh, work
mode is.
Dan: I like that. I don't know if
you are able to, but are you able
to share what your sort of next,
like the product thing is that
you are hoping to move? Or is
that, uh, it's okay if it's
secret. You don't Yeah. You don't
have to
Bekah: it is top secret, you
should still tell us anyway,
Dan: yeah. Or you could tell, you
could tell us
Bekah: that you heard it first on
the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
Jörn: No, no, it's, it's not,
it's not secret. So we are
building, um, like a, um, a
damage reporter kind of, um,
product. But, um, so basically
every, um, every city has, has
something like this already. And
you would think like, okay, well
why should you build something
like that? And the. The thing is,
what we want to do is we want to
create like smaller products to
get inside of the public
administrations to teach them
that like digital products. Are
something that can actually be
good and you, you, you can do
something with it. So our product
is not really focusing on the
citizen, like, okay, it will be
easy for a citizen to report a
damage somewhere, or like the
garbage trash cans are, um,
spilled over at the playground.
So you want to report that you do
that through their website. But
usually it's like, okay, there's
going to be some mail to, to the
public administration and then
they say, okay, well maybe we'll
do that when we will do something
about that. But they don't really
care too much about what, what
this means in general. Like if
there are multiple reports of
that in the same area, maybe they
want to tell the police that
they. for maybe some teenagers
doing weird things every weekend,
basically. And you can see that
if you, um, if, if you have some
kind of mechanism to, to track
these things a little bit more
easily. So, um, we are building
products like this in order to,
um, to show them. As the public
administration, you have new
possibilities. Now you have, um,
more things that you can do with
that. And we want to use these
smaller products to get into the,
okay, what can we do to, to get
bigger, like into bigger projects
that you want to tackle. You want
to show them. All of the bigger
projects are failures. If you
talk and if you have trust in, in
the people who are building that
with you. And I think there is a
really big problem right now. Um,
when you, when you hear stories
about, okay, what, where's the
tax money going? Right? People
are building. um, projects or
doing projects for, for the
government, they use lots of
money, and in the end you get
something. Well, they could have
used an Excel sheet for that you
know, that, that's how it feels
like when you, when you're a
taxpayer there. And I think the,
the thing that we want to, to do
is more like, okay, we want to
customize. Things really to, to
the administration so that it
really makes sense. And it's not
necessarily just an Excel sheet
basically, but, um, you should,
you should really have like a
good, well thought out and
connected experience. In, in all
of what you, what you do. But we
want to grow into that and not
like, okay, we will build
something and then take it
because that won't work.
Especially not as a small
company. So it's more like, okay,
we are testing, uh, different
things with different small
products, and then we will, um,
eventually get somewhere, I
guess. and it already landed us
some, some of these projects. So,
um, it kind of works out, I think
Bekah: Nice.
Dan: I think that's awesome. I,
yeah, it sounds very complicated
and it sounds like a lot of
talking and bureau and
bureaucracy, which I think you
said you didn't like at the
beginning of the, the podcast,
but
Jörn: Yes, yes.
Dan: I, as a taxpayer and as, as
a, um, you know, Citizen of a of,
of, yeah. Of a human being. I, I
think that's great. I am all, all
for that. And I think your
approach sounds really cool too
because, you know, you hear
about, um, I think the
traditional experiences I've come
near and, and I've never worked
with government contracts or
anything, but is, is like they
say, oh, we need this thing and
put out a request, you know, and
people bid on it and all that
stuff. And that, I think is
usually a recipe for disaster.
point, it's too late. Right?
because they've probably decided
the wrong thing that they need.
You know, I, we deal with this a
lot with our client work, um,
where a client will come and say,
Hey, we need X. You know, they,
they've talked or whatever for
their company and they're like,
we need this thing, you know, and
they're trying to hire it. And,
um, last times with sprockets,
what we do is we get in and learn
about the thing and they're like,
well, you don't actually, like,
maybe you need this eventually,
but this is what you need first.
And it sounds like exactly what
you're talking about, like, One
of the, like easiest ones was a,
there's a company that builds,
um, decks, uh, you know, for the
back of your house. And, um, they
needed a website, you know, and
they came, we need a website,
like we're not, you know, we're
not getting leads or whatever.
And they made fancy decks and
like expensive ones for like nice
houses and. Uh, it turned out
like, well, you, you didn't need,
like, the, the first thing that
they needed wasn't like, people
aren't Googling them or whatever,
you know, like they're never
gonna like find them. What you
need is like, your neighbor gets
a really nice deck, well, those,
like their neighbors are the ones
that you know, that want to buy a
deck. Right? And so first thing
they did was buy, uh, we, we
convinced 'em to get truck, like
big, big wrap decal wraps for
their trucks so that everybody
knows when they're getting a new
deck that like, this is the
company that get it, you know, in
their, their business. Like
immediately increased. You know,
it was just a small thing. It was
like not a huge investment. It
was just like five or something,
you know. And I, and eventually
we did website you know, but at
that point it was like, okay,
now, now we need to like, you
know, but it's still, you know,
um, lots of times. My, I guess my
point is, lots of times the
company or the, or the, in, in
your case, the government agency
doesn't actually know exactly
what they need. They have decided
like, there is a hole there,
there's something wrong. But at
that, like at the point where
they're like doing a request for
like, for, what's it called? A
request. Something, whatever it
is, I can't remember what the
acronym Uh, but at that point,
they're asking for the wrong
thing lots of times, you know?
Uh, and so do I think what you,
you've like identified this need
and it's a small thing, you know,
it's like, it's not a huge, like,
we're gonna redo your whole, your
whole everything, you know? Um, I
think it's a great approach.
Jörn: I mean, we are, we are
working for like bigger companies
that work for the government,
like. Having really big project
for the government, you can't
really get there, get in there
easily. So you work with other
companies that work for other
companies who do all the, or get
the project basically. And, um,
then you find out that nobody
really knows what, what everybody
needs, you know, like, and it's,
it's really hard to. to, um, to
get like, so, so we are at the
base level then talking to the
people who need to interact with
that product. In the end, we, we
talk to them and we find out that
they don't really know what, what
they will get because they are
not actually involved into the
buying process. we need to find
out what they really need in
order to make the product like
the best fit. And, um, yeah,
sometimes it's, it's not really
easy to say, like, okay, um, this
is going to be the, like, will it
be the same as, as what? The
buying process basically said it
would be or will it not? I
honestly, I, I can't always tell.
Because I, I think sometimes you
just don't need to, to sell
something like, like just as you
said with the tech company, I had
a similar experience with, uh,
someone who wanted to move their
block from a privately hosted
WordPress instance into blog
blogger.com because he heard that
you can host on blogger.com for
free. And he was paying 500 Euros
for his really big, uh, WordPress
blog to some private company, and
I told him no, just move it to
wordpress.com itself. And it will
cost like 50 bucks per month
maybe for the traffic that you
have instead of 500. So you will
save a lot of money and you don't
need to to get me to try and
rebuild everything that you
already have into your
blogger.com, something which is
really limiting your abilities
and it's not great. But he has
heard that we were. I'm doing
that for another, like a
satirical newspaper, which is,
uh, quite famous in, in Germany,
which has like 300,000 visits per
day, which is really a lot. And
um, yeah, it's hosted basically
for free on blogger.com. It's,
yeah, the tech stack is really,
is Theus. There's their content.
But it worked And I, I told them
like, no, I'm, I'm not going to
work for you. You, you move to
something else and just save
money there and don't do that.
And I think that builds trust.
That is the trust that they will
tell other people that if I ever
really need something, then I'll
come back to you anyways. So.
Dan: Absolutely. And there's
like, if he's lucky that he came
to you first, cuz there, I'm sure
there's plenty of people that
will, that would just say, okay,
well cool blogger.com, the client
asked me to do this. Here's my,
here's my invoice. You know what
I mean? And
Jörn: Yeah.
Dan: you know, um, so I think,
Jörn: And then they will say
what? That much
Dan: Right, right.
Jörn: Yeah.
Bekah: All
Dan: hand type. Oh, sorry. I was
just continuing on the joke. It's
okay. I'm, I'm done.
Bekah: make you not be funny. So,
um, all right, before we wrap up,
I've got two more questions for
you. And the first one is, what
is one word that describes you
Jörn: Optimistic.
Bekah: optimistic? Oh, I like it.
And how do you think that's
impacted your journey to where
you are?
Jörn: Well, um, with every
failure. Failure or every failed
attempt to something, I could
just. Get back up and, uh, work
through it, I guess. So
Bekah: great. Well, thanks so
much Jörn for being with us here
today and sharing your story.
Jörn: Thank you for having me.
Dan: Thanks hearing
Jörn: was a experience.
Dan: Yeah.
Jörn: Well, you, you should
handle your expectations, right?
You be low. So you are always
like, happy If something good
have thought of that. If I would
say, say like, Hey, this is the
best thing I ever did, and then
something negative comes along my
way, then I can't be optimistic
anymore. So
Dan: So true,
Bekah: there. You heard it first.
All
Dan: All right.
Bekah: We'll talk to you soon.
Dan: Bye Jörn!
Jörn: Okay. Thank you. Bye-bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!