Bekah: Hello and welcome to
Season seven, episode two of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the virtual
coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey, and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned,
and we are here to share it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host Dan.
Dan: What up Beck? How's it
going?
Bekah: It's going.
Dan: good. Um, hi. Yeah, we have
an awesome episode for y'all
today. Uh, we're talking to Joe
Karow. Joe's been a member for a
while and he's been pretty
involved in the community. Um,
and he's, he's a really great guy
and we had a lot of fun talking
with him. Joe has been an active
volunteer for a while. He's done
things like run our JavaScript
coffee table group. He's appeared
on TypeScript Tuesdays, and he's
been a really active open source
contributor for our virtual
coffee projects. So today we're
talking with Joe about, uh,
career transitions and also his
experience with ADHD, in his tech
career. And it was a really good
conversation.
Bekah: Yeah, it's always great to
hear a good transition story. Joe
used to be in hotel management,
so there's some skills he was
able to bring over from there.
But to be able to kind of compare
those experiences and see Joe in
a position that seems to really
fit his skillset in the things
that he's interested in.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast, like we start every
virtual coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. Today's
question is, would you rather go
to a waterpark or an amusement
park? We hope you enjoy this
episode. My name is Bekah. I am a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and I would
prefer to go to an amusement
park, which is ironic because I
will be at a waterpark next week.
Dan: Which waterpark
Bekah: Kalahari in Austin giving
a talk.
Dan: At Kalahari?
Bekah: Mm-hmm. Yeah. At the top
of the water slide. I think
Dan: Best technique for, you
know, maximum
Bekah: where they put the
keynotes. You're like at the top
slide. And then if you are not
doing a keynote, then you have to
go to like the lower
Dan: Oh man.
Joe: Yeah, and the whole slide
down is, it's a metaphor for
something.
Bekah: Yeah, exactly.
Dan: Um, all right. Well, hi. I
am Dan. I, uh, live in Cleveland.
I do computer thingies and, uh,
what is the question? Oh, um,
yeah, I would say I don't really,
I'm not a huge fan of either,
honestly. I don't really like
large crowds of people, and I
definitely don't like standing in
lines. Um, but I think I would
say the amusement park. My sense
is that the food will be better.
That's gonna be my, that's gonna
be my, like my main, you know,
like a get like a really good,
you know, corn dog, like a, you
know, like a funnel cake. Yeah,
yeah. Like all that, all the
fried stuff, you
Bekah: Have you had one of those
funnel cakes that has like ice
cream and whipped cream and
strawberries on top?
Dan: I don't think so. But that
sounds good. And now I shall find
one we used to go to, um, before
our covid and stuff, we'd go to
Octoberfest here at Cleveland,
like at the fairgrounds every
year. And that would be our, that
would be like our fried food, you
know, fix like final cake and
corn dogs and stuff. And also
beer, you know, it was just, it's
like the perfect combination. But
yeah, amusement park would be my.
Joe: All right. And I'm Joe
Karow. Um, I'm the lead engineer
at a small nonprofit, um, and I'm
based in the Washington DC metro
area. As far as the question
goes, I'd probably go also for
amusement park. Um, I don't know,
like, again, I'm, I'm also not a
fan of large crowds, so if I'm
gonna be miserable, I'd rather
not be damp and m. I'll go for
dry and miserable
Dan: Yes.
Bekah: Dry and miserable.
Dan: Yeah. Dry, miserable. Yeah,
no, that occurred to me. Yeah,
that was one of my things.
Waiting in line if you're, if
you're gonna be waiting in line
rather be dry. Yes.
Joe: Yeah. I also, I, I got my,
my fix of all those, cuz like, I
grew up, uh, in Tampa, Florida.
So the default school trip for
anything was Busch Gardens. Um, I
can't, I think it was, it was one
of the, I think it was like my
sophomore year in high. just
based off of like, you know,
different departments like that.
I think I went to Bush Garden six
times in the same year for school
trips.
Bekah: Oh my gosh.
Joe: Yeah.
Dan: Yeah, we, we did a lot of,
that's, that's impressive. Six
times is
Bekah: Did you do a Cedar Point,
Dan?
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. A lot of Cedar
Point. Yeah. Was there a lot of
times as a, you know, as a kid
last time, I think the last time
I was there, I got really bad
food poisoning. It was like a
field trip. My dad had to come
pick me up and stuff.
Bekah: Oh,
Dan: So it, uh, I, I refused to
try to think about which food,
what caused it, you know. I've
had, I haven't, I don't think
I've, I haven't not been back to
Cedar Point because of that, you
know, like I would, I would go
again, but yeah, it was, it was
not that fun.
Bekah: We had Kennywood, so
that's in Pittsburgh.
Dan: Oh yeah. I've driven past
there.
Bekah: I used to love the
rollercoasters, like back in the
day when I was younger and now
having kids and like doing roller
coasters with them. I find them
very terrifying.
Joe: Well, awesome. So now like.
We're older, we get back and neck
problems
Bekah: Yeah. Alright, so I think
the, the takeaway from this is we
are all boring Don't go to the
amusement park with
Dan: We would rather be dry and
boring than damp and boring.
Joe: right? And one of us will
hold your bags.
Bekah: Um, welcome Joe. It is
good to have you here on the
podcast. Uh, we always like to
start off with your origin story,
uh, but first I have asked you to
choose one word to describe your
developer journey. So let's get
started with.
Joe: I dunno. It's somewhere
between chaotic and good. I
didn't really expect to kind of
Bekah: wracking is
Joe: nerve wracking. There we go.
Yes. Um, I didn't really kind of
aim to be a career changer. It
just kind of happened. Um, uh,
because prior to this I was in
the hospitality industry. Um, you
know, kind of wore several hats
in that. So I started off doing
front desk, which is like people,
people, people all the time, you
know, you're there to solve
everybody's problem. And then I
moved over to finance and kind of
worked my way up, you know,
through the ranks of that. And I
was still just solving everyone's
problems, but it was just
internal ones. Uh, but with Covid
it just, the industry just went
into disarray and it was just, it
was not enjoyable anymore. So,
um, I had, I had decided to take
a break, um, and then at that
point I was like, Hmm, what do I
want to be when I grow? you know,
and it's always fun asking
yourself that question, you know,
at the age of like 37 Um, and it
was just something where I, I
kind of started looking, you
know, into web development. Uh,
cuz it, I've always messed around
with technology. Uh, I actually
did web development, like when I
was like high school, middle
school, um, like literally back,
I actually found one of my old
websites, which is somehow still.
From 1999.
Bekah: We would like a link to
include in the show notes.
Joe: never gonna happen. Never
gonna happen. Uh, but I'll tell
you right now, when that, when
that site meant free hosting for
life, they meant it
Dan: Yeah. That's impressive.
That's awesome.
Joe: But yeah, so, um, I, you
know, I kind of said along what
Vil meant. It was, you know, I
kind of talked it over with
family when I went, I went back,
uh, for holidays. You know, chat
with them and came back in
January and I was like literally
getting ready to like pull a
trigger on doing one of those
multi-thousand dollars boot
camps. And I stumbled upon um, a
Reddit post for uh, 100 devs and
I was like, well, let me try this
first before I go. And I, you
know, commit to money I don't
have, cuz I figure if it doesn't
work out, the only thing I've
wasted is time. And that was the
one thing I had plenty of So,
yeah, going through that it was,
you know, it was, it was really,
well, you know, the way it was
done. Um, and the, I think the
biggest part about doing that
versus doing like the whole kind
of free code Camp Oden project
thing is having that community
around you. Because when you're
just there by yourself, you're
like, it's really what I'm
supposed to be doing, you know?
And you don't really have anyone
kind of like holding you
accountable or. in the trenches
of misery with you whenever you
just can't figure something out.
So at least you can, you know,
kind of be like, oh, well I'm not
the only one who can't figure
this out. So it's not just me.
And then I, I happened upon this
job and I've been, um, working
here for, since about Labor Day,
so going on like a little over
four months now. And I love it.
Nonprofit life. It's, it's, slow.
It is laid back. Everyone is
super nice. So it's like a really
big change from like the chaotic
world of hotels where everyone's
like, I need this and I need this
now.
Bekah: Yeah.
Joe: yeah, we'll get to it.
Bekah: That's really nice and I
really appreciate the thing that
you were saying about learning
with a community of people and
not feeling like, oh, I'm the
only one that doesn't know this.
Like the ability just to know
that you are not the only one
that doesn't get it is somehow
really motivating in a lot of
different ways.
Joe: Yeah, and this is probably
not gonna sound right, but like
it's always nice to kind of,
sometimes you go and you're
seeing like how other people are
struggling. You're like, well, at
least I'm not there.
Bekah: Yeah.
Joe: I'm doing better than
someone.
Bekah: Yeah, it, no, I think like
all of us have kind of had that
feeling too, though. Especially
when you're really struggling a
lot and you're like, okay, I
know. I know I shouldn't take joy
in this, but this is what I need
to motivate me right now.
Joe: It's kind of like, you know,
watching Hoarders, we're like,
all right, my house really isn't
that bad,
Bekah: Um, I wanna jump back to
your word to describe your
journey a little bit more and see
if we could dive into that a
little bit. So, nerve wracking,
right? So as you're going through
this developer journey, this
learning process, and, you know,
as a career changer and somebody
who's not doing it in their early
twenties, how do you think that
that kind of like impacted that
journey and how were you able to
get through it when it felt so
nerve-wracking or chaotic?
Joe: I think the biggest thing
was going to be like anticipating
the imposter syndrome because
I've already experienced it, like
with other roles, you know, like
especially right around like kind
of promotion time and you're like
sitting in your new office and
you're like, man, I wonder how
long it's gonna take for them to
realize that they've made a
massive mistake by doing this. So
I think it was just kind of like
nerve wracking of like, you know,
anticipating that imposter
syndrome. Cause I knew, I knew it
was gonna come, whatever job I
had landed at that, at that
point. But it was also just kind
of like, um, you know, cause I, I
essentially was out of work for a
year and I, I, I had a bit of a,
a monetary buffer going into it.
But, you know, watching that
dwindle is also never really fun.
So I managed to, Luckily get the
job right around the same point
where I was like, all right,
things are getting kind of tight
right now. Um, so it was just
kind of like, just nerve-wracking
of life of like, am I gonna, you
know, is this all gonna work out
in the end? Like I don't wanna
have to like, you know, start
selling plasma or something.
Bekah: Yeah, that's really hard.
And I imagine that going into the
interview process, that made it
even more nerve wracking because
you're, you're watching that bank
account go down. and you know
that there's a time period where
you're gonna have to make a hard
decision potentially. So how did
that impact how you interviewed,
where you applied in that whole
job application process?
Joe: so. I got really lucky. I'm
just gonna say that flat out. I
got incredibly lucky. Um, because
the way that I actually came
across this job was, um, I had
stumbled across this job board
where they only list like
nonprofits, public benefit
corporations. It's like, you
know, companies who do good. Um,
and you could, you know, you
could submit your resume to their
talent pool and you could also
like look at all their listing.
So I did that, forgot I did it
for like a month and a half, and
all of a sudden get this email
from this job board saying, Hey,
um, this, you know, this company
would like to meet you. Here's an
introduction. Um, and that's
where I work now, so I only
interviewed once. Um, so I, it,
you know, and it just, And to be
like, you know, I was thinking
like, okay, well maybe I can kind
of take this offer and like, you
know, shop around other places.
But between, you know, what the,
the, you know, the, the product
was and the team and the mission.
I was like, no, this is, this is
work. This is where I belong. You
know, and it it, that's the other
thing about working for a
nonprofit is not only is it like
super laid back and everyone is
really nice, um, you also, you
get that satisfaction like, you
know, I'm, I'm doing something
that's, that's benefiting others.
Bekah: Joe, Do you know, do you
know the name of the job board
that you use just in case we can
share that out with other folks?
Joe: um, I believe it was all
hands. I can, I can give you a, a
link for it in the, for the show.
Bekah: Awesome. Thank you cuz
that sounds really awesome. And I
know that there's a lot of people
out there that are looking for
different types of opportunities
and I think my first job
experience, uh, full-time
position outside of college was
at a nonprofit organization and I
really learned a lot. Through
that experience and working on a
really small team of people, and
I think it just provides like a
unique insight into the ways that
you can do things differently,
the communication, and it was
nice to have that sense of
mission at the end of the day.
Joe: Yeah. And one of the other
like biggest points of, you know,
especially like working on a
incredibly small team is you get
exposed to a lot more. Whereas,
you know, if I went and I got a
job, um, at some big megacorp. I
know that like my, the first six
to eight months of my job would
be like, here, work on this
button, and that's all you're
ever going to do for the next six
to eight months is this button.
Whereas, you know, I, I'm leading
the rewrite of an entire site
right now and it's exciting and
scary and exciting.
Bekah: Yeah, I like didn't know
somebody and that was their job.
Like the first six months at a
big corp. It was just like
dealing with three buttons.
Dan: I mean, buttons are
important. You know, you gotta
gotta make sure the buttons do
button things, I, I guess,
Bekah: Yes. If your buttons do
not do button things, then you're
really in trouble. It's gonna be
bad.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah.
Joe: make sure you get that exact
right shade of blue. You don't
want it to be too blue, but you
want it to be blue enough.
Bekah: Mm-hmm. border radius,
it's gotta be perfect.
Joe: Right.
Bekah: Total aside for my
internal hackathon project, I was
like all about the border radius.
I'm like, these border border
radio is are Ray, what is the
plural of Radius?
Dan: that was, that was it. Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. They didn't match
and I wasn't gonna let that go
Joe: Line by line, every css.
Gotta make sure that they're
pixel perfect.
Bekah: I'm not, I'm not even good
at CSS. Like I think that's the
funny part. Like I ended up
designing a lot of stuff and I'm
really bad at design, so
apologies to anyone that saw my
project. But we did win
Joe: Honestly, I think there's
probably only one person in on
the on earth that's actually good
at css. Everyone else is just
frustrated by it and just does it
cuz we have to.
Bekah: We have what Dan, you've
been doing the CSS battles with
Jörn who was on the podcast, um,
this season as well. What, what
do you do in your CSS battles?
Dan: those are fun. Yeah. So
it's, it's like CSS battle io or
battles, I'm not sure. but the
the idea is, uh, you get like a
picture and then. A little iframe
and you have to basically add
markup and CSS to make it look
like the picture, like exactly.
You know, so if they overlap,
there's no difference. And then,
um, you submit it and then like
it gives you a score based on,
um, whether passed and then how
few characters you can use to get
it to do that. And as a, as a
group, we like kind of all just
kind of hang out and do it
together, you know, sort of like
somebody else will share. And
then like other people will
either, Just like tag along or do
it on, you know, themselves on
the side, you know, which is what
I usually do. I usually try to
race everybody see what I can do,
but
Joe: are these like web layouts
that they're giving you or are
they like, um, like
Dan: Nope. They're like, they're
like designs. Yeah. They're like
just little not web layouts at
all. Yeah.
Joe: Okay. Cause yeah, cause I've
seen people who are like rec, you
know, they're creating like these
incredible like, Graphic images
using nothing but CSS
Dan: Yeah.
Joe: and I, I wouldn't even know
where to begin.
Dan: Yeah, I mean, like it's,
it's not like anywhere close to
that, like, you know, that like
depth, you know what I mean? I
mean, the ones we've done, and
we've only done a handful, but
the one this time was just like
three little like semi-circles,
you know, sort of. But one was
flipped and, you know, and so
it's like a mix of trying to get
the design right and also trying
to be efficient, you know? And I
don't know, we just usually start
by just like trying to get
something down and then see how
everybody else did it. And then I
spent like two hours trying to
get mine as small as possible.
Last week it was bad but also,
Bekah: you update it after Jörn
made it?
Dan: um,
Bekah: It was like one fewer
character or something.
Dan: I didn't, I didn't, yeah, I
didn't. It, uh, now that you
reminded
Bekah: Sorry. I'm sorry. It's fun
to, it's fun to watch everybody
talking about it. I haven't
jumped into the challenge, but I
don't know. It's
Dan: Yeah, it's fine.
Bekah: like fun.
Dan: Yeah, and we always like
have somebody just, you know,
somebody stream and everybody
kind of helps them, you know,
kind of try out their approach
and there's always like a million
different ways to do it too. So,
um, that's part of the fun too,
is seeing what everybody kind of
goes towards without like looking
at other people's, you know,
solutions first. So, I don't
know. It is entertaining.
Bekah: So, um, kind of going
along with that, Joe, you talked
about enjoying the work that
you're doing, but you don't
really work with a team on. what
you're doing right now. Is that
right? Or.
Joe: Yeah, well, sort of, yeah.
So I, um, I'm the only engineer
actually on like the, on our
payroll, um, as a or an employee.
Um, I work with. Two other
contractors. Um, and then it's
interns and volunteers. So I've
only had one intern up until now,
but I'm about to get like three
more, uh, next week, which is
going to be fun and exciting. Um,
you know, so it's, it's, it, it's
been a bit of a change in
management style just because
like I'm used to. having a team
that is like there at a certain
time, you know, but with this,
it's very, it's very async. So
it's just a change of mindset of
like, you just need to take kind
of like time outta the equation
really, and just be like, all
right, is stuff kind of going at
the pace that it needs to be
going? And, and so far we're,
we're good.
Bekah: Yeah. That's really great.
So it seems like you kind of get
to be doing some mentorship with
your work, and I wonder, are
there skills that you found in
hotel management that have helped
transfer over to what you're
doing now or that you find to be
useful that maybe other people
might not think of?
Joe: I feel it. I mean, it's ma
mainly like the situation
management was probably like my
biggest takeaway. Um, just
because for like the longest part
of my time in hospitality, I was,
I was managing more situations
than I was people. Like there,
you know, there were some times
where I was managing people, um,
you know, modest team sizes, but
a vast majority was like managing
situations of like, okay, this is
cropped up. How do we fix.
Because, you know, with hotels,
like you're dealing with the
craziest variable of them all,
and that's people Uh, so it's a,
you know, so it's a lot of like,
on the fly problem solving. And I
think that kind of, that lends
itself into development because
yeah, bugs crop up and, you know,
sometimes you gotta get real
creative.
Bekah: Yeah.
Joe: you know, other than that,
like with, you know, people
management, I was also kind of
very lucky because with, um, the
team that I did have, um, it was
a very diverse team. Um, mul, you
know, everyone from different
cultures, you know, different
countries, different ages, um,
you know, but it was great cause
we all just, we got along
together as like people, and
that's, I think that's the
biggest asset to a team is like
when you can all just get along,
you know? casually and, and you
know, with each other that just
kinda makes everything else fall
into place. Um, yeah. Cause like,
I, I, my management style is
like, I'm not very hard at
people. Like, I'm just, I just
treat people like people and I
think that's really all you can
do.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. And I'm
gonna back up in time a little
bit because you went through 100
Devs bootcamp, and so for anybody
that's not familiar with a
hundred devs, can you dive in a
little bit more into how that's
run, what the community looks
like and what your experience was
with.
Joe: Yeah, so, um, 100 devs. I,
I, so I went through the second
cohort, uh, but it initially
started, uh, the first cohort
was, I wanna say it was like
October-ish of 20. Uh, so there's
this guy named, uh, Leon Noel.
Um, he actually works for a
nonprofit called Resilient
Coders. Uh, by day what Resilient
Coders is, um, they're also kind
of like a, a bootcamp, uh, but
they work within certain, I think
they've got, I think they're in
like Boston, Philadelphia and
maybe somewhere else, but they
work in, um, trying to kind of
help people. like economically
disadvantaged backgrounds, um,
and just also bringing a lot more
diversity into the tech world. So
they work with a lot of, uh,
people of color and stuff like
that. And, you know, just
offering those resources. Um,
it's, I think they, it's like
heavily, I don't know if it, if
it costs anything, uh, or if
anything it's heavily subsidized.
Um, but they, they, it's more
than just like a, here are the
buttons to press and here's how
JavaScript works. It's all the
total package of. All right,
here's how to code, but here's
how to interview. Here's how to
network. Here's actually how to
get your foot in the door. So he
took a lot of that and brought it
into 100 devs. So we just kind of
brought it online, um, without
borders basically. And everything
is a hundred percent free. If
anything, if you do 100 devs
correctly, even before you get a
job, you're making. because one
of the things that that happens
to that is, um, there's a, a
whole section on freelancing. And
one of the assignments is you
have to go out and you've gotta
get a, a freelance client. He's
like, I want a signed contract
and it's gotta be worth at least
x amount of dollars. Um, so, you
know, the, the great thing about
that is, um, you start seeing in,
you know, inside the, the
community, like everything is
kind of centered around the
discord, um, which I think now is
up. Like 30 or 40,000 people,
which is insane. Like, I don't
think anyone thought it was gonna
get this big, but you kind of,
you start seeing people like
celebrating like, Hey, like I got
$2,000 to do just this. And
people are like, what can I
charge that? Yeah, of course you
can. You know, if someone's
willing to pay it, you can charge
it. So it, it's, it's also really
helped a lot of people kind of
building confidence within
themselves. You know, cuz you,
especially if you're, if you
haven't really been in tech
before you, you're like, I can't
ask someone to pay this much for
that. And you realize, yeah, you
can, because they're not, you
know, they're not paying you to
do like what might only be a few
hours worth of work for you.
They're paying you just to get
this done because they don't know
how to do it. They don't wanna
know how to do it. It's just,
that's not, that's not the best
use of their time. You know, if
they're running the business,
they need to be focused on
running the. and then you know,
you're, cuz you're just really
providing a service to them and
you know they're willing to pay
for it.
Bekah: Yeah. Uh, it's really
great to see people coming
together and doing that and
having that broken down in a way
that seems practical and usable
during the process. So do you
work with teams or groups at any
point during the bootcamp?
Joe: so. because, yeah, so when,
when, when we first started,
everyone was just kind of in
like, you know, like the, the
discord was just one main channel
where everyone kind of
congregated and it was kind of
overwhelming at first cuz there
were, because again, like the
size ballooned. Um, but as we, as
we went on, then they actually
started, um, breaking us off
into, into other groups. So,
There was two different, uh,
categories that we were broken
off into. One of them was, um,
like regional. So you would, you
know, you could pair up with
people who were kind of within
either the same city or the same
time zone, at least as you. And
then another one was just kind of
like, um, like identity and
affinity based. So, um, like
there was groups for like over
40, over 30, um, adhd. There was,
there was a bunch of other ones,
but yeah, so you could, um, so
you could also be kind of broken
up into that. And that's
generally where our, our groups
could kind of form because
you're, you're getting into, uh,
conversation with a smaller group
of people. But we would also
have, um, like project nights
where we would go on this one
platform called Remo, which, um,
the first time we did it, we, we
broke it because there was so
many of us on it. Uh, but Remos
kind of like, um, it's almost
like a virtual conference in a
way that like there's, you know,
it has like a little floor plan
layout that has like a bunch of
little tables, but each table is
like a, like a little zoom
breakout room with a maximum of
like six people. So we would just
all get shuffled into these kind
of like, random tables. So we
would just meet these people for
the first time and go, all right,
let's build something together.
Bekah: and. Seems like a really
interesting approach, right? If
you throw a bunch of people into
a room and try and figure it out.
So how did you kind of work with
the other people to figure out
what your roles would be and how
your project would develop?
Joe: Um, I, I often kind of found
myself taking the lead a little
bit just because everyone was
kind of sitting back and like
looking around. So I was like,
all right, I guess I'll. I'll
gets kicked off. Um, I, I would
just, I would kind of just at
least break down of like, all
right, this is what needs to be
done. Who wants to work on this?
So I, I don't really like to kind
of assign things. I, I want
people to like volunteer for it
first. Cuz if you, you know,
you're gonna volunteer for it,
you're gonna be more motivated to
actually do that. Um, but I think
some people will just look. as a
whole and they just don't know
where to start. So, you know, you
need to kind of just break it
down to those smaller pieces and
then it's easier for them to, to
digest and, you know, and kind of
wrap your head around cuz it's
not just like, oh, all of this.
No, just work on this little part
right over here. Um,
Bekah: I think that's great. It
seems like it, that matches up
with your previous career skills
too.
Joe: Yeah. And it, I mean, it is
even, you know, it's carried
forward. Even the way that I'm
working today, cuz you know,
right now we are working on a
complete and total ground up
rewrite of, of our web app. Um,
so I, I just go into, to Jira,
break everything down into small
tickets and just kind of leave
everything new column. I'm like,
all right, have at it, you know,
and it, and if it gets to the
point where some things are
starting to get stale, then
that's where yeah, I'm either
going to assign it. Maybe just
take it on myself.
Dan: Yeah. That's cool. It's cool
to hear. And that's, that's,
that's, that's a hard skill to,
to learn. Uh, you know,
especially the fact that you just
kind of came into it while you
were learning this stuff, already
having that ability is, um,
That's very cool. Very.
Joe: Yeah. Which, and it's a,
it's a bit of a departure from
like my normal life cuz generally
I am not organized in my personal
life. Like if we go downstairs
and look at my dining room table,
it's not a dining room table.
It's just like a we'll put stuff
here for right now and we'll deal
with it later.
Bekah: I had a boss once who told
me I was the most organized
person she had ever met, and I'm
like, I have a tendency to be
organized with work things, but
when it comes to home things, I
don't know. It's I, I have my, my
piles, you know.
Joe: Yeah. Cause even like when,
um, you know, when I worked in an
office, uh, like. I had piles on
my desks, but I knew where stuff
was because those piles were
chronological. So I could be
like, oh, well this happened
around this time, so we're about
here But sometimes those piles
just ended up being like a, oh,
I'll just throw this out in two
weeks instead of like throwing it
out right now.
Bekah: Yeah, I feel that. I feel
that too. I recently was looking
for something that I worked on
this summer. and I thought maybe
I drafted it online. And so I
looked through like all of my
regular places. I looked in docs,
I looked in Confluence, I looked
in Google, keep, like, looked
through my email, not there, and
I'm like, oh crap, it's gotta be
in a notebook, but, but the
problem is I have like 20
notebooks or something. And so
then I was looking through all
those notebooks until I finally
was like, you know what, I can
just redo this entire thing and
it will be fine. Like,
Joe: Hey, cause. because even,
um, you know, cuz working in
hotels, like you get a lot of
emails cuz you're just on like 50
different email lists and you
probably only care about two of
them, but you still have to be on
on the other ones. And I had some
coworkers who would like
meticulously have like the very
large nested folder structure and
like, oh, this goes here, this
goes here, this goes here. Mine
was like, everything goes into
archive. And people were like,
well, how do you find anything?
I'm like, Hey, do you notice this
thing up here? It's called a
search bar. Type in three words.
You get it
Dan: Yeah, that, that one, uh,
you know, Gmail came. because it
wasn't really an option before
that. You had to like, you know,
you only had certain amount of
space that you could have on your
email, you know, whatever. And so
you had to make all those
decisions. Yeah. And then Gmail
came out and was like, here's a
gigabyte of storage, which
doesn't sound like much now, but
you know, then it
Joe: but back then, yeah.
Dan: big deal. And yeah, I did
the same thing. I and Emily is
the same way. Yeah. My wife has,
you know, nested folders and
labels and all these automations
and stuff, and I'm just like, I'm
lucky if I even archive it. you
know? Uh, but the search is, you
know, the search is like the key
for that. Obviously being able
to,
Joe: Yeah, well, sometimes you
get to the point where you're
just like, all right, I'm just
gonna select everything from here
down and just put it to the
archive. Cuz if I haven't. For it
or add it yet. I'm probably not
going to
Dan: yeah, no, that's, um, this
sort of thing is I think, uh,
pretty common. I don't know. I, I
have ADHD and and, and, uh, I
know Bekah does too. We've talked
about it a bunch on the podcast,
but I think it's pretty common to
me. Okay. I was, I knew you did,
but I didn't wanna like really,
you know, uh, um, diagnose you on
the podcast. But, uh, it's a very
common thing I think with, um,
people with ADHD is like, we
learn these coping mechanisms,
all, all these different things,
ways to be successful at what we.
but like our brains aren't still
like, set up like that. And so
lots of times there's, we all
have these areas at home or, or
wherever, you know, where it's
not as vital to be on top of
everything, right? Nobody is
going to be, uh, I don't know,
losing money or something if my
clothes aren't picked up, you
know what I mean? Like right away
or whatever, you know? And so,
um, I, I, I, uh, I've been
learning about these coping
mechanisms, um, and things like
that and, and like even
identifying things as coping
mechanisms. Um, Since my, when
you diagnosed my, my son got
diagnosed, uh, recently with ADHD
as well, and so like, I'm not now
like relearning about all, all a
lot of this stuff, you know, from
kind of a different perspective.
It's, it's really interesting.
Joe: Yeah, and cuz like, I'm, I'm
actually, you know, I'm one of
the like late in life diagnoses.
Um, like I only got. The formal
diagnosis, um, back in like April
of, of 2022. Um, and I think
it's, you know, cause it's before
really before the pandemic, I
just felt like everything was
just so busy and chaotic and that
was just the way that it was. And
then when, you know, like the
pandemic happened and like
everything just kind of shut down
and you're just kind of like, you
know, the entire existence was
like disrupted. And you're just
kind of sitting around watching
Netflix and thinking way too
much. And then, you know, a lot
of like self-reflection. You're
like, maybe things don't always
have to be this difficult, you
know? Cause I, I know that
there's been a big spike in
diagnosis since the pandemic and
I think that's just been a, a big
pattern of like, you know, people
just had a lot of time to. Sit
back and just kind of reevaluate
things and going, this isn't as
hard as it is for me, as it is
for everyone else, you know?
Dan: Yeah, yeah, yeah. For.
Bekah: So I probably mentioned
this on the podcast before, but
uh, Dan ha was telling me about
his ADHD experience when I was
working for him, and he was
saying things and I was like, oh,
that's not how everybody does it.
Like in, in my mind, I had like
no idea. It was totally off my
radar. And I remember telling my
sister-in-law when I got
diagnosed, I was like, yeah, I
got diagnosed with AD or no. I
said, I think I might have adhd.
And she was like, oh, you didn't
know. And I was like, oh, no.
Dan: Nope. I, yeah, I, I was
diagnosed, yeah, in like 2019,
but I exact same thing, except
with, with Emily with my wifi. I
was, was like, kind think I have
80. She's just like, oh, I just
thought you knew no, I didn't
know.
Joe: I don't wanna bring anything
up.
Dan: She's just like, yeah, I
know. I just, uh, yeah. You know,
it's, I don't know. It is a very,
uh, interesting experience and
so, yeah. So when the pandemic
hit, I was, that was when I was.
I'm really learning about it, uh,
for the first time, you know,
and, and kind of finding other
people to talk to about it and
all of that stuff.
Joe: well it, I mean also, you
know, cause we're all, you know,
around like the same age, so
when. you know, we were younger
and in school it, like, ADHD
really wasn't thought about
unless you were like that kid
that was just bouncing off the
walls. But, you know, like, cuz
one of the, you know, the, the
things that was like, oh, well
you're, you're doing well in
school, you can't have it. Or
like, you know, it was also very
generative, like, oh, girls don't
have that. That's only a boy.
Dan: Yeah. And yeah, and a lot of
that is because that bouncing off
the walls thing was the only,
like, it was being disruptive in,
in different environments was
like the only basis for diagnosis
before. Yeah. And, uh, it's
gendered because of that, because
women are taught not to do that
much more than boys are, you
know, um, the girls and boys I
guess when they're, when they're
kids, uh, in America,
unfortunately, you know, and so,
yeah, it, it's, it's a weird
thing, but I'm, I'm, it seems
like it's been changing a lot
more recently, and I hope it
continues to improve because I
think, you know, I mean, I've
found, I've personally found
being diagnosed very valuable.
It's, it's been like a
interesting. Not always easy
journey you know, but, um, but
yeah, it's, I don't know,
Joe: Yeah. I think the biggest
thing is it helps you at least
kind of rationalize what's
happening inside, you know, and.
I think also, you know, like, and
the fact that you were, you know,
you were able, that your son was
diagnosed, you actually have the
ability to make sure that his
life is not going to be as
difficult as yours was going
through. Like, you know, like
that, that period of school, uh,
you know, cuz like, I, I just
remember of like always getting
like harp on and be like, why are
you waiting till the absolute
last. You know, you've had a
month to do this. Why are we
doing this night before? I'm
like, because this is how it gets
done, and I'd always get it done.
It was painful while I was doing
it, but it always got done.
Dan: Yeah. I can't always say
that it the same my personal
experience of actually ever
getting things done, but you
know. but for sure
procrastinating. Yeah. And like,
and, and back to what you said
about like trying to provide
stuff for, for my son, for
Bennett, it's like the, yeah. I
don't want him to have that
experience, you know? And I
didn't know why, like, I couldn't
do homework and my, my parents
were, you know, I mean like good
supportive parents, uh, like kind
of disappointed. My grades were
awful. my test scores were really
high and my grades were bad. And
I, it's like now a pretty, like,
typical, I think a, a very common
anyway. you know, sign or
whatever, un undiagnosed, uh,
adhd. But it's just like it. I
still don't know how to do
homework. I don't know how to get
people to do homework. You know,
like, so part of this was like
getting some tools for me to
like, help, help him, you know,
cuz I, like, I don't know what
the right solution is. He has
also, he's in first grade and has
homework, which is just like
killing me. Like, I, I, my first
instinct was like, no, we're not
doing this at all. We're, we're
just not doing that. But I feel
like that's probably not. The
whole school career thing, so,
Joe: Right. You're like,
Dan: uh,
Joe: these things off on 'em. I'm
like, oh, we can wait till later
to do that.
Dan: yeah, but
Bekah: the very light, least you
can communicate on his behalf to
people, because especially with
like kids, they don't, they don't
know what's going on or what's
happening or why it's happening
or. You know, in the case of one
of my kids, they don't really
care why it's happening. They're
just having a good time, you
know, So like trying to break
that down and communicate with
them and communicate with
teachers as needed, I think goes
a long way to help everybody be
on the same page and your kids
feel supported.
Joe: Yeah. And I mean, uh,
probably the, the other biggest,
you know, valuable thing is just
the fact that like, you can help
him understand like what's going
on in his mind, because I don't
know about, you know, for you
guys, but like, you know, back
then it was like, if you're
procrastinating, that's because
you've chosen to procrastinate.
That's the way it was drilled
into you. Like, why are you
choosing to make things harder
for yourself? And you're like,
I'm not, like, I literally, it
doesn't exist in my mind until
like now tomorrow,
Bekah: I think I, my reaction has
always been opposite, so I've
never really procrastinated. That
gives me a lot of anxiety, but
it's in the other extreme, like
it's gonna be done a week
beforehand, so I know that it's
done and that I, and if something
happens, like I still have more
time to do it, but. And I think
I, I have been speaking to more
and more adult women who have
ADHD. They all got good grades in
high school. They weren't
disruptive. So, you know, a lot
of, like the common markers are,
are not the issues. And a lot of
it comes down to interpersonal
communication, relationships with
other people, and like
recognizing that for me, made a
huge difference in how I
communicate with other people,
how I understand myself. How I
understand social situations,
because I always used to say I
was a shy introvert, and I'm not
really sure. I, I think I'm just,
um, just a shy, ADHD person like
introvert and extrovert don't
really serve me anymore because I
think that there are times where
the ADHD energy comes out when
I'm in social situations and that
feels very extrovert. But there
are other times where I think
having to, um, Like behave in
ways that are socially acceptable
and not ADHD behaviors becomes
really exhausting, which would
be, uh, something that somebody
might classify as being an
introvert. So I'm not really sure
where I stand on that, but I
think what's been helpful to me,
at least right now, is
recognizing like, all right, you
know, if I have to be in a crowd
of people where I have to behave
in these, uh, these ways, I'm
going to be really tired after
that. You know, if I'm gonna be
giving, I am always exhausted
after giving a talk, and I think
it's because I have to stay
focused for that amount of time,
you know? And after that I'm
like, all right, I just need to
go, like, sit in a chair
somewhere and be by myself for a
little bit, regain that energy
before I can come back out. But I
think that that's really driven
by that the, the ADHD part of my
brain.
Joe: Yeah, like, I think like
with, with like public speaking,
not only do you have to like stay
focused, but like the fact that
you have like everyone looking at
you, it's hard not to like, you
know, like let your mind break
away going, well, what is that
person thinking about me? What is
that person think about me? They
hate this, but they love it.
Bekah: Yeah, this was the whole
thing last year. Dan came to my
talk at KCDC on, uh, TensorFlow
Js. And I, really struggled.
There were people that got up and
walked out, which is like normal,
like people do that, you know,
but I just could not recover from
those moments where, and I just
like felt terrible out about the
talk for the rest of the day.
Didn't matter what anybody else
said to me.
Joe: Yeah. Because in your mind
it's not like, oh, they need to
go to the bathroom. You're like,
they hate me.
Dan: And the whole rest of the
room stayed and, and enjoyed the
talk too.
Bekah: Doesn't matter. Those
people don't matter.
Dan: right?
Joe: one who broke it.
Bekah: Yeah. I'm glad that we're
talking about this like less than
a week before. I'm going to give
a talk. Super anxious about it.
Until then,
Joe: Yeah. But I, I think, you
know, at least kind of knowing
it, you, you know, you can kind
of. Model, you know, like design
your behavior around it. Like,
you know, like you're saying
about being in, you know, in
large crowds, you know, you know,
like, alright, I'm, I'm not gonna
do well with this. So you can at
least plan like all I'm just
going to go, you know, take a
walk off somewhere else, you
know, somewhere else and just
take some deep breaths and just
kinda center myself and then I
can go back in there refreshed
instead of just trying to like
hammer through it all in one go.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. And I do find
that one of the things that helps
me is knowing somebody there, uh,
particularly someone that I've
met before, because I know, like,
is this a person that is not
gonna judge my behavior in this
moment? If I'm too loud, if I'm
talking too fast, if I go off
topic in on 27 tangents in a
conversation, because then that,
that just is. One of those spaces
where I don't feel like I need to
be editing myself before I speak.
Joe: Mm-hmm. Yeah. Cause like, I,
I went to, um, this AWS event,
um, in DC you know, a few months
ago, and, I was hoping that I was
gonna at least, you know, like,
you know, know some other people
there, you know, meet up with
some other people, but that
didn't end up happening. So at
like, some of like the end of the
night, like networking things,
like one of them I managed to
actually strike up, uh,
conversations with, um, a couple
of these girls and we just kinda
hung out the entire time. That
was really. the next night, which
was like the final one where it
was like everything was like, you
know, big, crazy loud, and like
they've got people jumping on
trampolines and doing flips and
stuff like that on stage. I tried
to kind of like insert myself
into this one table, and then it
was just kind of like, oh, hi,
you know, mind if I da, da da.
And then everything's kind of
fell silent and I was like, oh,
okay. Now this is awkward looking
around for an escape. And the
other thing too is like, I. I,
you know, also stopped drinking.
So I was like, oh no, I don't
even have like that social
lubricant anymore. And just
between like all that and like
everything that's happening, I
was like, you know what? Let's
just call this tonight. Let's
just go home. let's go home. Pet
the dog. Watch some tv, eat some
dinner.
Bekah: Yeah. Well, I think that's
really being able to think
through that and understand,
okay, it's not, it's not worth it
to continue to push this, like,
this isn't doing me any good, and
so it's better for me to preserve
myself, my energy and to, you
know, do do something that is
better for my mental health or
physical health or whatever. Uh,
it, that self-awareness I think
is really key to anything you do
really.
Joe: Yeah,
Bekah: We've made this the ADHD
episode officially,
Joe: right. Yeah. How surprising.
We planned one topic and we ended
up with a completely different
one. Who would've thought.
Bekah: which I'm totally fine
with. I think that this is a
really good conversation to have,
right? It the I get. Frequent
messages from people about ADHD.
I think it's in my Twitter
profile and sometimes people will
just DM me and be like, I have
ADHD too. You know, and it's
often that like story of I was
just diagnosed and exactly what
you were talking about at the
beginning, Joe. It's the same
thing of not feeling alone, you
know? Because if you don't know
anybody else, or you're on this
journey, whatever journey it is
for the first time. you're
setting out alone, and that feels
really lonely and overwhelming
sometimes. So if you have
somebody that's there who you can
hear like, oh, I had that
experience. Oh yeah, I feel that
way too. Somebody else feels that
way, then like suddenly you're
not alone. Even if you don't know
this person and you're just
listening to them on the podcast.
Joe: right? Yeah. Like yeah, it
is definitely scary when you
first start up, but yeah, when
you kind of start to build up
that little group of community,
it's not so bad.
Bekah: Sorry. I looked at Dan and
I thought that Dan looked like he
was gonna say something.
Dan: I was having an idea. was
the, wasn't planning on saying it
out.
Joe: idea where you start to it
to yourself first, and then
you're like, alright, I can say
this out loud.
Dan: uh oh, no. No. I, no, I was
just, uh, you know, being a
developer with ADHD and like has
been, has been an interesting
experience. My idea was having
like some sort of panel or
something like that, you know, or
a podcast episode or whatever
specifically about that. But it
wasn't a well formed idea and I
wasn't really planning on saying
it out loud until Bekah forced me
to, so,
Bekah: we should definitely do
that. I think that would be
really awesome. Um, where.
Joe: that one you're gonna need
like a Zoom room so we can use
that hand raise function,
Bekah: Yeah, uh, we're at about
time anyway, and so we're gonna
wrap up with my last question to
you, which was, what is one word
that describes you?
Joe: inquisitive. That was the
one I chose. Yes. Um, just
because like, I mean, through
about every career that I've had,
my one thought was like, how can
I make this better?
Bekah: Yeah,
Joe: you know, like, how can I
improve upon this? Um, and that's
kind of, I, I think that's kind
of what has led me to where I am
right now is like, you know,
there, there's gotta be a way to
automate this part. You know, I
would've automated answering the
phone and talking to people if I
could have.
Bekah: That's awesome and I think
that's a really good quality to
have, um, and a great way to end
this episode. So thanks so much
for being here with us today,
Joe, talking about your journey
and sharing with us your
experience about ADHD.
Joe: No problem. Thank you for
having me.
Dan: Thanks, Joe. See you later.
Joe: Alright, bye.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!