Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season seven, episode three of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey, and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
We're here to share it with you.
Here with me today is my co-host,
Dan
Dan: Yo, what is.
Bekah: the Sky.
Dan: sky. I like it. Um, how's it
going,
Bekah: it's fantastic. It's just
an amazing day here.
Dan: Is it, it's really, really
cold here. so it was, uh, yeah,
it's 17 degrees Fahrenheit, so,
uh,
Bekah: 47 here.
Dan: Really? No, you're lying to
me.
Bekah: It's not, it's really
Dan: Bekah's always lying to me.
Bekah: I don't, I, I don't lie. I
don't
Dan: No, no, that's, that's me.
I'm the Eagle Scout. You're the
non-Eagle Scout
Bekah: Oh, we all know about
Eagle Scouts and what kind of
people they turn out to be.
Dan: as soon as I said that, I
knew you were gonna bring that
up. Bekah found. Actually, I
might have found it, I don't
know. Remember I was saying about
how Eagle Scouts are all
honorable and never lie, and we
found an article just
Bekah: are a lot of murderers
that are Eagle Scouts,
Dan: Yeah. Major crimes committed
by Eagle Scouts. And that was
sad. And some people, sometimes
people fall off the, you know,
Bekah: Eagle Scout Trail,
Dan: the path. Yeah. The trail.
Exactly. Yes. So, you know, what
are you gonna do?
Bekah: We really derailed this
really quickly.
Dan: Uh, yeah. It is kind of our,
our way, you know, uh, I think
it's kind of apro. Um, anyway,
today we are talking with Kai.
Kai is a tech content specialist
and mental health advocate. Um,
they've been a member for a while
and very active in the community,
and we had a really great
conversation.
Bekah: Yeah. I really appreciate
their input on the learning
experience about mental health,
about finding different paths
into tech. I think that we all
come from different perspectives
and to think about the different
ways, think about the different
journeys that we take to get here
can create a hopeful space for
people who are thinking about
coming into tech.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast, like we start every
Virtual Coffee, we introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. Our
question today is, what is your
favorite story with a happy
ending? We hope you enjoy this
episode. My name is Bekah. I'm a
technical community builder from
a small town in Ohio, and my
favorite story with a happy
ending, I'm gonna go with the
Princess Bride just because
that's a fun book and a fun
movie, and I enjoy it every
single time.
Dan: You stole mine. I gotta stop
lady. You gotta stop going first
cuz you're always, it's the
worst. Um, the Princess Bride is
amazing and it, that's, that's
like, anyway, it's a good choice,
obviously. Uh, okay. I'm Dan. I
live in Cleveland. I do computer
things. Uh, yeah. Favorite story
with that? You know, I don't
know. Um, I don't know, does Star
Wars have happened? It's hard.
It's hard cuz now Star Wars has
all of this like extra stuff, you
know what I mean? Uh, you know,
like, so if I just think of
Return to The Jedi, it's mostly
happy, but you know, then all
these things keep happening and
whatever and you know, uh, I feel
like everybody nowadays has to
make everything all, you know,
awful. Uh, I'm a
Bekah: Not cartoons, though.
Every cartoon has a happy.
Dan: you. You think so? Cuz I
don't, I don't know if that's.
Bekah: Children's cartoons, not
like adult
Dan: Children's cartoons, Okay,
uh, yay. I'm gonna go with, um,
I'm gonna go with Elf cause I
like that movie
Bekah: Love.
Dan: it's happy. So that's gonna
be my answer. There's a lot of,
you know, there's a lot of
choices in that Christmas movie
realm, but, uh, elf is like one
of the best ones. So I'm going
with Elf. That's, that's my
answer.
Kai: Hi, uh, my name is Kai. I am
a tech content specialist, and I
completely panicked at this
question because if you ask a
neuro divergent person their
favorite anything, they will just
blank, and that's what happened.
But I've, but I've, but I found a
solution,
Bekah: Yay.
Kai: which is, there are two
movies that I go to when I feel
sad, when I feel bad, when she
needs some comfort. I'm not
usually a re watcher, but Moana
and Encanto both like do the
trick and I guess technically
they have happy endings. So I'll
go with those two.
Dan: those are, yeah, those are
very good ones.
Bekah: Yeah, those are really
good choices. I recently was
driving in my car with nobody
else and just listening to the
Encanto soundtrack because it
makes me
Kai: is, it is so good. There's,
there's no highest level volume
that is apt for that. It just
always needs to be louder.
Bekah: Totally agree. I also like
to sing it as loud as I can too,
so
Kai: same. Same. I'm not good
with the Spanish parts, but, um,
I try
Bekah: Yep, same. Well, welcome.
We're really happy to have you
here and the way that we always
like to get started is. With your
journey into where you are now,
but I'm gonna ask you first to
think about your developer
journey and give us one word that
would describe it.
Kai: Overdue or long overdue, if
I can hyphenate.
Bekah: There you go. I like it. I
like it. So now tell us this long
overdue journey and how you got
to this point.
Kai: I've, I've kind of been tech
adjacent for a very long time.
Originally, uh, study journalism.
I worked as a journalist. I
worked like daily broadsheet,
broadsheet newspaper kind of
stuff. Um, so something entirely
different, but I've always had an
affinity towards, uh, games,
tech, et cetera. Um, and then
when I had enough of journalism
for various reasons, I decided,
well, PR is kind of right next
door. I'll do that. And I ended
up being the first, uh, PR hire
ever at a very small Austrian
eSports company. It was an
eSports agency, and that's,
that's kind of how. Like properly
slid into tech. I had previously
obviously like had messed around
with a bit of website stuff like
when I was younger, futz around
with, with WordPress stuff, but
nothing ever seriously, and even
then for it took me another.
Well, I think 15 years to
properly get into it. I've spent
the past 10 years or so,
self-employed as a tech content
specialist. Started as a
copywriter and then kind of just
segued into consulting with
startups and the world tech
startups. And my, my oldest
client, um, is a SaaS provider.
So yeah, I've been tech Jason for
a long time and I always like to
say I, I speak developer. Or that
are that, you know, some of my
best friends are developers, but
like they are They really are
We're always the people I clicked
with most. And um, yeah, about
six years ago, my partner side
stepped into tech. They did a
bootcamp back when we lived in
Scotland. and still I wasn't, I
wasn't coding myself. I was like,
no, it's too much like math. I'm
sure I can't do this. And
everyone's like, no, Kai, you'll
be, you'll be fine. I was like,
no, no, no, no. I don't have the
brain for this. And then finally,
finally, when I realized I wanted
to go into Dev, I was like, oh,
maybe I should, maybe I should
get on that coding thing now.
And, uh, I did the, the Free Code
Camp, uh, boot camp for web dev,
which is HTML and CSS back in
September. and I was hooked. I
was very surprised. No one else
was surprised that I really took
to it Um, but I was also very
surprised that it was indeed not
very math-y. It was actually a
lot like writing.
Bekah: Yes.
Kai: If I think about it, like
I've been writing for such a long
time, I barely think about what I
do when I do it, I, I think about
it when I try to help others,
right? I think about coding, and
then I realize that the way I
think about coding is very much
what I tell other people when I
try to help them write better.
Like you put down a structure and
then you fill in the blanks, and
then you fill in the details and
you think of your story first,
and you put that down and then
the rest comes by itself. And
yeah, whether you, you go. Text
to edit and proofread and
restructure. Sometimes you have
to restructure. That's totally
normal when blogging, for
example, or whether you go and
you, you go through your code and
make it better. Like it's, it's
the same thing at the end of the
day. So yeah, that's, that's how
I ended up where I'm now, which
is. I can do HTML and css, which
is not a lot, but I feel like I'm
getting better at it, and the
probably next step will be
Python, but we'll see.
Bekah: I really love those
parallels between writing
technical content and coding
because my background is in
English. I taught college English
for 10 years and I found that
same thing, and for me it kind of
like took a while to make that
parallel because I think I. Just
wanted to get out of that space
for so long. Like I was, I was
done. Being a teacher, I was done
with that English teacher side of
myself. And then when I finally
like let go of that anger I was
like, oh, okay, these are kind of
similar and I understand what's
happening here in this context.
And then actually like once I
made that connection, it became a
little bit easier because for
those reasons that you said, like
you're breaking it down, you're
looking at the patterns and the
structure, and you're able to see
it from a different perspective.
Kai: Yeah, and it's also, I mean,
you say you tried to get away
from it from, for me it's kind
of, I really love like blending
those two, which is why Dev
appeals to me so much because
it's a way to. Bring everything
I've already sort of collected
over the years and skills and
weird skills and weird knowledge
to the table, but also this new
thing for me, which is coding,
and it's kind of awesome how that
can all kind of meld together.
Dan: Yeah, I think, I think
that's really great. Uh, I I
don't know, you, you were at the
beginning of your story, you were
talking about how you sort of
avoided, you know, avoided all
the coding stuff cuz um,
Kai: I didn't avoid it. I just
never like properly learned it
and I thought I wouldn't be good
at it,
Dan: Right. Avoided, avoided,
like actually diving in. Right.
And that's, I, I feel like
that's, uh, a, that cer certainly
in my personal experience, uh,
and I think that this is a common
occurrence with her, divergent
people. Is that, that sort of
thing where, where like, uh,
Something is like an unknown and
it, and it, and your brain does
this thing where it's just like,
no way. I can't, like I'm either
I can't do it or I don't wanna do
it or, or whatever. You know,
like it, it becomes this like, I
don't know, this weird block
thing. Right. You know that
Kai: Do not.
Dan: Right, right. Yeah. Yeah.
And I've had that experience so
many times, you know, and, and
whether it's like some piece of
technology or some like thing, I
avoided react for a, a real long
time cuz it was just, I don't
know. I just, like, I looked at,
I glanced at it, read a blog
post, didn't really immediately
understand it completely. And so
I'm like, Nope, I just, you know,
I don't know. And then once you
dig into it, you find that you
actually like it. I, I, I feel
like that that resonated with me
and I, and I, and I also feel
like, might resonate with other
people too. I, I think it's kind,
kind of common thing.
Kai: I am really glad you said
that because I recently started
cuz I thought like JavaScript
would be a good next step and I
started looking at it and I had
to fight the urge to, to quit.
Because the resources I had tried
didn't work and I just kept
looking at different resources
until I found one that didn't
make me want to run away. But
like that urge is there and I'm
kind of relieved that I'm not
alone with this,
Dan: yeah, yeah, yeah. Big time.
Bekah: For sure when I was
learning, I was going through
Free Code Camp initially, and I
got to the JavaScript portion and
that was like a brick wall. I
could not make it through, and I
thought, you know what, maybe,
maybe this is not for me, until I
found a different curriculum that
approached it in a different way
and then suddenly it was like,
okay, I can handle this. It's, it
wasn't ever easy, but it made
more sense to me and it was. An
introduction that my brain could
kind of understand and ease into.
Kai: that, that's exactly like, I
also tried it with Free Code Camp
cuz I was like, okay, I did the
bootcamp there. I know what I
dislike about Free Code Camp.
Like some of their, some of the
structure they force upon you
within an h l file just does not
work for me. But like I know
that, and I, I am aware of that.
I can deal with that and I'll
just do the JavaScript thing
there and I opened it and. What
the hell? I, I just like you
said, hit the brick wall and I
tried exorcism and that was like
less explainy, but also kind of
assumed that I would know more
than I did, which was zero. Um,
and then I keep, I kept like
looking around for different
resources and finally it was Code
Academy that actually worked the
best for me. I don't know what
you used, but now I wanna.
Because maybe I should try that
as well.
Bekah: I ended up going into a
bootcamp, so I went to a Flatiron
School bootcamp and they had some
pre-work that you could do, and
once I did the pre-work, it
suddenly, like all of these
things started to click into
place for me and that's when I
kind of thought like, this is.
This makes sense. And luckily I
was able to get a scholarship to
go there. Otherwise, you know,
that wouldn't have worked out.
But exploring all of the
different resources that are out
there, I think is really
important to that learning
journey because we all learn in
different ways.
Kai: Yeah. And also like
different topic might require you
to use a different, um, resource
is what I've learned through
this. Like HTML CSS that worked
for me with Free Code Camp. Not
ideal, but it worked. Js
currently not. So yeah, I think
it's a good idea to keep, keep an
eye out for all these like
different resources. Even if you
found one that works for you with
one thing, maybe for another
language, you need another one,
you know?
Dan: And I imagine some of that
is probably, there's different
authors that. you know, those
guides. I mean, I'd be, I guess
you know that, so that could be
part of it. And, and yeah,
everybody learns completely
differently. I always like
hearing how, how people like
prefer to learn, right? Because
it's always,
Kai: Yeah.
Dan: my learning style is
ridiculous and it's just it's,
Kai: bet it is. I bet it is not
ridiculous. What is your learning
style?
Dan: oh, I don't know. Like, I,
that's the problem is I can't
really describe it. I, I, I can't
do videos. I can't have people
talking at me. I can't like, uh,
long form. Reading, you know, is
honestly not even ideal for me.
It, it's, it's more just like I
need to just like start using my
hands immediately and then
Kai: I, I don't
Dan: into a s i, I know, I, I, I
was,
Kai: ridiculous, then I'm also
ridiculous because that's exactly
how I
Dan: yeah, yeah. I know. It's,
it's like, it's, it's not
ridiculous. It's just hard to
describe. And also like, like I
can't be like, Hey, do this. You
know, it's not, um, other than
saying, get to building as soon
as you can, like, that works for
me, you know? But after that it's
just like, there's no, there's no
specific, you know, resource or
style or whatever that's ever
really worked for me other than
like trying to push through by
myself. And, um, and then like I
run into a specific problem and
then I'm like, okay, let's go
look to see how to solve like
this one thing, you know? And I
don't know, it, it, it has worked
for me. It's, it never feels like
the most efficient way. Um, and
it's, it's hard to sort of
translate that into. Um, advice
for people often, for me anyway,
it's hard for me to translate
that into advice, uh, but like,
or at least actionable advice,
other than, um, other than
getting your hands dirty, uh, for
me, you know, it works and, but
like I said, everybody works, uh,
learns differently and some
people like to have a lot more,
you know, uh, a lot more like, I
don't know, a plan in their head
before they start doing that or
whatever. And I, I get that too.
So
Kai: I think, I think we're very
similar. Um, yeah, I think it's
called kinesthetic learning. Like
if you learned through doing, if
I'm not doing it, I'm not gonna
remember it. people are always
super helpful with like, oh,
that's this great book I read.
It's like, Nope. If it's not
nonfic, like it's not fiction,
I'm not gonna read it and I doubt
it's gonna be a fiction. Of
course. Um, and people, I was
like, oh, but like udemi and
videos and, and I'm like, I do
not learn from it. I mean, I have
this one udemi course that I'm
now working through, which is
basically just to fill some CSS
holes maybe, or whatever. I'm
listening to it at like the top
speed. It's, I think two times
as. Twice as the top speed and
I'm just zooming through it. And
that's, that's the only way I
can, my, my ADHD brain can handle
this because Yeah. No, I feel, I
feel the same way. I'm, you
gotta, you gotta tell me, okay,
this is a little bit you can do
and then let me do it and then
I'll figure it out from there.
But, um, that's how I learn.
Bekah: I really love, uh,
learning through examples, but
like examples that you can
manipulate, right? Like if
there's a sandbox in there, Expo
has, um, Expo Snacks for a bunch
of things and that has been
really helpful to me. Anytime I'm
trying to use Expo, because I can
see what they're doing, I can
play around with it, I can make
it my own. Okay. This is, this is
how this works. It's already
there constructed for me, but it
gives me, you know, a little bit
of leadway to explore it.
Kai: Yeah. I also, I don't know
how you all feel about, um,
things that feel pointless, but
if, if you give me an exercise
and I don't see the point of it,
like of course with Free Code
Camp, you have these like
projects that you have to do and
it's like create a product page.
I'm like, I don't wanna create a
product page for some. In the
end, what I did to get myself
through it, I created a product
page. and the product was, you
can, you can send my dogs pets,
you can pet my dogs from afar
through a form. And that's how I
got myself through it. But like I
wasn't, I was never gonna write
like, fake documentation just
through the project. I just did
the basic stuff, uh, to pass the,
you know, the test and that was
it. I'm not proud of it, but I
figure I'll need that stuff at
some point when I do an actual
project. I'm just not good at
doing things senseless. Is my
main issue.
Bekah: I, I find like even
writing blog posts, like dev
related blog posts where I need
to come up with a code sample, I
have a really hard time like not
trying to come up with some kind
of meaningful project. And I know
that I'll spend like way too much
time. Like this is, this is not
what it's about. Like the point
of this blog post is not to
showcase a meaningful project,
it's to showcase how to utilize
this code. And so then I, I was
working on this project a couple
months back and. it, it got
really in depth, right? And like
there were, there were so many
different features going on, and
I'm like, this is, this is all
wrong. This is not how you're
supposed to do this. And so then
I just like restarted it. I I
made one component and that was
it. But it was like this whole
big thing in my mind because it
didn't make sense without like
having this important idea that
it was capturing but the wrong,
the wrong important idea.
Kai: I, I think that's a
storyteller brain though, as
well. Like you need the story
like, but what's the story? You
know, but what, what is the story
And if I'm, yeah, at least doing
something fun or funny helps,
there's this like tribute page in
the code camp thing that you have
to do. And I can think of anyone
real. So I made a tribute page to
Han Solo.
Dan: Oh,
Kai: at least that used me and I
looked up random Star Wars facts,
you know? So, yeah, I don't know
that, that that's how we get
through it. I think we, we build
our own stories to make the
learning bearable. Like I love
learning new things, but it's
gotta be my way.
Bekah: Well, and that also helps
you commit those things to memory
too, right? Like when you are,
whether you're creating a story
or hearing a story, you're more
likely to remember that thing.
And so I think that if you are
learning and you are making it
something fun for you or
meaningful, or telling a story
through the project that you're
creating, then you're gonna be
more likely to understand that.
and to remember how to do it the
next time, and I don't, well, I
gave a talk on that yesterday, so
I feel like that's undervalued.
Kai: I totally agree with you. I,
I, I guess when I, when I, you
know, I started out as a
journalist, copywriter, and then.
Added more things sort of to my
portfolio skills and at some
point I just, I just called
myself a storyteller, which
sounds super pretentious and
obnoxious, but that was kind of
the best way to sum it up because
whether I was writing or whether
I was helping startups figure out
their target group and had to
structure their website and had
to write the copy and had to,
what kind of images to use it, it
was all about telling a story and
I think everything is about
telling a story in the end.
Everything that's good is about
telling a story.
Bekah: 100% right. Smash that
like button. Whatever you do when
somebody says something that you
100% agree with.
Kai: Yeah.
Bekah: Yeah. You know, in finding
that there, there's such a
balance that comes with that,
right? Like, um, you ever look up
a recipe and they like wanna tell
you the whole story of like their
grandma's birth and like how they
grandma seasoned their cast iron
pan and then like three hours
Kai: the one case where I don't
want the story.
Bekah: Right at least now a lot
of them have like skipped a
recipe. Yes, please. But it's
like, it's finding that balance,
I think of weaving that story and
then like also giving the
information that people need.
Because if it's really heavy on
the storytelling or it's not
contextual, I think that you can
tell stories through how you
write your code. Um, But you, you
have to find that balance in
order to, um, you know, support
what you're doing and your
audience.
Kai: Yeah, no, I've, I've.
Definitely have that issue with,
with blog posts on, like recipes
and stuff. Because very often the
story is also not very well told
and not very, and you can tell
they wanna get to the recipe, but
I guess for SEO or whatever
purposes, they're putting all
this stuff before and you keep
thinking, oh sure, our next
paragraph's gonna be the no,
still not the recipe. But surely
now the story is, no, it's still
not over. And I think it also
says something about how they,
like a lot of people write
stories where with a good story
you feel when it's, when it's
getting to an end. Like when you
feel like if you've got a 30
minute TV episode and you can
feel when it's end, when it's
about to end. Even if you don't
look at the time because the
story is told in a certain way
and the plot points are
positioned in a certain way,
positioned in a certain way that
you, you can just tell, you can
feel it. And I think. that's also
part of good storytelling. Um,
you need to know when to end,
even though I dunno when to end
my sentences clearly.
Bekah: I, I have the same
problem. I will frequently end
sentences with the word, so it's
like a filler word for me. Like
say a whole sentence and I'll be
like, so, so I'm to do it.
Kai: last year. Last year I gave
my first talk in a very long
time, and when I listened back at
the recording, I realized that in
the, because my, my teachers
hammered it into us, not say, um,
or ah, you know, as fill word. So
instead of doing that, apparently
now, I say now, now, All the
time. And now I'm trying to not
do that and I guess I'll just
pick up the next filler word on
the go. One day I'll, so as well
at the end of a sentence, you
just
Bekah: I am sorry. I'm sorry if I
pass that on to you. the world
doesn't need more of that.
Kai: different, you know, every
time I
Bekah: was just gonna start a
sentence with, so, and now I am
like hyperaware of all of it.
Kai: We can fix it in post.
Bekah: can't do it. So
Dan: try, try using triz now.
Maybe that'll work.
Bekah: Now you're doing all of
this content creation. Um, You
have all of this experience.
Right. And I wanna back up for a
second and talk a little bit
about this idea that you speak
tech. I think that's what you
said, and I really like to think
about it in that way because I
think that there are also people
in tech that don't speak tech,
right? Communication is can be a
problem. Being able to
communicate your ideas and you're
doing it in a lot of different,
Right, like you gave a talk last
week. You are writing blog posts,
you're definitely doing dev
things. And so how do you
approach creating that content?
And, and maybe also like, what do
you like the most? What are, what
is most enjoyable content
creation for you?
Kai: So with blogging, I blogging
has kind of lost its spark
because I blogged for the same
company for the past eight and a
half years, and at some point I
didn't get around to blogging for
myself anymore. And that kind of
just, just, Went away. Like I was
like, you know, when you, when
you some whatever you do for
work, it's really hard to do that
for fun as well. Um, I feel like
developers are less afflicted by
this, but you know, chefs, they
cook all day in the kitchen. They
come home, they're not interested
in doing that at home. They eat
peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches. Um, So that's, that's
how I feel a bit about blogging.
But I, but I also miss it. So I
actually started because
everyone, I was like, you gotta
learn in public, you gotta learn
in public. And I was like, yes, I
know, but I'm so chaotic when I
try to figure stuff out that I
don't wanna do this entirely in
public. But I just, like,
literally an hour ago, started
writing a blog post about why I'm
currently hard coding my website
and that I don't think I am, I
have lost all my marbles for
doing this. And I really. Like
my, my main client has always let
me bring my own voice to my post
and everything, so that's great.
But I really enjoyed writing for
myself again, which I think
partly is because I've now been,
so I've been taking a break in
January of from work. While I
transitioned from self-employment
to employment, and I think just
like these were two, three weeks
of not blogging for work have
made it much more enjoyable for
me, and I feel like I'm finding
my way back. That said, I also
went to film school for a year,
so I've, I've done that kind of
kind of storytelling as well. Um,
I enjoy live streaming because
it's very ad hoc. It, my d h d
brain likes it not having to
prepare too much and just going
with the flow and it's exciting.
Um, same with podcasts and stuff
like that. I was on a podcast
last week, um, which is called
Coming Out Pod, about my, um,
coming out journey basically. Um,
Really enjoy that. But what I
think what I like most about
giving talks is that I can sit
down and I can take my time and
write my story and refine it and
like really, really. Make it not
perfect, but as perfect as it's
gonna get. And sometimes that's
like the evening before the talk
where you make the last take. I'm
pretty sure you know that. I
think you said something like
that,
Bekah: Yep. That was me,
Kai: when you just, you just feel
like something in the. In the way
you build your talk. Like it's
okay, but something isn't quite
right. And for weeks, like, like
with the last one for weeks, I
couldn't figure it out. I knew
something was wrong with my
intro, but I couldn't figure it
out. And then like, I think the
day before my talk, I was like,
now I've got it. And I changed it
and it flowed. And this, this
feeling is really amazing. And
especially when you, when you're
giving talks live and not
recorded, even if it's like just
online. Um, I enjoy that bit of
the adrenaline and everything. So
yeah, I'm currently really
enjoying writing talks, which is
good because I thought I was
giving my next one in two months,
but I found out yesterday. It's
really in one month and it's a
new talk that I haven't written
yet, so, so that, that's great.
And, uh, hilariously it's a talk
about being organized with ADHD.
So now I've got a really good
intro into, good intro into that
talk
Bekah: That is, that is.
Kai: So, yeah. Um, to get back to
your question, I, I enjoy all
kinds of different content. I
enjoy the ad hoc style where you
just actually talk to people. And
I love interviewing people. I
love talking to people and then
figuring out how to tell their
story as well. I've done a lot of
showcase interviews and stuff
like that. Um, but I also love
being able to just like, sit down
and create my own story and find
a way to tell that because a. The
talks like the talks I give are
personal, um, mental health
related, ADHD related. It's kind
of nice to find a way to put that
story into words.
Bekah: Yeah.
Kai: Yeah.
Bekah: one of the things that can
be hard, no matter what kind of
content you're creating, is to
learn how to not be precious
about your content that you have
on the page. Right? Like when
it's in rough draft stage, that's
a rough draft. And even though
you might like a particular part,
it might need to be cut, right?
Kai: kill your darlings. It is
terrible. I hate it
Bekah: Yeah, it's hard. I, I have
my, my talk that I gave
yesterday, and so I write out the
whole thing. I enjoy doing that.
It helps me to focus and organize
and kind of see things
differently. And then as I go
through, I start cutting those
pieces, but I'll put them in
another document. Cause I'm like,
well, this might not be the end
of you forever.
Kai: Same. I
Bekah: place for you.
Kai: and if it's a different
talk, you know, like
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah. So is that
like kind of your process? Like
what does your process for
content creation look like from
start to.
Kai: So, um, first of all, I
don't get writer's block because
the way I started out in
journalism, you don't have
writer's block. If you have
writer's block, the paper doesn't
go out the next day. So the first
time I was like, oh, I dunno what
to write. I think my, my editor
back then was like, you just sit
down, you write something and
then you work on it. So that is,
I've been offering one-on-ones
to, uh, to devs to help them if
they wanna get into writing more.
and the, the first thing I always
say is just put something down.
Um, do not put the heading down.
Like if you're writing a blog
post or an article, you write the
headline last. And I think that's
something that people outside of
journalism maybe don't always
know, but it's incredibly helpful
because you gotta write the story
to know what like the point of
the story is, and then you can
create the headline. So I'm, I'm
a recovering perfectionist, I
would say. I think that's
probably the best way to describe
it. And over the years I've
learned to just live with that
first draft. Just put it down no
matter how cringe. And, uh, just
put it down, leave it, come back
to it another day and put your
editor's hat on and then go
through it as your edit. Like,
just pretend you're your editor
Um, and I think that's, That's
the best way. Sometimes,
sometimes I sit down and write a
blog post from top to bottom, and
it's perfect the way it is. Like
obviously editing a little bit,
but like it's perfect and other
times the right one. And just
like with the talk, it just
doesn't, it just doesn't sit well
with me and I then I start, then
I start futzing with the
structure and pushing things up
and down and around, and I try
not to copy. Stuff that I wanna
keep in into a different document
because then I'll get confused.
But yeah, I've done a, I've done
a lot of command X command V. In
a document, if someone were to
look over my shoulder, they'd
probably get dizzy. Like I've
actually edited other people's
work and tried to be like,
gentle. And then I just like, no,
just do you thing. And then they
look over my shoulder and they're
like, what the hell are you
doing? It's like, just wait. Just
wait for it. It's, it's gonna be
good in the end and just need to
figure out how this works. It's
like a puzzle. I think sometimes,
so yeah, sometimes you just write
a thing and other times you have
to write a structure first
because you need that to, to sort
your thoughts. And sometimes none
of this works and you have a
messed up puzzle that you have to
put back together in the end or
put together.
Bekah: you've talked a little bit
about mentoring other people
through that journey too, and
working on other, working on
content with other people. So
what do you think some of the
most important moments for you
have been as a mentor?
Kai: I mean, I dunno if I would
call as myself a mentor at this
point. Um, it's just, uh, I
really like when I can help
people, like when I can see that,
what I tell them. That to me
maybe seems insignificant because
I've been doing it for. 20 years
at this point. Um, to me it seems
insignificant, but to them it's
like, oh, I had never thought of
it that way, because they're not,
they don't have my history and my
experience in writing. So to them
it's a new thing. And it's maybe
the one thing that like loosens
that guardian knot that they had,
why they couldn't get the writing
done the way they wanted to. And
also sometimes, like honestly,
half the time when I talk to
people, they think they're so bad
and they send me something and
I'm. You're not actually bad.
Like it's fine. You can get
better, but you're not bad. I've
seen bad you're not bad. And then
sometimes that's all they need.
Just someone to tell them that
it's okay, and to give them the
confidence to just do it. Like
basically just what people have
have done with me when I started
coding. She's like, just, you're
gonna be fine. Just do it.
There's really nothing you can
lose I just really like seeing
that whatever innate thing my
brain comes up with that I think
surely that won't help anyone,
then actually helps people. I'm
like, oh, huh, interesting. Cool.
Guess I did learn something in
this 20 odd year com career.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that. We
often undervalue ourselves and
our experiences and just kind of
like what you were saying before,
what works for one person or what
might be meaningful for one
person won't be for another
person. So I think that anytime
there's that self-doubt in there
or thinking like this won't be
helpful, it probably will be
helpful to somebody. it just
might not seem like that would be
helpful to you because you know,
maybe that's not your style or
maybe there's some self-doubt
that's really holding you back
from seeing the value in the
things that you're doing.
Kai: Or also because I've just
forgotten that 20 years ago, that
has helped me as well, and it's,
it's also nice to, to be reminded
of how far you've come, I guess.
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. That's
super important. So, uh, right
now you are about to transition
into a full-time role. How are
you feeling
Kai: Part-time. Part-time.
Bekah: Oh, part-time,
Kai: part-time. That was
Bekah: a not self-employed role.
Kai: Yeah, so I, um, being
self-employed in Germany is not
something I enjoy, and since I've
been doing the same kind of work
for the past couple of years, I
also kind of wanted another
challenge and to segue into Dev
or to sidestep into Dev, I knew
that I, I would have to probably
become employed. I feel really
weird about it. So I start at the
beginning of. First week of
February. Um, and it's four days
a week, luckily, and the company
seems really nice, but I'm still
like this teeny tiny bit. Like
I'm super excited, but I'm also
slightly apprehensive because the
past eight and a half years when
my boss was shit, it was me, you
know? Um, and I was lucky enough
to. Have worked in, in a pretty
niche position, so I, I could
really set my own rates. I didn't
have to work long hours. Um, I
don't think else only have to
work long hours in this job. They
seem really cool. But there's,
um, there's also a lot of, I
think, a lot of trauma involved
for me with regards to
employment. So the last time I
was employed was. 2014. Um, and
before that I, I had a really
hard time finding the right jobs.
Um, staying employed long enough,
my ADHD always got bored with the
jobs that I could get. Um, and
then when I started working,
self-employed, I was, uh, I knew
I wanted to start my own business
and I was looking for a part-time
job to tide me over and like kind
of start gently on the side. And
all the jobs I applied for,
people were like, I'm sorry,
you're overqualified. Or Why do
you only wanna work part-time?
That's super weird. What's wrong
with you? But that was all
outside of the street
technically. Um, and I realized,
in tech, things are much better
today. We so many people I know,
especially integral, so many
people I know work, uh, part-time
in some way, shape or form. Uh,
so many people working companies
that are actually not toxic. Um,
but still in, in my head, this
like, or right down my head in my
heart, this feeling is still in
there of all those bad
experiences, 10 years ago. That I
got away from because I became my
own boss. And um, so if a client
seemed like a potential client,
seemed they weren't gonna be
good, then I wouldn't take them.
I have a disclaimer on my website
that says I don't work with
bigots. Like I literally picked
my, picked my client's chair,
pick them, and. Yeah, and I think
also being self-employed became
part of my identity in a way of
my professional identity because
it's the, that, that's when I
started having success in my
career and building a career. And
it's odd to let go of that a bit.
but also it just, it was just a
step. It's, it's fine. I have a
portfolio career. I've done so
many different things in my life,
including working at a gym and
making crepe and selling soup,
and I was a video editor at some
point, an assistant, and like,
I've done so many different
things. I shouldn't, I shouldn't
be scared of change, but this, it
feels like, like I'm giving up a
teeny tiny part of my identity,
which is silly, but that's
Dan: It's not, it's not silly.
It's not silly at all. I, I mean,
I've been independent for, you
know, I don't know, whatever it
is, 15, 20 years, something like
15, whatever, long time and, um,
and I totally follow what you
were saying. And I've also, I
mean, I've almost, I've only ever
actually applied to one job, but
I've, I've al I thought about it
a bunch of times, you know what I
mean? And it's, there's that,
like, there's that part of ADHD
thing that it's like, I wanna
stay where I'm comfortable, but
there's also the, like, I'm
bored. Let's like, oh, here's a
new shiny thing. You know what I
mean? And I
Kai: when you're self-employed,
you can follow the shiny thing
easier.
Dan: Which is, which is yes, yes,
yes. Absolutely. Uh, which is
what I, one of the things I, I
love about it. Um, uh, but like
that being said, in the tech
world, I, there's new shiny
things all the time, And so even
if you're, uh, working for the
same, I mean, I have a client
that I've had for that whole
time, the 15, 16 years. With
especially front end development.
It's like there's, there's new
shiny stuff, all the time. I was
wondering what, um, you said
there's something about being
independent in Germany that you
didn't like. Is that tax tax
stuff or is it,
Kai: Yeah, the overhead is, um,
so I hated it in Austria. Um, and
then we moved to Scotland and for
five years, or I was blissfully
like, I just forgot the bad
things in Austria that are the
same things that are in Germany,
like in the uk I could just, I
could do my own taxes. I used a,
um, like the bookkeeping program
I used that, I wrote my, my
invoices with automatically. Um,
collated everything at the end of
the year. Just had to go through
it, add a few things, fix a few
things, and then like directly
send it to the HMRC, like
literally from within the
program. Fantastic. Here in
Germany, first of all, I was
immediately push into the VAT
range because so if you're in the
uk, if you are a self-employed
sole trader, um, so you're not a
company but a sole trader, if you
earn more than 82,000 pounds a
year, then you have to do that.
Otherwise, you don't have to do
that. You're a small business
owner in
Dan: Can you tell
Kai: uh, uh, uh, a val value add
tax.
Dan: Okay. All right, so it's
just more taxes.
Kai: It's something that goes in
and comes out and actually you
don't lose or win any money with
it, but it's extra work. So in
the UK I could easily avoid that.
In Germany, the limit is far
lower. It's at, I think, 30,000
euros. So I was immediately
pushed into that range, which
means that now four times a year
I have to do this. Um, VAT tax
thing. I've done it four or five
times at this point. And, um, I
think the first three times I
cried because, like literally
cried because it is complicated
and the bookkeeping programs here
are shite also because like the,
the actual laws around it are far
too complicated. Um, so like,
Suddenly I was, I was working the
same amount. I was earning about
the same amount. Uh, but I also
had to do VAT tax shit, uh, four
times a year. And then I also
actually got less out of my
earnings because in the UK I just
put 20% aside for taxes and
insurance and it was fine. Here I
put one fourth of what I, what
comes in immediately gets put
aside for. I hope it's gonna be
enough. I don't know if it's
gonna be enough. We'll see. Um,
and then I pay insurance, which
is about 670 years a month for.
And then I also put money aside
so that I can pay the tax advisor
that I need at the end of the
year because there's no way I'm
tackling that on my own. Like
the, the VAT thing was already
difficult enough, so it kind of
just sucks the joy out of it.
Also, cuz I can, I can literally
not save any money. I earn the
same amount and I cannot save any
money. And it's just, yeah, I was
just done with it, I
Dan: Yeah, yeah. No, I mean, I
totally get it there. I mean,
there's a bunch of pain in the
butt stuff, uh,
Kai: But I think it's, it's e
easy, like it's less bureaucratic
in the US isn't it? Like taxes
are the same for whether you're a
business owner or not, or am I,
am I mistaken on that
Dan: I, taxes are complicated.
And I try not to pay too much
attention to it. Um, I, I mean, I
pay somebody to do it a as well,
you know, and they, they just
tell me the things to do, and I
trust that they are, are
accurate. Um,
Kai: if we were to move back to
the uk, I would easily do it
myself again. But, um, I'm not
gonna be self-employed in Germany
or Australia again in my life.
Thank you very
Dan: Um, yeah, no, I mean,
that's, that's totally fair. I,
uh, and if, yeah, if it got much
more complicated than this, I
would, I then it is now for me, I
would, I would certainly, uh,
struggle with that too. That tax
stuff just makes my brain shut
down every time. Like, all the
the businessy stuff around
running a business. I, I don't
actually enjoy, you know, even
though I've been self-employed
for so long. I know enough to get
by and I haven't gotten audited
or anything like that, But, uh,
you know, other than that, it's,
it's a struggle for sure. It's
definitely one of the big
downsides, uh, of being
independent.
Kai: definitely.
Dan: Uh, so that's exciting. So
your new role is Dev,
Kai: No, um, not technically. Uh,
actually I'm gonna be in the
content department. Um, so I'm
officially, I think it's content
marketing manager, but I will
also be teaching developers to
write better. So that is
something that I'm really, really
excited about with this role. And
it's, I think it's, I. Probably.
So at first I was just like
interviewing and talking to them
and everything, and that part
came up and I was like, oh wait,
that is exactly what I wanna do.
That is, yeah. So I mean, I guess
technically it's developer
education, so I think it'll be,
uh, a good stepping stone into
Dev proper. But like I, I only
heard about Dev I think a year
ago, like before that. I didn't
really realize what it was like.
I had a few friends who were in
Devel, but no one ever bothered
to explain to me what they were
doing. And
Bekah: I think, I think it's
probably because nobody really
knows what they're doing.
Kai: And then
Bekah: I say that as a Debra
person, and so.
Kai: and then a year ago was, I
was talking to my friend, uh,
Ramon, who's also in Virtual
Coffee, and we've been friends
for a few years and he was like,
um, actually Kai. Because I was
complaining about being
self-employed cause it was a
headache and a half. Um, and he
was like, you know, Kai, all
these like skills that you
already have, minus coding is
pretty much never, why didn't you
go into that? And I started
looking into it and that's when
I, yeah, basically pivoted a bit
and read my website. Kind of
started networking more, joined
some, some communities and
started like casually
interviewing, talking to a few
people. I got really lucky. I, I
had. Had a few casual
conversations, two proper
interview, like tracks with
companies and, and that was it.
And then I landed this, uh,
within like, uh, I think maybe
nine months or so. So that's
pretty cool. But yeah, I just.
It's just funny cuz I found out I
had all these skills and
interests and they all came
together endeavor. And I had no
idea this was there, And I think
that's also what what makes me
feel a lot better about like,
stepping away from being
self-employed because this, I
don't feel like I'm leaving
anything behind. I can bring like
my whole self to the table, all
my, all my skills, all these like
random things like. I used to be
a video editor. I enjoy public
speaking. I'm one of the sweet
people who enjoys public
speaking. I know. Um, I love
networking. I love talking to
people. I love interviewing
people. I also love writing and
create, you know, and it all kind
of comes together. And now turns
out, I also enjoy coding. So
that's kind of cool and
convenient. I'm, I'm glad it
turned out this way. And
Bekah: Yeah. That's awesome.
Somebody asked me at the
conference I was just at, how I
knew that I should get into
Deval, I think, and how I did it.
I was like, I, I didn't, um,
somebody just told me I should,
and then I was like, oh, I
suppose I am doing all of those
things right.
Kai: So that is how it goes.
Interesting. That's good to know.
Good to know. Like, yeah, get
friend who's like, you should be
doing this.
Bekah: Right. I, and even
thinking about backgrounds, I
really love how devel lends
itself to non-traditional
backgrounds too, because a lot of
us have come from doing things
like writing or teaching, and
these are all skills that you
need. You have to be a good
communicator, right? And all
those years of experience in
communicating. Lends itself to
Dev as you learn new things and,
and you're better able to explain
that to the people that you're
working with.
Kai: I'm really hoping that. as
more people like us end up in
Dev. Maybe also the, the job spec
specs will get rewritten a bit
because I do understand that like
the technical knowledge is
important. Like, yes, you need to
learn a code, but I also think
you can learn a code. It is, it
is much harder to teach someone
to communicate. When, like,
obviously we've all learned to
communicate well, but it's, it's
been the lifetime process often
and to write well and to create
content well. And, um, yeah, I'm,
I'm really hoping that the, the
tide will change a little bit. I
feel like it already is with some
projects that, that really
support career changes and
everything. But yeah, it's still
very often it's like when I was
looking through job apps, like
job ads, very often I would get
to the tech requirements and it
was an absolute must have, this,
this, this, and this. And I was
like, Hmm, yeah, I don't have
that. I could probably, um, but
right now I don't have that. And
then I just didn't, I didn't
bother applying to jobs where
that was hammered home so much. I
think. And I hope that changes.
Bekah: Yeah, absolutely. I.
Kai: maybe once the comm, once
the economy is better, but
Bekah: Right. Yeah. That's a
challenge right now. Well, Kai,
we wanna thank you for being here
with us today. I've got one more
question for you, and that's, if
you can describe yourself with
one word, what would that one
word be and why?
Kai: Um, I think the word would
be curious because that curiosity
has been. What's been driving me
all these years with everything,
like, everything new I learn.
Yeah, the ADHD wants the new
shiny, but also I'm very curious
to learn new things. I love
learning new things. Curiosity is
what makes me good at
interviewing people and writing
about them and writing about new
things. And yeah, I think I, I
don't think curiosity killed the
cat. Come to think of it, I think
curiosity is a really good thing
to have.
Bekah: Yeah. I love that. That
was great. And I think that
everything that you talked about
today really captures that.
Kai: I am glad
Bekah: Well, thanks so much for,
for being here with us today and
sharing your story. We really
appreciate it.
Dan: Thanks Kai.
Kai: Thank you for having me.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast. This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel. If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You can
find the show notes, sign up for
the newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io. If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!