Bekah: Hello, and welcome to
Season seven, episode four of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
I'm Bekah, and this is a podcast
that features members of the
Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
group of developers at all
stages of their coding journey,
and they're here on this podcast
sharing their stories and what
they've learned, and we're
here to share it with you.
Here with me today
is my co-host Dan.
Dan: What up back?
How's it going?
Bekah: it is going amazing.
Dan: Nice. Yes.
Uh, so is it still
70 degrees and sunny?
Where you are.
Bekah: It is 70 degrees in Sunny.
It is very
Dan: It is sunny here.
It's actually nice.
I was complaining about the
weather earlier today, but,
uh, it is like 50, but it's
sunny, which that is, uh, you
know, , that's a, that's a good
thing, uh, in my mind anyway.
I like the
Bekah: is nice.
Yeah, sunny, just like this
episode was really sunny.
I felt really warm and
happy while we recorded it.
Dan: Was an awesome segue.
Bekah: Thank you.
Dan: Yeah. Uh oh.
Speaking of sunny
conversations, uh, yeah.
Today we talked with,
uh, , um, and yes, had
a great conversation.
She is a delight to talk to.
Um, and we talked about a lot
about, uh, open source and about
her journey, you know, becoming
a developer and, um, all of
the amazing work she did during
Octoberfest this past year.
Uh, she, she topped
our leaderboards.
I looked it up during the
podcast now I can't remember,
what was it, ten nine?
I think it was more than,
I think it was more than we
thought after I looked it up.
Bekah: yeah,
Dan: anyway,
Bekah: even number.
Dan: yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Eight or 10.
Anyway, she had an incredible
amount of poor requests
during Octoberfest and, um,
yeah, she hit like her, her
four or whatever that we
wanted for Heover Fest really
early, I think, and then
just kept the ball rolling.
It was really cool to see.
Bekah: Yeah, she was a first
time open source contributor
and she contributed to my
postpartum wellness app, and
I got to work with her as a
mentor this year, but she did
not really need any mentoring.
She was just tearing
up the issues.
It was so fun to watch, and she
just kept going and it was, I, I
felt really energized by seeing
her do all of the contributions
during octoberfest and during
our conversation today too.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, and it's like she's,
she has that, um, I don't
know that any like thing that
you lots of times want to
see in developers where they,
where they enjoy it a little
bit, , you know, and they,
they kind of keep, keep going.
She, um, and, and with
open source, I feel like
the people that contribute
often to open source, that's
a pretty common thing.
Um, and, you know, if you're
not paid, You have to find time
and, and, and do it on your own.
And, um, uh, it's one of
the, one of the many, many
reasons I love Hector Fest
because it, it, it helps
people get over that initial
hump of, of getting into it.
And, uh, and then sometimes
you get end up with people
that, um, do it for, for
their whole lives or whatever,
Bekah: Yeah, right.
I mean, you're really building a
community at that point, right?
Like in an open source
community, and it can be a
really great place to be.
Dan: absolutely.
Bekah: Well, we start every
episode of the podcast, like
we start every Virtual Coffee,
we say our names, where we're
from, what we do, and answer
a random check-in question.
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Today's random check-in question
is, who's your favorite hero?
My name is Bekah.
I am a technical community
builder from a small
town in Ohio, and I don't
know the answer to this.
Dan: Is this like fiction?
Fictional. Fictional hero.
Bekah: I'm definitely
going with fictional.
Dan: Okay, cool.
Yeah, because otherwise then
you'd have to like probably
say your mom or your dad
or something and you know,
otherwise you'd feel guilty.
All right.
Bekah: I mean, but you can,
if you wanna say your mom
and your dad, that's fine.
I'm gonna go with Wanda
from, um, the Marvel.
Dan: She's a bad guy. Bekah,
Bekah: She's a hero
in her own story, right?
Dan: sure. So we're lots of
Bekah: has
Dan: people.
Bekah: some heroic things. Or if
Dan: not recently.
Bekah: More fine, Sam
from Lord of the Rings. Okay.
Feel very boring saying
Dan: Wise, he's a good.
Bekah: All right.
Who's your, who's your
excellent pick, Dan?
Dan: uh, okay. Ho. Hi, I'm Dan.
I live in Cleveland.
I, um, you know what I do
and gosh, I don't know.
Um, and see, I like if he
had, if I had time to like
really think, I probably
could pull out some like
interesting one, you know.
But like Han Solo is the one
that comes to mind, and I
know, like, honestly, these
answers, I'm always like
making Star Wars things.
It's like always the, you
know, first thing I think of.
But, uh, yeah, Han Solo
is, my favorite because,
you know, he, he,
Bekah: a scoundrel.
Dan: he's a scoundrel,
which I like.
And also, um, whatever, he
didn't like set out trying to
be hero, you know what I mean?
But like his heart told
him to do the right thing
and all that stuff, which,
which I like, you know?
So that's my answer.
I'm going Han.
Aishwarya: hello.
So my name is Aishwarya
. I'm from India.
I work as a front end developer.
Uh, I mostly work with,
uh, react and recently
started with, react Native,
uh, and for me fictional.
Hero, are we going with
like a movie star or
something like that?
Bekah: Could be.
Dan: You could do
it however you want.
Yeah, I was trying to think
of books and my mind went
totally blank, but it.
It could be anything.
It's you make the rules.
Aishwarya: Okay, so I'm not
sure I remember his name,
but the book is Me Before
You and he sort of helps.
Sir, I can't remember
his name right now.
And I love that
character very much.
Dan: Nice.
Aishwarya: It's a
movie plus book. Yeah,
Dan: Me. What was it?
Bekah: Hey, before
Aishwarya: me before
Dan: before you. Nice. All right.
Bekah: yeah, I'll have
to check that out.
I've definitely heard
about that before.
And maybe we've about
it at Virtual Coffee.
Aishwarya: yes, he meets with
an accident and she's sort of
taking care of him and he pushes
to her towards her dreams.
Bekah: Oh, nice. Cool.
That sounds awesome.
We'll have a link in the
show notes to that too.
Um, so we wanna thank you so
much for being here, uh, with
us and on our season seven of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
And we always like to get
started with Origin Story.
So before you jump in and let
us know what your origin story
is, how you got to this point
in your career, what is one
word that describes your career?
Aishwarya: I'd say a bit
difficult or evolving.
Uh, everything is changing.
You get to a point where
you are like, okay, so
I have a hang on this.
But, but, uh, at a certain
point it just, uh, spans
you and it is just evolv.
Bekah: uh, that
resonates with me a lot.
I like that.
That's a really good one.
So tell us a little bit
about this evolving journey
that you've been on.
So how did you get started
doing computery things and where
you are to get, and how did
you get to where you are now?
Aishwarya: Okay, so my stories.
, same old school actually,
I've done my engineering,
uh, in computer science.
And, uh, I wasn't that
involved in coding back then,
but, uh, then at one point,
I think, I remember in my,
one of my classes, uh, there
was one senior who came to
meet my professor again and
I was facing some issues.
So he was like typing
right away on terminal.
And I was fascinated.
What he was actually doing, and
he wasn't even looking anywhere.
Just tapping fast, fast, fast.
And I, it really hit me like,
okay, this is something that
I would also like to do.
And it is always something that
every time you do something
different and new and it is
challenging you at every point.
So I started, uh, I was
actually continuing my
engineering, but I was not
sure at that point that what
would I actually be interested.
, so during interviews
and stuff, so I was also
doing Java and all, but it
wasn't, uh, getting into me.
So at point, I, I thought maybe
I'd do something different.
Uh, but then I, uh, went
into web development.
Uh, so started out with html,
fall in love with css, and, uh,
then JavaScript, uh, started a.
. Uh, previously I would, I was
not mostly working in any kind
of, uh, like logical things or
something, but uh, at Venice
Switch companies, when you get,
uh, take home assignments, at
that point I really started
getting into coding, like
real coding, not HTML and CSS.
So that was the beginning,
and, and that is me falling
in love with javascript.
Bekah: That's awesome.
I love that.
And so now you're doing a
little bit of React native.
Will you talk a little bit about
like how you ended up there and
the differences that you've seen
between React and React native?
Aishwarya: Okay.
So React Native is, uh, I
started in Hacktoberfest, I was
contributing to a React Native
repository, uh, and then it was
just kind of, uh,  that much.
But then, uh, recently
I've started, uh, working
on it, uh, at work.
So the difference mainly is
that, in React you use divs
and in React Native there
are views kind of stuff.
Uh, and that main difference
being that, uh, you use
React for Web and, uh,
react native for, uh, iOS
and Android, Android apps.
So mainly.
It is, uh, helpful because
of, if we, if you are using a
native language, it is mostly
for a particular, uh, device.
So it is either for
Iris or either Android.
But if you are using React
Native, it is for both of them.
Dan: Yeah. Do you.
Having actual CSS  when
you're working with React
Native, that's a, that's my
biggest, that's always my
biggest, uh, struggle when
I have React native projects
I'm working on is just like,
this would be so easy if I
could just add a style, you
know, to this or whatever.
Um, yeah. That's awesome.
so you studied computer science
and you, did you say you were
mostly doing Java during, during
your actual studies, or did
you get into JavaScript stuff
while you were still in school?
Aishwarya: actually, Yeah,
actually, uh, web development
was only a subject for one
semester, so it was mostly Java
based things during college.
And, uh, I also did some
python and stuff, but it
wasn't much back then.
Dan: Yeah. Yeah.
No, that's, that's cool.
So you got, uh, one, one class
of, of web stuff in and that
kind got, got the bug going.
Yeah, I, I think that experience
at, Is a shared one with a lot
of people where you, somebody
gets into web development by,
you know, by doing h l and
css and I, I, I think that
I would count that as real
coding, you know, personally.
But it doesn't have
the, the logic puzzles. Right.
It doesn't have some
of those pieces. Yeah.
And um, and I think that there's
a lot of people that get into
front of development that way
and then find their happy place.
You know, like doing this
stuff, doing react or, doing
react native, um, And including
myself, , you know, because
you still get some of the,
you still get some of the
instant, uh, and sorry, if you
guys can hear my, my dog is
chewing on a bone behind me.
So, uh, Ollie is here, uh,
in the podcast Studio  today.
Um, but uh, what I was saying
was something about react.
Oh man, I was about
to make an amazing
Bekah: CML and the instant.
Dan: Instant gratification.
That's what it was. Yes. Okay.
You get a lot of the front
end development, you can
still get a lot of the sort of
instant gratification stuff.
Right. And you get to like, see
and mess around with the
thing that you're building,
which is one of my favorite
parts, um, about front end.
Um, but you still get to do
some of the like, hard, you
know, harder logic stuff too.
Um, so, so yeah. That's cool.
I'm, I'm always happy when
people kind of have, have
like found, you know, found
something that they, they are
enjoying and, and succeeding in.
It's.
Bekah: And you mentioned doing
some React native work during
Hacktoberfest, and so I wanna
transition into that topic,
working through Hackfest
and Open Source this year.
Was this your first year
doing Hacktoberfest?
Aishwarya: Yeah. Yeah, it was
Bekah: And many pull
requests did you have at
the end of this Hackfest?
Aishwarya: Actually it was nine,
Bekah: Nine? Yeah.
Aishwarya: to nine. I.
Bekah: You just,
you just rocked it.
You just kept going.
You got your four and
that didn't matter.
It was all of all the
things that you could do.
And I was super impressed
by not only were you doing
this for the first time,
but you just crushed it.
You blew it out of the water.
So what was that like
for you getting started
with Hacktoberfest?
Aishwarya: actually, uh, when
I, uh, started, I think I was a
day or two late maybe, and most
of the, uh, two weeks that I've
seen were almost like, oh, my,
uh, two prs were a approved and
accepted and all that stuff.
So, and going into, I was
not sure if I had even do.
Two or more than two.
So I went into like, okay,
I'll at least, uh, learn
something and maybe I'll
do it seriously next year.
I got into it in that attitude.
But, uh, when I started actually
doing it, I really loved it.
It was really great
experience for me.
Uh, got to improve my
coding skills, got to
learn new technologies.
And it was really very
interesting and also, uh,
everyone is always saying
Open source, open source, but
when you actually experience
this, it is very rewarding.
Dan: Yeah, I agree.
And it's, and it's, it does
take, and this is one, one
of the reasons why I love
Hacktoberfest so much, and I
love like what we, what we do at
Virtual Coffee, because it, it
is a different approach, right?
I mean, it's, you know, it's
a little bit different than a
situation where you're in a job
and somebody tells you what to
do or, or you're, uh, building
your own thing and you kind of
have it all in your head, right?
Um, there's, there's
some different steps,
I think, but once.
a lot of people have had
that experience here.
Once you get through the first
couple, you know, the first
couple poll requests, and, and,
and you feel that reward, you
know, uh, hopefully  anyway.
Uh, you know, and not everybody
has, uh, not everybody has
awesome experiences, but I
think most of the time they are.
And, um, that's really, it
is really great to hear.
And I, I wanna do, I just
looked it up on our, on our
roundup, but, uh, we have
you at 10 pull requests for
Hacktoberfest, not nine.
you know, you're shorten
yourself one, so made it to 10.
Oh, you were top our, top
our leaderboard for, uh,
for total pull requests.
So that's pretty awesome.
Bekah: Awesome.
So when you decided to get
into Hacktoberfest, what were
your thoughts on open source
contributions in general?
Aishwarya: So actually, uh,
before, uh, Hacktoberfest I
actually, uh, might have Googled
something, but I was not sure,
uh, about the repositories
or where to contribute.
I was not confident enough to
do actually, uh, ask someone
if I could work on this.
But, uh, then afterwards it
sort of just fell through.
Bekah: Yeah, so that
can be a really.
And tricky thing for first time
contributors, making sure that
everybody feels supported and
and finding that first issue.
And it seems like that
was a challenge that
you found as well.
Even registering a couple
days later, whatever happened
with that, everything
gets picked up so quickly.
So do you have advice for
anybody that is considering
getting started in open source
on what to do in that situ.
Aishwarya: so my main advice
would be that, uh, you
should find the good first
issues or break beginner
friendly issues using that
tag in GitHub in my case.
and you should at least try even.
Uh, first contribution
should not always be
a coding contribution.
It can also be like a
document you contributing to
a documentation, any typos,
fixing, anything like that.
So first contribution
is like, you should at
least try and see how it.
Dan: Yeah, I love that.
I, I, and I think that like,
that's something that we, we try
to push as well and it's really
good advice is it's find you
can find, uh, pull or you can
find issues that aren't code and
that can help you get started.
Um, and.
I've, I'm sure I've said this
on the podcast before, but, you
know, learning too many things
at once, uh, lots of times
results in you, in, you know,
getting frustrated or whatever.
And so if you are trying
to learn open source stuff,
then then concentrating on
something that you don't
have to like learn some,
a whole other thing to do.
The issue is great advice.
Uh, I think that's,
I think that's,
Bekah: Yeah, and I, there
are more companies out there,
open source companies that are
creating those issues as well.
I think it was AppRight
who was one of this year's
sponsors, had issues open
for people who wanted to
write blog posts, so maybe.
You are not up to taking
on an issue, but you
can write about that.
And writing about that
helps other users to
understand, these are the
ways that we can use this.
Oh, this is how you
implement that feature.
And I think that's a really
interesting take on getting
more people involved in
open source contributions.
But I think for me, that's
something that seems.
Like a good path to be able
to get into a project and kind
of evaluate the project too.
I'm a little bit more
confident writing than I
am with coding, and I can
see what those interactions
with the open source
teams are like while doing
something that I'm a little
bit more comfortable with.
You know, one of the things
that I think is impressive about
what you did in Octoberfest as
well was you had been working
in React, but then you still
took a React native issue.
So what got you thinking that
it would be okay to take on an
issue working with a technology
that you hadn't used before?
Aishwarya: Uh, so the main.
main point was that I was
familiar, uh, with the
maintainer and it, uh,
communication was really
great and, uh, I knew if,
and, uh, while reading the
issue, I was confident enough
that I actually, it was a
big thing for me, uh, to even
write that message that if,
can I work on this issue?
But, uh, when after
communicating and, uh,
after, uh, The, uh, the steps
were very clear of what I
wanted, what I had to do.
So it was really helpful
in that point of point.
And uh, so that helped me a lot.
Bekah: Yeah, I like that.
Knowing the maintainer can
make it, again, decrease
those barriers to entry.
And so reaching out to a
maintainer, Um, whether you know
them from Twitter or in Slack
or if you can add something to
the discussion, it never hurts
to start that conversation
with them and see what the
expectations are as well.
So most of my open source
projects are there to help
people get started in open
source and to encourage that.
So I think, actually think
in my postpartum wellness
app, the majority of people
who have contributed.
Have not used React
native before.
Aishwarya: Yeah.
Bekah: And so, uh, the not
every open source project
is created to be okay.
Now my brain stopped.
Um, not every open source
project is created with
the same mission in mind.
Uh, that's what I was gonna say.
And so, you know, there's
different ways to evaluate open
source repositories as well.
And one of those
ways is what does the
communication look like?
What are the expectations
of the maintainers?
And sometimes you can
get that from the issues.
And I, you know, I talked about
this before about one of the
things I learned a couple of
years,  was writing issues can
be really hard if you wanna
write a good issue or time
consuming really, because you
wanna help people understand.
What you want.
Part of the problem is
a lot of times I don't
understand what I want.
Um,  requires me to make some
decisions, but if you can
look at an issue and, and
understand, or if you feel
like the maintainer would be
open to answering questions,
then that can be a really great
way to form that relationship
and to work on something new.
And uh, just one last
thing in that tangent.
Open source is a really great
space to be able to use.
Its new technology that you
might not have the opportunity
to use otherwise and see like,
Hey, maybe, maybe you hated
React Native and you thought,
I never wanna touch this again.
Right. Um, I don't, I don't think
that happened because now
you're working on React
native stuff at work.
But I think that having
those experiences helps
you to learn and to grow
in a, a different way.
So when you, so you went through
this whole open source journey
and in the beginning you weren't
really sure of what to expect
or what things would look like.
How did your perspective
change or did it change at
the end of Hacktoberfest when
you completed your 10 prs?
Aishwarya: actually my, uh,
perspective changed when I
completed four and I, uh,
was really interested in com,
uh, doing more open source.
Change in perspective was that
I got more, a bit more confident
in uh, com, uh, asking for,
uh, asking two maintainers if
I could work on this issue.
Also, I was a bit more
confident in my skills as well
there at that point of time.
Bekah: Yeah. That's great.
And so you were a first
time contributor, but how
long have you been coding
before this Hacktoberfest?
Aishwarya: I'd say, uh,
this march is going to
be a three years for me
working in this industry.
But in, uh, initial days
I was only working with
html, css, and, uh, did a
little bit of WordPress.
So means our script is
mostly like two years.
Bekah: I think that's important
to point out because we
have had a lot of different
contributors who have varying
degrees of experience, right?
And a lot of times people
think that first time
contributors are people who
are very new to coding, and
that's just not the case.
You know, there are
people out there that.
Are interested or maybe
are aware of open source,
but haven't contributed.
And so like finding those
different levels of providing
issues and support for people
is, I, I think, uh, it's really
important to think about like
their developers at all stages
of their careers who are willing
to contribute if they feel
supported in the way that they
need supported to do that thing.
So I think that it's, it's great
that you jumped in this year.
Aishwarya: Yeah, actually, uh,
I had a very great support with
you guys as well because, uh,
in the Hacktoberfest channel,
so we used to get a lot of good
first issues and, uh, because of
that, Also, I did not have to go
out of the way to find issues.
Uh, most of the time I
would get it there as well.
And supportive.
Uh, maintainer is also a great
point in this because, uh,
if I'm able to communicate
with, I know that, so the
person in front of me is
going to explain what the
problem is, then it helps.
Bekah: Yeah, I love that.
And finding that community
of people that are
willing to support you
can be really important.
And I know, you know, one
of, one of the things that I
saw at Virtual Coffee that I
really appreciated is there
were a lot of maintainers out
there who were willing to.
Add issues for people
of varying levels.
And so, like you were saying,
uh, in those first couple
of days, those, uh, beginner
issues or good first issues
are really snatched up quickly.
so if people wanna join
in later, it can be really
hard to find something.
So it, it was nice to see.
People asking like,
Hey, I'm looking for a
good first time issue.
And people saying like, Hey,
I'll write something up,
or I have this issue, and
then that way you know that
you have the support of the
maintainer and you know that
there's a possibility for more
interaction there as well.
So if somebody is thinking
about getting into open
source now, outside of
Hacktoberfest, what do you
think other than looking at
good first issues, how do you.
I think they should get started.
Aishwarya: So what I've been
doing is, uh, recently, uh,
I've been searching on YouTube
videos as well, uh, when most
of the people, Explain in
their videos, which, which
are the, organizations that
help, uh, begin, that have,
uh, beginner friendly issues
to, for you to work on?
So I've been doing that
actually, and mostly Google.
But in case of Google, sometimes
what happens is that few of
the links are broken or old.
or also, uh, if it is not
October 1st, I've seen that, uh,
mostly everyone is not available
to reply to, uh, your message
if you are asking for an issue.
So maybe, uh, just waiting
it out is what you'll have
to do at this point of time.
Think.
Dan: I think that's really.
I mean, I think all
that was good advice.
Your last point is, is an
important one I think, for
people to remember because, if
you're gonna be a contributor to
a repository, lots of times it's
because you, you know, maybe you
found it like, like, like you're
doing with Google or, or YouTube
or, or maybe it's a package that
you use or something like that.
Um, and you would like
to see an improvement.
but what'll happen is you
get all excited, right?
And you know, and maybe
comment on the issue or
maybe try to work up a
poll request or whatever.
Um, and all of that stuff
is in your brain, right?
Because you're working
on it right then.
But maintainers are, especially
with smaller packages or
smaller projects, um, aren't,
you know, in there every
day doing stuff every day.
And so there's like this
whole context which thing
that needs to happen.
And, and so, um, I really
appreciated how you said having
some patience, you know, and
like building that into your
mindset because, um, because
it's important and you know,
everybody's doing their best.
I re just, just recently
had a poll request.
I, I made an issue. What was it?
No, I saw, I had,
I had a problem.
I ran into a problem, found
that there was somebody else
had, had the problem and wrote
the issue and I was able to
like, make a poll request
to fix it, you know, so I
made this poll request and
commented and all this stuff,
and then just didn't hear
anything for like two weeks.
And then after two weeks it
was just like, got merged.
, Nope, no comments,
no, like, nothing.
And, you know, and like,
I'm like, honestly,
that's cool, you know?
Uh, like, the urge to go
back and say, oh yeah,
did you miss this email?
Or, you know, please, you
know, check back,  all that
stuff is understandable.
But, um, but I, you know,
everybody kind of, everybody's
busy and all of that stuff,
so, um, I think that's, I
think that's a really good
plan of, you know, making the,
making the effort, but like
also trying to, trying to,
you know, use some patience
and understand that people.
Just constantly watching their,
their get help notifications,
you know, day and night
Bekah: I like that tip too, of
checking on YouTube and seeing
where people are pointing you.
I have never thought about
that or heard anybody else
give that advice, and I
think that's really unique.
So I do appreciate that and I,
I would say, Along with all of
the great tips that you gave.
Sometimes just putting it
out there into the world.
I'm looking for a
good first issue.
Does anyone have one?
Somebody might respond
to that, you know?
Um, because it, like the
searchability is often not
great for these things, uh,
for a lot of the reasons that
you said, you know, sometimes
projects, Kind of die after
octoberfest, or they're no
longer being maintained.
And so you try and take
something on and nothing
happens, and then that
can be frustrating.
And we definitely don't
want people to be frustrated
with that experience.
So, so looking and seeing
what the activity level is
like is I think, um, really
important as you, uh, navigate
into open source contribu.
Dan: I, uh, actually was
I, I had wanted to call
it that YouTube, your
YouTube tip as well.
Um, I was wondering if you.
It's okay if you don't know
them off the top of your
head, but if you could share
some of your, some of their
creators, excuse me, some of
the creators that are doing
those videos, um, the, like
that you were talking about.
Uh, I would, you know, and
you can send them to me after
if you don't remember, uh,
like off the top of your head.
But I'd love to like
check some of them out.
Maybe we can link a couple
in the, um, in the show
notes, because that seemed
like a really good idea.
And I also had never, I
hadn't heard of that and
I, I think it's great. So, Yeah.
Uh, I don't know if you know
it or remember off the top
of your head, but if you do,
Aishwarya: Actually, I
don't remember them, but
I'll share the links with
Dan: Yeah. Yeah.
I, I would love that.
And we'll, we'll make sure
to put 'em on the show notes
because I, that sounded like
a really cool and interesting
idea and, and a unique idea and
maybe something we could get
into at Virtual Coffee as well.
So , we'll see.
Bekah: what do you think some
of the biggest challenges you
faced during your open source
contributions have been?
Aishwarya: main is, uh, finding
a good first issue and that
not being more than two people
who are already asking for that
same issue, but I don't think
I have faced it that much.
And also, What I'm faced
mean was, uh, the merge
conflicts, when you're,
uh, merging a branch or,
uh, when you're creating
a pull request, actually.
So that was something that I
found a bit difficult because,
uh, I, I've been previously
working with, uh, Azure DevOps.
So it was, uh, there, there
I used, uh, . So it wasn't
like much of a terminal use.
So the, this also much conflict
was something that I found
a bit difficult, but once
figured it out, it was also a
bit, uh, easier to understand.
Dan: So wait, what
was your solution?
Did you end up using some
command line things, or
did you use different, did
the GitHub UI or you know,
Aishwarya: No, no.
I ended up using,
uh, terminal only.
That also was the main, uh,
it got me working on terminal.
He.
Dan: that. I love
Bekah: merge conflicts.
I, I have been known to like
delete repos and start over.
Dan: I, uh, no, I
mean, it is, it's a.
They're, they can be
hairy and not fun. Um, for sure.
Uh, but I love the idea
of like, I, I love your
approach anyway, of taking
it as an opportunity, right.
To, to learn something
new and, and get better at
something that you wanted to,
like you're, uh, the senior,
um, in school who was typing
really fast in the terminal.
You know, . That's right.
You're, you're just about there.
That's that's really.
So, do you have any, I I might
have checked out your GitHub,
you know, profile just recently,
but I, I saw you're working
on a personal project, which
looks, looks kind of cool.
Uh, is that like
an Instagram app?
Is that like, that's just
like a personal hobby project.
Aishwarya: Uh, yeah, actually
I want to explore more
reactive, so I've started
working on that a little.
Dan: Yeah. That's awesome.
So is it like something you
just kind of came up with
in your head, uh, like that?
Or is it like you're following
a tutorial or, you know,
Aishwarya: Uh, no, actually
I found a tutorial.
So, uh, they make, so I
tried first myself, then
see what they are doing.
So I also kind of get
to know different,
uh, coding, uh, types.
So doing something with my
style, but doing, uh, the
person that YouTuber is
doing his style, so combining
and so I'm going that.
Dan: That is, that's really cool.
I, I, I love, like,
I love seeing.
people's like work.
I, I've seen people work on
projects like that, you know,
and, and, but that's one of my
favorite things about GitHub
is, is being able to see like,
what are, what are people like
noodling with, you know, what,
what are people kind of doing?
And you can kind of see
everybody's like project shelf,
you know, like in my garage I
have this just shelf of stuff
that maybe I'm half done.
Maybe, you know, I, maybe I used
it to like do something else,
or, or maybe I meant to finish
it and maybe it's just something
I'm currently working on, but
it's like all there, you know?
Um, and I like that about GitHub.
I like that people kind
of by default put things
in public, you know?
Um, like this, you know,
and it doesn't have to,
like, it's not ever, it's
just for you, you know?
It's not like a, I don't
know, other thing, , whatever,
you know, it is not like a
thing that you're looking
for contributions on for,
for example, you know,
but you still, it's, it's
still, it's like public and
it's, and it's out there
and I think that's great.
I think that's very cool.
Bekah: Yeah.
One of the things that I've
liked about GitHub recently is
the feed that you get on your
main page, I guess, because if
you are following people, you
see the projects that they're
working on or the projects
that they've starred, and
that's been another way that
I've seen people find new.
Open issues just by kind
of browsing through,
like, oh, that person
just started this project.
Let me go check that out
and see what that's about.
Like, oh, there's an
issue that I can take on.
And so sometimes you'll
accidentally fall into
that thing or you learn
something new through that.
I guess it, it's a, a feed of
the people that you follow.
I, um, I don't know.
I just think that that feature
has been really, really
fun to check out lately.
What are some, Ugh,
Dan: Sorry, . I was
just gonna say agreed.
Uh, I, I never remember to look
there cuz I just like have.
Potter's bookmark, but
every time I go back to
the GitHub homepage I'm
like, whoa, this is neat.
There's so much stuff here, and
then I forget about it again.
But I think that's good advice.
Bekah: Are there projects
that you are interested
in contributing to that
you've been checking out? Ashia.
Aishwarya: yeah, actually,
uh, some projects that I've
been working on, uh, during,
uh, , I'm trying to see if
there are any open issues.
Actually, I'm not, I'm
not following anyone.
Or I was just, it was like
a resume for me back then.
Uh, but nowadays I'm trying
to see star, all the starring
and following each other.
And now that you've said,
uh, looking into all at
the field, I think that
will also, we are not next.
Dan: Yeah, I'm, I'm really bad
at, at doing, interacting with
the social stuff on GitHub too,
like the stars, you know, I,
I'm sure I have some star repos,
but I think at the beginning I
was using them as like, I don't
know, some sort of bookmark
thing or whatever, and you know,
like I wasn't really using it.
How, how, how people
use it now, you know?
And I just kind of stopped.
and same with following.
I don't think I, well,
probably I follow a couple
people just cause I wanted
to see how it worked, but
like, I, I just always
forget about it, you know?
I don't, I don't know, I don't
think about it, but like, I,
there's so much, there's so
much cool stuff that Gub is
doing, um, to, and I, I think
a lot of it is to, do what
we're talking about, right?
Is to like expose other things
that other people are working on
to encourage, you know, people.
To jump over and, you
know, help out and stuff.
It is really cool.
So that's gonna be my mission.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna start
starring and following people
on GitHub more often, uh,
Aishwarya: Yeah me too now
Bekah: yeah, I think some of
the cool ones that I've seen
lately, so I've been messing
around with ChatGPT a lot.
We've been talking a lot
about that at Virtual Coffee.
Um, there have been a lot
of people who have put up
repositories that have like
good commands, good, uh, topics.
To look up different ways
to approach it, resources
for that, companies that are
using it or AI in some way.
And it's kind of been fun
to use it as a resource, uh,
rather than thinking of a
traditional open source project.
It's just a markdown
repository of things.
And so to be able to
learn in that way too,
I think is really nice.
I wish that there was
some way to sort, maybe a
little bit better in terms.
Like there's a lot of great,
really great resources that
are listed there on GitHub,
and then there's a lot of
like great code repositories.
It would be nice to
have a tag, this is just
me talking out loud. Sorry.
I, this is something that
I would like to  to be
able to see how many people
have resources that are up.
And that was one of my,
actually, I think that's
my very first open source
project that I ever.
Was, I was part of a moms and
tech group, and so I created a
markdown repository of resources
and organizations that supported
moms in their tech journey,
and that was, I don't know,
that was fun because I got to
meet a lot of new people and
kind of talk through some of
those issues and I, I really
enjoy the conversation part.
being an open source maintainer,
and I know that's probably
because my projects are small
and I don't have a ton of
people who are contributing,
so I have the opportunity to
do that, but I, I don't, that's
how I would like to keep it,
I think because I, I do enjoy
being able to talk to people
about their experiences and
to support them in different.
Are there any bigger projects
that you've looked at or
have you checked out any
of like the React native
repos that are out there?
Aishwarya: Uh, yeah,
actually I was also looking
at React, uh, repository.
I would like love to
someday contribute somehow.
Bekah: Yeah, it's always fun
to, to see what is out there
and to just like a peek and
see if there's something
that you can contribute to.
A lot of times those ones,
I think that sometimes when
we get into open source, we
think of those projects first.
Like, oh, the big ones,
you know, people always say
contribute to the projects
that you use every day, but
those ones often require a
lot of in-depth knowledge
and understanding of.
Everything and their code
base, and I don't, I think that
many of them, the issues take
a long time to work through
and that can be overwhelming,
especially if you're trying
to hit four pool requests.
I think one year I was doing
octoberfest and I had already
spent like three hours on.
an issue, and I wasn't close
to being done and I was like,
this is never gonna happen.
I'm never going to hit four if
this is what it's going to take.
And I wonder if there's any
information out there about
the average time it takes to
complete four issues into,
I don't, maybe like level
setting, expectation setting,
but do you, what would you
say on average, how long did
it take you to complete an.
Aishwarya: I think for me it
took, uh, like when I started,
it took me around four to five
days, but, uh, the accepting
part is seven days per request.
So it would be more
than that in that.
but average time, I think,
uh, it also depends on what
you're searching for and how
much, uh, you get to work on,
but mostly I think it should
be done in 10 days at least.
That's my understanding.
Bekah: Yeah,
Aishwarya: I've seen people,
posting tweets, uh, saying
I've completed my third
request on second or third day.
Bekah: I, okay, so I was
one of those people, I don't
think I tweeted about it.
It was like the second day
I got the notification that
I had hit my, and I think
what happened was some, I
had outstanding prs on some
repositories, and then somebody
decided that they should merge
them or something because I
don't know how I got those.
Although I still haven't
gotten my t-shirt yet, so I
hope they don't revoke it.
Like she shouldn't really get
those prs, cuz I don't know.
I don't know where
they came from.
Dan: it's
Aishwarya: today.
Dan: Oh, really? Today. Nice.
Yeah, I got mine, uh,
a week or two ago,
Bekah: Yeah, so
understanding that all of
these things takes time.
And then going back a
little bit to what you
were talking about with.
Looking at the issue and seeing
how well it's broken down is
really important for, I, I had,
uh, someone at Virtual Coffee
that I was mentoring their
first octoberfest as well last
year, I think, and they chose
something that said Good first
issue and it required them to
install docker and write tests
and do a, a sub substantial
amount coding, which I thought
that's not, there's no way.
that's a good first issue.
I have no, I, I'm
afraid of Docker.
I didn't I don't want to use it.
Um, maybe, maybe one day I will.
It just seems scary.
Dan: Yeah.
Those things that, uh, it's like
if somebody has set everything
up for me, then I'm down.
You know?
But like, I don't, I don't
want to be building my
own whatever, configs and
all that stuff, you know?
it's a, it's another one of
those tools that I'm like,
well, if somebody else does
all the hard work for me,
then I'm fine using it.
Bekah: Yeah. Yeah.
Dan: like, Webpack
the same thing.
I'm like, I don't, I don't
ever want to like specifically
configure this, but, uh,
I'll, I'll use it if somebody
really, really helps me.
Bekah: All right.
We're close to time for
today, but we always, um,
well, this season we're
doing something a little bit
different and we're asking
people one word that they would
use to describe themselves.
So what is that one word for you?
Aishwarya: I'd say dedicated
towards what I want to achieve.
And sometimes if I don't
know something, then I'll
like to, uh, Google it myself
and try to find it instead
of, uh, directly saying no.
Bekah: Yeah.
I love that idea of being
dedicated to the things
that you're working on.
Do you have any tips or
advice for people who are
finding it challenging to
be dedicated to what they're
working on right now?
Aishwarya: if it's in the
sense of coding, then I'd say
do not follow, uh, tutorials.
only follow documentation.
Not follow is not a correct word.
Uh, just take a break,
work on some projects.
That is main advice I'd give
my two year back self also that
stop watching tutorials and,
uh, trying to remember things.
It just comes to you
when you are constantly
working on things.
Bekah: I love.
Uh, I think that, you know,
it, it's really challenging
to stay dedicated, but you
definitely have shown that
you are dedicated, and I
love that you use that word
here, talking about these
things, especially when.
You knocked Hacktoberfest
out of the park with your
10 prs merged in this year.
So I, I will second that.
Dedicated is a good word
for you and I just wanna
thank you for being a part
of Virtual Coffee and for
coming on the podcast today.
Aishwarya: Thank
you for having me.
Dan: Yeah. Thank you and we will
talk to you soon.
Bekah: Hi.
Aishwarya: Hey.
Dan: bye. Thank you for listening
to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by
Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot Weigel.
If you have questions
or comments you can
hit us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO, or email us
at podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show
notes, sign up for the
newsletter, check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io.
If you're interested in
sponsoring Virtual Coffee
you can find out more
information on our website at
VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to
our podcast and be sure
to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and
we'll see you next week!