Bekah: Hello and welcome to
Season seven,episode five of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I'm Bekah,
and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey,and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned,
and we are here to share it with
you.Here with me today is my
co-host.
Dan: What up,Beck?How's it going?
Bekah: It is fantastic.How's it
going with you?
Dan: It's going pretty good.
Yeah,I've had probably too much
coffee this morning,but other
than that,feeling pretty good.
Bekah: Nice.
Dan: And so today we have another
awesome,interview with another
awesome member of Virtual Coffee.
We're talking to Rebecca Key,uh,
who is a software engineer based
out of Atlanta,Georgia.Rebecca
had a really cool story.She was
actually an organic chemist for
years.She has her PhD,so I'm
sorry.I should have said Dr.
Rebecca Key.I meant to do that
earlier.And,uh,she,so she was an
organic chemist,did that for a
long time,worked in a lab,all
that stuff.And then,um,around the
Covid times,I think,uh,
transitioned to being a
developer,which I think a lot of
our career changer people,did
that during that time.Uh,you
know,sort of a tumultuous time
for everybody and um,yeah,it was
really good talking to.
Bekah: Yeah,it was really cool to
talk about that transition and
then also bringing her hobbies
into things.She talked a lot
about her experience with her ham
radio,which I thought was really
cool,and I really love getting to
know like all of the sides of the
people who come to the podcast.
So I,I think that we got to
explore a lot of different
aspects of what it is to be a
person.
Dan: Yeah,absolutely.
Bekah: Well,we start every
episode of the podcast,like we
start every Virtual Coffee.We say
our names,where we're from,what
we do,and a random check-in
question.We hope you enjoy this
episode.Today's random check-in
question is,what's one fun fact
that you know.So one fun fact
that I know is that possums have
13nipples and they go in a circle
with the13th,one in the middle.
Dan: can't be real
Bekah: It is.I looked it up.I,
and this like a side note,I was
at a conference once and they
were giving out drink tickets and
they were like,tell us a fun
fact.And I told them that Fun
fact.And they were like,well,we
meant about yourself,but that
will work too.Cool.
Dan: yeah,you just broke my
brain.I,that's kind of thing a,a
child would draw,would draw Um,
Hey,do you want to do the rest of
the intro?Or you just like,Like
your
Bekah: dang I just got really
excited about the question.Screw
this all up.My name is Bekah.I am
a technical community builder
from a small town in Ohio,and
there's also an animal that
poops,um,in squares,but I can't
remember which one it is.Who
Dan: that one I knew it's a
wombat,right?
Bekah: Yes,wombat.I know that.
Dan: I knew.that one.Uh,that is,
uh,yeah,that is the talent.I've
always been jealous of,you know,
like,that seems like a,a.a,a cool
ability,
Bekah: Do you know why they poop
in squares?
Dan: Um,I don't know for sure.My
guess is something about rolling
downhills,but I don't actually
know.
Bekah: Yeah,it's to mark
territory so it wouldn't roll
down hills.They needed to have
square poop.So they made it
happen.
Dan: uh,nature is a miracle.uh,
okay.Hi,I'm Dan.Um,Yeah.
Cleveland aisle computery things.
Um,let's see.Fun fact.Okay,
Bekah: you gonna get on me for my
intro?And you say computery
things.
Dan: well,I said something,you
know,uh,okay.Um,there are,uh,
let's see,broccoli,uh,
cauliflower,kale,something else.
all are,um,all are related and
oh,Brussels sprouts,um,and come
from the same plant,and they're
all human made.So the,this one
plant humans,uh,like took this
plant and then selected for,you
know,flowers and made cauliflower
and selected for something else.
I,I don't really know all the
genetics,but like all of those
plants don't come from nature.
They come from,they come from
human,uh,you know,like plant,I
don't know what you call it,gene
manipulation,but,not in a
chemistry lab.
Bekah: So why do they choose all
the bitter things and,and not
like chocolate
Dan: I think the plant was
bitter.I,I don't think they
could,
Bekah: Yeah.But why would you say
like,I'm gonna take this bitter
plant and make more bitter plants
out of it.Like,
Dan: well,some people like bitter
plants.
Bekah: I mean,I also enjoy eating
all of
Dan: I do too,right?
Bekah: like
Dan: But they're,and they're
different like the,you know,like
you can.broccoli and cauliflower,
that makes those like,kind of
look similar,uh,except for the
color,but like the,uh,yeah,kale
and,and I don't know if asparagus
is in there.
Bekah: doesn't it come from the
mustard seed?
Dan: I don't
Bekah: Sorry.
Dan: I have no idea.I mean it
comes from some kind of a seed
cuz it's a.I don't,I don't
remember what the,I should work
on this fun fact so that I can
actually say it,you know,uh,uh,
for drink tickets.apparently But,
uh,yeah,that's my,that's a fir
first fun fact that popped into
my brain,so I'm going with that.
Rebecca: My name is Rebecca.I am
a software engineer based out of
Atlanta,Georgia.And a fun fact,
one of the first ones that's
coming to my mind is from an.Old
school email chain.And I remember
it's apparently impossible to
lick your elbow.
Dan: like nobody can do it.
Bekah: Does kids have tried?
Yeah.
Rebecca: And then according to
the,you know,the email chain are
further down,it's like a certain
number of people are going to try
to lick their elbow after reading
this But,um,I don't know if that,
um,myth has been debunked or not,
but,um,apparently it's tough or
too impossible to do.Get to
Dan: wanna
Bekah: It wanna try.
Dan: Everybody at Try right now.
Bekah: don't do,you can't do that
thing,then I am usually gonna try
it.But in the circumstance,I,I'm
not gonna try it in front people.
After we're done recording,I will
try to lick my elbow
Dan: Oh fine.Uh,yeah,I wonder if
there's like the,you know,the
people that can do the,the like
crazy,you know,I don't know what
you call it.Um,or they can beat
super bendy and stuff,you know?
Uh,yeah.Yeah.I wonder if there's
something like that,you know,or
there was,who was it?In Lethal
Weapon,the guy Rig.What is,I
forget what the actor's name is,
but he had a trick,he had a
trick,a trick shoulder where he
could pop it out,you know,like in
like he used it to get out of,
you know,bad situations.But I
wonder if he could pop it out and
then like turn his arm around,
All right,if you have a trick
shoulder,I want to hear from you
to let us know.
Bekah: That's right.Send us,send
us some messages.Podcast Virtual
Coffee.io.Right?We have that
email address.
Dan: Oh yeah,definitely.
Bekah: Send us all your feedback
and fun stories.We're here for
them.and speaking of fun stories,
we have Rebecca Key here with us
today and oh,we are very
thankful.So thank you for being
here.We're very excited to hear
your story.
Rebecca: Thank you again for
having me so.Um,as I mentioned
before,I'm a software engineer.
Um,I come to tech after many
years in being in science,um,
specifically organic chemistry.I
served in many roles over the
years in research labs,being a
laboratory technician all the way
up to a research director in the
pet care industry.And,um,from
there like.being an r d director
that was in the height of the
pandemic.So,you know,with the
world shut down,everyone kind of,
or some people,you know,paused.
It's like,okay,you know,where am
I at?Where am I going?Where do I
wanna go?And I had.Made solid
contributions in my role,and what
I wanted to do was be able to use
my problem solving skillset to be
able to make a broader impact.
And when I say broader impact
with software engineering,namely
front end development,which I
spend most of my time doing,you
have.A pretty quick feedback loop
on your work.Like in science,it
can be an order of years from an
idea from inception to completion
to any sort of publication.And
within that,your lab experiments
can,you know,last from days to
weeks.Again,where I hit refresh
on a UI and I immediately,again,
know where I'm going and a wrong
answer is at least an answer to
get me back on the right track
and I can do that quickly.Um,
hopefully not taking a matter of
days,years,et cetera.You gotta
get,get help along before that
comes along.So that's what
brought me to the field.I started
working with,a fitness-based web
app that.I started,um,race prep
Fit.I'm hoping to get that
eventually is a,um,subscription
service.the premise of it is
having users customize their
training program to meet goals
for an event of their choice.Um,
I've also,beyond that,have done
some independent contract work,
um,most recently with Dan.Um,UI
elements in React,and it was a
really neat experience where,you
know,I'm a,I'm a React developer
more than anything else in tech,
but I was able to learn more
frameworks in React versus just
the Create React app where I
started.So it was,you know,neat
being able to use Storybook,you
know,getting familiar with remix
and even dabbling a little bit in
type script,which I had been
wanting to do,and that gave me a
reason.To work on that.Done some
other freelance work where I'm,
you know,building static
websites.Companies billing a
landing page,getting a form ready
for people to subscribe to the
company's email list.Um,I've
actually most,most recently
started diving into content
creation,reviving my blog for
hand,radio Adventures,RF Quest.
Um,alongside that,um,I'm editing
a video of where I built a40
meter antenna in my backyard.Um,
hopefully hoping to get that on
YouTube here in the next few
days.So,You know,definitely
keeping myself busy with things
like that.And also with working
with the ham radio,I'm able to
keep my speaking and writing
skills up to snuff because
unfortunately that is a very
perishable skill set,and it's so
important no matter what field
you go into,to be able to
communicate,whether it's,you
know,speaking or.And then also
with radio,I'm able to,um,do
different contesting,um,parks on
the air is something that we've
been doing more recently where it
gets us out of the house.We set
up radios at different,you know,
state parks,wildlife management
areas.Um,Public fishing areas,
and if you can get more than10
contacts on radio,you've
activated the park.Um,also within
some of these state parks,you've
got,you know,mountain biking
trails on some of them.There's
hiking trails.You can go paddle
boats.So it really.You know,it
encourages us to get out of the
house,you know,with,um,remote
work is great,but you do have to
make an effort to,you know,
separate yourself so you can
recharge and then,you know,be the
best you can be.Um,even with the
exercising I do,I'm running in
the neighborhood,I'm,I got a
power rack in my living room,so
I'll weightlift in my living
room.I didn't crochet in my
living room,so this is a really,
um,great way to get out of the
neighborhood.You know,talk to
people through technology.It may
not be coding,but it's definitely
hitting that science and
technology check mark.That's been
a consistent in my life.
Bekah: I really loved it.
Dan: Yeah.I,I love it too.Sorry,
Bekah.I,I think we're both
excited about it though.It,it's,
it's such a cool idea.Um,I have
like so many questions about the
hand radio stuff.I,um,so the,the
program,what is the program
called?With the parks?
Rebecca: It's called Parks on the
Air or POTA.Um,there's also SOTA
Summits on the air where you can,
you know,hike or mountain bike up
a mountain.That's a designated
summit for the program.There's a
lot of them in North Georgia
that's relatively locally.For
that one,you have to make four
uh,contacts,um,to activate the.
So that one's a little different.
There's a big prize on that one.
Um,I think it,I think it's a
hundred contacts in a year.Um,
ham radio,sodium enthusiasts,
correct me if I'm wrong,but it's
the Mountain Goat Award and
that's a really,um,big one to
get.Um,we met someone not that
long ago that,um,did it on two
meters,which is more of a local
line of sight band.So that was
definitely a challenge added to
that as well.
Dan: Nice.so you built a big
antenna in your yard,is it the
same,are you using the same radio
like at home and when you're
traveling?Or do you have,like,is
there a smaller one or,you know,
Rebecca: so this particular one,
um,this antenna is actually just
a long,um,about61feet of wire for
this particular one.This one was
actually made in mind,um,to take
with us for portable ops.
Dan: Oh wow.The one in your
backyard.
Rebecca: Um,there are some in the
backyard for,um,the,the home unit
that's,
Dan: Yeah,there's a hill unit.
Yeah.Yeah,that's what I,that's
what I was like,yeah.So how heavy
is the,how heavy is the one where
you are taking it to parks and
you know,mountains and stuff?
Rebecca: so,uh,the one we take is
probably just a couple of pounds.
I mean,you've gotta take,you
know,the batteries as well with
it.Um,I always have to make sure
to charge those beforehand so you
can actually use radio.I mean,
antenna's pretty lightweight.Um,
real easy to work with.The brand
that we built this antenna with,
um,it's called SOTA Beams.They
actually,it's a company that kind
of has the SOTA contesting in
mind,for people to just be able
to easily transport it.
Dan: That's so cool.it reminds me
of,of,um,well,I guess Pokemon Go
now.there was a game called
Ingress before that was that,you
know,the people who made Pokemon
Go,uh,ingress first,you know,and
then they basically kind of
rebranded it.But the thing that I
loved the most about it was,it
was that same thing,right?Where
there's like,there are goals and
stuff,but it,you have to,you have
to travel around.Like,it not
maybe as,I mean,you,you can
choose how much you go,you know,
but you get rewarded for going
new places and,you know,
exploring new places and,and
stuff like that.It's,it's really
neat.I love those,combinations
of,you know,technology and,and,
Forcing you to get away from just
sitting at your computer or your
phone or whatever,you know?Cuz
lots of times when you think of
that kind of stuff,for me at
least,I end up just sitting on my
computer you know,doing neat
stuff,but like,still just,just
sitting here,you know?So I love
that.I love anything that helps
you,helps you,um,you know,
rewards you for getting out,uh,
into the world,
Rebecca: For sure,even locally,
it's nice to have a good little
change of scenery when you need
it,and some of these state parks
are within about30minutes from
where we live,so that's not too
bad of a drive.
Dan: Nice.
Bekah: I think it's interesting
cuz you've talked a lot about how
we touch on technology in our
lives,like outside of the coding,
uh,but how impactful that it
could still be,how it can still
create connections for us and how
you.Are kind of utilizing your
interest to be able to do that.
And so you talked a little bit
about this app that you're
creating,that you want it to move
into a subscription service,
which sounds like it's,it's
filling that need as well.So did
that get started as a project
personally for you or to help you
learn and,you know,how have you
kind of,how has that developed
throughout your skillset
development as.
Rebecca: So it was kind of a
little bit of everything.It was
kind of my first foray into
learning React.Um,I've been in
probably a consistent runner,
probably f.Within the last10
years,I've been running on an off
since I was14.it's something that
is a great form of exercise
because it's readily available
and easy to do.The best forms of
exercise are ones you can do,and
if figured it would keep me
motivated to keep running,it
would,you know,get me going and
react.But also kind of think of a
way of.Okay.What can be,what con
contributions can you make that
aren't already out there?And
that's kind of like in chemistry
as well.You're doing research on
something that's entirely new or
you're finding a new twist on
something that's already there,
or you're building on,you know,
something else.Just showing
something new and.You know,what I
was hoping for to show,um,
something new with this is to be
able to have something where a
user can customize a training
plan as opposed to something
where it's like,okay,I ran three
miles today.Which that's great
that those things do have their
purpose,but you know,someone
wants a little bit more than
just,you know,logging miles.This
is a way to say,okay,I wanna
train in this manner.This run's
gonna be a temper run.This run's
gonna be at pace.Or you're kinda
log where you run at intervals
and things like that.If you're
doing speed work for example,it
kinda gives,kinda opens some
doors to having a little more
data and you know,is a somebody
who's spent my career handling
data telling stories.That's also
kind of something that appealed
to,um,working on a more of a
fitness based.
Bekah: I think that's really
great.I had used,uh,like a
handful of years ago,couch to5K
or,or whatever it was.Um,and it's
pretty straightforward,right?
Like everybody has the same
workouts I think every day.And
then I found,When I started
getting back into running about a
year ago that I wanted to
improve,but I didn't really know
how to,because there's,at least I
couldn't really find anything out
there.So that idea of like what
you are talking about,that kind
of,um,customization,different
kinds of running.Workouts or
whatever is really appealing
because it,I,I know I pretty much
know nothing about running.Oh,I
can't run now cause I tore the
meniscus in my knee.But one day
when I,when I get back there,
that idea of improving my speed
is something that I'd like to
focus on.And finding the
application of data to do that is
a really interesting concept.I.
Rebecca: For sure is,is going
well,and I'm looking forward to
seeing your,where it goes,where
it takes me,and all of that.
Bekah: It sounds like you're
doing a lot of different things,
right?You,you've got,um,a lot of
hobbies and activities and you're
doing contract work and you're
doing this.How do you.Balance or
not balance,all of the different
things that you're working on.
Rebecca: So,um,I have to
prioritize,you know,basically
with deadlines.Um,some things are
a little more pressing,need to be
done a little faster.So those
things I do,you know,prioritize.
first there's some things,
depending on what needs to be
done with it.I take more time to.
Dedicate to that.But what I try
to do big picture,you know,I have
my written list of things I do
need to do.and,you know,try to,
you know,give,prioritize,you
know,stuff that's needs to be
done sooner,that needs more time.
Um,take,you know,take those first
and then if there's something
that can wait,you know,that kind
of gets put to the bottom of the
list.um,you know,try to big
picture,you know,try to
multitask.But there,if there's
something that,you know,needs my
attention a little more,you know,
briefly,you know,put some other
things aside,get the priority
done.And what I also do,and I did
this in science as well,um,I'm a
note taker.I'm hardcore pen and
paper.But if you,if I get to the
end of something around at a good
stopping point,I will make notes
of what I need to do next when I
come back to it.Because sometimes
you get taken away from something
longer than you want to,and
having that cue of what you've
done and what you need to get
back to is a way where I.
Ideally,you know,minimize time,
just scrambling,trying to figure
out what I did,going behind
myself.So that's kind of a,a,a,
um,tool that I've had for many
years that I carry with me if it
serves me pretty well in tech as
far as,you know,getting caught
back up to speed on something
that I haven't touched,maybe in a
bit.
Dan: I think that's,I think
that's such a great idea.I.I
struggle with the problem that
you have solved And,you know,I,
you know,and,and for me lots of
times it's like,okay,well I'm
just gonna leave these four,you
know,14tabs open and,you know,
hopefully they're still open when
I come back to them and I can
decode what I was thinking.You
know,something like that.I,I,
the,uh,it doesn't work that well.
I mean,it sometimes works,it's
sometimes not.Um,and,and I think,
you know,when you're independent,
like,like you are,You don't have,
you know,you don't have a,a
manager like telling you all the
different things and stuff and
that sort of ability to
prioritize and quickly,quickly
change context.You know,I,it's
such a valuable skill and,and I,
I feel like you have,I feel like
you've figured a lot of that
stuff out.It's really cool to
hear.I'm al also also very
jealous.A all time with people
who,who can take notes and,you
know,do take good notes and
useful notes.Uh,I'm,I've,I never
learned that skill,you know,I
struggled with it in school and.
just didn't even try after school
But,uh,the times that I've taken
notes,I'm like,man,this is
awesome.I should do this all the
time.And then I don't,
Rebecca: It Nice with the to-do
list.I have kinda that visual cue
of kind of where to start,where I
need to look and go.And I also
use org mode,um,with emax to kind
of keep another list of some
things like what progress I'm
making,where I'm at on it.Um,it
gives you,you know,to do in
progress and review done.So I,I
use that as well to accompany.
But yeah,even if I'm in a meeting
with someone,I think one of my
first meetings with you,Dan,on
the work we did,I'm like,I'm a
note taker.If I'm looking down
doing this,I'm not ignoring you.
I'm just taking notes cuz I've,
you know,gotta have my pen and
paper nearby.I dunno if that
comes with just,you know,keeping
laboratory notebooks all those
years.I mean,even my knitting and
crocheting,I've got a lab
notebook,quote of the work I do
with it.So,
Dan: That's awesome.
Bekah: I love that and I,I met,
um,with an owner of a company a
couple of years ago and I really
appreciated when he said to me,
if I'm looking down,it's because
I'm taking notes.Right.Because I
think sometimes that can be
off-putting and I appreciate
that,that you mentioned that too.
Like if I'm not looking,and I try
and do that as well because I'm
a,a big note taker.I don't know
where I'm going with this train
of thought.other than,um,
notetaking is one of those things
that we actually talk about a lot
at Virtual Coffee and getting
started in note taking and
different tools for note taking.
And it can be a little bit over
like.Sounds straightforward,
right?You take notes,but it's,
it's not like it's complex for a
lot of people.And then the tools
over there,out,out there can be
really overwhelming.I find myself
mostly,um,pen and paper,but I do
have,I use obsidian very lightly.
Just because I mostly use it for
markdown to be able to do that.
Have you gone on like a
note-taking journey where you've
tried some of these other tools?
I tried notion like a handful of
times and every time I'm just
super overwhelmed.I can't handle
it.
Rebecca: So I've,I've kept up
with org mode a little bit and
there's a lot org mode can do.
It's,it's definitely more of an,
an EMAX based,um,Um,that one I
just kind of keep trying some
general notes and also kind of a
backup in case,you know,
something happens to my,my spiral
notebook or I can't find the
information readily readily so I
have it electronically so I can
kind of grasp where I'm.Where I'm
at with it and find it.Um,I've
worked with not a little bit,I
don't dislike it,but I didn't see
where it really,helped me
specifically.So I don't use it
very often.Um,no,it's not a knock
on the,the tool,it's just
something that's not really
working for me right now.Um,but
what helps me with taking notes
and sometimes I'll go back
sometimes,um,I don't know
necessarily need the detail,but
it gives.um,if,when I need it,
space and time,cuz if I have
space and time,I can usually find
what I'm looking for.Um,I tell
people one of my superpowers is
finding needles in haystacks,and
that helps me too.That,
especially if you can gimme a,a
timeline on that.Um,also as well,
you know,just writing the notes
sometimes helps me.Better retain
the information,so it helps me
slow down,absorb what I need to
absorb.Kind have that reference
as well.Um,and you kind of
circling back to ham radio,I
actually might see song on my
Twitter.I have this clipboard
where I'm writing down my
contacts.I've had that clipboard
since I was10years old.I got it
for my birthday and I have,it has
seen,you know,QSOs for ham radio.
It's seen my weekly spelling
list.it's seen my PhD
dissertation notes.It's,it's seen
a lot,but,um,it's,you know,
something that,It's just nice to
write it down.And I've learned
when I'm taking quick notes,like
with my radio contacts,I have to
get those logged in cause you
have to log them into their app
to,for it to count.I've gotta do
that pretty soon because you can
get a backlog or it's like,I
don't remember the details of
this particular q s,so I need to
just go log.Get it where it needs
to go.So I get the important
details where they need to be.
Um,of course,you know,if I'm
writing fast,the longer time
goes,the less I'm able to read my
own handwriting.I'm left-handed,
I got that straw going on Um,but
yeah,it's like,um,I am a
shameless note taker.and,um,just
any,like we've talked,yeah.
Virtual Coffee.It's like,okay,I
just need some college rule
paper.I need a,an extra fine
point on it because being a
lefty,you get all this ink down
your hand,it makes such a mess.
Um,when I would ta in,in grad
school when I was on the
whiteboard,even whiteboard,
present day,I'm always checking
myself to make I don't have all
the residue on my hand.But,eh,
lefty problem.So,
Bekah: always wanted to be
left-handed.There's a fun fact
about me,
Rebecca: Blessing and a curse
Dan: What?Yeah,I mean,you could
train yourself to be left-handed.
Bekah: Well,I tried to for a
while when I was a kid.Um,just
dunno that I have that kind of
time
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.of a,
Bekah: I feel like it's kind of
cheating.Like,oh,I'm not really
left-handed.I just forced myself
to be able to be,
Dan: yeah,I think,I mean,
honestly,being,being ambidextrous
would be the,the coolest.I think
that'd be,that'd be really cool
to be able to,you know,do
everything equally with both
hands.
Rebecca: Fun fact actually
left-handed people have a greater
tendency to be ambidextrous,
Bekah: Oh,interesting.
Dan: Is that a social thing or is
that like a,
Rebecca: Well,in,in a
right-handed world,it's like we
have to adapt.So I learned to
play guitar.Um,back in college
and,you know,I was brought up to
the teacher,I'm like,I'm
left-handed.Do I need a
left-handed guitar?And he's,and
he presented that,you know,
lefties can be more ambidextrous.
And they're like,you know,that
makes sense.He's like,you know,
you try to learn right-handed
because you're really gonna cut
yourself off if you,you know,
have to be.If you have to guitar
left-handed,but guitar left-hand,
what controls the neck?So it
actually worked out for me.I
don't play a lot.I haven't
played,I can't remember the last
time I played.But,um,you know,
taking kind of that iteration,I
was able to do that right-handed.
I sometimes have to cut
right-handed cuz the scissors
don't like me.But that's,once I
get of scissors,it works like
they're mine,
Dan: Yeah.Yeah,that,uh,the
scissors was a big,so my,my,uh,
younger son is left-handed,and
that was like,and none of,none of
my family is,you know,like,uh,
and the scissors,the fact that
right-handed scissor,there's
actually right-handed and
left-handed scissors,and they're,
they're,they're built
differently.Like,that was a mind
blowing thing.I,I had no idea,no
idea about that.Like,I,I thought
it was just like,oh,the shape of
the holes,you know,the shape
that,you know,it's just like a
comfort thing.It was actually
like the way that the cutting
edges are.Is opposite on
left-handed scissors.Uh,and,and
it's something about the way
that,you know,cuz the way you
hold it,your,your thumb is
moving.The scissors,you know,so
that blade is the one that's
moving.And so when you do it the
opposite side,it doesn't cut that
well if you have right-handed
scissors and you're using your
left hand.And I had like,I had no
idea about that.is like a mind
blowing thing,so,
Rebecca: little scissors in
school,those little,little basic
safety scissors,those are a
nightmare lefthanded
Dan: Oh,I mean,that's why we
Yeah,that,well,that's exactly why
we did that cuz we have those,
those safety scissors and so we,
you can buy left-handed safety
scissors and they you know,you
know what I mean?And so we,we did
that and it,like,it made a
difference.But I had,I had no
idea.Yeah.Uh,learn,learn new
things.uh,I feel like Sam said,
so he's four and he gets confused
sometimes cuz his,you know,
Bennett's right-handed his,his
older brother that he,you know,
falls around and does all this
stuff.And so he's goes back and
forth.His,his mind is
left-handed,you know what I mean?
But he's like,he just gets all
mixed up.I'm like,why,why you
using your right hand?I'm like,
you can do whatever you know,but
like,I think it might be easier
for you if you,he's like,oh yeah,
I forgot.So I dunno.
Rebecca: it's always to remind
myself like,am I left-handed when
I do this from I right-handed
when I do cuz I played,when I
played softball many years ago,I
played right-handed because I
was.I could throw with,I throw
better with my left and I'd throw
left dominantly to this day,but I
couldn't catch,cause you have to,
your gloves on your right hand
playing softball.And I couldn't
catch as well with my right hand.
So I had to switch that up
because it's like,more efficient
if I can catch left-handed and,
you know,get by with my,you know,
right-handed arm So,yeah,it's,
it's definitely.you go through
life figuring it out.and in any
leftal can empathize with,um,
backing out of a parking space
the wrong way.And there get the
wrong end of the door.Like,you
know,with the bar you push on the
wrong side.
Bekah: I do that all the time.
I'm not sure what's wrong with
me.That's my brain still wanting
to be left-handed.Yeah,it's
interesting.I was talking to
somebody recently about this.It
might have been James Quick,and I
wonder like there are some people
that they will,right.Left-handed
or Right,right-handed.But they'll
do things like play golf or play
sports left-handed.And so then I,
I wonder like how do you,like
what makes you right-handed or
left-handed?Is it just.The hand
that you write with,and that's
what you choose because if you
use your left hand dominantly in
other things,then what?Are you
just ambidextrous?Is that what
you say?I don't know.
Rebecca: so for me,um,I would
tell people I.Pretty decently
lefthanded cuz some people are,
are a little more dominant on the
lefthand than others.So,um,I have
a cousin who's left-handed,you
know,she played basketball
right-handed.I played basketball
left cuz I was much better
left-handed than right,although
you had to,you know,if you're a
short five,three person like
myself playing,you gotta play
point guard,handle the ball.But I
was more dominant on the left
hand side.Softball again,I was
just able to be more functional,
playing right-handed so I could,
you know,throw in catch whereas,
you know,having to catch with my
right hand,it would,it'd been
more of a learning curve at the
time.
Dan: yeah.So you could teach
yourself to do anything with
either hand if both hands work
the same,but left-handed isness
or right-handed whatever.It's,
it's genetic.Like it is a genetic
thing,but,um,there's like a lot
of social,you know,things like,
uh,There was,you know,there,
there used to be like
superstitions about left-handed
people,right?And so that got like
corrected.And,and so the writing
is like,probably they just were
taught,either taught to write
right-handed before anybody
realized that they're
left-handed,or,you know,cuz it's
kind of hard when you have like
little kids,it's like they're
really paying attention to what
I,what they're doing or whatever.
And so if they start writing and,
and you say,use your right hand,
use your right hand,you know,uh,
before you realize that they're
left-handed.That's probably how
that happens.You're making a lot
of faces,
Bekah: I am,I'm going down a
rabbit hole of like,what makes
some,like what happens in your
brain if you're left-handed.And
it,I mean,it's wild.Let's see.
Um,
Rebecca: We're in our right mind.
Bekah: handedness is associated
with functional lateralization of
cerebral dominant.I,I just have
Dan: totally.I mean,I was gonna
say that I
Bekah: less lateralized brains.
What?This is really,I don't know.
I never really thought of the
neur of left-handedness until
right now,and now this is gonna
be something I'm stuck on.Wow.
There's studies that are done on
identical twins with different
handed.
Rebecca: Yes,that is actually,I
had,um,identical twin friends in
high school.Um,they're,a lot of
times they're mirror images of
each other,so they're
Bekah: Whoa,
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Rebecca: images.One's usually
right-handed,one's usually
left-handed or maybe a little
more of the ambidextrous side,
but that's actually very common
with identical twins,at where
one's where handed ones left.
Dan: Yeah,I have good friends
that are in the same,the same
situation I had,I had forgotten
about that till just now.But
yeah,it's,uh,that honestly has
frus frustrating.You have,you,
you as a,as a parent,you have
then you have to buy different
sets of everything,all at once.
um,different baseball
Bekah: uh,I'm gonna provide some
links in the show notes for
anybody else who is in the brains
of left-handers.
Dan: this is,yeah,this was an
interesting,we,we always have
these strange offshoots in the,
in
Rebecca: All about like the ink
mess on my hand,It's just
something that I've always been
cognizant of because makes such a
mess.And we talked about note
taking,believer in note taking.
This is how I do it.
Bekah: I love it though.I mean,
like,this is,uh,a lot of the
discussion about like who people
are,right?And I don't know,I
don't have these conversations
all the time.I've never had this
conversation about
left-handedness.So it's like fun
to kind of think about like,
okay,who,who are the people who
are in tech?And like,this is,
Maybe more fun than talking,more
fun for me than,than comparing
technologies.Um,I wanna circle
back just for a second,uh,
because you have a PhD
Rebecca: I do,
Bekah: we,we didn't really talk
about that that much.So your PhD
is in chemistry,right?
Rebecca: yes.I'm specifically
organic chemistry.Um,I went,went
down the chemistry path.Um,in
college,I was a biology major.At
first I changed my major to
chemistry.And um,when people ask,
it's like,okay,why are you a
chemistry major?Why did you
change?I took organic chemistry
and I accidentally liked it,So,
you know,you get these horror
stories about organic chemistry
is so hard.It's soul sucking,
it's torture.And you know,I
really started enjoying it in
spite of,um,kind of a funny story
about,um,a lab writeup I did many
years ago.Um,I remember going to
office hours and getting
frustrated and I finally got the
answer.And then I remember
telling my then,professor,I'm
never gonna work in a lab.famous
last words,Cause I,um,spent,
spent years in research in labs
and funny enough that professor
was actually my contact on my
first academic research job.So
I'm sure he laughed a lot about
my then19year old self
proclaiming.That's never gonna
happen,will
Bekah: That's funny.I,my freshman
year of college,I wanted to be a
math major,and so I wanted to
take Calc two,but they didn't
offer it.Instead they offered an
English class,which I took,and
then I ended up being an English
major and taught English for10
years after that.So it's funny,
like the way that things happen
that you don't expect.Yeah.And
now I'm in tech,so
Rebecca: For sure and um,even
when I was a lab tech,when I was
applying to graduate schools,
cuz.You can learn a lot as a lab
tech,but you also hit glass
ceilings.So I wanted to do more
work where I could do independent
work,I could own my own projects,
um,you know,write papers,you
know,a lot,have a lot more,um,
options than you could as a lab
tech.And so in spite of getting
into the life sciences program at
the medical college,I was doing
research on,I'm like,you.Organic
Chemistry was where it was at for
me.I need to go down that path.
So I went to Georgia Tech and my
first half of my PhD was building
catalysts to purify compounds
that could be active
pharmaceutical ingredients,
another type of a P I And then I
did my second half of my PhD in
total synthesis where the
compounds I was targeting had
activity against.So there was
really some neat research there.
And then once I finished at
Georgia Tech,I went to UT
Knoxville,university of
Tennessee,where I was able to,in
my postdocs,take my organic
synthesis skillset,build catalyst
to convert lignan into valuable
fuels and chemicals,where that
was the end goal with the
catalyst,um,get these valuable
fuels and chemicals to have an
alternative for,um,non-renewable
resources.You know,should they
become de.So that's,you know,
some of the work where work with
my,you know,PhD research as well
as my postdoc.
Bekah: That's fascinating.And so
you spent a lot of time,it sounds
like,doing all of this stuff and
definitely a lot of schooling,
and that's a huge investment.And
then you decided to move into
tech.Was there any part of you
when you were making that
decision that.Like sad leaving
that behind or you know,I can't
imagine it.It was an easy
decision to move over,but maybe
that's a part of the story we
don't know yet.
Rebecca: Well,some of it too,you
know,it was,you know,we were in
the height of the pandemic and
you know,even though at my time
my work was on site,cuz in
chemistry you can't really you
know,unless you're safely set up
to have the fume hood and do this
stuff at home,you don't do that
stuff at home.And I was at the
point of like,okay,well.how,what
is normal gonna look like when
the world opens up again?And I
wanted to have those options of,
of being able to use that same
problem solving skillset to be
able to do a role where I could
do anywhere.Um,so some of it was
the sign of the times.It was a
lot of it.And again,you know,
having that flexibility of,you
know,doing your work from
anywhere,you know,it provided you
do it well,you know,that time you
don't commute could be time,you
know,you find a mountain bike
trail and you know,you get a ride
in.Cuz those things were
important too.So,um,I do,you
know,look back and can be,you
know,proud of the work I've done,
the contributions I've made to
the field.Um,but you know,I've
had a good time in tech,a great
time,you know,troubleshooting.
Like I'll go through,you know,
some of my apps and you know,you
know,kinda take the same approach
as I I did in science.It's like,
okay,I gotta troubleshoot.I gotta
take one variable at a time.Um,
in tech,of course,you know,I'll
play user on my UI and going back
to taking notes,it's like,okay,
I'm gonna.Do,uh,engagement in
action,I'm gonna write down what
happens and then have that record
of,you know,where maybe something
went south and it's like,okay,
I'm gonna target this here,start
here.Cause I know this isn't
doing what I want it to do.And
then,you know,push it forward.
And,um,yeah,it's,it's not,you
know,being in,in a lab.you know,
being able to troubleshoot still
and be able to do it on that
rapid time scale,um,is something
that I really enjoy and I'm glad
I,you know,took that step.You
know,and it is a risk in a way
cuz it is different than,you
know,setting up your experiments,
but you know,to be able to still
troubleshoot and solve problems
and,you know,still even
collaborate.So it is like,you
know,in research.you know,with
collaborations,you know,plant
scientists for example,instead of
me learning how to be a plant
scientist,I go talk to a plant
scientist.We talk about some
problems that we may need to
solve for the project and they
can,they've got the
infrastructure to set up those
experiments.Whereas I would have
a lab accessible where we had,
you know,stuff setting up to do
synthetic organic chemistry.It's
less time for me to set up what I
need to set up.I have the
know-how and the AC and the
instruments and.Um,other setup to
get those things done.And even in
software and Virtual Coffee,even
specifically,I have an idea of
like,okay,I don't do ruby gun
rails.I know Meg does.I know
people who do view type script.
Dan being one of those people,
you know,content creation,Bekah,
you.You do this every day,um,you
know,you,you know who you can
reach out to that can give you
insight on things that you need
to know,but you don't need to
spend day-to-day doing.So still,
I'm still getting all those
goodies that I got,you know,
working in a research lab.
Bekah: I think that's such a
great mindset,and I think there
are a lot of people out there
that think that you have to do it
all and you definitely don't.
It's,it's knowing who you can
talk to about doing those things
and utilizing them when you need
to.That really makes you strong
at what you do.That's,that's
really.
Dan: Yeah,especially as,excuse
me,especially as an independent,
um,developer,you know,it is such
a strong and important skill to
have in your clients,so I think
we would appreciate it too.You
know,not have.Like the exact same
thing,right?Like,oh no,like I
have to do this thing that I know
nothing about.Do I want the,do I
want the client to pay me for
like two weeks to learn a new
thing?Or,you know,an hour of
somebody else's time that already
knows it,right?The same,same
thing.It's,it's,it's so cool.
Bekah: So I,I do have just two
more questions for you.And the
first one is you.Got this really
great journey that you've gone
on.Uh,you've learned all of these
things.What is one word to
describe your career journey?
Rebecca: I'd say dynamic,um,
hands down.Um,it constantly
changed whether I was seeking
those changes or they.you know,
presented themselves in this.
Like I was keeping an open mind,
like,okay,this is the better fit
for me right now and um,I'll use
it again.You know,I accidentally
liked organic chemistry.I went
down that path in science,and
then when I switched over to
tech,I thought the data science
was gonna be my jam.And,you know,
I don't close the doors on
anything.But,you know,having that
skillset in science to be able to
visually,you know,tell stories
with data,you know,I'm like,
that's,that's me.That's,that's
written about me.But you know,I
ended up getting really
acquainted with the front end
and,you know,being a visual
learner,that actually looking
back makes a lot of sense.And
I've been.You know,more front
end,heavy,more react heavy that
way.And then I've also learned a
little bit more on the back end,
um,circling back after a little
bit from the initial Python and R
with data science.So yeah,it's,
um,I'd say dynamic.It's
constantly changing.It's gonna
change from this point forward.
And keeping an open mind has
always,you know,been beneficial
cuz you just never know what you
might be a good fit for to given
time and.
Bekah: that's exactly what I was
gonna say.What is strength that
you have in that openness to
consider other things that might
not seem like the natural path,
cuz that can be really hard to
do.And my last question for you
is,what is one word that
describes you?
Rebecca: I'm gonna go with the
word consistent.So,um,I would say
I am a,what you see is what you
get kind of person
personality-wise.I would've told
you that years ago.And,you know,
in spite of,you know,the learning
experiences,the things you know,
That we grow from.I would say
that the Rebecca you're talking
to now was the same Rebecca you
would've met in high school,more
or less.And then as far as
staying consistent on,you know,
goals or projects that matter to
me from anywhere of,you know,
videotaping myself for three
months,doing cheers and jumps and
handsprings so I could finally
make my squad success,I did,I did
that three months straight to,
um,you know,see myself to train
and see what I needed to do,um,
to,you know,present day.Been
consistently working on coding
and you know,even though you may
not see this big significant
change in a day,
Bekah: Hmm.
Rebecca: consistent has
consistently served me well.So,
um,I definitely say I'm,I'm
consistent.If I can keep,you
know,keep at something,sometimes
it happens,you know,rapidly.
Sometimes you wish it would
happen faster,but that
consistency has always been
something that,that,again has
served me well.
Bekah: This is great.Well,thank
you so much for being here with
us today and talking through all
of this,your interesting journey
and giving us,I think,a lot of
insight into what you're doing.
And your approach to me is
something that I'm gonna go back
and reflect on because I think
that there are so many strengths
that you have there and ways that
I would like to grow in my own
journey.So I really appreciate
you.
Rebecca: Absolutely,and thank you
both again for having me.This was
a fun conversation.
Dan: Yeah.Thank you Rebecca.Uh,
alright,we will talk to you soon.
Rebecca: All right,I'll see you
then.
Dan: Bye.
Rebecca: Hi.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel.If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO,or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.You can
find the show notes,sign up for
the newsletter,check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io.If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!