Bekah: hello and welcome to
season seven,episode six of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I'm Bekah,
and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey,and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned,
and we are here to share it with
you.Here with me today is my
co-host.
Dan: What up,Bek?How's it going?
Bekah: Hey,it's going okay.
Dan: Going all right today.
Bekah: Just,just,all right.
Dan: Just chilling.
Bekah: Yep.
Dan: Um,well,glad to hear it.Uh,
yeah.Um,today we are speaking
with Arthur Doler,who has,uh,
been a Virtual Coffee member for
a while and he's been a software
engineer for a long time.Uh,
well,let's see,his bio says19
years,so that's,that's a pretty
long time.Um,and he's worked on a
bunch of different things over
his career and he's also gotten
into,um,mental health advocacy,
during his career.So,uh,
especially related to tech stuff,
I think,um,although maybe not
exclusively tech related mental
health stuff,but,um,he's done a
lot of blog posts and talks about
mental health,uh,over the last
few years.It's,it's been really
cool.It's one of the things that
caught my eye about Arthur when
he joined the community,uh,
joined Virtual Coffee was his
work and his thoughts in that
area.Uh,and we talked about a
lot,uh,in it was.
Bekah: Yeah,I actually got the
chance to meet Arthur last year
to one of his talks that we've
included in the show notes about
burnout.And one of the things
that I love about Arthur and
talking to him is I will always
learn something in those
conversations.He'll teach me
something about mental health and
I,it's from a perspective that I
might not have known had I not
had that conversation or heard
what he said,and I know.Now that
as I'm kind of transitioning and
looking for a new job,I've taken
a lot of what he's taught me in
that talk about burnout and kind
of applied it to the process that
I'm going through right now.And
so it,it's great to be able to
talk a little bit about that,
but,um,about a lot of different
aspects of mental health in this
episode today.
Dan: Yeah,totally.And we,we
talked a lot about,um,we also got
into the idea of the,the human
sort of network that is a
company,right?And,and how a,a
company or a,a team or whatever
isn't just.Some sort of plug and
play thing.And it's not just a
machine,right?It's a bunch of
people and they all work
differently.Managers work
differently,uh,contributors work
differently,and it all has to
work together somehow.Right.And,
um,so we,we talked a lot about
some,some of that,uh,the mental
health,uh,vis-a-vis management
and,and how it's sometimes hard
to forget when you're having an
issue with somebody that,that
they have all these feelings and,
and motivations and,uh,
everything too.And usually it's
very easy to like villainize
somebody,who you're having issues
with.And,um,how that's not always
the most helpful,helpful thing in
the world.although it can feel
good,you know,in the moment when
you're doing some bending,but,
uh,to actually move forward,
right?There's,there's like needs
that connection and the empathy
between,between two.as opposed to
just manager and reportee,you
know?Um,so
Bekah: Yeah.Yeah.That of
motivation is.Arthur had some new
takes on it that I hadn't heard,
that I know that actually I was
like just looking at my,my
reading list of books that I want
to read in the next couple weeks.
And there were a couple of them I
think that he mentioned that I
have on there too.And so,uh,
hopefully you'll find some
resources here.You'll find some
new ideas,exploring motivation,
exploring mental health and all
of the things that we talked
about that maybe can be applied
to your.
Dan: Totally.
Bekah: So we start every episode
of the podcast,like we start
every Virtual Coffee.We introduce
ourselves with our name,where
we're from,what we do,and a
random check-in question.We hope
you enjoy this episode.Today's
random question is,what is your
favorite hobby?We hope you enjoy
this episode.Hi,my name is Bekah.
I am a technical community
builder from a small town in
Ohio,and this is an easy one at
weightlifting is my favorite
hobby.I don't really have any
other hobbies besides raising
children and gardening badly,so
that was easy.
Dan: Gardening badly.Uh,you could
be bad at something and still
have it be your favorite,you
know,but it's probably easier
when you're good at something to
have it be your favorite.So
that's cool.Um,yeah.I'm Dan.I
live in Cleveland.It was like63
here yesterday,and today it is
like38in raining.So that's
Cleveland life for you?Uh,yeah.
Well,it might be coming,I don't
know.
Bekah: It is Friday.It's gonna be
cold.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.Yeah.And,uh,
favorite hobby?Oh,my favorite
hobby is disc golf.So that's golf
played with,uh,you know,flying
discs or Frisbees if you want to
use the brand name.And,uh,yeah,
I've been,I got into it in
college and,uh,playing,playing a
lot since then.So,just played36
holes on,um,Last Friday.So it's
good stuff.Keeps me in the woods
pretty soon.Uh,I got Ollie,
here's,is he here in the
recording studio with me So
pretty soon he's gonna come,
start coming with me too.I'm
excited about that.I was looking
into
Bekah: I was just gonna say for,
for context,Ollie is Dan's dog.
Dan: Yeah,yeah,yeah.And I was,
well,I was about to,I was about
to clue that in because I was
looking at disc golf bags for
dogs,so I can have him just carry
all of my stuff around you know,
and it,it would be perfect.So,
uh,I'm,that's the dream really.
That's,I'm excited about that.
Arthur: All right.Uh,hi.My name's
Arthur Doer or Art.Um,I'm from
Omaha,Nebraska,where it is cold
and snowing right now,so you're
gonna get it probably in a couple
days.Um,and I'm a senior software
engineer and,uh,community and
culture steward is,I think what
we're calling the other half of
my title.my favorite hobby is
actually,I don't know if it
counts as a hobby,but public
speaking,it's more of a lifestyle
I guess.But,um,it's definitely
the thing that takes up a ton of
my time,that is not my job.So
Dan: I'd say if you,yeah,if
you're not getting paid for it or
maybe even if you are getting
paid for it,I don't know.I guess,
yeah,if you're just doing it by
choice,then it,then it,we can
call it a hobby,right?
Arthur: how often do you have to
get paid before it becomes a side
gig?Like,
Dan: yeah.That's the,yeah,that's
always the problem.Uh,you know,
it is,uh,Sometimes when you're
good at a hobby and it can,you
know it's possible to get paid
for it,you know,it becomes tempt
tempting to follow that down.So
just like this,golf,I almost went
pro and then,uh,no,I'm just
kidding.I was,I was never good
enough.
Bekah: Is there pro disc golf?
Dan: Yeah,big time.Like million
dollar contract.Pro,pro.This
golf.Yeah,it's on ESPN and all
that stuff now too.So yeah,it's
the same with.
Arthur: like,
Dan: Well,sure,sure,sure.Yeah.I
mean,this is like,this is the
same with lots of sports where
there's companies that want you
to buy their products and so they
start sponsoring people that are
really good at it.And that's,you
know,that's,that's how it goes.
And so you,and,and of course the
sponsors,they,you know,they can
only use those ones,uh,and they
still win tournaments.And so
you're like,well,I should buy
that company's,you know,discs or
shoes or whatever.is a baseball
hat will make me better at disc
golf.I'm sure
Bekah: For sure.I'm a
professional weightlifter,so
Dan: Oh,nice.
Bekah: Yeah.Not really I'm just
manifesting it.I think that's how
that works.You say it and then
people make you it.So next week,
watch out.
Arthur: sponsorship's rolling in.
Dan: the,the thing to watch out
for there,right,is like,oh,you
start going to a gym and like,
oh,like,oh,I'll teach a class,
you know,here and there,
whatever.And then like you teach
'em more and more classes and
then,you know,pretty soon
somebody's like,wanna hire you
full-time.And then it becomes a
job and then it's no fun anymore.
Bekah: I just,I just want them to
give me workout gear,like,here's
a pair of new leggings.Sweet.
Arthur: Exercise influencer.
Bekah: I know.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: Yep.maybe that,um,welcome
Arthur.It is good to have you
here on the podcast.We always
like to get started with your
origin story,and we're gonna
start by asking you what is one
word that describes your career
journey?
Arthur: Uh,I think my word is
gonna be concentric,um,in that
I've started.I went to school for
computer engineering and then
rapidly realized that that was a
thing that,um,you know,you went
to a couple,couple different
companies,like one of a couple
companies,and then they burned
you out and then you moved on to
other stuff.But,um,The story of
my career has been kind of ever
expanding circles of kind of what
I care about,where it's moved
from,caring about the technology
to,okay,let's care about the
architecture.Okay,let's care
about like the process that we're
doing to now.It's very about the
humans,um,that either the humans
that we're writing the software
for,or the humans who are writing
the software,or the humans who
are affected by the software.So,
Bekah: I really love that.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: So how did that,so I,I
like the different concentric
circles and almost,I imagine
there's some kind of journey
behind each of those different
circles and how they're kind of
related to each other.So do you
wanna talk a little bit about
maybe I,however you wanna tell
your story of your tech journey.
Um,but if there are highlight
moments that you think were
really pivotal there,I'd love to
hear.
Arthur: Sure.Um,I mean,really
it's,it's a,it's a story of
getting frustrated a bunch,uh,
and just going like,well,there
has to be a better way to do
this.Like,um,I mean,it started
out in a,um,I went to a small
technical college in Terre Haute,
Indiana,um,and paid a lot of
money to learn the lesson that I
am not the smartest person on the
planet,which is a very valuable
lesson to learn.Uh,and then kind
of fell back afterwards into a
job,um,doing JSPs.Uh,cuz that
was,that was the style at the
time.Um,and.
Dan: can you,can you,what are,
what are JSPs?
Arthur: Uh,Java server,it pages.
So back in the bad old days of
the internet,um,it was,you know,
we didn't have your fancy reacts
or anything.It was all like
server driven,you know,server
side stuff.So it was,okay,well
we're gonna write these webpages
in Java.Cool.Um,
Dan: sounds great.
Arthur: Fantastic.Uh,so I mean,
again,there's like,yeah,there has
to be a better way to do this.
What are we doing with our,what
am I doing with my life?just been
a lot of being frustrated about,
um,the technology that I work
with,the way that we're building
it and kind of realizing,oh,
okay,well this situation gets a
little better if I can affect
something downstream.Like,or
upstream rather,like,okay,so if
I'm frustrated about,oh,well I'm,
I'm being asked to code something
and I wanna make it great.Okay,
that's easy.And then,I mean,it's
not easy,sorry,but it's a,it's a
simpler problem.And then,
Realized that I'm being asked to
code something that is stupid.
Why am I being asked to code
something that is stupid?Well,
that's what the requirements say,
and it's like,okay,so let's move
into that and think about why am
I being asked to code something
that is stupid,that I think is
stupid?Does this make sense in a
context?What is the user
thinking?And kind of expanding my
scope in that regard.And then
starting to realize,well,these
pro,like now we're trying to.
Learning these things that make
sense about the users and about
what they want,but.You know,we
keep running up in crunch.We keep
winding up with a deadline
overrun.So let's think about the
process and how are we building
these things.And kind of parallel
to all of that has been my
personal journey of trying to
understand what the hell is
happening inside of my head.Um,
which is a thing that I've been,
I mean,it's a lifelong struggle,
but it's been something I've been
actively working on since I was
15.Um,And so there's been a lot
of research into,okay,I mean,
it's like any good therapist or
psychologist starts out as just
like,well,why am I screwed up?
Let's figure that out.Clearly
somebody has understood this and
there must be a book out there
that will perfectly describe why
I do the dumb things I do and how
to not do those things,and then
you rapidly realize that that
isn't true.But there's a whole
bunch of other interesting things
that people have learned.Um,so I
vanished down that rabbit hole,
um,about at the same time I took
a job.um,drove me back into
therapy.Um,cause I was,you know,
went through the whole therapy
gamut and diagnoses when I was in
middle school and high school and
then,uh,kind of fell out of it in
college.Um,stopped taking my meds
cuz that's what you do in college
is do dumb things.Um,and yeah,I
mean,it's a perfect time for it.
But,um,so this job I was in my,
my late twenties.No,that would've
been early thirties cause that
would've been2011ish.Um,and just,
it was a nightmare job.Um,for a
bunch of different reasons.
Things like,we released too fast
for the support team of the
company.Um,so they refused to
support our products.So all of
our customers called our BA
directly and then she would
immediately wind up on,like,
standing on our desks for things.
It was exciting.Um,and it was
all,um,it was election related
stuff,so.Just ratchet all the
stress three notches higher on
all of it.
Dan: Yeah.
Arthur: Um,I kind of found myself
at a,on the phone with somebody
from,I think it was Hamilton
County,Ohio,actually from their
election board.Um,I mean,in the
median age of somebody that works
at an election commission
anywhere is like80.So I'm on the
phone with this guy attempting to
teach him how to copy paste over
the phone.And it was just like
one of those moments you see in a
movie where it's.From office
space or whatever,it's just like,
what am I doing,Um,so I mean,
about that time I was starting to
dig into some stuff like,uh,
Daniel Pink's Drive was one of my
gateway drugs to really getting
into,um,What is effectively pop
psych,um,you know,popular
psychology books and starting to
understand a lot more about
organizational psychology and
behavioral economics and
cognitive psychology and,you
know,chasing down a bunch of
rabbit holes there.And it was not
that much later,um,a couple years
into a new job and I realized
that I started wanting to get
into public speaking and.Was
like,okay,well let's figure out,
you know,I started doing,um,uh,
we do lightning talks at work and
we used to do'em every week.We do
'em every other week now.But it
was a,um,forced myself to give a
lightning talk every week and
rapidly ran out of technical
things that I wanted to talk
about,and then decided I was
gonna start talking about
cognitive biases at work and
went,wow,this is a lot more fun
and exciting Um,and that was,
that was2016.And.Started speaking
at conferences and have been
doing that and my making my focus
a lot more about the humans of
software since then of,okay,how
do we get people to build these
things?Understanding that there
are systemic forces that are
driving this instead of looking
at individuals as the problem or
even looking at teams as the
problem.and trying to understand
that there,this is stuff we've
been learning about since the
fifties for Christ's sake in some
cases.Um,it's one of the most
frustrating things about some of
the talks I do is I go back and
look at the resources and like
studies and it's like,well,we
knew about it in the seventies
and we're still,we're still
screwing this up now so.
Dan: an example of is there is an
example that pops in your mind of
one of those things?
Arthur: I mean,one of the basics
would be from Daniel Pink's
drive.Like the,the study research
about intrinsic versus extrinsic
motivations has been around since
the seventies,easily,like as a
known fact.And,um,the difference
there is,is an intrinsic
motivation is something that is
internal to the person.So,a,if
you work out,for instance,like
Bekah does,one of the values that
you like,the benefits that you
get out of it is in the doing of
the.right?The benefit comes from
the act as opposed to an
extrinsic motivation,which is
like paying your kid$5to,uh,take
out the guard.It is a motivation,
a r a,uh,impulse that,or rather
impetus,rather that is external
to the thing.So without digging
too much into the book and kind
of restating his entire thesis,
um,intrinsic motivation is a lot
more sticky.Um,extrinsic
motivation.You,you get what,uh,
some people call the hedonistic
treadmill,um,or hedonistic
acclimation,where after a while
the level of reward you get stops
being effective.Eventually your
kid's gonna want10bucks to take
out the garbage.Um,but even
without that,it.You can never,I
mean,I don't have kids,but I've
talked to people who do,once you
pay them to do the chores,it's,
you're never gonna not have to
pay them to do the chores again.
Uh,it's really one of the big
lessons of that is that extrinsic
motivators actually kill
intrinsic motivation.You will be
less intrinsically motivated
after I've,you've applied an
extrinsic motivator,but extrinsic
motivators are easy and.it's easy
for a manager to go,well,we're
just gonna have a thing.And the
people personally fixes the most
bugs,gets an Xbox.I mean,most
managers have moved past that
point,but there are still a lot
of extrinsic motivation about,
um,you know,even things like
velocity.Are you meeting your
velocity?That's an extrinsic
motivator,not an intrinsic
motivator to the task itself.
Bekah: That's really fascinating.
I actually hadn't really thought
about it like that.Now I need to
go listen to that book,so that's
gonna be on my list.But I,I think
that the idea of extrinsic
motivation,I've been thinking a
lot about company.Culture what?
How to determine if a company has
a good culture.We see a lot of
people at Virtual Coffee that
interview for roles that seem
great,and then they get there and
the company culture is not great.
And oftentimes a lot of the
things that we see is,um,there
are those extrinsic.Motivators,
right?Like,we pay a great salary,
we have unlimited paid time off.
We give you a budget for food,we
give you a budget for the gym or
whatever.And in a lot of ways,I
think that companies are trying
to use,they use extrinsic
motivators to kind of lure you in
and make you feel like there's a
good culture there.But maybe that
what,what.Makes a good culture is
finding ways to cultivate that
intrinsic motivation.Or at the
very least,getting to know your
employees and figuring out how to
utilize their strengths and allow
them to fulfill the things that
they're good at doing.
Arthur: or what they want to do.
Right?I mean,if,if I have a.You
know,we have a,I don't wanna say
we at the company,but like in,
I've seen cases where folks are
feel frustrated or angry because
they care a lot about something
and they're not being allowed to
do it.They care a lot about
quality,they care a lot about the
process and the way that this
thing works.And then the company
is not allowing them to go be in
DevOps or in,you know,or shaping
things so that they have a role
to play where they can bring
those desires to bear.And that's
a loss on both sides because now
one person's frustrated and then
the company's not seeing a
benefit out of it.With that they
could be,um,yeah,it's what I mean
by like the extrinsic motivators
are easy.Right.It's one of my
fun,I mean,it's not my favorite
hobby,but it's a fun hobby is if
you go to another company and
they've got like a break room or
whatever,a foosball table,like
just.Is the table dusty?Like is
anybody actually using it?Um,
like,you know,we have one at our
company and you know,people use
it cuz it's like the Foosballs
people are sometimes broken and
there's like pieces and repair
parts around the,the room.Um,you
know,we have a dart board and a,
a ping pong table and there's
like just,you open a drawer
somewhere and it's like just full
of ping pong balls cuz people
actually use them and they're,
um,various bits and pieces need
repaired.So that's,but it's,
it's,is there a question?They
have these extrinsic motivators,
like you mentioned,uh,unlimited
pto the culture set so that you
can actually take it.Is there an
expectation that that will
happen?I mean,unlimited PTO can
be a trap where suddenly it's,
oh,I'm gonna take this PTO that I
think I'm allowed to.But there's
a company culture where you
actually can take way less PTO
than you would have if it was
yours.Right.
Bekah: Yeah.I've seen a lot more
job descriptions out there saying
unlimited paid,uh,paid time off.
But mandatory two weeks off or
something like that to indicate
that we have this,but we are
going to force you to take off
two weeks.And even at my company,
we have unlimited P T O,but we
also have company-wide days off
that are usually,you know,some
type of holiday that we.um,em
embrace as a company,right?And so
at the very least,uh,those days,
everybody will get off.And that
doesn't,that doesn't happen
everywhere anymore either.I'm
really,it amazes me that there
are companies out there that say,
Hey,you get two or three weeks
off during the year.If you wanna
use'em on those days,use'em on
those days.But we're not taking
company wide holidays,which is
kind of mind.
Arthur: I find that for a lot of
cases to be,um,I mean that's
where,where I work does that,
it's easier from an
administrative standpoint.It's
also,it can be more flexible for
a diverse workplace.Um,
especially when,you know,a lot of
major holidays in the US are
religious to an extent,um,or at
least some of the,you know,the
huge ones.And so it's a question
of,okay,well how do you,how do
you accommodate things like
Ramadan at your workplace?Um,so
it can be a way to do that,but a
lot of cases it's not,it's just
an,you know,it's a little easier
to be an accounting,uh,to manage
it from an accounting
perspective.And then it's a
question,like you said,it's,am I
gonna work that day?Well,I
should.Okay.I guess I'm gonna,
you know,maybe I'll work remote
now after the pandemic,but I'm
still,you know,gonna clock the
hours.
Bekah: Yeah.And all of those
things are super tricky,
especially in the remote world
where it's almost like work
doesn't ever turn off.Especially
if you're working on a team that
has people in lots of different
time zones or you know,if they're
a global organization,then
somebody is always working.And I
know,like,at least from my
perspective,I have a hard time
turning work off,you know?Slack
or email on my phone frequently.
And sometimes I'll delete them
and then it's like,well,I'm
traveling so I need to ha have
access to this somehow and it
gets back on my phone.But,but
there's this,I think that tech
can be really hard right now in
the fact that it's,it can be very
hard to turn off because of the
continued,somebody is always
working right.
Arthur: Mm-hmm.Well,and some
people like it,like I have
coworkers.I way more time than I
would ever want to spend.But to
them,it's not a question of,
being unsustainable.That's just
the pace that they like and the
way that they like to work.And
you get,you can get trapped,kind
of holding yourself up to a
standard for somebody else that
doesn't meet your,your lifestyle.
Uh,but you can also get trapped
by,I mean,I talked about kind of
my journey concentric,right?Um,
as you.Okay,so let's start with
the thesis.Um,that tech is
actually creative work.
Bekah: Hmm.
Arthur: really engineering work.
Um,I know that's a huge bombshell
for argument,but.Tech is in,a lot
of tech is not.We're doing the
same thing over and over.It is,
we're kind of doing the same
thing,but these things are
different and it's weirdly
innovative and new in this way,
and this situation is different.
The user wants this piece
slightly different this time.So
there's a bunch of novelty every
time.And that novelty means that
we have to be creative.And the
thing about creative work is
that,I mean,you can go ask the UX
folks at your work.I mean,if
they'd been through like a.
Curriculum.Right?Um,they learn
fairly quickly that there is no
turning that off.Uh,there is no
moment where your brain won't tap
you on the shoulder and be like,
Hey,that thing you thought you
were,you know,you were thinking
about.Uh,yeah.We have the answer
to that now.if you can't,I mean,
trust me,if we could turn the
brain off,it would be,life would
be a lot easier on a number of
fronts,but
Dan: True.
Arthur: if,if you know you since
you can't turn it off,how do you
navigate that balance between,
or,or find a balance between,um,
hey,this is when my brain decides
that it would be productive for
me to work,versus how do I
maintain that balance,you know,
that,that the distance between me
and the actual job so that the
job doesn't flow backward into my
life and define me.And that's,
um,I mean,there's no simple
answer to that.
Bekah: Yeah,if there is,let me
know cuz I
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: been working on that.
Dan: I love that framing though.
The,the job floating,floating
back.Wait,how did you say it?I'm
sorry.Cuz it was
Arthur: Yeah.The job flowing
backward into your life.
Dan: flowing backward into your
life.Yeah,that was,I,I I love
that.Um,just that framing of that
whole problem.It,it's such a,
that's a really nice metaphor.
I'm,I'm a collector of metaphors
and I,I like that one.Uh,and it's
a problem in it,and it's like a
great way to frame it,right?
Because you,you know,you,you have
a job and.Obsessively need to get
work done and all that stuff.But
you don't want your job
necessarily to be defining
things.And I think we talk about
it or defining things in your
life,you know,and I think we talk
about it in different ways.
Work-life balance is like a
phrase that gets thrown around a
lot.All all that stuff.But that
idea of that flow,you know,and,
and having your decisions,like
what is driving your.Decision
making in your life,uh,is,I mean,
that's obviously,like you said,
that's a big problem and,and not
an easy answer,but,um,I think
that framing is,is really useful
and I,I like that idea,
Arthur: Well,and it's easy things
to be like.It's an easy thing to
say,Hey,we pro,we strive to
promote a good work-life balance
here.Um,and then you get into the
thick of it.Like,I mean,like
Bekah was talking about companies
that promote that.As,you know,
here we,you know,we love to
balance work and play or
whatever,and I mean,sometimes
that's a huge red flag.Um,
Especially like the phrase,work
hard,play hard,like that one's a
huge red flag.Um,
Dan: Nope,Nope.
Arthur: but.It's easy to say
that.And then what you see in
practice is a series of
exceptions where it's,oh,well,
just this once,okay,just this
time,well,this thing's happening
and I need to get this done.And
th and tho it's a death of a
thousand cuts where,um,that those
exceptions become the norm and
they define the norm.And if you
don't have cultural.Guardrails
around that at a corporate level,
at a team level.Cuz it can't just
be corporate.It has to actually
be at the team levels as well.
Cause it's easy,again,to say at
the corporate level,well,don't do
this in your teams.And then the
manager,you know,it happens and
the manager gets a slap on the
wrist and says,don't do that with
your teams.And meanwhile their
team is burnt out and chattered.
Um,so it,it's,you can't just,
especially,you know,if you're.I
know through in Virtual Coffee
you have a lot of folks that are
breaking into dev,into,into being
devs.You don't have a ton of
power there.Um,especially since
there is a,there's often a high
supply of new devs,right?It is a
career that does pay a lot.Um,it
has a lot of upward mobility.It
has a bunch of cool benefits.
Like you get to work with code,
you get to work with really cool
problems.Uh,it is a desirable
career,so the supply of new devs
can often.You know,large,and that
means that you have less
leverage.So,you know,as a junior
dev,it's really hard to be like,
no,I'm gonna go do disc golf
tomorrow and not show up at work.
Like,you can't,how,how do you
have that discussion with your
manager when your manager is
like,but the client is,you know,
having this,you know,there's a
hair fire and you have to deal
with it and you're the only one
that can handle it.Um,so as some
of that has to be at that level
of the manager doing,Um,that
guidance,but it can't,again,it
can't just be the manager either.
It has,that actually has to exist
almost like fractally at each
level of the organization where
everybody is working to protect
that because everybody benefits
from it.
Dan: My,my wife at her last job
had a bad culture like that,you
know,the,the,like,the bad example
of this.And she was a manager,
you know,in her own right and she
felt very strongly ab,you know,
in favor of protecting her,you
know.You know,her direct reports
and things like that.But it's
exactly what you're saying
happened,you know,is that she
would protect the people that
reported to her,but nobody was
protecting her.And,and so she got
burned out.Honestly,she got
burned out.Her man,her,her
reportees were like,loved her and
was like,you're the best manager
ever.And she's like,I'm getting
out of here You know,like right
now,cuz uh,is is the same thing
cuz it was a,it was a cultural
thing.It went way.to the top,you
know?Um,so I,I was wondering,you
know,listening to you talk and,
and,um,with the amount of like,
thought you've put into this,uh,
do you have any advice for people
who find themselves especially,
especially,uh,lower,you know,uh,
newer devs,do you have any advice
for people who find themselves in
those situations?Um,where they
are,they don't have a lot of
power.They don't have a lot of,
you know,they can't like throw
their weight around but are being
asked to.maybe do things that
they are,that are outside of
where they would like their
boundaries to be.Um,you know,
like is there any actual advice
aside from finding a new job?Uh,
which is a fine piece of advice,
honestly,that I've given before,
but not,you know,not always,uh,
possible So,
Arthur: I mean,it's a,I often,I
have a toll talk on burnout that
I talk about,and it's like one of
the options for burnout is find a
new job.But not everybody can do
that for a lot of different
reasons.Um,
Dan: it,it could take a long time
too,so you could still be stuck.
Yeah.
Arthur: So my best advice in
those cases is kind of to,I tend
to think of it in terms of almost
Aikido.Um,Which is,if you're not
familiar,it's a martial arts
style that is very focused on,
um,as they would frame it,like
redirection of energy.And what
they mean by that is typically
that in Aikido it is entirely
defensive.Um,and you are
typically taking somebody,
throwing a punch at you,somebody
throwing a kick at you,and you.
Blocking,but taking that energy
and re taking their motion,their
momentum,their actual velocity,
and redirecting it in a direction
that you want,um,you can use
those moments to kind of do the
same thing to haggle in the
moment about,okay,if we're gonna
do this,then we need something
else.Like,what can you give me in
that moment?Right?Because in
those moments,you do have a
little more power of.They want
this exception,they want this
thing.You can turn around and
say,you know,accept that thing
and try and in the,you know,the
best terms of improv.Yes.And it,
right.Um,where you're giving them
what they want and then trying to
go,okay,but I would like comp
time tomorrow for this.Or,can you
give me off Friday so that I can
go to this appointment?if you're
not making a ton of leverage,
they're trying to,I mean,not to,
um,immediately politicize it,but
trying to almost unionize to some
degree of,can you as a team
define your working structure as
a uh,individual?Can you find
other people who agree with you
about,Hey,we don't want to do X,
we don't want to do Y.And try and
make that the norm inside of your
team itself.Um,And the key thing
here is you don't wanna try,I
mean,you don't wanna alienate the
manager,right?Because if you
start doing that,then you wind up
in a situation where you've
immediately created an US versus
then situation.And once you do
that,there's a whole bunch of
human psychology that starts
coming into play where it's so
much easier to demonize the other
person to,uh,believe that they
are,you know,that their actions
are due to innate,um,attributes.
Uh,there's this thing called the,
well,in this case it would be the
ultimate attribution error where,
um,We have what's called in
groups and outgroups,where an
in-group is a group you're part
of,and an OUTGROUP is a group
that you're not part of.Um,we
tend to believe that our
outgroups,you know,groups that
we're not part of,they behave
certain ways because of innate
attributes of those groups.Um,so
as an example,like qa,people are
all extremely persnickety and
uptight,right?Or,you know,for the
opposite way,devs are completely
loose and utterly lazy and have
no,you know,rigor or,uh,
coherence to their work.Right.
Dan: Right.
Arthur: neither true,but it's
easy when you're on the other
side of it looking in and it's,
it's a shortcut your brain takes
basically to go,okay,we can think
about people in this way.Um,So
alienating your manager and you
want to kind of pull them in and
be like,okay,you're part of the
team.We are together on this.We
all want to succeed.Um,which is
true to an extent in that you
have a shared goal,um,with,you
know,the rest of your team.You,I
at least hopefully all want to
deliver good software.Right.And I
mean,if you don't,then you're in
a harder position where now you
have to try and find something
that does unify you,um,with this
manager,et cetera.I mean,in the
cases where you can't make any
inroads and you can't,you know,
they're completely,uh,othering
you,as in they're gonna manage at
you and they don't consider
themselves part of the team.
Those are harder situations,and
those are the ones where I would
start going.Maybe you can try and
find a lateral move in the
company.Maybe you can try and,
you know,um,yeah.
Dan: Yeah,no,there,there is.I
mean,there definitely are just
situations where the manager is
either unaware of those issues
and,you know,or,or,or knows about
'em and doesn't care.right?Like,
you know,they're feeling pressure
from above somehow.And,you know,
uh,they deal with it in,in
different ways,obviously.
Arthur: Well,I mean,they can
Dan: times where there's,where
there's no solution really with
Arthur: they can be burned out
Dan: a manager.Right?Exactly.
Yeah.And like lots of people,I
think,experience burnout in
different ways.And react,react,
reacted to burnout in different
ways.Um,or just even pre burnout,
you know,like,uh,stress you know,
people react to,uh,all sorts of
inputs in different ways.So,um
Arthur: once you're at a manager
level,um,there's all kinds of
internal status things that start
pinging in your head about,you
know,uh,human group dynamic stuff
that starts caring about like,
oh,I have a certain amount of
status in this group,in this,in
this workplace,and.This is where
like if you're,this is where the
Aikido thing comes in.Cuz if you
start immediately coming against
them,they start responding.And
this is a challenge to their
authority.
Dan: Mm-hmm.
Arthur: not necessarily because
they're bad people,right?Uh,this
is just a natural human thing to,
especially if you're doing it in
public,in meetings,their brain,
like,you know,the monkey brain
starts screaming,just going like,
duh,what do you do?Like,you've
gotta stand up for yourself.
You've gotta demonstrate that you
are in charge.Um,and I mean,
that's something they can combat
and should be working to combat,
right?But,uh,it is definitely a
human response to respond that
way or to feel those emotions in
that moment.Uh,and so what if you
can help them through that?Uh,
that makes it a little easier to
have those negotiations,to have
those discuss.
Dan: Yeah.Right.Uh,yeah,if,if you
can like align on the goals,like
you said,everybody want on the
team wants to make a good product
or whatever,right?And so keeping
that goal,Mind,you know,um,seems
like a way to work together,to,
to get things done right.Uh,and
like there's,there's deadlines,
there's,you know,always,oh,
probably lots of times.Too much
work for everybody.And,you know,
um,just kind of remembering,I
think you said remember that the
other person has like emotions
and has,you know,their own,their
own things going on.Uh,I think
we'll take you a long way.Um,I
try to use that,that sort of
empathy in all,all these kinds of
situations,but that.Um,you know,
human thinking,like remembering
the people on the other end of
anything is,are people right?And
have their own have their own.
Uh,Hey Bekah,you okay?You just
smacked your microphone there,
Bekah: Sorry,trying to come back
quiet.
Dan: yeah,yeah.You know,you
failed at that one.Um,but what I
was saying was,um,remembering
that people have their own
motivations and trying to figure
out what they are,you know,uh,
it,I mean,it can help you in a
lot of ways.I think people have
talked about that with winning.
Winning haggling situations,but
like it can help you and just not
in that and not in devious ways,
but like understanding where
people are coming from,um,I think
can help you get what you want
and also what they want together,
Right.That's,
Arthur: Well,that's exactly it.
Dan: that's the ideal,
Arthur: We often approach
conflict as a,um,uh,what ar shown
term model one,um,which is a,it
is an,a combative,uh,zero sum
game where you are working to
control the emotions of the other
participant.Um,where you are,if
you win,they lose and vice versa.
And if we look at conflict in
that lens,y.I mean,it's possible,
but you're in for a hard fight
right now.You've gotta bat
somebody down.If you're a
manager,you're trying to do
things like,uh,have quick
conversations so that you are
the,there's no time for the
emotion.It's like,well,here's
your performance review and this
is,and here's the things that you
can do to improve.And then the,
and the meeting's over and the
person's still like sitting there
processing their own emotions.
Um,but you win because you don't
have to have the hard
conversation or,you know,see
them.And emotionally respond to
any of it.Um,and the alternative
to model one is model two,which
is,I mean,they're not great at
naming things,but,um,it is a,a
collaborative win-win approach
where you are recognizing that
conflict is,is inherently
emotional,that humans are
inherently emotional and you're
respecting and acknowledging the
emotions of others,including
yourself.and attempting to find a
situation that benefits all
parties to a,you know,it's
stereotypical,but to find those
win-win situations.
Dan: Yeah,absolutely.Go ahead.
Bekah: was just gonna say,like,
I,I think as part of that,it's
really important to understand
how people communicate,right?
Like for me,I,my emotions go from
zero to a hundred in like a split
second,right?And so if there's a
situation that I know is going to
be an emotional one,I'll ask
people like,Hey,can you gimme a
heads up before we talk about
this?Or,I'm,I'm getting better at
saying like,before I just like
jump into my emotional response.
Can we take a step back and talk
about this later?Uh,because I
know that I'm not going to give
the response that I want to be
giving,and it's not gonna be
productive for anyone in that
situation,right?And I think that.
Understanding that we communicate
in different ways,that we,um,we
receive feedback in different
ways is incredibly important to
finding that place where you can
have that productive conversation
where you can have those hard
conver,nobody,I mean,I don't
think anybody likes to have hard
conversations.I don't,it takes a
lot of work to do that,right?And
so finding the best way to do
that.Is going to benefit everyone
and then you'll be able to grow
through those conversations.
Arthur: I think what you're,
there's two things I want I want
to touch on that you pulled,you
mentioned,um,the first is that
there is some degree of,uh,the
concept's called it kind of
called managing upward.Um,but it
works regardless of.The
description of the concept is
that you are providing
information to your superiors
about how you work and what the
best way to manage you is.Um,
there is a tendency to believe
that just because somebody is a
manager,that they have.All seeing
human powers,um,is absolutely not
true.Uh,you know,they're,they're
just people like you,right?So
they don't necessarily,I mean,in
a lot of cases,especially in
tech,they are somebody who was
really good at the tech side.And
it's like,well,what's the program
motion path?Well,now you're a
tech lead.great.And you have all
of these human things that you've
never had any training in and
never,you don't have a ton of
experience in.Um,so helping them
out and be like,well,this is how
I respond to things.This is the
best way to tell me about X.This
is the best way to do that can
help.But that doesn't have to be
just that their manager that can
actually be at your entire team.
This is the best way to work with
me.This is the way that I tend to
respond to things.But the other
piece that Bekah mentioned that I
wanna pull up is,is making space
for your emotions and making
space for emotions and work in
general.Um,which sounds like,I
mean,we're,you know,in the tech
space,so it's like har,we don't
want to talk about any of that.
Um,god forbid we ever admit that
we're angry about something or,
you know,upset or scared about
something.Um,I think that
recognizing and making space for
your own emotions is important.
So as a,as a perfect example for
Junior Debs,um,if you didn't go
through like again,an art school
education,um,art school,they,
they train you about on how to
literally separate yourself from
your creations.We don't get that.
What we get is,You code.If you do
good code,you are good developer.
And that in like ties our concept
of,wait,the,the flip side of that
is if I don't code well I'm not a
good developer.So when we start
doing peer reviews or pull
request or whatever your
methodology is for these things,
or even peer programming,um,
Where you code a thing and
somebody says,that's not right,
here's the right way to do it.
Now you've got a moment in your
brain where your brain is like,
oh no,I've gotten conflicting
information.Um,I wanna believe
I'm a good developer,but somebody
has just told me I did a bad
thing.So am bad developer,and it
helps to have a moment to go.
Okay.I'm just,I know that I'm
gonna respond to this poorly,so
I'm going to,like Bekah said,
take a moment to go.Can we talk
about this tomorrow?Or in a case
of a peer review,to explicitly be
like,I'm gonna take a minute to
think about this.Um,and that
could go for being a reviewer as
well.I know there are moments
where I look at like the PR and,
uh,I,I,you know,make a comment.
I'm like,I don't like this.I
don't know why I don't like this,
but I'm gonna try and figure it
out.Give me24hours.And I'd sit
back like,cuz I'm having an
immediate gut response of like,
that's wrong cuz my brain is
telling me that.And I don't
necessarily know why.So I give
myself some time to think about
it,to chew on it,and I come back
to it and I go,okay,if I have a
reason,I can put the reason in.
If I don't have a reason,I
basically say,all right,I don't
still don't like it,but I don't
have a reason for it.So go ahead.
Um,
Dan: yeah.That's awesome.I That's
a great idea on a poll request
too,cuz Yeah.I was,you.Wanna get
it,like to hit submit.You want to
have all of your thoughts in
order.But I think that idea of
saying,Hey man,like,you know,
just like,pause on this for a
second cuz like something,you
know,I wanna think about this a
little bit longer.You know,I'm
not ignoring your poll request.
You know what I mean?Uh,I just
wanna like get through it.I think
that's great advice.I like that.
Arthur: It just gives them a
little breathing room from,I
mean,it's a space for those
emotions to exist,right?And the
same thing can be true,
especially in things like
retrospectives.We,I mean,if
you're using an agile philosophy
or whatever,or you know,
explicitly scrum,you get these
retrospectives.And a lot of the
time it's.Um,okay,well,we're
gonna make complaints about a
bunch of things that we can't
control.uh,or a bunch of
completely superfluous,like,oh,
well,maybe we could be slightly
better about pointing things.
This,like,you're,you're nibbling
around the edges of these,um,I
don't wanna say useless,but not
often super productive,uh,
changes that you make to the way
that your process works,et
cetera.Instead of asking
questions about,well,what are the
emotions we have about this?What
are people getting frustrated
about?Um,and what are the things
that,I mean,we've used a,a thing
in our own retros,like,uh,on the
team I'm currently on,it's like
the,the glad,mad,sad retro board.
Like they're a million different
types of retros.Cuz at this point
I think somebody has a job where
they're just cranking'em out.Um,
but like we use,like,we use this
one where it's explicitly these
emotional columns and.Like we've
drained the emotion out of the
actual things that we're putting
under these individual columns.
We're not talking about it in
terms of,um,Hey,I'm actually
really glad that this thing
happened.I'm actually,uh,really
upset that this particular thing
happened.I'm mad about this
particular thing,or,I'm really
sad that this,you know,this thing
occurred.Um,and it,it's a
question of like if,um,Agile
methodologies,they'll do like
fist of five.Have you ever heard
of that?Like,um,it's kind of a
confidence thing after you do
your planning where it's like,
how confident are you that you
can actually deliver what's in
the sprint?And what's interesting
to me is that that is a.weird
performative kind of thing.Most
of the time when I've seen it
used,uh,where it's,if you have a,
like,if you have dare to raise a
one as like,I'm not sure.Um,it's
like the whole team comes,like
the,the whole force of the team
comes to bear on you.This
tremendous normative force to be
like,why are you not conforming?
and suddenly you've got to like,
I mean,and the same thing can be
true even if you're just doing
normal pointing,right?I mean,
like,that's the,the Agile joke is
like,well,everything's a three
because there's this,again,
tremendous normative force to
push.if you have something that's
outside where it's a one or you
have a,an eight,or God forbid,
like a13,if you're doing like FE
numbers or whatever,um,there's
this tremendous force to be like,
why is that the case and not to.
You know,to recognize that
typically those things mean that
there is an emotion there.If I'm
looking at it as a13,it isn't
just that it's technically
difficult,that could be the case,
but in a lot of cases it's,I'm
scared there's risk here,right?
Or we've tried something like
this before in the past and it
didn't work,and I'm afraid that
it might not work again.But we
never frame it in that term and
we should.we should be talking
about.I am scared about this.Why
am I scared about this?I'm,you
know,we're in the middle of a,a
revamp of,um,some code that is,
uh,let's just say,let's be
charitable and say it was hastily
written.Um,there were
externalities that,that has had
to deal
Dan: I just,just call it legacy
code.It'll be fine.
Arthur: this.This is the most
legacy code I've ever seen.Um,I
mean in,in,in real talk,some of
the ca the code that we are
working with is25years old.
Bekah: Wow.
Arthur: Um,there are nine
different languages on this
project.Uh,yeah,it's exciting.So
there's a lot of emotions,and we
are currently supporting this,
this code that's,I mean,it's in
production,it's running,and there
is a lot of emotions around.I am
afraid that we're on the hook for
something that we're,you know,
code we didn't.and code that we
don't understand,still don't
understand.And being able to
literally say those words that I
am,I am scared of.This,opens the
door to a better understanding
instead of having to,to wrap it
in,um,the trappings of,of
scientific,you know,fake science
basically.Well,I'm worried about,
you know,I mean,even,you know,
words like the externalities that
I used,right?Like we're we wrap
it in terms like that,where it's
like there's a lot of
externalities,this code,there's a
bunch of complexity,there's a
bunch of technical debt.We've
made up words that basically all
mean the same thing,which is
like,it,it's a nasty,dark thicket
of code and I'm scared of it,
right?That doesn't mean that
there isn't reason for it,right?
We also dismiss the emotions as
as,as irrational or.Less valuable
than a narrative cognitive
explanation,but in,in a lot of
cases,they're equally valuable,
at least in terms of
understanding your situation and,
and the human element of it,and
understanding what the next path
forward is.If you're scared of
the thing,you fix that by
understanding it,you fix that by
starting to go through and
figuring out what the replacement
is,what the path forward is.
Right?I mean,going back to the,
the human behavioral health side
of things,right?There's the.The
idiom that,um,anxiety lives in
uncertainty and the more you can
be certain about something,the
less fear room there is for fear
in that environment.
Dan: Yeah,absolutely.I,I've had
the experience many times and we,
we,uh,Oh,just today it went out.
Um,with,with Kai,we,we talked
about that.Uh,I've,like me
personally,I've had this
experience of just avoiding
things that I should learn or
should do just because it was.A
big ball of unknown,you know?And
my brain had,my brain was just
like,no,run away from this.You
don't know anything.Like,you
don't understand it.It's like
it's,you know,it's,it's like
that,it's exactly the dark
thicket,you know,like,I'm just
gonna skirt around this,this
instead of diving in,you know?
Um,but I guess to extend the
metaphor,right?Get a flashlight
and a me a compass and,
Arthur: Or a machete.
Dan: Or a machete.Yeah,yeah,
yeah,yeah.Exactly.Uh,one way or
the other.Figure out how to,how
to,how to get through it,you
know?Uh,yeah.I.
Bekah: Well,Arthur,I wanna say
we're,um,at about time and I
wanna thank you so much for
chatting with us today.I know
that these are,this one of those
conversations that I could have
had for probably another three
hours and found so much value.
So,first of all,I wanna know when
your book is coming out because I
wanna read it and I would love to
see you put something out there
like that.
Arthur: I probably should at some
point.I'm actually working on a
course for,um,folks at work that
want to get into speaking and I'm
up to like98pages,so I don't
think I'm accidentally writing a
book about that.Um,so we'll see
if that happens,but if it does,
maybe there will be another one.
Bekah: That would be amazing.Uh,
and I'm gonna end with our last
question,which is,what is one
word you would use to describe
yourself?
Arthur: I think my one word is
idiosyncratic.Um,I love that word
because I think it describes like
it is just about being slightly
different,about approaching
things a different way,about,um,
not being what you would expect,
and that I feel like that
summarizes a lot of my life.
Dan: Pull up that.
Bekah: Yeah.I appreciate that.I
think it,it,that's a really nice
way to.Word to pair up with the
concentric circles in the journey
that you're talking about,
because it is that different
perspective.So thank you so much
for sharing that with us and for
sharing the time with us on the
podcast today.
Arthur: Thanks very much for
having me.
Dan: Yeah.Thank you Arthur.We'll
see you.Uh,see you soon.
Arthur: See you.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel.If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO,or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.You can
find the show notes,sign up for
the newsletter,check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io.If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!