Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season seven,episode eight of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I'm Bekah,
and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
coding journey,and they're here
on this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned,
and we're here to share it with
you.Here with me today is my
co-host,Dan.
Dan: What up,Beck?How's it going?
Bekah: It is going wonderfully.
How is it going with.
Dan: It's going great.Thanks for
asking
Bekah: You're welcome.I ask all
the.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.Never,never fails.
Um,yeah.We had another great
episode for y'all.Today.We have
Ramón joining us.Ramón is a
developer advocate and DevEd
enthusiast.and we had a really
great conversation with him.Um,
he,in his career,has made a point
of helping other people like
learn how to code.Um,seems like
his,you know,main,his main happy
place,right?And,uh,Spent a lot of
time doing it,and so has a lot of
thoughts on,on the whole process,
how to be a better learner,how to
be a better teacher.Uh,a lot of
things.I,I had a,I had a really
fun time talking,to Ramón.
Bekah: I really love how
empathetic he is in his approach
and thoughtful,and he spends a
lot of time really reflecting on
the process and his awareness of
other people and where they're
at,and I think that's one of
those things that you.I don't see
enough people have that sort of
self-awareness when they're
teaching,and so it's really great
to see and to talk about what
that process looks like and how
we can better support each other
as we learn and grow together.
Dan: Yeah,I totally agree.It's a
great point and I,when you were
talking about that,it made me
think about some of our other
recent,um,guests and I think,uh,
there is a common through line
of.The,some of the Virtual Coffee
people that have been around for
a while and that are more
experienced in their career.
Right.And,um,of that empathy.
Right.Uh,Ryan,one of our guests,
um,I don't know,a few weeks ago,
was,uh,was talking about that a
lot too.Right.And,and it's,I I
think that's one of the things
that sets some people apart from
others is,is that,is that.
Conscious empathy,you know,uh,
approaching,approaching
everything.Uh,and of course,I
mean,we all know it can help your
relationships and everything like
that,but,um,keeping in mind when,
when you're learning,when you're
teaching,when you're,when you're
working together,uh,it's,it's
all,um,I don't know.It's,it's
such an important and under,I
feel like undervalued and then
under,I don't know what's,what's
an under,you know,not talked
about enough I dunno,whatever the
whatever the word that starts
with under that means not talked
about enough,uh,But you know what
I mean?Like,it's,it's just,it's
one of those things that we,I,I
feel like we try to talk about it
a lot at Virtual Coffee and,um,
but it doesn't,I don't see it
come up that often outside of
Virtual Coffee.And,uh,well,
hopefully we can try to change
that a little bit,you know.
Bekah: Yeah,I like that.What you
just said about c.Conscious
empathy.Um,because I think that,
I actually had this conversation
on Twitter recently where I told
somebody,empathy is a skill,
right?You're not just born super
empathetic or super not
empathetic.Like May,maybe you
are,but it's something that you
can actively work on.To get
better at.And I think that idea
of being conscious and having
conscious of it and having those
conversations,that helps you to
grow in that skill and to
understand how you can get better
at that.And that's definitely
something that is a common theme
on the podcast and the stuff that
we do at Virtual Coffee.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.Uh,I mean,I
absolutely agree.It's a skill,
um,that needs practice and
sometimes it.Uh,you know,it it to
be pointed out to people.Uh,some
people like need some help,you
know,with that and may not even
realize it.Uh,especially because
nobody talks about it you know?
Uh,and so I dunno,the more we
talk about it,I think the better
everyone will be.
Bekah: Absolutely,and we start
every episode of the podcast,
like we start every Virtual
Coffee.We introduce ourselves
with our name,where we're from,
what we do,and a random check-in
question.We hope you enjoy this
episode.We start every episode of
the podcast,like we start every
Virtual Coffee.We introduce
ourselves with our name,where
we're from,what we do,and a
random check-in question.We hope
you enjoy this episode.Our random
check-in question is,would you
rather see10minutes into the
future or150years into the
future?My name is Bekah.I am a
person in tech from a small town
in Ohio,and I think I would
rather see10minutes into the
future because.150years seems
like a really long time,and I'm
not really sure what I would do
with that information.It would
probably send me into some kind
of crisis,like what am I gonna do
if this thing is bad,and can I
change that?And what happens with
time travel?So10minutes in the
future,I can stop myself from
saying something that's like mean
or embarrassing.So that seems
useful.
Dan: Hmm.Okay.This is a tough
one.All right.Hi,I'm Dan.Uh,I
live in Cleveland and I do
website development on my
computer.Um,yeah,I mean,this one
is,there's just too many.I have
too many questions.You know what
I mean?It's like,Okay,so you see
10minutes in the future,but then
you change something,you know,
and like10minutes into your
future,or like10minutes into,can
I know what's happening,you know,
in Ramón's house in10minutes
also,even if I'm not there,you
know,like,you know what I mean?
Or is it just like your own?
Bekah: own space.Like we're,
we've got like three feet of
personal space here,so we're
gonna limit it to.
Dan: Right.So like I couldn't
like send my son on a bike ride
and then,and know that in10
minutes he's gonna like crash and
skin his knee or something if
he's out of my sight when that
happens.
Bekah: I mean,that seems useful,
Dan: That's what I'm saying,like
Bekah: But I think,no,no,you
can't do that,sorry.
Dan: do.So I can only like see
things that happen to me
personally,10minutes in the
future.
Bekah: within your site and
hearing range.
Dan: Okay.What about,okay,but
then if you change something,see
this is just like,there's no way
you're not ending up in just like
a paradox and
Bekah: Okay,Dan,and just see
Dan: mentally
Bekah: years into the future.
Dan: years in the future.Okay.
But I mean,the same question,
it's just the paradox,you know,
stuff will happen like slower cuz
it's,the feedback loop is slower.
Right.But like,The,the thing that
pops in the,my brain is like,
okay,well I can see that,you
know,X company,apple,what,
whatever the new Apple is,like a
huge company.And so buy stocks,
you know,but then if I buy all
the stock when they come out,
that will change thing,you know,
that will change the,the,the
trajectory of the company,you
Bekah: it,will it
Dan: well,it could,or maybe it's
successful because I bought all
this,you know,this is like,this
is too much.I,uh,
Bekah: So you'll just keep your
life the way it is.I think
Dan: I
Bekah: that's the,
Dan: I just,uh,yeah,no,this like
fuels into my indecision loop and
I would just,either way I think
get stuck and end up curling up
in a corner,And that would just
be my future.So,
Bekah: there's your10minutes.
Dan: there's my10minutes.All
right.That's my answer.
Ramón: That's totally fair.Uh,hi
everyone.Uh,my name's Ramón.I'm
originally from Chile,but I'm
living in Vienna,in Austria.I'm a
developer advocate at Suborbital
software systems and,uh,
part-time.And,uh,in my spare time
I do lots of developer education,
lots of like working with
emerging devs and just having a
good time trying to do my best
to,uh,empower others.And,uh,I'm
gonna,I gotta say I'm a little
bit with Dan on this one.Like,I
would love to have a conversation
with the person who,or the entity
that's like,cursing me with this
choice,um,because like,on the one
hand,10minute,like being a,like
being able to tell what's gonna
happen10minutes to,in my
immediate future,to me,like no
problem understanding like the
scope of that,but.Um,or,or
accepting the scope of that
rather.But I think that would
create so much anxiety in me of
like doubt.Like I already doubt
myself a lot.If I already know
where that doubt leads me,I think
that's gonna make it exacerbate
that So,um,so that would make150
years in the future.Tempting.
However,I see a,I see a,like a
practical a practicality to the
like,well,if I order this meal at
a restaurant and it comes in10
minutes,will I enjoy it or not?
At least like I like.
Bekah: Oh,that's a good one.
Ramón: Just my choices.Uh,if an,
like,going by what you were
saying,Dan,right?Like if an app,
if Apple's gonna have one of
their conferences in10minutes,I
could see where the whole stock
thing will go.But also like when
having conversations,I,I,I,I can
say,uh,the correct,like how I
could say the things that don't,
uh,make me look silly.
Dan: Oh.Or like the argument
where you think of the comeback
later,you know,but you like look
in your head and say,you're like,
oh man,that's what I should have
been,you know,
Ramón: did you know that there's
a French term for that?Uh,they
call it which is like a f a
staircase argument because it's
like what you think of as you're
going down the stairs.After
having had that conversation,
Dan: Uh,yes.That's great.That,
Ooh,I like
Ramón: I,I really like it.
Dan: Yeah.That happens to me a
lot.Yeah.But like,time isn't,you
know,it's,it's,it's a brand,you
know,it's like a tree.There's
like decis,you know,what happens
in the future?this is what I'm
saying.If you change your mind,
then you're gonna change the
future,but then you have to look
again or something.you know,it's
like a,what was that?One of the
Adventures movies.And Dr.
Stranges is sitting there like
for like an hour,imagining all of
the different futures,you know.
So if you can see10minutes in the
future,can you see all the
different branches?Or can you
just like see the branch that
would exist if you didn't look
you know,you know what I
Bekah: ever seen the episode of
community where they have the
different outcome?
Dan: Yes.Yes.I love that
Bekah: I think it actually won
award.It's a really good one.
Dan: Yeah,it's the,uh,I don't
know,Ramón,if you've seen the,
the meme of,um,of what's his
name,carrying the pizza box into
the room and everything's on
Ramón: I thought so.I have seen
that
Dan: episode's from that one.
Yeah.Yeah,yeah.Don Glover.Thank
you.That episode,that's what that
episode is.
Ramón: Yeah.Okay.Okay.I did
wonder,like I've,I've never seen
community.I was like,huh,what?
What's this show about
Dan: anyway.Uh,
Bekah: we,before we go down the
community rabbit hole uh,we're
here to talk to you.And so,uh,we
always like to get an origin
story of everyone who's on the
podcast and we're,I'm gonna ask
you to kick that off by giving us
one word that describes your
journey into tech.
Ramón: thank you.Um,I will admit
I have come prepared because
these kinds of questions,uh,send
me spiraling.Uh,so the one I
settled on was,uh,curious.Uh,and
I think that's because like,I,I
have over the years,like I was
talking to Dan a little bit about
like,uh,being,being in,uh,being,
uh,working independently and what
I love about that,uh,sorry,am I,
am I allowed to like,expand on
it?
Bekah: You definitely are
allowed.Go for it.
Ramón: awesome.Um,One thing I
like about it is that one thing I
like about like being,being,uh,
independent and,and having the,
and,and,and the line of work that
I do is that it allows me to,you
know,explore different,uh,not
just tech stacks,but industries
through freelancing.Like,you
know,I've gotten to work with,
like,uh,in my past I was a,a,a
freelancer and I've gotten to
work with like,you know,um,
medical,uh,companies I've gotten
to work with,like FinTech I've
gotten to work with like
refugees.And what I,what I've
learned over time is that,I kind
of get a kick out of the whole
like,onboarding process,not just
for like a company,but also for
like a code base.And so I,it's
gotten me comfortable with being
uncomfortable that moment where
you're like,all right,guess we're
gonna like figure out how the
JavaScript tooling for this one
works.And you know,it's,I don't
wanna say rarely consistent,but
there's always some
inconsistencies there.You're
like,okay,I guess I'm gonna
install this thing I've never
heard of before,Um,and I kind of
like that it's gotten me
comfortable with it.It's gotten
me comfortable to like,dig in a
little deeper.It's gotten me
comfortable with also like
knowing where to draw the line in
terms of like how deep I need to
go into something to consider it.
Understood.I dunno if that makes.
Bekah: Yeah.Yeah,I think so.And
I,and that's really tricky cuz
there's often not a hard line,
especially with tech always
changing,right?Like sometimes you
feel like you're right there
hitting that line and then it
moves and like,ah,now I gotta
learn this new thing.
Ramón: Yeah.And you know,I've,I
get the impression that this is
some,a skill we pick over,over
time because like when I work
with,uh,emerging developers,a lot
of the time they're,they,they
will grow frustrated.For example,
uh,I gotten folks who've gotten
frustrated like,okay,I understand
the concept of recursion,but like
I need to go deeper and like,
and,and I need to understand,
like,I don't understand why it's
do,why it's,does this,why it does
that?Why is it that we use this
library?I don't understand why,
where,where do,where do push and
pop come from in,where are they
defined in the JavaScript
standard library,for example.Um,
and,and stuff like this.And one
of my favorite questions I've
ever gotten,I'm getting a little
ahead of myself,but it just keeps
coming back to me.Um,I used to
do,I used to cocha,uh,rails girls
workshops,which I think they were
pretty prevalent in Europe.I
think the equivalent for the,for
North America would be,uh,rails
Bridge.which was,uh,which are a
series of workshops for getting,
uh,underrepresented folks into,
into tech through learning Ruby
on Rails.And so I would do a lot
of those and I,I would coach at a
lot of those.And one of my
favorite questions I've ever
gotten that to this day
infuriates me in a good way is
they,somebody ask me like,Hey,
Ramón,um,why is it called a diff.
and I am to this day,livid with
myself that I never wondered why
it was called a diff.It was just
the thing that I've been taught.
There's too much of in my markup.
You know,
Bekah: Okay.
Ramón: turns out it's divider or
division one of the two.Um,
Dan: Yeah,
Ramón: but,but the point is that
I,I never wondered this,so that,
that what it,what it.What I'm
trying to strive for is more of
that curiosity.It's like
questioning things.That's how we
get those advancements in not
just tech,but in like
communities.Industries and and,
and,uh,how we live as people.
Dan: I,I love that so much.And
like the,the idea.I,I absolutely
agree with you that that skill
of,that,the skill of like finding
that stuff out is a skill that
you learn over time and get
better at over time.I feel like
that's one of the,you know,one of
the,I don't know what the right
word is,signifiers of Kind of
like one of the big differences
between somebody who's closer to
maybe a senior dev than a junior
dev is the ability to be able to
do that,right?To dive in and,and
pick stuff up on your own and not
be,you know,everybody gets
overwhelmed sometimes,but like,
not like instantly maybe feel
more comfortable,um,you know,
diving into a new code base that
you have know nothing about,um,
like you were saying.but the
curiosity is,I don't know if you
can teach that.Right.And that's
like,that's one of those things
that,um,even with somebody who's
brand new to development,you can
kind of see that.And that is,I
feel like a signifier that a
person maybe,you know,has a good
chance of you like a very good
developer.Right.Is that,that
curiosity,um,that,I don't know.
Urge to like,do what you're
trying,like why is this called a
div?What,like what,what does this
thing do?You know,like as opposed
to,and,and sometimes you have to
just.accept that somebody is
saying,okay,use,push and move on.
Cuz we're not like trying to
learn about push right now,you
know,like use this array thing
because,you know,but eventually,
like you're gonna go back and,
and kind of dig into it,you know?
Um,and I dunno,I just,I guess
agree with,I dunno if I'm really
adding anything to what you said,
but I,I agree
Ramón: no,you are.Thank you.
Bekah: Yeah.Okay.So let's take a
step back and think about your
journey into tech and how it
started.So,where was the
curiosity first sparked for you
and how has that kind of shaped
your career trajectory?
Ramón: Yeah,totally.Um,and I
think I,I think I might've
misused my,my one word cuz there
were two of them,right?One of
them is like to describe me and
the other one is to describe my
origin source.I think I might've
done that the way,other way
around and I apologize.
Bekah: that's cool.
Ramón: and I'm gonna cheat
because I'm gonna use a
hyphenated word.Uh,and that is
pay it forward.
Bekah: Hmm.
Ramón: Uh,because at several
stages of my career,so I started
out,uh,in high school,I was like,
I don't know what I wanna do.Uh,
and I was really into,uh,
theater,but that didn't look like
a career that I could do here in
Australia.Cause my German isn't
great.So,uh,I thought of another
thing that I did okay in,and that
was,um,I,I did okay in computer
classes.So I enrolled at,at
university to do computer science
and I wasn't a great student.Uh,
if I'm,and,uh,and I was
struggling.I was like,classes
were in German,and that was,that
was,you know,it's not my first
language.So it was,it was,it was
a bit tough going,but uh,you
know,and then when I met my,when
my,when my met my partner at the
time,spouse now,uh,and the
question came with like,all
right,let's find,let's find an
apartment to move in.And I didn't
have an income.I didn't,I had
zero experience.Like I had just
bought the,the first aluminum
MacBook,you know,the2008
Dan: Oh yeah.Nice.
Ramón: and I was like,Hey,like
this was,I think this was like
about the time that Max were,
were like getting cool with like
developers and like students and,
uh,a again,and,uh,and I,I,you
know,I had installed Xcode,which
is the development suite for
making MACHAs.And uh,and I was
thinking like,okay,well let,I'm
having fun with this,but there's
no.Experienced enough.So I was
looking at want ads online for
like babysitting jobs,and my
partner goes like,Hey,why don't
you like,here's a Mac developer,
um,job post.Somebody's looking
for a freelance Mac developer,
which is great for me because I,
because I'm not European.I,I
can't get a job permit as a
student or it's harder for me to
do.So it just made more sense to
be a freelancer.I,I promise this
is the short version,um,So I,on a
whim,like I'm,I'm not exact,I'm
not.On a,on a,like a confident
whim,I applied and the person got
back to me and said like,Hey,
let's,let's go get a coffee at
Cafe Mozart because you know,
this is Vienna.You gotta go to
you gotta go to a fancy coffee
house.That,of course,happens to
be called Cafe Mozart.Anyway,so I
meet,I wore a suit for like the
third time of my life,Um,and,uh,
and,and this person,he,he sits me
down and he says like,Hey Ramón,
listen,um,really nice to meet
you.Super cool that we went to
the same,uh,high.that is super
lucky that,that I,that,that was a
coincidence.But he sat me down
and he said like,Hey Ramma,
listen,I gotta ask you like
you've got no experience.Why did
you apply for this?And I told him
like,his name is Philip.I told
him like,Hey Philip,listen.Um,I
know.and again,feeling confident
and,and,and I was like,listen,I
think I can learn this well.Like
I've been doing some excode,I've
been learning some pro,I've been
doing some programming stuff.
I've got some of the basics from
university.I'm no expert.I,I,to
this day,I still have,don't have
my degree.So that's a whole other
rabbit hole.Um,you can take as
long as you want in ocean
universities.Anyway,um,so he sat
me down and,and so he,and,and I
told him like,look,I think I can
learn quickly.I think I can,I
think I can get.um,quickly with
developing these,uh,his Mac apps
and,uh,and he said,listen,well
listen,uh,talking to you sounds
nice.I don't think you're ready
yet,but I'll tell you what,I need
somebody to do email support from
me for my apps.Here's a book I
recommend.Uh,and so he gave me
the link to buy,uh,um,there's
this publisher called Big Nerd
Ranch,and they had these,uh,
programming books from,for,uh,
different platforms,including
Makos,and they were great.Uh,and
he's like,uh,yeah,do this and
let's talk about it again.And
since then,like he gave me a
chance.And so a few months later
he,I still have an email from
him,like,I need to frame it.The
subject line was like,highly
impressed with your work like
that.It's so,it's so small things
that like you carry for the rest
of your life,you know?And,uh,so
eventually he,he gave me that
chance.Like I read,I went through
the book.I felt confident and I
started like fixing bugs,adding
small features to different apps.
I work with him to this day,but
it's,it's the fact that he took
me under his wing.He taught me
like he taught me version.This
was subversion at the time.Um,
Dan: yeah.
Ramón: uh,he taught me version
control.Like he taught me like
how to use,uh,Redmine,which is
one of these project management
tools.Uh,he taught me all of
these things that I would've
learned at university.But I think
for me,Learning in a practical
way,learning on a hands-on way.
Like this is like real life
stuff.Like I think one of the
hardest things about learning
version control in,in a,in,in an
enclosed like non-specific
environment is that that
collaborative,like the,a little
bit of the chaotic part is lost
of like,you know,merge conflicts
and all that.So like learning to
navigate those was something that
was really helpful for me.But
yeah,so this,this person just
sort of gave me that.and,and I've
got a hand,I've had a handful of
those in my life where,for
example,my first job endeavor was
my friend Jess reaching out to me
one day and saying like,Hey,
listen,I see like I can see on
your cv.I was feeling a little
bit,um,again,confident and I was
like,you know,I've been,you know,
giving talks,uh,coaching at
things.I've been like working at,
uh,NGOs to help underrepresented
folks get into tech.Why not turn
that into a,you know,you know how
on your cvs,or sorry,your
resumes,you'll have like little
areas that of your skills.I
thought I'll put Dev in there and
see what developer relations in
there and see what happens.And it
happened,just reached out to me
and said like,I've got this job
offer.I don't want to like,um,do
you want a job?Do a job share
with me.So we get,we split,we
split the salary,we split the
work.I,she brings in her,uh,
devil expertise.I bring in my,my
knowledge in in tech and we sort
of like turn that into one
developer advocate.And the fact
that she gave me this chance,the
fact that she,you know,gave me a
hand,um,that sort of shaped me.
And,and this has happened a
couple of times,has said,and
that's why I say pay it forward,
because like,you know,why not?
Like,why not do what I can?Given
the luck,the,the fortune and the
privilege I've had to empower
others to do the same.And again,
that was a short version,
Bekah: I think that's awesome and
I really love.The theme of you
saying you were feeling a little
bit confident or something.Cuz I
think,you know,even for me,so a
couple weeks ago I was laid off
and now I'm trying to figure out
what I want to be doing and just
kind of taking some deliberate
time to think.Things through,do I
want to continue on the Derell
path?But the great thing is it's
led to some conversations that I
wouldn't have otherwise had I met
with somebody who's part of,um,
a,a small but prominent business
in tech this morning,and they're
hiring for a full-time role.I
don't want a full-time role right
now.And so we kind of talked
about what I could be doing in
terms of consulting and it's
different than what most roles
are.Advertised,but I think that
the idea is kind of like what you
were saying with Jess,both of you
contributing something to become
one dev,and so there's like a
different take because right now
in tech there's a lot of
uncertainty about things and so
like maybe finding that position
where you can still be.Helpful in
an environment or in a company is
a way to get your foot in the
door and see whether or not this
is a good company to be working
for or to gain some of that
experience.Because we also see a
lot of folks who are not finding
jobs right now and trying to
figure out like,how,how do you
stand out in,in what you're
applying for?When you're doing so
much applying and I think that,
you know,you even just putting
dev on your,your CV or your
resume is one way to do that,
right?You're like taking a step
in the right direction and you
are doing things that you might
be nervous about or reaching out
to people,even though you might
be a little bit nervous about it.
You know,I yolo a DM two days ago
and I've got a meeting on Friday
with someone I've never met and.
Somebody said like,oh,you have to
teach me how to do that.Like,I
don't know,I I wait for that
exact second where I have like a
little bit of um,uh,confidence
and then I make sure I do it
right then because if I start
thinking about it,I'm not going
to do it.
Ramón: I feel you.I feel you.Big
time and,and,uh,and I think it's,
it's something that's been
dawning on me over the last year
or so.It's,it is those moments
where you feel like,because the,
I mean,as you well put it,it's,
it's,I think,I think it's,you
know,standing out.And I think
beyond that,it's also sort of,I
read the,I,uh,a few years ago,I
read the book,uh,what is It?How
The,how to Make Friends and
Influence People by Dale
Carnegie,
Bekah: Yeah.
Ramón: and,um,I think I Got it.
Yeah.Something like that.How to
Win Friends,anyone.Yeah.Um,and
one thing that I really took away
from.That book was,uh,the fact
that just like you love helping
people,so do pe so do the,the pe.
Most of the people that you reach
out to will love helping you.And
that was a tough pill to swallow
Cause I hate asking.Um,no,it's
not that I hate it,I'm bad at
asking for help.
Bekah: Yeah.
Ramón: Um,but it's those moments
where you just assert what it is
that you want,what it is that you
need.And if somebody can provide
that,and they,of course,Can and,
and are willing to,they will,and
it will make all the difference.
Bekah: Yeah,and I think that
asking for help,it is one of the
hardest things,but it's also a
strength.I think that so many
people think it's a weakness to
ask for help,but it's
Ramón: No,no.Yeah.
Bekah: you.It helps you to grow
so much faster in what you're
doing.It creates connections and
relationships,builds
relationships with other people,
and it builds that trust because
you know that if someone's
willing to ask you for help,they
trust you in some sense,and
that's gonna be reciprocated.
Ramón: absolutely.I agree100%.
Like I let to be,let me be super
clear,like I have a deep
admiration for folks who are just
like,huh,I'm stuck on something.
Let me reach out for help.Uh,
that was,um,Not to side note too
much,but like,that's something
that I felt very strongly about.
I wrote,um,I wrote a blog post a
few months ago about like,when
you're stuck in,in,in a coding
problem,when do you reach out for
help?Because I am definitely more
on the side of like,I will never
bother anyone.Uh,this,I think
this was a lot for me because I
was freelancing a long time that
I didn't have anybody um,to,
cause you know,I wasn't a member
of a.That I was,it was actually,
Ooh,okay.I'm sorry.I'm all over
the place today.Um,uh,so right.
Um,so I think,I think that
reaching out for help learning to
reach out for help is,is,is it It
is a skill.It is a strength,but I
think it can be honed.It can be
developed,
Bekah: Yeah,absolutely.And you
know,we,a added a section to the
site,I'm gonna have to get that
blog post link from you,uh,about
how to ask for questions with
your code because we get issues
over and over,you know,and
there's a balance there.Right.
And you've worked with a lot of
folks who are coming into tech,
so can you talk a little bit more
about like,where is the balance
between asking re too quickly
and,you know,waiting for the
right moment to do that?
Ramón: Yeah,and,uh,it's,I mean,I
really,really hesitate to say it
depends,but hear me out.Uh,I
think,I think the,the exact
heuristic can vary from person to
person.I think the exact like
timing can vary from person.Like
my,my,uh,go-to is half an hour if
by half an hour.I haven't like,
gotten anywhere or half an hour
plus a walk cuz my head,my,my,
like when I,when I walk my dog
for example,that's one of my best
debuggers in the world,like the
back of my head.Um,so right.So
if,if,if by a certain time I
haven't,uh,come to a solution,
then I will reach out for help
because asking too early,Yes,
it'll get you a solution,but
especially if you're like,
starting out,I find that that can
sort of impede you from
developing a skill of like
problem solving,uh,how to,how to
research an issue,how to like,
deal with a,like,how to navigate
an error message.I think it's,I
think it's easy to forget how
scary error me error messages can
be when you're starting out.and
later on as well,let's be honest.
Like who,who hasn't,who hasn't
pushed a Gajillion Times domain
trying to like get an a GitHub
action to work,right.
Dan: Yeah.
Ramón: I'm glad it's not to
speak,but um,yeah,so doing it too
early can,can,can and of course
impede you and cause
interruptions in a team,but I
think waiting too long,which is
something I'm guilty of,can also.
Delay a timeline,delay a team.If
you're not com,like
communication.Like one of the,
one of the most important skills
I picked up from freelancing is
that of communication.Like one of
my most essential core skills.
Uh,as a freelancer,it's highly
critical because I need to tell a
client,Hey,this is where we're
at.Like,you know,being,if
they're,if they're,if my client
is non-technical,then I need to
put it in a way that,that is,
that is.That is,uh,in a,in a,in a
way that they can,um,that,that,
that can be,yeah,easily,uh,
understood or,um,
straightforwardly understood.And
if I'm,for example,dealing with,
uh,if I'm working in a team,this
helps me sort of like give good
code reviews and all that,and
give updates and all that.
There's something that we pick up
a lot.Um,yeah,so,right.So
delaying a team too much can also
be detrimental.So finding that
sweet spot,I said for me it's
half an hour plus a.How about
you?I'm.
Dan: I,I mean,I like that.I like
that rule.Sorry,Bekah.Do you want
to go
Bekah: no,you.
Dan: Uh,I,I just was,I just
wanted to call out some of the,
like,you know,you talked about
being independent versus being on
a team,things like that.Right.
And I,I found like,and,and,and of
course I,I'm like,I've been doing
this for a long time,and so lots
of times when I get stuck it's,
you know,there's a lot of things
going on right?I still get stuck.
Like I,I do,like,don't,you know,
don't get me wrong,but like my,
my issue lots of times is,is
there's so much context around it
that it takes so long to explain
the problem,you know,and I'm
independent myself.And so there
aren't any team members that also
have their heads all the way down
into.
Ramón: Yeah.
Dan: The,the,the,you know,the,
the,the,the space that you're in,
right?Um,like you will find when
you're working together on a
team,which is one of the reasons
why being on a team is,is can be
so valuable and powerful.Um,but
the,I'm,I'm,I mean,I'm awful at
asking for help.I get stuck all
the time and I just,you know,um,
I don't know.I.Just slam my head
against it,until I can get
through it.Usually
Ramón: I feel.
Dan: Uh,but it,I guess my point
is the,the problem for me is,is
identifying like what the actual
question is.And I think that is a
skill that like can be honed and
can be useful for people of all
at all,like skill levels and all
like experience levels of,of.
Sort of asking the right
question,you know,sort of like,
what is the actual question?This
thing's broken,you know?And,and,
and we've,we've had,we've helped
people in,in Virtual Coffee lots
of times,like,we'll have people
do this where somebody has says
like,oh,this thing's broken.Does
that mean anybody have experience
with this?Can you help
Ramón: Yeah.
Dan: paste in code You know,and
like the trying to narrow down
what the actual problem is,is,
is,is one of the things.I A g may
mean a good question.Answerer
would,you know,have is that
skill,you know,but it's like a
skill you can do for yourself as
well,right?Okay.Like,what is
actually happening here?Take a
step back.Um,you know,that,that
sort of thing.So I,uh,well,to
answer your original question,I
don't really have a rule about,
about when to ask for help
because I'm bad at it.But,uh,I
think that's a solid rule.
Ramón: Totally underst.
Bekah: I think for me it's been
different since I've been in
Devra because I'm not working in
large complex code bases most of
the time,and so it's developing
code for open source projects or
for a blog post or something,so
it makes it a little bit.Simpler
to maybe debug or figure things
out.But I have a,a couple of
things,like I've been using chat
g p T a lot in my work,and so
being able to ask questions
there,like,can you explain to me
what's going on in this function
and if there's a better way,For
this thing to be done,um,often
leads me down that path of asking
more specific questions about
things.So I feel like that if
you,if you don't have someone to
ask questions to and you are
learning how to code,using tools
like that can be really useful
for helping you understand like,
what are the questions that you
should be asking?And it doesn't
necessarily have to be about code
like we're homeschooling my13
year old now.And his ability to
ask questions and then to dig
further into topics is a really
useful way to engage in some kind
of response and,and learning how
to ask those questions.Um,but
back to your question and when do
I ask questions?I usually don't
time myself,and I probably should
because I,I will lose all track
of time.But it's,um,the feeling
when I have.19tabs open,and then
I'm starting to open up tabs that
I already have open and I'm
rereading the same responses,and
I'm like,okay,I have already
tried all of these things,so it's
probably time for me to ask
somebody a question since I.I
still don't have the answer,and
I'm still looking at all of the
same things.So it it,it depends
on the,the number of tabs I have
open,I guess.
Ramón: Yeah,I,uh,I really,I
relate very much with that
especially like the,the,the
mental tabs as well.I have Um,
but what you said about like
formulating questions and like.
like,one of the things that I
think a lot about is like how to
make yourself as helpable as
possible.I think it's also a
skill that we develop over time
of like narrowing a doubt.Like
what you said,Dan,about,like how
at the beginning,and this happens
to a lot of us,like I spent a
long time teaching children to
code,and that's,and that's
something that,that's,that's very
prominent to the beginning
because you don't know what's.If
something is working or,or if
it's meant to be broken or not.
So what?You just go,it's broken,
then it falls on me.The,the,the,
the mentee to be like the mentor,
pardon me?To be like,okay,is this
a good time to go into like a
little bit of a deep dive?Am I
just gonna fix this for them?Do I
help guide a,a big,a big tool?I
like in situations like this
where there's not a lot of,like
narrowness is,uh,guided
questions.Are you familiar with.
Bekah: I don't think so.Tell me
more.
Ramón: Oh,these are,that's like
one of my favorite tools in like,
uh,um,not just teaching,but I
think in,in,in,in most of our
core skills in general,which is
like asking a question that
insights critical thought and a
discussion.
Bekah: Mm-hmm.
Ramón: So for example,like,uh,I
don't know,say like,this doesn't
work.And,and,and these can,and
these can start out quite broad,
right?This doesn't work.Oh,cool.
Um,what's it meant to be,and I
know this sound like,I know this
sounds condescending,but I think
like going into like a little bit
of like,okay,let's,let's take a
look at this.Let's try and
explore this together.What's,
what exactly isn't working and
make it and being,you know,you
can be open and clear from the
start.Like,let me help you sort
of develop that problem solving
skill.Let's go into that.What
should be happening?Uh,Paige
should be rendering.Okay,cool.
Like,let's,why,why?Um,what does
the error.What's,let's put that
error into Google stuff like,you
know,the,the,the,the problem
solving skills,the,the
conversations we have in our head
on a constant basis when we
encounter an error.Let's do that
out loud.Um,start getting a list
of like,okay,cool.What,what,what
is the narrower version of that
problem?What have we tried so
far?How do we reproduce it?
Especially if you're working
asynchronously,having,and we see
this a lot in like GitHub issue
templates,right?When you're
reporting an issue,like you'll
see these things.What,like what
browser are you on?What have you
tried,what uh,how do I reproduce
it?And sort of like narrowing
that down so you can be as
quickly helpable as possible as
well.Uh,sorry,I kind of went on a
side note there.
Bekah: I think that's great.
Dan: Yeah.And you'll find a lot
of that in our guide that Bekah
mentioned too,on Virtual Coffee.
Cuz you know,we,we have that help
pairing channel and Virtual
Coffee and we have people asking
questions all the time and
they're,they're all,you know,
it's all the same,not the same
stuff,but it's like a lot of
people in the same situation
where they're stuck on something,
you know?And you,we,we do,I mean
I think a lot of people will help
people try to ask better
questions too,you know?Um,cuz it
can help so much,you know,uh,
the.and,and it can help also
increase your likelihood of your
question getting answered
Ramón: Yeah.
Dan: you know,so it's like,so
you're helping the,you're helping
the people that are answering
you,but you're also like helping
yourself right?By,by asking
better questions and things like
that.Um,my,my thing is like get
getting stuck,like the,the act of
like,ans asking those questions
and going through those thought
patterns yourself,you know,ahead
of time.Um,For me at least half
the time I figure the answer out
when I'm,when I'm like
formulating the question,you know
what I mean?Or I've done this,
like I've gone down,I've been,I
found,thought I found a problem
on some open source,you know,
packages that I was using and
like.You know,figuring it out and
trying to get,like,I,you know,
we,we've,all three of us have
maintain,have maintained open
source repository.So we know like
what,what it's like to deal with
issues that are,uh,not good.So I
always try to do a good job on
submitting issues,you know,but
creating a,a reproduction,things
like that,um,for the problem.And
I get like,Way down deep into
making this,like,boiling this
down and then I figure out what
the problem is.it's not a problem
with their package and it's a
problem.I was using it or
something,you know,and maybe it's
like a,actually just a
documentation error or,you know,
issue or something like that.But
that process of like,um,
formulating a,a well-formed
question um,can lots of times
actually like help you answer it
before you even have to hit
submit,you know?Um,so it's a good
practice stick into,uh,for,for
many reasons.
Ramón: totally.
Bekah: and it all comes back to
that idea of being a good
communicator,right?It doesn't
matter what you're doing.You need
to be able to be a good
communicator,and I worry about.
you know,I mean,a lot of people I
oh,I worry about all of the
people,um,but particularly people
who are in programs where the
goal is to get through the
program as quickly as possible,
right?Because you often don't
have time to ask those questions,
or you think it's about
memorization.And you know,even my
kids who are in US schools,the
focus,they have Iowa tests coming
up and they're like,oh,we.Hate
Iowa tests.I'm like,it doesn't
matter.You can do really terrible
on these standardized tests and
it does not make a difference.
You,you have to go through it as
part of school,but they get
really nervous and,and what is it
doing?It's,it's basically,
Measuring a lot of the stuff that
you've memorized,there's not a
lot about understanding the
thought process that goes into
these things,which I think is,I
find is way more valuable.Like,
how did you get to that answer?
You know,what could you have done
to find the right answer?And so
there's this focus on let's
memorize these things so we can
get out,get done,and we can imply
them in a job and really,that's
not the most valuable part of
being a developer.The most
valuable part is being able to
communicate and to be curious,
you were talking about earlier,
because tech is always changing.
If you wanna memorize everything,
all the documentation for one
technology,go for it.But in a
year it's going to be different.
Ramón: I,ooh,that,that,that hits
a,that hits a really,really,Big
light bulb for me,which is like
being able to,to,I mean,first of
all,that whole like memorization
how tough it is to communicate to
folks that they don't have to
memorize things.Um,to,to
understand.Like,and,and I
understand why like,it's,it's
not,um,It's not impossible to see
why folks are,let's believe that
because so much of like,
especially like when we're
talking about like emerging devs
and like finding that first job
and finding that first job is
hard.Um,I'm,I'm not gonna sit
here and say like,it gets like
exponentially easier,but getting
the first job is probably the
toughest one.Um,because you
don't,you don't have that,you
don't have that experience.Like
you don't have that,that,that,
how do I put this?Not,not
professional experience,but like
paid,you know,paid experience to
to,to back that up.And so like a
lot of that involves,like I,and
I've seen folks come to me and
say like,Ramón,do you really have
to like be able to write an
Express JS app from scratch?And
I'm like,I don't even know if I'm
mpm installing Express.Or Express
js.Or Express js.I don't know.
Um,and,and,and,and one thing I've
learned is that,you know,I,I'm
not.I'm not a fighter per se,but
I have,I have come to the
conclusion that what I can do is
demonstrate that you don't have
to.And so like my,my friend Jess
and I,we run,we um,we run some
boot camps to,uh,some free boot
camps to help folks,uh,get
started in web development or in
JavaScript.And I've got this,
I've got this moment.So these,
these were live streamed and I
was like doing the,uh,free code
camp exercises for and answering
questions with learners and
showing essentially how I.Like,
you know,talking out loud,by the
way,talking out loud is such a
good debugger anyway.Um,and so I
was doing one of these and if
you've done free code camps,uh,
free code camps,JavaScript,uh,
certification,you might remember
the record collection exercise
cuz it is,it is manipulating a
complex JavaScript option.I'm
talking like,like,I'm talking
like three levels deep with a
raise in objects inside it
complex JavaScript object.And
you're supposed to write a
function to manipulate this,uh,
In a non-function way,you know
what I mean?Like you're
manipulating the object itself.
And so I'm doing this and this is
like an hour long stream,and what
happened?I couldn't get it
working like I couldn.I was
stuck.I was massively stuck.And I
was doing like the,I'm supposed
to do like a bunch of these,and I
have never in my life felt worse.
I felt like I was failing.Like I
was trying not to look at the
chat,but the chat's like,oh my,
oh my goodness.What is he doing?
Uh,uh,he,I'm lost.Can we start
over?They're trying to tell me
like,oh,go to this,go to line
three,and like,look at this.I,I,
I'm so nervous.I'm like,I,I don't
even know what the number three
is.Please.Like,ah,um.and uh,I did
manage to eventually figure it
out and I fixed it and like we
fell a little bit behind.I had to
give some extra homework.But
after I finished that stream,I
gotta tell you,I was feeling
lousy.Um,cuz I was like,you know,
I couldn't demos.Like,I,I
couldn't,I mis I,I felt like I
had misled folks,but I got a
couple dms for folks and they
were pretty consistent in saying
like,Hey Ramón,um,you know,
thanks for doing the bootcamp as
always.Um,uh,that looked really
tough.Uh,don't know how I'm gonna
do it when I get to it,but I just
wanna say like,Thank you for
showing that even someone who's
been in this for like over12
years can still get stuck,can
still struggle and can come out
through,because we forget.We
forget that,you know,when we get
stuck on a problem and we're
like,oh gosh,I'm never gonna
finish this.But you do eventually
figure it out either
collaboratively or by yourself.
And so like when I,when I was
able,when once I had that,there
was like a game changing moment
for me to like realize that I can
show that.I mean,if we,if we knew
everything off by heart,we
wouldn't need documentation,you
know,so that,that,that really
meant the world to me.
Dan: Yeah,that's,that's cool.And
like I,I've experienced that as
well of,um,just,it,it's so
important to be able to like to
show that you.that people who are
like more experienced,um,still
get stuck,right?Because people,
you know,you assume that,you
assume that people that are um,
that have been doing this for a
long time just know everything
and can handle everything and are
like,yeah,whatever.Here it is,
you know?And,um,it's obviously
just not true you know?Um,and uh,
I just love that.I love that
practice of,um,you know,learning
in public and doing all that
stuff.
Ramón: Yeah.This is something
that I really like about,um,
about live streaming in general.
Um,and that's that I,even if I
want,I'm so bad at recorded
video,but live streaming,no prob
like not,not to go too,too far
off topic,but I always laugh
because like when I have to do a
two minute video,it takes me
three hours.
Dan: right?
Ramón: Cause you're like doing
retakes and all that.Ugh.
Dan: Yeah,yeah,yeah,yeah,yeah.
Right.Um,no,that's why I prefer
live streaming too.Uh,
unfortunately you can't like just
go take a walk.I guess.Maybe you
could.I suppose that might be
interesting but
Ramón: whole point is that it's
a,it's an open format where
you're just like,Hey,you know
what folks,you know,you know how
a lot of streamers,if,especially
if they're like playing games for
like six hours or something,
they'll just be like,they'll put
up a B R B A B right Back overlay
and just like,go get some water
or something.Or go walk through a
dog.Yeah.
Dan: Yeah.
Bekah: And sometimes part of that
too,your chat people who are
watching can help you navigate
that experience,right?Like they
might have some ideas.And that's
one of the things I love too,
because there's als often
horizontal mentorship that's
happening in those scenarios
where somebody who might just be
starting out knows the next
question to ask something that
you've forgotten or something
that you wouldn't have thought
of.And so then everybody can kind
of participate and you can all
support each other.
Ramón: Totally.
Dan: I do find it difficult
personally,too.When live
streaming and when you're in that
position where you're just kind
of stuck and trying to figure
things out.The I don't know.This
is,this is like an experience,
like very specific to live
streaming.Right.Um,but I,I,I have
a hard time like getting my brain
to,if I'm really trying to figure
something out,but then like
people are talking and I'm.
Trying to read their comments and
see what they're like,understand
what they're saying while my
brain is still churning on
whatever the thing is that I'm
stuck on.You know,I've only been
in that,in that boat where I just
like,like you said,like,yeah,I
don't even know what numbers are
anymore,Like,I'm,I'm so stuck
right now.Um,but I think that's,
I think that's,you know,that's
kind of specific to live
streaming it,you know?
Bekah: I,it's part of the
experience,right?And I think that
even whether you're live
streaming and you get distracted
by the chat,or I'm at my desk and
I get distracted by a snack or
something,like,there's always
something that can take us
outside of that process.And I
think that's often an indication
of like,okay,take a step back,
take a reset,and you can do that
at any time.In live streaming,it
can be helpful to have somebody
else around who can be the
navigator for the chat.If you
feel like,okay,that's something
that I get distracted by,and it's
all to say that there's lots of
different ways of doing things,
of communicating,of debugging,of
learning and growing and finding
the right thing that works for
you is a really important part of
the process.
Ramón: Absolutely.And.You know,I
find,I find that,um,this is why
like before I started live
streaming,like I'm a big believer
in,uh,you know,you don't have to
do things just because
everybody's doing them.Um,so,you
know,if you try out live
streaming and you find it's not
for you,but you still wanna try
this sort of like learning in
public kind of thing.Like,one
thing that I was doing prior to
the pandemic a lot and a little
bit during the pandemic as well,
was,uh,what I call the study.But
what my friend Jon Ash taught me
eventually is called formally
called a community of practice,
which I really,I like that term.
And what it is,is,uh,sort of a
meetup.Uh,I think in some places
you'll see them called like
Coffee and code.They,they've got
different names.Like I used to go
to one for Rust called,uh,rust,
uh,Rustin Learn.Um,um,that was,
uh,online based in Berlin.And
really what it really was is just
like you meet up with some
people.and you just code on
whatever you can collab if you
want,but you're just like around
each other coding on stuff or
like working on a side project or
you know,doing whatever and when
you need some help or,or if you
wanna like show off something,
you'd be like,hold up,let me get
on the projector for a second and
show y'all.Like,let me show y'all
what I'm working on.And.What I l
and,and,and I think for me it
really emphasizes that
collaborative aspect of,of
learning what you were talking
about earlier,back about like,
uh,horizontal mentorship.Like I'm
a big,big,big believer that
mentor,like the distinction I
make between teaching and
mentorship is that a lot of the
time don't wanna generalize.Um,
teaching when,when teaching,I
feel like knowledge mostly flows,
uh,in one direction,teacher to
students.Whereas with mentorship,
it tends to be a lot muddier than
that.It can go both ways.It can
go in other way,like you said,
horizontally,like you said,Bekah
and,and that's something that I
find really invigo.
Bekah: Yeah,I really love that
and I think that that's kind of a
good way to conclude our episode
today because so much of what we
talked about stems on that idea
of being curious,having those
conversations,being a good
communicator,and,and I really
love the idea that you mentioned
before of how to wait.I wrote it
down.How to make yourself as
palpable as possible,which I
might just steal for the title of
this episode,because
Ramón: Oh,
Bekah: that,that's key,right?
That's essentially a huge part of
this journey.
Ramón: I agree.I agree.And I
find,I find that,um,not to
diverge too much,uh,from that,
cuz I know we're wrapping up,
but,you know,I,uh,being on the
receiving end of that,how
important listening is.Um,And I
mean,listening strategically.For
example,uh,one of the things I
always emphasize when I'm
dealing,when I'm working with
somebody and,uh,let's say they're
showing me a solution that,and
they want to make sure that it's
okay with me or,or that,that it's
good to merge and they're
explaining the solution to me and
I don't agree with it one bit,
and I'm like,no,no.And my,and my
head,and I'm screaming like,no,
no,no,no,no.We need to rewrite
this.We need to use a functional
solution or something.How
important it is to let that all
be.Sounded out,you know,like
said,said out loud by,by the
mentee and just be like,explain,
like showing and explaining the
solution to me.Cuz a couple
things might happen.And this is
something that I really love,
which is either by being a
proverbial rubber duck,you know,
like rubber duck programming
where you explain something to,
to,to,to anani object by being a
proverbial RobotC to,to the
mentee.They might,by explaining
it,be like,oh,hold on,now that I
say it out loud.This isn't that
great a solution,how about we try
this?And I was like,sure,let's
try it.Um,and I let they,they did
all of that by themselves and I
think that's so empowering.Or,
uh,I might realize that I was
wrong cuz I'm human.I make
mistakes.Maybe their solution is
just absolutely fine.And just
because it's not the way I
would've done it doesn't mean
it's wrong.It's just different
and it still fits the code base
or it incites a convers.um,yeah,
sorry,didn't wanna take us too
far off topic.
Dan: No,I,I think that's great.
And I've had that experience too,
of trying to help.Through it and
being like,this is wrong.This is
like,in my head,this is like,
this is totally wrong.I never,
you know,no,don't do this.And
then talking through it.
Actually,I end up coming around
to there.Point of view,you know,
like under,you know,so that,
that,like listening is,is such an
important skill.Um,and it's,it's
worth talking through.Um,all that
stuff.I,that's,that's for
anybody,that's for mentors or
anybody,even,even if you're on
the same thing and doing a poll
request on somebody or,uh,you
know,uh,peer review on somebody
else's work.Um,just keeping that
like open mind and,and then like
trying to listen to what they.As
opposed,you know,instead of
interjecting your own opinion and
thoughts on top,uh,right away,
you know,try to understand what
their thought process was first,
because sometimes there's gonna
be stuff you're gonna miss,um,
that you didn't think of,you
know,and,uh,I dunno,it's very
valuable.So I agree
wholeheartedly with that advice.
Bekah: Thanks so much for being
here with us today,Ramón.It was
great chatting with you.
Ramón: It was a joy.
Dan: Thanks,
Ramón: so much for having me.
Dan: All right,we'll talk to you
soon.
Ramón: Take care everyone.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel.If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO,or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.You can
find the show notes,sign up for
the newsletter,check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io.If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!