Bekah: Hey,and welcome to Season
seven.Why are you laughing me?
Hello and welcome to Season
seven,episode nine of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.I am Bekah,and
this is a podcast that features
members of the virtual coffee
community.Virtual Coffee is an
intimate group of developers at
all stages of their coding
journey.And we're here on this
podcast sharing their stories and
what they've learned,and today we
are here sharing our own stories.
Here with me today is my co-host
Dan.
Dan: Hey,what up Beck?How's it
Bekah: going?Yo,it is going good.
We just wrapped up our lightning
talks.They were
Dan: amazing.Amazing.My gosh.
Yeah.So many good talks.
Bekah: We had11or12,which was
really
Nick: fun.
Dan: Yeah,I know.I can't count,
but like there was so many and,
uh,yeah,I did,I did a talk and,
um,somebody made me not touch my
talk until last night at like
nine o'clock.
Bekah: Oh,someone made you do
that?
Dan: Yeah,yeah,yeah.It was not my
fault at all.Uh,so I did the
thing where,you know,you know how
you commit to something wait way
ahead of time to make yourself do
it.
Bekah: Yeah.And then like someone
reminds you constantly.Right,
right,right.And then you have
somebody that you,and then you
still don't do it.Like,kind of
like
Dan: that,that reminds you a
bunch of times to work on.and you
ignore them over and over again.
Uhhuh.Yeah.Yeah.And then at the
end of the day,like the night
before,it's late and you have to
do your slides and all that
stuff.And it's not your fault at
all.Right?
Bekah: wrong.very wrong.Anyway,I
I was up late too.I don't know
what that feels like,Dan.I don't,
that's not me.I'm not
Nick: that person.
Dan: Yeah.Well,I,I,I've just kind
of always been that person.
Although last,this,this was like
an extreme example and I'm not
really sure why,you know,it just
happened,uh,where I was like,
every day I was like,I should
work on my lightning talk.I
should work on my laptop.One of
the problems was I couldn't cite
on a topic.I was waffling between
two topics for a really long
time.And,uh,you know,so I finally
decided on a topic on I think
Wednesday.When did I send you the
ti?I sent you a title just to
like,I sent you a title,I think.
Uh,On Wednesday or Thursday just
to like commit myself I still
honestly had thought there was a
point last night at like7:00PM I
think where I was like,I should
tell Beck I'm doing the other
one.
Bekah: I will say,I will say
that.It was very good,so.Well
thank you.Yeah,it was fun.It
turned out to be insightful and
something that I haven't really
heard anybody else talk about.So
I did very much appreciate Good
Nick: your
Dan: av.That's good.Cause my
other one was like a css,you
know,thing,you know what I mean?
And it would've been fun and
stuff,but like,it was like more
of like a tech talk,you know?And
this was the first one,uh,that
I've ever really done.I've really
done.That wasn't just about like
some technology,you know?So I
dunno.It was fun.I liked it.I
liked a lot.Interesting.You wanna
catch up later,you know,check us
out.Virtual coffee?No.
youtube.com/virtual coffee io.Is
that right?
Bekah: Me too.Yeah.And YouTube
changed things a little bit.So
sometimes there's some issues if
you do slash virtual coffee io,
cuz now they have handles.So it
might be slash at virtual coffee
io.But either way you should be
able to find your way there
Dan: either way.Or go to virtual
coffee.io and
Nick: there's links to YouTube.
Bekah: Yes,there's that.I am
gonna introduce our very special
guest today.Who?Who?
Nick: A special
Bekah: guest we do who was our
very first guest ever on the
virtual coffee podcast.I'm gonna
pause there so you all can go
check out who was our very first
guest who was,was Taylor.And he
taught us about structured yolo,
which is influenced my entire
life.And here he is today.
Nick: Hey,what's up friends?Hey.
Bekah: Hey.Hi.He's,how's going?
Fancy haircut
Nick: and everything.Pretty good.
Yeah.Yeah.I,uh,yeah,I got a
haircut and lost five pounds just
cutting my hair.So,uh,that was
good.So,uh,con,continuing with my
weight loss journey.Just get a
haircut and you're halfway there,
so,uh,
Bekah: well,okay.We're gonna get,
let's,let's formally get started
because we start every episode of
the podcast,like we start every
virtual coffee with our name,
where we're from,what we do,and
our random check-in question.And
we're gonna pull from Kirk's
question from Thursday.Oh.Which
is,what job did you want to have
as a,oh,yeah.
Nick: So,okay.My name's Bekah.
You gonna
Bekah: go?I,I am starting a job
on April10th as lead developer.
No developer experience lead at a
place.That's a startup.Oh.Place
that you can find out more
Nick: about later.you've never
heard of tb D uh,Dan,it's,it's a
pretty,pretty popular company.A
lot of people are
Dan: TB io.Yeah.Yeah.Oh,man.
Bekah: All right.And I answered
this question yesterday,so I
wondered be a vet and then my mom
was like,do you know that you
have to put a thermometer up Dogs
butts to take their temperature?
And I was like,I don't wanna do
that.How about I be a forensic,
forensic pathologist instead?
Dan: I feel like dogs,dogs Butts
is like the best case scenario in
that situation too,
Bekah: we were like very,very
big,um,X-Files fans,so,okay.I
just wanted to be a Scully,
really.That's all I.
Nick: And okay.That,that,that's,
that's valid.Uh,yeah.I'd probably
take a,yeah,I'd probably take a
Scully over,uh,hold on a sec.Let
me stick this thermometer in your
dog's butt.You know,just in terms
of,uh,you know,at least,you know,
when you're doing small talk at a
party,I don't mean to,I don't
mean to brag,but I,I stick a
thermometer up Dog's butts daily,
you know,um,can I buy you a
drink,I dunno if that's violating
any of our code of conduct.I'll
find,I'll find out after we're
Bekah: not yet there,so we're
good.Alright,Dan,
Nick: you're
turn.
Dan: Uh oh.Wow.Yeah.Okay.Hi,I'm
Dan.I,um,live in Cleveland.I am a
web site developer.I don't know.
That seems so weird.
Nick: I'm never know your title
web
Dan: developer.I don't know.I
don't have a title is the
problem,
Nick: you know.You get to make up
your own title.Businessman Dan,t
b Dan TB
Dan: That that's right.And,uh,
yes,going along with the T B D
theme.I,I mean,I,I never had a
job that I wanted to do as a kid.
I don't,I mean,like,I'm sure
there's jobs that like,sounded as
exciting or whatever,but there
was never,like,I never latched on
anything.The only thing,I was
talking about this on Thursday,
the only thing that I can really
remember related to that was that
I knew for sure that I did not
want to be a lawyer cuz my dad's
lawyer.
Nick: All I
Bekah: wanted to be from the time
I was11until the time I was21.
That's what I wanted to be a
lawyer.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.Well that's
different than a forensic second.
Well,now you're changing
Bekah: your story.Okay.Because
what?Well,but it was like the
first job that you wanted.But
from the time I was11until21,
that's all I wanted to be.And
then I didn't do great on my
LSATs.Okay.I didn't hit that161
Nick: tldr.No dog thermometer
butts,no dog thermometer,butts.
That's the continuing theme,
basically.Mm-hmm.Yeah.Yeah.
Dan: Although I,you know,hearing
the stories my dad tells,uh,
honestly,like if he had to choose
between sitting through another
like board meeting with the
people,you know,they get to deal
with or.Doing the dog,but thing,
I think he probably will choose
the dog butt thing.honestly,in
retrospect.Um,but yeah,I mean,he
is like,he does like property law
stuff,you know,and it's,it always
seemed very,very,very,very boring
to me.And so,although he's,he's
a,you know,successful,you know,
self-driven career as well as
that stuff,so no shots,uh,
against lawyers.It's just like
never seemed good to me.And so I
don't really have an answer.That
was my non-answer.And,uh,
Nick: yeah,that's it.Okay.I,I
don't have a really good answer
either,but,and,and I'm gonna give
a long story,sorry.But,uh,so I,I
didn't really know what I wanted
to do.And like,I don't know if
you grew up with people that are,
like,they knew what they wanted
to do from like,day one.Like,I
remember in high school,like
grade seven,somebody's like,
yeah,I'm gonna be a doctor.And
they became a,I think they did
become a doctor,but like,I'm
like,No idea.You know,like I had
Doritos like an hour ago.That's
was exciting.Um,But,uh,I,I don't
know,like,as,like,I had,this is
like less of a job these days for
like kids,but like,I used to have
a paper route and I was okay.But
like,I remember as a kid,like my
dream job was to be a gas pump
station attendant,partially
because I do like the smell of
gas.You know,there's,there's
people that either like the smell
of gas or they don't.I am on
team,smells good.And I don't
know.There was,I agree.Yeah,
yeah,yeah.But I don't know why,
but it just seemed like a cool
job and it's what I wanted to do.
And in retrospect,I,I,well,one,I
didn't end up doing that.Uh,so
probably smelling those fumes all
day is probably a good thing.I
didn't do that,but,um,in high
school,the,I don't know if they
still do this,but they used to
give out,like surveys you would
fill out,like what's your career
gonna be by some criteria you
fill out.And my,my career was
supposed to be a cheese maker,so
I was like,I'm like,I'm cool with
that.I like cheese.But,uh,I
honestly,I never really had
anything like big dreams of
things aside from I love
basketball.I,I've,I've told this
many times to people in virtual
coffee,but,uh,for folks who can't
see us,cuz it's a podcast,I'm
five seven,but I used to be
obsessed with basketball and I
used to literally be able to grab
a regulation rim.Like I couldn't
dunk it cuz I couldn't palm a
ball,but I could literally jump
high enough to grab the rim that
is and.Crazy impressive.Yeah,it
is.It,it,it,it was impressive.At
the time I was135pounds.Now I'm
like,I'm a little bulkier,so
like,I'm like195right now,but,
But the thing was,I was so
obsessed with basketball,like,
you know,like a lot of people,I
was,it was in the nineties,so
loved Michael Jordan,the bowls
and stuff,and I was constantly
jumping like all the time,like
I'm not exaggerating.Like I
bought these books from the back
of a body building magazine on
how to improve your vertical.
This is like I'm,I don't know if
they still sell stuff in the back
of books like that,like buy this
pamphlet or whatever.
Bekah: Like listen,we just bought
some kind of bands to improve our
vertical in this house.Okay.So
like we would be those people
Nick: Yeah.But the thing is it
worked.It's just you have to
consistently do it.And I was
literally in my parents'living
room using a dining room chair
doing one legged jumps and then
like eventually I was able to
touch our ceiling.It was like a
split level house,but basically,
Pretty high.I used to have these
things called moon boots,uh,and
they're basically running shoes
where your platform is in the
front and your heel is never
touching the ground.Uh,I did all
those things and like in,in,this
is such a long answer,sorry.But
like in between all that,I broke
my ankle playing basketball.So I
was like in a cast,uh,before
grade nine,all the way up to my
knee for like the whole summer.
Oh.So part,part of getting back
to,into things like it took me a
year to be able to run again.So
like physio,all that stuff,and
that's one of the moon boots and
the jumping.And anyways,uh,that
didn't pan out because one,I'm
five seven and I'm also realized
I am clearly not good enough to
play in the N V A,which is pretty
much probably most people,but.
Yeah,that was,that was kind of
it.That's my long-winded story.
Maybe I should have been a cheese
maker.Who knows.
Bekah: I think you're doing a
pretty great job at what you are
doing,so I don't think you should
be a cheese maker.Um,but the last
time we had you on,you had a
totally different job.You wanna
tell people about what you're
doing now?
Nick: Yeah,yeah.So,yeah.So the
first,like you were saying,the
first episode of this podcast,I
was working at dev dot two.Uh,so
I've been working in opensource
professionally since January,
2020.I was contributing to
opensource prior to that,and I,I
still do contribute to opensource
outside of work hours,but,um,now
I'm at Netlify,uh,I'm on the
ecosystem pillar,which is just a
fancy name for like the big team.
And then I'm on a,a smaller team
within there called the
Frameworks team.So,uh,basically
my job is to make sure.Whatever
framework you're deploying to
Netlify.It works.Uh,it's not just
my team.Like,there's obviously
people that run the platform and
stuff,but like,I'm kind of,my
team is at the center of like,
the actual build of the framework
and making sure it works properly
with like serverless and edge.So
that's,that's kind of what I've
been up to.I've been there.It's
actually gonna be my one year
anniversary on Tuesday,so,Hey.
Nice.It's,it's pretty wild.Like,
I feel like I've been there
forever,but I mean that in a good
way.You know,like how it,it's
kind of like if you're just
hanging out with people for like
a weekend or something and you
feel like,or like a great
vacation and you're like,it's
like five days,but you feel like
you've been there two weeks,you
know,kind of.So it's,it's felt
like that,and I have really
great.Managers and skip level.
They're,they're super supportive
and everybody's really cool.So
it's,you know,last time I was on
the podcast I said Dev two was my
dream job,and it was at the time.
And like,so right now this is my
dream job.So like,not that I plan
on leaving any type suit,but
like,hopefully I can keep saying
my dream job is my next job all
the time.So,uh,yeah.I love
Dan: that.I love that.We love
Nefi Edwards coffee.We would,
we've been nullify.I,I,I
wouldn't,I don't wanna say
customers because they nullify
has a,an amazing open source
like,I don't know,plan or
whatever you wanna call it.Um,
yeah,so if you're,you're open
source repositories,they'll host
your sites for free and give you,
like the pro plan,give you what
Nefi,uh,uh,is the pro plan.If
you're a business and you have
private repositories,um,if you're
an open source organization,
they'll give you the pro plan for
free.And,um,we've been on Nefi
since,I don't know,whenever the,
whenever like we.redid the web
like
Bekah: it was the first year for
Octoberfest Octoberfest.Yeah.So
that's probably April
Nick: 20,October of2020.Um,and
yeah,we've been,
Dan: we've on that since then.
And I,I've been,I I've always
been a huge fan,so I,when we,
when I heard you were going
there,I was,I was very,very
excited.It was,it was
Nick: awesome.Okay.I just,sorry,
I'm just laughing cuz Triple B's
in the chat,uh,bald bearded
builder or Michael O Jolly and I
said,Hey,triple B,but I wrote
triple B and so now I triple,
triple,triple.Yeah.Or maybe we
could call him triple trouble.I
don't know.but yeah,no,it's,it's
great.Yeah,no like,uh,Netlify is
a big fan of open source,so like
that's why they offer those plans
like that.It's uh,uh,you know,
it's,they don't just give'em out
to anybody.But definitely there's
lots of,lots of great.Open source
projects that,uh,we like to
support.
Dan: So,yeah.And we didn't like,
it wasn't,I,I think they give it
out to mostly anybody if you're
actually an open source
organization.You know,they,like,
we didn't,I mean,I applied and I
got,it was like a form,you know,
and got a response.Yeah.The same
day or the next day or something
like that.You know,it wasn't
like,it was very easy and it was,
it was totally cool.So.Awesome.
Speaking of frameworks,Onfi,are
you gonna be.Getting some
WordPress going on there pretty
soon.
Nick: Hp Yeah.Yeah,yeah,yeah.
Well,you can actually,I,I know,I
know you're,you're,you're joking,
kind of being slash serious,but
you can actually,my,my coworker
Matt Cain,who,uh,currently isn't
on the frameworks team,but he
was,but uh,you can actually run,
he has an example of running PHP
and Wam on the edge.Uh,I can find
that tweet.So like,if you wanna
deploy your,uh,your Word press
site within Wam,within an edge
function,Dan,there you go.
Dan: So,yeah,that,I think that
fits right into the,like,
squarely into the,you know,you
were so interested in seeing if
you could,you didn't stop to
think if you should
Nick: Oh,yeah,yeah.No,it was
definitely,definitely a,a proof
of concept,a fun thing.It was
more.I,I remember when he put it
out.I,I,I think I responded with,
now even JavaScript devs can get
their Lamborghini cuz like
everybody always has those jokes
about Oh yeah.Well they're not
necessarily jokes like the,the
creator of Lave has a
Lamborghini,I believe.Uh,cuz like
p h P and Laravel are,are pretty
successful even though people try
to trash talk it all the time.So
it's,uh,no
Dan: pH php tells Awesome.I I
honestly actually work in PHP all
the time.But,uh,you know,I,I was
just trying to think of a,a jokey
framework and WordPress is the
first thing that I thought of,
so,you know.All right.Um,
Nick: that's awesome.What,Yeah.
Bekah: Michael also said,next
step,they put all that in flash
and we,there was like actually
flash stuff covered in our
lightning talks earlier today,
so,okay.It's that me,it's not
gone forever.
Nick: Yeah.I'll,I'll get,I'll get
working on that cold fusion and,
uh,while I'm at it,Michael,I'll
also work on getting Java apples
in waza working on the edge if
you want.So,uh,
Dan: Man,Java apples.I just got
like a shiver,like a cold shiver
of,
Nick: yeah,it was,I,I still
remember it.Uh,just like you'd
have your website and then there
would be this gray square with
this little Java logo coffee with
the,with the hot part of the
coffee kind of waving and it'd
just be like loading apple or
something.And it,and they took
forever cuz like,broadband
internet only really came about
like mid to late nineties.So
like,I don't know,I,I almost kind
of wonder if like,uh,it would,
uh,if it would've caught on
better,um,if,if broadband had
been more prevalent at the time,
cuz like it was slow,you know,
just cuz of that.But,uh,yeah,
Dan: I mean,you know,not to get
too far into it.I,I think the,
the real,the big reason like Java
stuff got shut down and also
flash was security,you know,
problems.Yeah.Rampant security
problems.Um,but the,Nope,I had
something else to say,but I,I
lost it so we can,we can move on.
Bekah: Sorry.I was just like,I'm
being super distracted by Michael
in the chat who says,I still
didn't know why I just didn't
remain a V B A developer by now.
I'd be integrating chat g p T
into Excel and Word like a boss
Michael.The time has not run out.
You can still do all of
Nick: those.
Dan: Yeah,also chat,G P T.Uh,
nice.Talk about chat G p T from
Matt today in lighting talks.So
yeah,check out virtual coffee,
um,
Nick: something,something
lighting
Bekah: talks.We had lighting
talks that will be up very soon.
They were livestreamed,they'll be
Nick: I to shout
Dan: out something and I dunno
what like to shut out
Nick: Triple B also,Jen hasn't
Bekah: been a podcast host for
very long.He doesn't know what he
Nick: is doing.Yeah,it's only
been seven seasons.I hear.I hear
season eight is when you catch
your stride.So yeah.Thanks.I'm
hoping,I'm hoping
Dan: for that.We'll see.
Bekah: Uh,yeah.Okay.So,alright,
we,I just wanted to,so we can
keep talking,but also Dominic
does a really good job of putting
together our Friday Twitter chat.
So if you don't follow us already
on Twitter,we're at v Virtual
Coffee,can't Say it,virtual
Coffee io.And every Friday
morning at9:00AM Eastern,we drop
our Twitter chat.And Dominic,
that's run by Dominic Duffin,who
was on the podcast this season.
So we can go ahead and dive into
some of those questions.Unless
Nick,there's something that you
want to bring up and to talk
about as our special.
Nick: Um,I can't at the moment.
I'll,I'll try and think of
something else.Uh,I,I got
slightly distracted cuz I have to
just reply to an email for
something,but,uh,I'll definitely,
I'll definitely try and think of
something cuz I,I know I'm super
happy to be on the podcast.It's
just like there's something that
had come up that I completely
forgot about,so I just had to
email them.But,uh,let me just
send that.
Bekah: Michael,you are on
Twitter,so in the chat I'm
responding to the chat.Michael,
if you're not on Twitter,I dm you
on Twitter.Um,we do not do our
chat on ma does he reply?No.yes,
he does reply we don't do
Mastodon chats because we're,
we're not.We're not down with
Mastodon yet,right?
Nick: I,I mean,I,I've been on
don't for a while,but I don't
even know where to start with
Mastodon.Nick.
Bekah: Nick is down with
Mastodon.You can DM him on
Mastodon.Free
Nick: to let free,feel free to
toot me.Toot me Toot away.Toot.
Bekah: Why is it called that?
Okay,that's not going to any
place that
Nick: caused you,okay,so,so I can
explain all this if it's not
clear,but like,also I'm the,the
MAs on instance.So like,unlike
Twitter,Twitter,it's like there's
just twitter.com mast on,you have
several instance,not several,
like as many instances as people
wanna create.And then,so like,
I'm on a instance,I joined in
2017.and it's called Tut Cafe.So
like,if you wanna reach me on ma
on my address is Nikki Nikki t
Online Tut Cafe.Um,the reason I'm
pretty sure why it's called Toot
is because the logo is a ma on
like the,which is I think,pretty
similar to a mammoth,like a wooly
mammoth.I'm not sure what the
diff difference is,but like,it's
so like elephant trunk and I
guess elephant trunks make a
tooting noise.Either that or
mastodons farted a lot back in
the ice age.I have no idea but
they,they just went with that.So
Dan: yeah,there's almost no doubt
that that's it,you know?All
right.I feel like,uh,Google says
MAs duns were shorter and
stockier than mammoths with
shorter and straighter tus.
Nick: So,okay.Okay.There you go.
Bekah: Gotcha.Okay.And what
everybody really wants to know is
that they are using DNA of
mastodons,right.With elephants to
breed them into existence.
Dan: I thought you talk about the
meatball.
Nick: Oh,meatballs.Did you say
Mastodon?Meatballs.Meatball.I
think I'm gonna have to do a hard
pass on prehistoric meat.
Somebody made a meatball from,
that's before.Uh,one A meatball.
No,no.This,
Dan: yes.No,this is like truly,
uh,truly.I don't know.What,what
do you call it?Like,just awful
stuff.But somebody made,um,do I
have to share my whole screen?Oh
yeah.Window.Alright,here we go.
Ready?Here it is.All right.
Window share.Did that work?Yeah.
Somebody get outta here ad
somebody.Made a massive meatball
with mo moly,mammoth dna.And,uh,
I've seen this Atlanta a bunch of
times.I've refused to open the
articles but still it stuck into
my brain.I don't,I I haven't
actually read the article.So,um,
Nick: meatballs,
Dan: I'll,I'll put this,I'll put
this in the,uh,and
Nick: may maybe that could,could
drive adoption of people using
Mastodon,like create an,create an
account and get like a,get like a
free bag of meatballs.Kind of
like,you know,like,I don't know
if,if,if your families eat the
IKEA meatballs,they're,they're
pretty solid.Those,those50.Yeah.
Yeah,yeah.And it's,it,it's just
they come with an Allen key too.
Almost bet.Almost.Right?Right.
Yeah.Sorry,
Dan: I got,I saw,um,Very good
prank.You know,sometimes pranks
are like mean spirited,and
sometimes pranks are really,
really good.And I saw a prank and
I think they actually got in real
trouble for it.But,uh,somebody,
you know how,um,Ikea has those
arrows to sh to like point you
through the way they like put in
fake arrows and made like a maze
that never ends in Ikea,which,
uh,was very entertaining to me.
So if you follow the arrows,you
just kind of keep going in
circles,you know?Uh,anyway,
that's my,my case story.
Bekah: So I feel like the,the
biggest issue here is that we let
Michael derail any conversation
that we had,which I,I should have
known better because I have
worked for him for an entire
year.This is what happens when
you.Michael comment on anything,
Nick: I'm,I'm,I'm,I'm embracing
the Triple B derailment of the
conversation.The,the
Bekah: Triple B derailment.We
have had some marathon meetings,
um,which were we're,we're very,
very great.Um,but that also
brings us to a topic about
perseverance,which,uh,we post
about in our Twitter chat.Have
you ever felt like giving up but
ended up not,what motivated you
to keep going and what did you
learn from that experience?Are
there challenges that you have
ahead,that you're afraid you
won't be able to complete?And how
can we help?That was our,that was
our back pocket topic on Tuesday.
Nick: Yeah.I missed,I missed
Tuesday as there Thursday,but,
uh,no,it's a,it's a great
question.It's,it's like,I,I don't
know.I mean,like,in terms of like
giving up,it's like I,like I've
mentioned this to you before,
Bekah,I,uh,yeah.Triple B's
derailing it's a manager
developed a lot of perseverance.
I,me,sorry,sorry,sorry.Folks who
are listening to this,you can't
see the chat,but,uh,triple B is
making us laugh.Um,no,I,I think,
you know,maybe,maybe the first
time where you,you think you
can't do something,it's,it's
pretty daunting.And then,you
know,like,you know,maybe you got
support or you did it on your
own,but you get past that hump of
like,okay,I did it.You know?And.
the more that happens,uh,I think
it's,it's easier to say,like when
you're,you're like,uh,I don't
know if I can keep doing this.
And then,you know,I'll,I'll think
back,like,uh,even if it's not the
same thing,I'm like,no,I got past
this.You know,and like,so,and
like,I,I don't know.It's
something that's over the years
also,like,just,just having,like,
you know,definitely had some
rough stuff happen to me in,in
my,my personal life that I don't,
I don't really particularly wanna
talk on stream about,but like,
there's just so many things that
I don't care about because of
that,like,that are just so,like,
it,it's,it's something I don't
worry about.You know what I mean?
And so like,when it comes to
tasks and stuff,I think it,it's
really,I think to persevere too
is,is you have to avoid getting
overwhelmed and the way.To avoid
getting overwhelmed.At least what
I've learned,and I'm,I'm probably
not the first to say it,but it's
like you,you gotta break down the
problem,whatever it is.So like,
you know,cuz if you look at,I
don't know,like say for example,
we,you know,Dan wanted to,uh,
redo the entire virtual coffee
site again.For some reason you
would never wanna do that,
Bekah: right?Yeah.That's not
anything you've never ever
mentioned recently at
Nick: all.Oh,I didn't,I didn't
even know that.Sorry.So that's,
uh,foreshadowing unintentionally
by me.Sorry,But,but like,you
know,at first glancing you might
be like,oh man,that is gonna take
forever.But if,if,you know,and if
you break it down,you know,it's
like,okay,well I'm gonna do this
part and this part and,and you
just slowly I'm not gonna look at
the chat.I just saw partially
what don't,don't listen to
Bekah: anything Michael says.
Okay.
Nick: But,you know,I,I think
breaking it down is,is so good.
And it,and it sounds so obvious
maybe,but like,as you chip away
at something,you know,whether
it's a tough problem or just
you're working on a feature or
whatever,it's like every time you
finish that task or that piece of
it,you know,it's like looking at
the thing as one piece.You're
like,oh my goodness,it's so much.
But like,as you slowly see like,
oh,I've got20tasks done already,
and then it's all of a sudden
it's like you,you can see the
momentum and the progress.And I
think,I think that's super
helpful.Um,the other thing for me
is like,it it,it's not a,a cocky
thing.It's more even when I don't
know stuff,I'm just,I just know I
can learn things now and.I know
if there's something like I'm,
I'm not certain about whatever.I
know,I'll figure it out.I'm,you
know,and,and,and just knowing
that also helps me figure out
things.And I'm,I'm trying to
still stay serious for a sec,but
I can't cuz Becca's smiling,cuz I
know she's looking at the chat.
Bekah: it's Michael.He's
derailing everything.I'm sorry.
Nick: Apparently I'm a flat
earth.Well,you're not a flat
earth.It depends.Well,you just,
you just don't go to the just,
just don't go to the end,you
know?Cuz that's where you'll fall
off.Right,Michael?So,uh,it's
true.Anyways,that was my
ramblings.I,I don't know if that
was coherent at all for anybody,
but,uh,Oh,oh
Dan: damn.
Bekah: Oh man,I didn't see that.
That's part thing of putting
comments up.Oh,here we go.All.So
what are you doing?Add the
banners like you're supposed to.
Was a earth.No,don't take away
that banner.We don't want that
one Good one
Nick: around accepting.We live,
live on a round.
Bekah: We just started using
Streamy Yard.We're just getting
used to this.
Nick: Friends.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.It's,it is a new
tool.I learned a couple things
today during the,during the
Lightning talks.Um,it's good,
Bekah: good to learn while you're
live.Right.
Nick: So I,I forgot
Dan: to share this with Bekah,
but I,I figured out.So when you
are hosting a thing on Dreamyard,
in an event,if you invite guests,
they can like start sharing
their,and it doesn't show up,you
know?And then you as the host can
like,activate it,you know?Yeah.
But I shared my story.No,I'm
saying,I'm saying,this is what
I'm saying.If,if,if you're the
host,if you're a hosts or like a
member host,like,you know,Sobek
and I are both like account.
Owners or whatever.Uh,when you
start sharing it,it goes up no
matter what is all already
happening.Um,both Beck and I
discovered that I,I did that,
which I did not
Bekah: know.I shared my,I didn't
my slides Yeah.During,sorry,
Brian Meeker.Yeah.During his
obsidian talk and it went up
there and like,luckily I feel
like I pretty quickly recognize
that like,this is not good and I
took it down and I was able to
switch it.Yeah.But I did not
anticipate that when I shared my,
I thought I was gonna go
backstage and dreamyard.It did
not go,go backstage.It went,
would've
Nick: straight up would've.Okay.
Yeah.I would've assumed it
would've.We're calling you out
first too.Yeah,yeah,
Dan: yeah.There might be some
setting,you know,that I haven't
found yet.Uh,no.I did the exact
same thing to Gantt,uh,this
morning at the beginning.Um,so
apologies to Gantt too.It was a
couple,a second of my slide while
he was still talking.So,and he
didn't have any slides,so it was
even more,you know,like.
Disruptive Cause it was just like
Gantt and then it was my slide
and Gantt,and then it was Gantt
again.So,yeah.Whatcha are you
gonna do
Nick: Good.John cracked me up.
GT's awesome.
Bekah: G Gantt is amazing.His
talk is always so good.And his
was,um,the title of his talk.
Give me a second and grab it.Um,
it was,nope,I did not grab it.I
clicked the wrong thing.Where did
that we're doing right here at
Virtual Coffee.Do you know?Okay.
Do you have it up,Dan?
Dan: What?No.
Nick: Oh,
here
Bekah: we conquering your stage
one laugh at a time.And Gant is
incredibly funny and has been
very impactful in my speaking
career.So everything he says is
like,it's gold.I just like,Eat it
up.Well,you can't really eat up
gold.I,it's like pepper.
Nick: Well,it's malleable.So
like,drink it.You could maybe,
yeah,there's gold swagger.Uh,is
that,I can't remember.Is that
real gold?In gold swagger?I feel
like it is.You think it is?I
think it is.No,it's for sure.
Okay.Yeah.Um,yeah.Um,what was I
gonna say?Uh,yeah,no,just,just a
shout out to the Lightning Talks.
I mean,I tweeted out before,but
they were all really great.But
the other thing that,uh,I really
like,uh,about virtual Coffee with
the Lightning Talks,and then we
also have lunch and learns for
folks who aren't aware that might
just be catching this podcast for
the first time.It's,there's,
there's a lot of people in the
community who were reluctant to
give talks initially,either outta
shyness or maybe a bit of lack of
confidence and the Lunch and
Learns.They've been so great for
so many people that I've seen
because like,I'm.I'm extroverted
and like I'm the kind of person
that will just talk to a random
person like anywhere.But I know
not everybody's like that.And it
was just the,the lunch and Learns
have been great for that because
it's like a welcoming space where
people can just,you know,be in a
safe space to.One,give the talk,
but also,you know,get,you know,
great feedback from people and
it's,it's a,it's a great space
for people to just keep improving
on,on their public speaking.And
the Lightning Talks are great for
that as well too.And,uh,I'm,I'm
smiling again cuz I see Bekah
smiling and now I'm gonna look at
the chat and see what Triple B is
written.
Bekah: Yep,yep.That's,that's
about it.Well,and you know,that
is like one of the great things
that's happened over the past
couple years at Virtual Coffee.
And one of the things I've been
thinking about a lot very
recently too,it's like our,our
mission is to be a welcoming tech
community that allows room for
growth and mentorship at all
levels to create meaningful
opportunities for learning,
leadership and contribution for
everyone.And we say that all the
time,and I can rattle it off like
I just did,but,but like I,we
spend a lot of time thinking
through those things.and
Lightning Ducks is a big part of
that because it allows people who
have never been speakers to
participate.It allows people to
learn in a way that they feel
comfortable because they know
they can go to a speaker at
Virtual Coffee who they never
talk to before,but they're
connected in that space to ask
those questions.And so I really
love the Lightning talks and I'd
love to see them happen more than
once or twice a year.Um,yeah.But
like it's,it's all part of that,
like that growing and sharing and
stuff that we do.Yeah.And that's
one of my favorite
things
Nick: to.Yeah.And,uh,uh,there's
been a lot of organic growth in
the community in the sense that
like,like,like for for folks who
are already in virtual coffee,
like the norm might just seem to
be,you go in the slack and
there's the automated,join
today's virtual coffee and the
Zoom starts.But that,that's not
how it began.Like,uh,I,I,a long
time ago,uh,I won't say in a
galaxy far away or whatever,but I
will,um,you can do it.I,I can't
remember.Exactly how I started
talking to Bekah.But like,uh,
when I worked at Dev two,uh,we
had acquired Code Newbie.And Code
Newbie had this Twitter,uh,
check-in.And I remember Bekah,I
don't even remember what she
wrote in there,but,uh,I was
trying to be helpful and I was
like,oh,try this or something.
And,but then after that,I'm not
sure how,but like you showed up
on my timeline,or maybe I gave
you a follow,I don't remember,
but I saw you tweet out.This is
like April,2020.Uh,hey,does
anybody wanna meet for virtual
coffee?And I was just like,I,I
just,you know,uh,it was,it felt a
little weird,but I,I Dmd,I dmd
you,I was like,uh,hey.Um,Is it
okay if I come to virtual coffee?
And you know,and it was literally
the,the first Zooms were like,
you were literally saying,here's
the link in like a Twitter dm.
Yep.And then all dm,that's how it
started.Yeah.And then I don't
think we even had Slack yet at
that
Bekah: point.No.No.And I had to
be talked into Slack.There was
somebody that,like early on was
like,I started a Slack and I was
like,I don't know about that.
Like,that seems like a lot of
stuff.I don't know.And we're not,
we're not doing a lot of stuff
and then,A couple months later,I
am pretty sure,as Brian Healy was
like,Hey,slack would be really
good to keep up these
conversations.And I was like,I
can't handle that.Yeah.And he was
like,well,then I'll start it if
you,if that's cool.And I was
like,all right,you wanna do it?
You go for it.And that's like
kind of been the whole thing of
virtual coffee,right?Like,we
always wanna support people with
what they wanna do.Like,Hey,you
got an idea,we're here to support
you.Go for it.You know?Yeah.And
so it's not about like waiting
for the things that we are doing,
it's about like,you do the things
that you wanna do and we're here
to give you the support that you
need.
Nick: Yeah.And there's been like,
just so many things that people
have just done on their own
initiative.Like there's a bunch
of things I don't participate in
just one cuz I'm super busy Yeah.
These days.But there's a lot of
great things out there.There's
like the,the tech study group.
There's accountability,bu
accountability buddies.I,that's
very difficult to say.Um,it is,
you know,there's the
Bekah: front end Friday battles.
Wait,what is it Dan?You know what
Dan: Uh,front end Friday.Lemme
look it up.Front end Friday.
Something,something.A whole bunch
of
Nick: Fs.Friday.Friday front end
Friday
Dan: folks fighting CSS Battle.
Nick: That's ok.Okay.But yeah,
there,there's,there's that.Um,
uh,what else is there?There's
just like,I went
Bekah: to my first feelings
Friday today.And that's run by
Ethan and which was inspired by
the founders of Flatiron Group.
And okay.It was like a really
nice space to talk about what was
going on in our week,how we felt,
and to be able to identify like
do we want feedback?Do we want to
just vent?Um,and like to
establish like what we want out
of that conversation.And so that
was like a really great way.We
had a member who had been here
for a while and then like went
through a lot of personal stuff
and dropped out off for a while,
and then he was back and that was
one of the first events that he
had coming back in.Like to just
be there and to listen.And it was
really,really great to be able to
extend that opportunity because
Ethan thought this would be a
really great space for people to
be able to share what they're
going through.
Nick: That's great.And the,
there,there's other,other things.
And even,even though they're
repeated all the time,uh,I think
people appreciate them.Like I
know you always do the Wednesday
check-in,how's everybody doing,
uh,Bekah.Um,and then there's
like,you know,uh,Friday,like,
what was your wins and so on.Or
like,how,how are things going too
there,stuff like that.Um,you
know,the other thing,you
mentioned it before,but like,I
think it was after,was it
Octoberfest2020or was it2021when
we started really doing a lot of
open source,uh,at virtual coffee.
It was2020,right Dan?Yeah.This is
the first one.Okay.Yeah.You know?
Yeah,that's right.Yeah,yeah.
Yeah.Cuz I was at Dev two and.
Yeah,I remember,uh,cuz I,I was
running octoberfest,well not
running it,but me and Christina
Gordon,who I used to work with,
we were kind of the face of the
dev two kind of stuff there for
Octoberfest.And then we,I
remember starting to do some
stuff,uh,with virtual coffee and
then Kirk started up some stuff
and then there was like,you know,
like,you know,if you're a
maintainer,you know,like this is
some things you can do and stuff.
And then,and then,I can't
remember,maybe you can speak to
this that,cause I can't remember
when the site came about,but at
some point I think you put up the
site and then,and then we,it was
open source.So then people from
the community,well also people
outside the community I guess.
But you know,that was a great way
to start getting people in a open
source,I think as,
Dan: Yeah,it was that first,it
was that first,uh,Hector Fest,
you know,I made the first version
of the,of,so,you know,Karen made
this site,uh,the first version of
site.It was like a single pager,
you know,nice little single page
thing.And then to basically
create some issues for Hector
Fest,we created the,like,similar
to the current version of the
site.It was built on11at,at
first,but that's right when we
got onto Nefi,like I was talking
about before,um,and all that
stuff.And,and it looks very
similar to how it looks now.Um,
okay.You know,we've just added
things to it since then.And at
some point,yeah,in the last year,
uh,switched over to remix instead
of,um,11.But yeah,it was,yeah,it
was,it was,it was to do that,to
encourage our members to kind of
get into a open door.So we
figured out a,a way to.The the
members page,you know,is,is all,
uh,people add their own profile,
like files to the repository.
Yeah.To,um,get their member,you
know,profile onto the site.And,
um,that was like the big,you
know,the,the big push for our
Hector fist thing,you know,you
can get one pool request for free
right here.I mean,you have to do
something,you know,you still have
to Yeah,do a poll request and all
that stuff.Um,but.It was cool.
And I,and I feel like it was
pretty successful.Yeah.Um,
Nick: yeah,I,I,I thought that was
a super fun way to get people
kind of kickstarted into open
source,cuz it's something you can
see,like it's literally your
picture on the virtual coffee
site,uh,or whatever you use for
your avatar for GitHub.So yeah,I
thought it was super fun.Um,
dealing with distractions.Yeah.
Yeah.Sorry,I'm looking Yeah.I'm
looking at the chat again.Yeah,
you should,uh,you should
definitely have,uh,triple B do a
lightning talk on,uh,
distractions.
Bekah: All right.Yeah.Michael,do
you hear that?Like you're,you're
going to have to do a lightning
talk next time because that's
what you wrote.So there you go.
That's your punishment.
Nick: Yeah.What is he being
punish slash
Bekah: reward for being
distracting in the chat?Oh,he's
intentionally trying to distract
us.
Nick: Uh,that's all good.It's all
good.Got it.Uh,uh,MI Michael's
good people.I know we're,we're,
we're,we're kind of tr trolling a
little bit at the moment,but
Bekah: Yes,yes,100%.Like Michael
is one of my,my favorite people,
and he was a very fantastic,um,
game leader for me in last year.
So I,I do appreciate Michael and
also his inner troll.You've not
been on the wait list,you've not
even signed up for the wait list.
Okay,man.Okay.
Nick: I've got10invites if you,
if you need one.Um,I've been,
I've been a little busy,so
they've been kind of stockpiling,
but,uh,yeah,I'm actually gonna be
hanging out with Michael in,I
can't remember if it's l I think
it's early June.He's gonna be on
the,on my,uh,live stream.Um,cuz
he,he's got a new role at,I
believe the company's called
Tigres Data.So,uh,so we're gonna
be talking about that.I know
nothing about it,so it'll be
classic,uh,you know,yolo.Let's
just look at something.
Dan: You know,I love the,the YOLO
stuff,so that,that
Nick: YOLO life.
Bekah: Yeah.You didn't have me on
your podcast again,I was just on
your podcast recently,but I can
talk about my new role at Yeah,
yeah,let's do it up,up Sauced.
Nick: Just say it Gosh.Oh,okay.
Oh,so it's no longer T B D.All
right.
Bekah: Okay.I mean,well,just like
right now,I'll just say it right
now.
Nick: Yeah,James is saying he
pushed a prod today.Yeah.
Breaking news all around.Yeah.
Pushing to prod Becca's spilling
the beans.So,no,but that's,uh,
no.Congrats,uh,on,on open sauce.
Yeah,that's huge.I,I love open
sauce.Well,Brian Douglas,who
created it is super awesome and
there's a lot of great people
over there like Brandon Roberts,
uh,Ted,I can't remember his last
name at the moment,but it's
Vortex.That's his,uh,that's his
handle on GitHub and stuff.But,
uh,but yeah,it's a great project.
I've contributed a bit there and.
It's one of,well,one,it's a great
community and I just love what
they're doing over there.They are
productizing it now,so like it's,
it is open source,but it's,
they're actually working on a
product now.But,uh,it's such a,a
great welcoming community and
it's like,it's a place I
consistently tell people to go to
if they're starting to get into
open source.It's,uh,Brian's a big
fan of like,you know,good first
issues,so,uh,it's a great.
Bekah: Okay,listen,I'm gonna have
to deal with this chat because
they're getting outta hand.All
right?Like I am not excluding any
of any of you.James,you can have
an invite into our Slack.You've
come to virtual coffee before
Michael.You need to join the wait
list,or you need to find an
active volunteer who is willing
to allow you to come into virtual
coffee,cuz that's how we do
Nick: it.Here I,I'll,I'll hook
you up,Michael.Even though you
told me I'm a flat Earth Yeah.
Bekah: Well,how dare you,
Michael.And look how nice Nick is
to invite you,even though you
accused him of such
Nick: things.Well,if the Earth's
flat,so if I just kind of push
the invite,it should just slide
across to,uh,I forget where
Michael lives.Is it not
Louisiana?Uh,Alabama.Alabama.
That's it.
Bekah: Yeah.Yeah.Yeah.Michael
could never give a lightning
talk.That's true.And then Chad,
he says,I,I Bekah knows that I
could never give a lightning
talk.What's the time limit?we're
a little over today.Um,we went a
half an hour past what we
anticipated was going to happen.
Um,there,there was,yep,
Nick: go ahead.
Dan: Mean if it was only a half
an hour and there it's11people
outside,only a half an hour.
That's two and a half minutes per
person.That's not that bad.You
know,promptness.Dan also,uh,I,
Bekah told me today,she always
just plans on me going over
Nick: is,but always goes over.
Bekah: He has never once not gone
Nick: over.That's fair.I
Dan: guess,but also,How dare you
is all I wanted
Nick: to
Bekah: say.I go last so it
doesn't matter if I go over or
not.So I have the fewest
Dan: times.Becca's.Yeah,I
Nick: noticed he didn't volunteer
to go all coming out,all the
dirty laundry's coming out right
now.I tried
Bekah: to gear my talk to be the
last talk cuz I was also the mz
and it's weird if the mc also
gives a talk.Okay.So I tried to.
Curate it to be that last piece
of thing.I like that.Thanks.
Thanks James.Quack.Yes.You
noticed that I am flexing the VC
mug.Oh,yeah.In our store
Nick: right now.I gotta,I gotta
grab one of those.Uh,
Bekah: I gotta send you one.Like
I said,I was going to the
Dan: enamel one here.
Nick: Okay.Okay.Look at you all
fancy.Yeah.
Dan: Well,I'm not gonna drink
outta it.Got a poly work one.It
doesn't have anything in it
because,um,if you put anything
hot in it,it burns you.
Nick: Okay,so don't buy it.You
drink coffee
Dan: for a mug?Yeah.Uh,I mean,I
didn't,I don't know.I test,I
didn't know that until I tested
it out.So,I mean,it's still in
the store if you want get it,but
just like be warned if you get
the enamel one.Yeah.
Nick: If,if you're looking to
burn your hands,even the handle
Dan: gets hot.
Bekah: like you can't find out
more about our
merch@virtualcoffee.io slash
store.Is that what it is?Are
Dan: you're asking me?I,I,I'm
pretty sure
Nick: that's right.Yeah.I,I can't
tell if Becca's gonna sneeze or
if she's just making funny eyes
squinting for some reason.I'm not
sure what's going.I,
Bekah: I'm making,so that's how I
concentrate.Breaking news.One.
Nick: Eye
Dan: breaking news.Don't go to
slash store So No,that's a404.I
mean,any of our things you can
always just go to the normal
site.Virtual coffee and find
links to everything else.Uh,the
link to our store is store
virtual coffee io.
Nick: Okay.I just had in the
Dan: wrong,I probably should add
a redirect for,you know.
Nick: Yeah,you probably should.
That probably,you probably should
do that thing.It,it,it is,uh,
it's one of those age old
questions.When do you do
sub-domain versus just like a
path?Well,it's
Dan: like Shopify and all that
stuff,so,you know,yeah.It's a
little,uh,more complicated to try
to have it on a subdomain or,I
mean,not have it on a subdomain,
but regardless,store dot virtual
coffee.io.
Nick: What a great store.I'm
gonna make squinting.I'm,I'm
doing terrible ice pointing now.
Yes.That's what
Bekah: I do.I do the squinting
eye.It's always the right eye.
You gotta get the right eye.And
that's what why was in the case
that you're thinking?Because I'm
thinking,okay,
Dan: yesterday I was trying to
open a glue thing and it was like
this little craft kit for Ben,
my,my seven year year old.And
there's like this like tube of,
you know,it was just a little
white glue,but it was,and we have
like tons of glue,but like the
craft kit came with glue,you
know,and.It looked like it was
open,but it wasn't.No glue was
coming out.I started squeezing it
and looked at it and then shot
myself right in the eye with glue
Oh,it came out,it came out,uh,
very suddenly and with,it
Nick: wasn't crazy.The
Dan: velocity?No,no,it was just
like white glue.It was just like
Elmer's,you know,what is
essentially Elmer's glue?Uh,
Nick: okay.So ultimately you can
practically eat that stuff.You,
you know,put that on pasta with a
bit of salt,you know?For sure,
for sure.But it
Dan: was not,uh,my favorite thing
in the world.I mean,and of course
it was like it was in my eyes,so
I couldn't actually do anything
else,but it was also on my shirt
and also all over,over the floor
and,uh,on the kitchen table as
well.So it was,it was a large
mess.And,uh,for once it was all
my fault,I couldn't blame it on
the kids even a little bit,uh,
that time.So,you
Nick: know,you,you could have put
the glue in front of the kid,
like,oh,Ben,what did you do?
Dan: Oh,yeah.Why'd you shoot me
in the eye with the glue?Yeah.
Yeah.Well,I,I wasn't thinking
very clearly because I had glue
in my eye.So it's a good call
though,Nick.You're you're right,
you're absolutely
Nick: right.Would,uh,glad it
wasn't crazy glue though,cuz Oh
yeah.That would've been
disastrous.Yeah,that would've
been very bad.Crazy glue is good
though for,well,it's probably not
medically sound to say this,but
I've crazy glued my head before
from like,like,cuz when I played
rugby,like I've split my head
open so many times and like,you
know,I,I'd usually get stitches
and stuff,but the,the thing with
stitches is if you don't get them
handled like quickly,like the,
you're gonna end up with a
massive scar because like,it
doesn't,like it literally starts
healing incorrectly.And nowadays,
like if you go to the doctor,
depending on the size of.You
know,the,the amount of stitches
you need.A lot of times if it's
kind of tiny,they'll,they'll
actually use medical grade,crazy
glue now.But,uh,I feel like I
might have pioneered that in the
late nineties by just saying,I,
uh,I need to stitch myself up.So
I,I mean,
Bekah: I,I will provide you with
stitches anytime you want.Just
let,lemme know.Oh my gosh.All
I've wanted to do in my life is
to stitch somebody up.I'm pretty
sure I'd be very
Dan: good.It's fourth time.It's
fourth time today.You've been
offering medical advice by God?
Nick: No.
Bekah: Okay.Did I,but I have told
on the podcast before,once I
almost gave stitches to somebody,
did I get,did I tell that story
before?Uh,
Nick: let's hear it.I don't think
so.Yeah.
Bekah: When I was a freshman in
college,I was friends with a lot
of the hockey team and somebody
came home and had a pretty big
gash on their head and I was
like,I could handle that for you.
I've had a lot of stitches in my
life.And so as we were gathering
the materials and he was totally
down with it,he was like,yeah,
you can gimme stitches.That's
totally like,yeah,you've had
stitches,you know what you're
doing.Sure you can give stitches.
And so somebody was going to go
get some,a sewing kit and some
sterilization materials and,and
then the um,uh,ra the resident
hall director came and was like,
you may not give him stitches.
You must leave right now.So I was
like very,very close to being
able to give someone else
stitches.So it is okay.It is my,
um,lifelong journey to be able to
provide medical care to somebody
since I have a master's in
English and I have been in tech
for a couple of years.So,
Nick: so that,that's,that's
practically you,that's that's
practically a surgeon.So yeah.
Practically,
Bekah: I mean,like.I can follow a
YouTube video and do the thing
just like a little
Nick: stick.
Dan: You had me until YouTube
video
Nick: Yeah.No,I actually alcohol.
You just pour
Bekah: it on there,right?Pour it
on there.
Nick: Yeah.I mean,
Dan: one time,I don't know if
you've ever seen the like bar
video game where it's like
bowling.It's like a,there's a
golf one too,but it,there's a
bowling game where it's like a
ball that you like push,you know,
and it,it's,it's like a,one of
those standup video games.And we
used to play this at the bar that
we used to go to.And I,you know,
I mean,I like to win games and so
I get like,kind of aggressive
and,um,slammed my hand against
the edge,cut my hand open.Whoa.
At the bar?Not,not like horrible,
you know,but like,it was
definitely like bleeding.And I,
and then I just like turned over,
turned around to the bartender
who I.Pretty well cuz we were
there all the time.And,uh,I said,
Jeanie my hand bleeding cuz of
your game.And she was holding a
bottle of gin and she looked at
me and she's like,oh no.And then
she just poured the bottle of gin
on my hand.
Bekah: Very good.She did the
right
Dan: thing was,you know what I,
no infection,no scar.I'm like,
I'm perfectly healed
Nick: now.So,okay.Well,I,I,I
gotta,I gotta say to continue on
Becca's story,I actually had
somebody stitch me up who wasn't
a nurse.Yes.So anyway,
Bekah: turned out amazing,right?
Nick: Yeah.Well,I have a scar,I,
I can't remember now,but it's
like under one of my eyes,like,
it,it is from rugby,but like,I
went to,I went to tackle somebody
and like the way,the way you're
supposed to tackle somebody,like
a,a textbook tackle is you,you,
you grab your arms and you wrap
it around their legs and like,
the side of your head is kind of
like on their butt cheek and you
kind of,you kind of just dump
'em.Uh,that didn't happen.And so
like,I basically got two cleats
into my face.Oh.And so like,I had
like,It was like this gash here.
I can't remember which side.I can
never tell.But,um,if you get
closer to the camera,I'm be able
to tell you.Yeah,yeah,yeah.I
can't tell.I think it's this
side.Uh,no,this side.That's my
nose Anyways,but,uh,and it was,
it was my first year playing in
university and it was,uh,rookie
night,that night.Um,and my
roommate,or no,it wasn't my
roommate,it was like one of the
senior guys.He's,I told him like,
I'm at the hospital,uh,I'm gonna
be late.And he is like,just,just
tell them to give you the
stitches and stuff.And the,I
asked the nurse there and she's
like,you,this never happened.And
she just gave me like the,uh,the
needle,the stitches,and like the
stair strips.And then I went back
to my,my room.And,uh,took a
couple shots of tequila and then
rubbed ice on my face and then he
just sewed it up and,uh,yeah,I'm
still here.So.And nice.It was
hopefully sterile.I mean,uh,what
did,
Dan: what kind of,did you use
just thread from like a So kit?
Nick: No,no.Like they,they
literally gave a,a stitching kit
from like,like what they would
use in the hospital.It's just
nice.They,they're not supposed to
give those out,you know.But the
nurse,the nurse clearly,cuz it
was a small town.The university I
was in,the nurse knew I was on
the rugby team and she knew I was
going to a rookie party or like
just a party.So she's just like,
she's just like,it's the end of
my shift.Take this,I don't care.
But this never happened kind of
thing.Oh man.So shout out to that
nurse.I'm sorry I don't remember
your name,but shout out
Dan: nurses are the best.
Nick: I can't stop reading triple
pieces.I know,
Bekah: same.Okay,Michael,we're
done being distracted by you.
It's been an hour since we've
been here and that is where our
podcast ends.So we wanna thank
Nick for being here during this
podcast episode.Listen,Nick,this
season we've been doing a one
word description of what your
career journey has looked like,
and I've given you absolutely no
preparation to think about what
that one word is,but I'm gonna
ask you about it now,as I like,
try and push through this
congestion that I have going
right now.sorry for everybody
that heard me.Sniffling,what is
your one word of your developer?
Nick: Yeah.It's like,it,it's,you
know,when we had the first
podcast episode,I,I said
structured yolo,it's something I
kind of made up on the fly,but
favorite,but I,I really do mean
it.And it's like when people hear
the term yolo,they think like
maybe Red Bull based jumping
stuff like that.That's not what I
mean in in that context.It's
really like the first,you know,
whenever opportunities appear for
you,uh,basically strongly
consider taking them because one,
not everybody gets those
opportunities.And you know,the
other thing is like,even if it's
something you're like,I don't
know if I can do everything
that's in this thing or whatever,
in my experience,like just
getting outta your comfort zone
as well,that and.Just taking
opportunities that present
themselves,you know,assuming
there's no major red flags,you
know,uh,it's,it's changed my
career trajectory,like immensely.
And it's like,I,I,you know,I love
getting outta my comfort zone
now,and it's,you know,it's always
the same thing initially.It's
like,ah,my brain hurts.I don't
get something,or whatever.But
then you get past that and,uh,
you know,aside from that,just,
you know,it's gonna sound cheesy,
but like,uh,just being kind to
people,you know,like,uh,it goes a
long way,you know,like it's,it's
not just your developer skills.
Like,uh,I,I think in my career,
like people have enjoyed working
with me and.And I don't mean
that,I'm not trying to say that
in a cocky way.I just mean just
by being fine and kind,that
changes like a whole dynamic of,
of like the people you work with
and all those things together
have just made my career pretty,
pretty successful I think so,uh,
that's what I would say.Yeah.And
I'll just,
Bekah: I just wanna add to that
because it's impacted my career
immensely to be able to learn
from you Nick,and to have that
understanding and to know that I
can go to you if I need career
advice,if I need support,if I
have a question that I don't
know.And like that idea of
structured YOLO is one of my
favorite things since starting
virtual coffee years ago now
because like there are times
where I'm like,I cannot do this.
And in the back of my mind,like
this little,this little feeling
comes ahead and it's like
structured yellow.And I'm like,
all right,I got this.You know,
like,it's just that bit of
confidence that I didn't have
because of the words that you
said years ago.Now to be able to
bring that into the things that
I'm doing,so sorry,
Nick: gonna make me,gonna make me
cry on the,on the live,sir.
Bekah: That's,that's all I want.
It really is for you to cry,
Nick: cry,cry and,and,and stitch
me up.That's,that's,that's the
criteria.Cry and stitch you
Bekah: up.That's what I'm here
for.You know?And also to be like,
get back out there and do the
thing you're supposed to do.You
Dan: know?Maybe not at the same
time the crying and the
stitching.Yeah.Yeah.You know,but
I feel like you don't want the
per person stitching you to be
crying
Nick: at the same time.Yeah.
Yeah.Exactly.Yeah.Oh,I'm
Bekah: so sorry.All,all of those
things have been incredibly
important to me.in the last
couple of years.And I just wish
for everybody who listens out
there to realize that there is a
support system for you.There is
an opportunity for you.And
sometimes it's very hard and
sometimes you're gonna have to go
out of your comfort zone.And yes,
sometimes it doesn't make sense
at all,but you do the thing and
it provides returns that you
never,ever thought that you would
Nick: get.Yeah.And,and I just
wanna say like for you,like I,
I'm super happy that I've been
able to support you,but you also
have to remember like,even though
I'm supporting you,it's,it's you
who did it in the end.You know
what I mean?Like,I,maybe I gave
you that slight little push
maybe,but it's really you that
did it,you know?So just,just
remember that too.So thanks Nick.
Dan: Thanks Nick.And thank you
everybody.Uh,this was a great
season of the Virtual Coffee
podcast and we'll be back.I don't
know.When does season eight
start?I always forget.We
Bekah: recorded a new episode
already.We already
Nick: did It starts in an hour.
Uh,I want starts,I starts an I
want Triple B Back in the chat,
James.Quick.Let's,let's get the
show on the road.
Dan: Uh,alright,well thank you
everybody.Thank you and Nick so
much for coming on this.That was
a special surprise.I didn't know
Anco was gonna come on.
Nick: Um,so that was,I didn't
even know I was
Bekah: Yeah,yeah.Hey,I figured
that out,
Nick: right?Yeah.Yeah,exactly.
Yellow.Yeah,there was an
opportunity.I took it.
Dan: Uh,all right,cool.Well,um,I
thank you both and thank you
Michael.You have
Bekah: no hair.It's still not
there.Okay.Uh,you can go put some
moisturizer on your beard or
something,but I'm,I'm not Yeah,
no hair to watch.
Dan: Watch.Yeah.You know,right.
Okay.Uh,so catch up Allen talking
to Michael somewhere on Twitter
or I don't know where.And,uh,
yeah.We'll,we'll catch you,uh,
next season,All right.Bye y'all.
Nick: Hi everybody.
Dan: Thank you for listening to
this episode of the Virtual
Coffee Podcast.This episode was
produced by Dan Ott and Bekah
Hawrot Weigel.If you have
questions or comments you can hit
us up on Twitter at
VirtualCoffeeIO,or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io.You can
find the show notes,sign up for
the newsletter,check out any of
our other resources on our
website VirtualCoffee.io.If
you're interested in sponsoring
Virtual Coffee you can find out
more information on our website
at VirtualCoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week!