Bekah: Hello and welcome to
Season eight,episode one of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I am
Bekah,and this is a podcast that
features members of the virtual
coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate tech community of
people at all stages of their
tech journey.And they're here on
this podcast sharing their
stories and what they've learned.
And here to share their stories
with you is my co-host Dan.
Dan: What up Beck?How is it
going?
Bekah: It's going amazing.Dan,
how's it going with you?
Dan: I'm feeling pretty good.I'm
excited about getting back into
the podcasting thing.We got new
season,whole new set of guests
and we are kicking it off with,
uh,maintainers podcast,which is
always kind of fun to get the
maintainers group together.And
this,uh,episode kind of
introduces our brand new
maintainer,Julia.Yeah,we're very
excited to have Julia on board as
a maintainer for many,many,many
reasons.And,um,and it was really
great to sit down with,with,uh,
Julia and Kirk and Bekah of
course,and,uh,talk about lots and
lots of cool stuff.
Bekah: Yeah,it was great to be
able to share kind of a little
bit about the process that we
took to finding a new maintainer.
It did take a while.Um,but for
us,the important factors we're
thinking about somebody who's
been active in our community is
somebody who we know that invest
time and who supports the mission
of virtual coffee and who's
willing to.Have conversations
with community folks to continue
to make this a welcoming and
supportive space.So,uh,when we
looked at our short list of folks
that we think,uh,we thought might
be a good maintainer for our
community,Julia definitely stood
out and being able to do all of
those things.So we really
appreciated bringing her in as
part of our maintainers,but also
hearing her share all of the
different parts that helps to
make our community strong.
Dan: A Absolutely I and,and I'm.
I'm really glad that we decided
to do this as the first episode,
cuz I think you'll hear all of,
you'll hear like,evidence of all
the reasons that we wanted Julia
to be maintainer.Were excited
about her.Um,she's like,she
brings a lot of thoughtfulness
and,um,I don't know,good intent
to everything.Good intent is a
strange phrase.So I'm gonna,uh,
I'm gonna walk away from that
one.But like,it,it,it's just the,
the way that Julia approaches
different things,approaches,
conflict,approaches happy things,
approaches all sorts of things is
both unique And like,uh,I don't
know.It's just,she's just like
such a comforting presence.
Empathetic.Yes.Exactly.Um,you
know,and,and she is,I,before she
was a maintainer,she,she would
help.She has helped many,of our
other members work through
things.Um,she's helped.You know,
when some members were having
conflicts or whatever,uh,and
nobody asked her to Right.You
know,at all.Um,and she wouldn't
insert herself,but would would
just provide opportunities for
people to,you know,maybe reflect
a little bit different on,on some
things.And,um,and I don't know.
She's great.
Bekah: Yeah,and I think that,you
know,in this episode and beyond
Virtual Coffee,we think that
culture citizenship is a really
important thing.And what is
culture citizenship?It's one of
those things that helps us to
define what makes a really
positive culture for a community.
And so whether or not you're part
of the virtual coffee community,
you're starting your own
community,or you're participating
in a current community culture,
citizenship is one of those
things that ensures that
everybody feels safe,heard,and
understood.And so we take some
time breaking down what that
looks for us in this episode of
Virtual Coffee to ensure that we
are constantly.Doing our best to
make sure that this is a positive
space for people,that it's
welcoming for our current and
future members of the
organization.And we wanna make
sure that we can support not only
our organization at Virtual
Coffee,but other organizations
out there that are starting or
are trying to create a positive
space for people.Because we know
that it's important to have
positive spaces for people in
tech and beyond tech.And this is
one of the ways that we can do
it.We start every episode of the
podcast,like we start every
virtual coffee.We introduce
ourselves with our name,where
we're from,and what we do.And a
random check-in question.We hope
you enjoy this episode.Uh,our
intro question today is,would you
rather be stranded on a tropical
island alone for a month or stuck
in traffic for one day?My name is
Bekah.I have a new job title.I'm
developer experience lead at Open
Sauce from a small town in Ohio,
and I don't like to be stuck in
traffic for30seconds,so I'll
definitely go to that tropical
island by myself.
Dan: Um,hi,I'm Dan,and as always,
I have questions.So the traffic,
is it like you're not moving at
all or are you moving little bits
all the time?you could be moving.
two different situations.Yeah.
Yeah.Okay.Yeah.So that's,uh,
that's the worst,right?Because
One time I was on a road trip
with my friend,I have two friends
down to Savannah,uh,Georgia,and
we got stuck in a traffic jam on
like a bridge,but it was
literally not moving at all.And
we got out and played Frisbee,
catch on the bridge,on the inter
on the interstate.It was awesome.
Uh,but yeah,no,if you're moving,
like,if you're moving little bits
all the time,that's the worst
What if you're stopped?Would you
rather be on the tropical island
if you were stopped?uh,I mean,
I'd have to think about it a
little bit more,you know,but
like,I don't know.I mean,also
this is just like,happens with my
life if I'm gone for a month?You
know?You know what I mean?Like,
you know,uh,I think I would,my
responsibility,I would have to
just choose the day,um,just
because of kids and I suppose job
and whatever,but,I feel like
you're making me look bad now.a,
tropical island for a left them
all.awesome.there supplies on the
island?No.Is it,is it,I mean,can
you guarantee that there is stuff
there to survive?Whether you have
to like do it yourself,but like,
you know,
Bekah: There's definitely some
water that you can drink and
probably some leaves or tropical
fruit that you can eat.
Dan: Okay.Yeah,and like fish and
stuff,
Bekah: Maybe.There's definitely
no toilet paper.
Dan: There's leaves.Yeah.You just
said right.
Julia: well,and like whatever
body of water surrounds it.You
could
Bekah: Natural B day,
Julia: You said it,not me.
Dan: uh,I wanna,I wanna go with
island,but like,you know,I don't
know.
Bekah: you're responsible.
Dan: Yeah,I don't know.It's tough
being on an island would be sweet
though.I always wanted to try
that,you know,like the castaway
thing.Always wanted to know,you
know,just to know if I could,you
know,survive it.So,I dunno.
Bekah: Did you do the rest of
your intro?
Dan: Oh,I don't know.Uh,I'm Dan,
I do web development stuff and I
live in Cleveland,Ohio.Now I'm
done.Kirk,it's your turn.
Kirk: Oh,I thought,I thought we
were going,if you're listening,
you can't see this,but like in
the Hollywood squares that we
are,Julius Next and Clockwise,
um,I have so many thoughts on.
The incorrect things
Bekah: Why don't you start with
your intro and then you can tell
us why we're wrong.
Kirk: intro is less important.
Uh,my name is Kirk.I currently
live in Alberta,Canada.Um,I like
functional programming.I'm one of
the maintainers of virtual
coffee.But the important part,so
first of all,living stranded on
a,like Irma is like not far away
from my actual life,really.
Julia: Minus the tropical
Kirk: I mean,you know,that's,
it's not that hard.You don't have
to poop in the ocean if you don't
wanna,
Bekah: I did
Kirk: That was definitely an
opt-in moment there.
Bekah: to be clear,
Kirk: You like encouraged it as
like option A for sure.And also
Dan said that story,Dan,you said
you were with your friend,we're
your friends.And we don't
remember this story,so that story
can't be true.Um,anyway,I would
do unspeakable things,so I have
to avoid traffic for even a
millisecond.And I would happily
return to a traffic.for a month,
um,actually did spend a week in
like my dad's cabin,which had
like no electricity,um,and just
like an open tank for water for
like a week before I went off to
college.And it was fine.
Dan: How to build cabins and open
tanks from scratch,though.
Kirk: Why not?
Julia: A person of many talents,
Dan: Is there a volleyball there
that you can make friends with,
Kirk: What?No.Okay.Like,
Dan: know,from Castaway?
Julia: you never know what's
gonna wash up on the beach.
Kirk: let's not let Tom Hanks'
lived experience be the,be the
example that we all must live by.
okay,we're then,I'm done.This
also reminds me of that episode
of Naked and Afraid that was in
fact filmed on my island,which is
a hilarious episode because to
spend the whole time going,it's
so cold.There's no food.But like
my island is literally the size
of like Manhattan.Like,you're,
you're,you're like never more
than30minutes away from a village
and there's like food everywhere.
Like,none of that made any sense.
So for those of you who've ever
watched a Negative,afraid on
Discovery Channel,it's not true.
Except they're naked.They are
naked,
Dan: Are there clothes on our
tropical island that you're
stranded on?Well,I mean like are
you wearing one set of clothes at
least?
Julia: Why does it matter?
Dan: Well,I wouldn't wanna be
naked on a tropical island for a
month.
Bekah: I mean,You can wear your
own clothes.You don't get dropped
on there naked.
Dan: Okay.That's how I was just
asking.I was just clarifying.
Kirk,Kirk,Kirk brought it
Bekah: wanna apologize to Dan's
mom if she is listening to this
podcast right now.I'm sorry.How
out of hand this has gotten?
Dan: Listen,inquiring minds want
to know,you know,gotta know all
the parameters to the question
before you answer it.
Julia: Well,I think it's my turn
Um,I'm Julia.I am a developer.
Educator.Um,And technical content
creator.I work with developer
tools companies.I live outside
Seattle.Um,and I,yeah,I really
hate traffic.Um,I think the only
way I'd be okay with it is like
if I knew I could get out of the
car cuz it,that's one thing we
have a lot of drawbridges around
here and sometimes you get stuck
with a drawbridge opening and
like,I got stuck one time in the
I five drawbridge between Seattle
and Portland.Or like,right as
you're going into Portland,when
that thing opens,you're stuck for
like two hours while it opens and
closes.Like the whole interstate
just stops.Um,and that's actually
fine.Like we blasted some girl
talk and had a dance party and
that was terrific.Uh,but that was
only two hours and you could get
out of the car.So I don't,yeah,I
mean,responsibilities.
Responsibilities.Don't.The
tropical island,I don't even like
tropical climates.
Kirk: I only think of drawbridge
as an association of castles.So
what I'm hearing you say is
Seattle is filled with castles
and you all just visit each
other's castles from near
castles.
Julia: No,but
Kirk: Right.
Dan: Incorrect,sir.
Julia: no,it's kind of,there's a
lot of water.That's why.Careful
Kirk: Drawbridges are for?
They're for alligators.
Julia: either.See,that's why I
don't like tropical places.I
don't.I choose neither.I.
Dan: I don't think that was a
choice.
Kirk: You don't have to,he's
naked.
Dan: gotta do what you gotta do.
Bekah: Okay,well now that we
spent nine minutes going through
that scenario,Uh,you might be
wondering why are there four of
us here when traditionally we've
had three maintainers,and that's
because yay,we've added Julia as
a maintainer at virtual coffee.
Uh,what does that mean?That means
that the four of us work together
to help look at the health of the
community,the wellbeing of the
members and the volunteers,and to
make decisions about what's
happening at Virtual coffee.And
so for this podcast episode,I
wanna talk a little bit about,
uh,culture,citizenship and what
it means to be a good member of a
community or a positive member of
a community.And that goes into
conversation about why we added
Julia as a maintainer to begin
with and how that process went.
And so for us,we.We're looking
at,there was a,a need to be
filled at virtual coffee.And so
we were thinking about,you know,
how can we continue to support
the existing members and who
would be a great person to help
us with that.And Julia has been a
really active member of Virtual
Coffee.She has,uh,been leading
the tech interview study group
every week,supporting members,
hangs out in the co-working room
and is always very thoughtful in
her approaches and responses to
other people.And so it was
really,um,Great to be able to
think of Julia in that role and
to know that she's somebody that
we can have conversations with.
And sometimes there's hard
decisions to be made or sometimes
there's complicated things that
happen.And to know that we could
be open and honest with each
other.So I just wanna,first of
all,thank Julia for all of the
positive interactions,um,and
support that she's brought to
virtual Coffee since becoming a
member.And then maybe kick off
this conversation about what it
means to be a positive community
member.
Kirk: yeah,it's,it's really great
to have,uh,Julia join the
maintainers.Um,and I mean,I don't
know,we can,we can talk more
about like how the process went,
like how that kind of works.Um,
and I feel like,I don't know,one
of the things I was thinking
about is that VC is a very,like,
we try to be a very opt in
community,you know,so like the
roles and responsibilities of
folks here,it's like either folks
are like,Hey,I would like to try
this thing,or I'm interested in
this thing.Um,so,you know,and
like on the one side of like us
being like,Hey,we think Julia
might be a really great fit for
this role,it was also Julia being
like,Hey,you know,like I really
like this space and this feels
like one of the ways I want to be
a part of it.Right.So that was,I
don't know that.That also feels
like really important,like at
both sides you're like,Hey,we
think this could be a good idea
and we can make this work.Um,and
it did,and I'm super happy about
Julia: Well,so far,I don't know.
When's my first evaluation's
like,oh,what are my OKRs?
Bekah: No,
Julia: I,
Dan: Oh no.
Bekah: no,we don't do this.
Thanks here.
Dan: Yeah,if you think we have
OKRs set up for anything,uh,
Kirk: if the first nine minutes
of this conversation didn't
indicate.
Julia: yeah,
Bekah: so,uh,let's take us in the
direction of culture citizenship,
cuz I know that's something that
we all have talked about as
maintainers in our conversation.
And so,culture citizenship,
there's a section in our code of
conduct about that.And so let's
see,the beginning of it says,and
we'll link this in the show
notes,one of the many goals of
this code of conduct is to
strengthen our community uplift
and encourage each other and to
recognize the positive effects of
our community on the industry as
a whole.Um,well I,let's start
there.I feel like maybe I,we
could break this down into
separate conversations.So the
idea of what are the positive
effects of our community on the
industry as a whole?What are we
trying to do at virtual coffee
that impacts more than the
immediate group of people?
Dan: I think there's a lot of
things,uh,personally,I mean,
sorry I don't jump in,but like I,
I was in today in virtual coffee.
We were talking about,uh,in my
breakout room,we were talking
about mentorship and you know,
how to learn.And somebody was
using,or thinking about using,
uh,code,code mentors or some sort
of service right?To,to basically
help them learn,um,help them
accomplish some tests.And we were
talking,and this was a new member
who hadn't,this was their first
time and hadn't been in the
slack.And we spent a lot of time
just talking about,um,our
community and how we've,like,how
virtual coffee has like,helped
each other.Um,learn how to learn,
you know,and learn how to,and
especially along with that,learn
how to ask for help and also
learn how to give help in.
Constructive ways.And I
personally,just speaking for
myself,have,I feel like I have
taken a lot of those lessons,uh,
over the last few years.A few
years,two years,three years.
Yeah.We're coming up on three
years.Right.Anyway,um,
Bekah: We've completed three
Dan: we have completed three
years.And,uh,that's what I said.
And,um,uh,I'll just have my
editor edit that out.I'm just
kidding.It's me.Um,and we have,
all right,I lost track of what I
was saying.Oh yeah.My personal
experience is I have become,
I've,I feel like I've become a
better,um,developer just from
learning how to learn better,
right.And learning how to ask
questions better and learning
like what kinds of things can I
ask questions about it,at what
point do I ask the question,what
point do I form?Like how do I
formulate a good,a good question
to get some help and or generate
some discussion?And I feel like
just as there's a lot of aspects,
and this is the only one of'em,
but,um,Creating better
developers,honestly,is like a,a
way that we are,uh,you know,
maybe having some positive
impact,impact on the greater
developer community and not just
developers,but better.Um,I don't
know,people,I don't know.I,I
like,I I want to,you know,we're,
we're not all developers,but I
feel like a lot of these lessons
apply to,to everybody.Um,and so,
I dunno,that's,that's my bit.
First thing that jumped in.
Julia: Yeah,no,I think that's,I
think the idea of like better
people,it's not just like a
throwaway,I mean,the purpose,the
purpose of any of the work that
we do in the end is about making
people's lives better,right?Like
what's,you know,the,the end goal
of any piece of software
hopefully has something to do
with improving,improving people's
lives in some way.Um,and I,I feel
like that's not just a,an empty.
It's like an,you know,an empty
value promise.You know,it's not
just marketing speak within the
VC community,like people really
take that idea to heart.Um,and it
gets talked about and expanded on
in a lot of different ways within
the community.And I,I have to
imagine that that spills over
into,um,what people are doing in
their jobs.You know,I've,like,
with my background as an educator
and like working in this sort of
developer experience,developer
education space,like I've,worked
with other VC members to kind of
f flesh out proposals for
changing processes in their
workplaces.Um,And,you know,that
kind of embrace those,like that
shared value,those shared
principles.Um,and I,I think it's,
I think it's really good to have
a community where people are
actually talking about those
things separate from,like,
anybody who's worried about the
budget or,you know,the,the
performance reviews.Like having
those conversations and seeing
what other people are doing with
those principles,like independent
of your workplace.I'd like to
think it has value.I don't really
know how to,how to be sure.But.
Bekah: What's interesting too,
um,I think it was Mark Newnan who
works at Cypress,posted about
where are the questions,maybe the
intro questions that we use in
virtual coffee.So I may want to
be using these for my team
meetings,right?And so even simple
things like that,I think that
there's value to be able to see
like,hey,this is something that
works in our community and I
wanna ex.Extend it to my other
parts of other communities that
I'm involved in.And one of the
things that,one of the ways that
I like to think of virtual coffee
is there's this idea of like the
ripple effect,right?Like you make
an impact on someone and that
ripples out to the next person,
and then they pass that on to the
next person.And so if we can
interact with each other very
positively,if we can share a
supportive environment,if we can
help people understand what a
positive space looks like,then
that's going to continue to move
out into the tech industry.So
although we cannot support
everybody being virtual coffee
members,hopefully through that
extension of our members into
other communities,they'll still
be able to experience that
positivity as well.
Julia: Right,right.Yeah,for sure.
Like I think,you know,other
communities that I'm involved in,
other organizations,like even
outside the tech industry,I
reflect on conversations that
I've had inside vc.That inform
like kind of how I relate to
people or ideas that I might
suggest in those communities too.
So,
Kirk: Yeah.And I think there's
also like a real,there's a real
nice,like,I was gonna use the
phrase value proposition,that's
not really it,but just,uh,what do
you call it?Like,uh,like gut
check.Like we have a lot of cut
check moments where people kind
like,Hey,I just started a new
job.Or like,Hey,I'm gonna have
this conversation if my manager,
Hey,I just had this conversation
with someone.My workplace like,
what is your take on this
scenario?And this is one of the
few spaces where I feel like I'm
gonna get.Like reasonable,
meaningful responses,you know,
and people will try their best to
answer earnestly.Um,and then
everyone might not have like,be
in perfect agreement.Like the
amalgamation of those things like
usually puts me in like a,a
better place or whoever's asking
the question,you know,and folks
can feel reasonably assured,
like,this is a bunch of responses
of like,my best interest in mind.
I can sort of take those and kind
of go with it.So,you know,like we
have the help parenting channel
where people ask,sometimes ask
like very specific questions
like,oh,I can't like get this a
diiv to diiv.Um,but people also
ask questions like,I'm about to
have like,my first performance
review.Like what should I expect?
It's not only a place to like set
expectations of what is maybe
like the standard or usual
behavior.It's also a place to set
expectations of like how you
should advocate for yourself.Um,
what behaviors like should,you
know,like it's,it's,it's a great
place to sort of establish like,
The right thing to do versus just
like the thing that happens,uh,
which is a nuance that sometimes
feels lost in like the greater
tech world.Like people are like,
oh,well this goes like this,
which isn't the same as like this
is how this should go,or this is
how it could go if everyone
involved was like trying to act
like more empathy to get towards
a good solution.So I like the
space for that.That feels pretty
good.
Dan: Yeah.And I think another
valuable thing that,um,virtual
coffee does that maybe some other
communities don't do,and there's
lots of other great communities
out there in the world,but,uh,
where,you know,our,our,like,our
focus on intimacy and
face-to-face interactions and,
you know,our,our coffees,which
are,are like main,you know,
obviously our main thing.Um,want
to say that I,I feel like that
is,is,proving to people the
importance of,of these,of,kinds
of effects,right?And lots of
times,you know,people get too
involved in like Slack or
whatever,and async communication
and all that stuff is important
and,and valuable,especially on.
You know,international teams,
teams of time zones and
everything like that.Um,but there
is something to be said about
the,small interactions.These,
like intimate,you know,uh,not
just our coffees,right?We have
our coffees in our bigger rooms.
We also have like the co-working
room,right?Which is another like
little,almost like a little
community inside our community.
Uh,and,um,I,and lots of people
talk about the coworking room as
like one of the special things
of,of virtual coffee.And um,uh,
Justin,one of our members just
did a,made a coworking room set
up,uh,for his,for his company,
and,uh,was pretty excited about
that too,which,which is cool.And
I guess what I wanna say is like,
the importance and the value of
these sort of interactions,um,is
something that's hard to quantify
and is something maybe hard to
explain,you know?Uh,but
experiencing it,um,is something
different.And that's,that's one
thing that our community does
really well.And I think another
way that we sort of can to make
the greater world,you know,
better,a better place for people
is,uh,is sharing this sort of
interaction and,um,sharing this
process,you know,uh,and,and
letting people in the world,uh,
try to practice it on their own.
Bekah: Yeah,and I think that's
really important.I know that we
talk a lot about there's a value
for community for every person,
so we encourage a lot of people
to find the right community for
them.Um,but then also
understanding that there's a
value for community for the
entire industry.It benefits the
industry when people find
community and a sense of
belonging.Um,because then they
can take what they learn in those
spaces and they can apply it to
where they are and the things
that they're doing.Um,the next
part of the culture citizenship
definition that we have,I really
like it's as if you see someone
who's making an extra effort to
ensure our community is
welcoming,friendly,and encourages
all participants to contribute to
the fullest extent.Please
recognize their efforts.And that
seems really nice because right
now,um,it is virtual coffee.Um,
Community Kindness month,I think
because this is,we've completed
our third year of virtual coffee.
We're moving into our fourth
year,and that's one of those
things that,that positive,
recognizing the positive
interactions,recognizing the
people who are giving back,I
think is a really important part
of setting the tone for what a
good community looks like.Um,and
so,you know,we are very,very
thankful for all of the people
who volunteer at Virtual Coffee
in different capacities and who
provide feedback and who are
willing to talk us through
different discussions and have
challenging conversations with
us.Because I think that,you know,
even in the hard conversations,
there's a lot of beauty and
understanding that comes out of
that because we can work on
listening,we can work on
accepting feedback,and we can
grow from that as well.
Julia: Yeah,I think that it's
also kind of an important
distinction maybe for people who
are newer to the community is
part of,know,I haven't used Code
Mentor or one of those sort of
paid spaces before,but I think
it's really important to kind of
continually recognize that
everybody who's part of VC is
doing it.Because they wanna be
there and because it is bringing
value to them.but that we need to
not take that for granted,you
know?Um,it's really important to
acknowledge and show,you know,be
thankful,you know,act
proactively,kind of showing your
gratitude to people.yeah,I don't
know.I just,and I think about
that particularly like with those
hard conversations that like,
part of being part of a
community,it's like if you want
it to be a better place,if you
want people to grow,sometimes
you're gonna have to.Do a little
work to help people grow,right?
Like we grow through our
relationships with others.Um,
but,and,and if you,and like if
you are on the receiving end of
somebody else's emotional work,
like it's important to
acknowledge that and thank them
for it and like be gracious about
the work that they are investing
in you and in the community.Um,
and I don't,I'm kind of rambling,
but I don't know.I just,I think
that that's,um,it's something
that maybe is not immediately
obvious how important that is.I
think.
Kirk: Yeah.Um,like while we were
talking about this in sort of
like the earlier point,you know,
like the difference between like
hearing code mentors,um,it's
really important that like the
intrinsic value of like being a
VC member is just like being a VC
member.Like this is a space where
you know,as much as possible,
like your worth is not determined
by like,how many lines of Python
you write or like your industry
experience or your job title,or
like,You know,any of that,you
know,like as a VC member,you are
like a whole and fully formed
person,and like you as a person
are the thing that like,makes you
like wonderful and valuable and
appreciated and like everything
else,sort of like,I don't know,
the,the only sort of thing there
is that again,like coming back to
the code of conduct and like
trying to treat each other the
way we wanna be treated and like
willing to have these
conversations and like,that's,
that's the gist of it.But,you
know,it's,it's one of the things
that I,I appreciate the most
about this community is that you
can come in this community sort
of wherever you are at.You know,
and in that,in that realm of like
making an effort at like
stewardship and making an effort
at empathy and making an effort,
like listening and understanding.
And then you know,like there's no
VC member tier,you know what I
mean?Like,um,And you're never
gonna like be evaluated here by
like your productivity or by,
like,that's,that's not the goal.
which is difficult to find like
in other tech spaces cuz they're
usually so hyper-focused on a
thing or a product or a tool or a
lifestyle where you find yourself
like having these like
architectures starting to be
assembled and then we end up in
this place,which I think can be
really dangerous.Where like,um,I
don't know the words like
culture,stewardship,community
like,can fall by the wayside
because we go like,oh,well this
person's good at this,or this
person's like,been here for a
long time.And I think one of the
things that like I try,I try like
more to challenge myself on is
like doing those objective
moments of,you know,Because I've
been here for a long time,I have
so much context that comes with
me into like every single
interaction and like finding ways
to step back and be like,oh,am I
actually making a good decision
here?Or is this like the weight
of my experiences,like pushing me
in one direction or another.And
then always trying to come back
to like,am I doing the best job
for all the people involved in
whatever's happening,including
myself sometimes.but that's not a
one and done or that's not like a
Oh,okay,I've nailed
communication.I am done learning
the end.that's never gonna
happen.And especially now,now
like membership is opening in,we
do have a constant cycle of new
members coming in,returning
members coming in,different
people interacting in different
ways.And just like,it's really
important to always have the
rudder of.What's the thing I'm
gonna try and use whenever I'm in
this space to try and like,make
it as good as possible for all
the people in this space.And
like,we always,like,always comes
back down to am I actually
listening to the other person?Am
I actually trying to understand
the perspective that they're
coming with?And like,am I willing
to come in with the idea that
like my stance might not be the
best stance or the appropriate
stance or like,I have something
to learn here.You know?and that's
not easy,right?Like,that's not
for free,that's not automatic.
Even though I think like we would
like it to be,it would be nice if
we could say,oh yeah,like my
empathy meter is always on max
and I'm doing great,but sometimes
it's not.and that's just like
being people and I don't know,
going all the way back to the
start of this conversation,what
Julia was saying,like,that's,
that's why I'm here.I'm like here
to like practice being like a
person.Being a person means like
also being a person when I really
don't wanna be,when I'd rather be
like Chad,g p t,I never wanna be
like Chad,g p t,but you know,
Julia: when I was teaching high
school,I used to sometimes say
that like,part of my job was
helping my students learn to be
people.And not that they're not
people,but like,they're not fully
realized people.And,uh,yeah,
sometimes I'd like to just be a
teenager again and not have to
like be fully accountable for
myself.But,um,the flip side of
that is that I think this and
this is part of what made VC so
valuable to me when I first
joined the community.which was a
little more than two years ago,
is like,this is a place Where
people really are valued for
their whole selves.Like,I found
so many opportunities to give,
even when I was like a rank
beginner in the tech industry.
there's still so much opportunity
to contribute and teach and share
and,and help.you know,if you,if I
think the flip side of that is
like that we do want people to be
like fully accountable human
beings.Like,not act like
teenagers.Not that there's
anything wrong with teenagers,
but.
Dan: There's nothing wrong with
teenagers.
Julia: Yeah,
Kirk: As a former teenager,I can
say there are a lot of things
wrong with me as a teenager.
Julia: they're
Kirk: wasn't terrible,but you
know.
Julia: That's what.
Bekah: Well,I think,you know,a,
as part of this idea of culture,
citizenship and all of the things
that we're talking about,and,uh,
in some ways,like we're in our
toddlerhood at virtual coffee,
right?And so,like,we are still
growing and as the community
grows,things change,change,the
members grow.Um,there's new
perspectives,there's new,um,
things that you need to
understand new,um,ideas that you
need to be sensitive to or,um,
often good opportunities for
listening rather than responding,
which is something that I can say
I'm working on.Um,and I'm better
than when I first started.But,
you know,a lot of times there
were things that I,I wanted to
react to immediately.And I think
like,you know,there's a,that
growth that you have as.There you
have to,you know,listen and,uh,
be willing to understand
different aspects of what people
are saying to you.And I think
that,um,that's really important
when we talk about this idea of
focusing on the impact of our
actions rather than our intent.
And I think that's one of those
things that can be really tricky
to understand.Um,does anybody
want to explain what that means?
Kirk: I'll give it a try.Um,
yeah,no,I feel like this is,I
don't know,this is like one of
the most important things,as
Bekah said,like,we're,we're three
years in storming,norming,
forming.What's the fourth one
performing?I can't remember.
There's a whole thing about it.I
did a class one.Um,but yeah,
there's,there's this being a
bunch of people in a space,being
a bunch of different people in a
space,being a bunch of different
people in a space where the like
boundaries are like,Good
communication,like good
stewardship and all these things
inevitable,inevitably you end up
in a space where it's like,
sometimes I'm having
conversations or I maybe always
be having conversations where I
probably think I'm right,but like
what happens if someone else
doesn't think I'm right?Right.
What happens if like most people
don't think I'm right or you
know,what happens if like someone
else is sing wrong,but I still
think it.Right.And like trying
to,to navigate that.Um,and you
know,just like for,for context
before,it's like in,in our
language and whenever we talk
about official VC language,there
are a couple things we always
want to establish.Like we always
want to have our documentation
the way that like makes it clear.
The values,like we're encouraging
people to like try and like
inhabit like,but in a way that
doesn't try and like suppress
themselves,right?It's like,hey,
these are things that are good
for the group.And not in a way of
like trying to squeeze your
behavior into some manner too,
but just like providing the
guardrails to like just help a
community flourish.And,you know,
I don't see online,like virtual
communities are very similar just
like I r L communities and the
fact that like you have to share
spaces with people who may have
slightly different values in you,
but you still have to kind of
make that work.Um,and yeah.Then
getting back to sort of the
question of like actions and
intent.sometimes or frequently I
feel like almost all the time,
like we have good intent.Um,
there are very few people who
come in with bad intent and one
thing I like about this
community,I can say like,I don't
know.I can count on one hand the
amount of times where I feel like
someone is coming into an
interaction with bad intent.Uh,
but for whatever reason,the
actual action,you know,like was
probably not like,received in the
way that they expected it to.Uh,
and then what I tend to feel
like,regardless of the side or
like where you are in that
conversation,there's always an
opportunity for like,am I having
this conversation in a way that
like,gets me to what I want?And
typically the thing I want is
like,I want this other person to
understand my perspective and be
able to receive where that's
coming from.Um,and sometimes like
it's very easy to do yourself a
disservice in the way you do
that.Right.And I don't know,
that's,that's usually like most
of the time that's where like
communication breaks down where
people either feel like I'm not
being heard,uh,I'm not being
understood.Or sometimes like,I'm
not being like empathized with
like,and I don't know,navigating
that I feel like is probably the
crux of human interaction,right?
Like it's,it's the thing like we,
we try and teach each other all
the time and that willingness to
be like,I don't know if I agree
with this person in this moment,
but you know,like I wanna have
the conversation that like,
brings me closer to understanding
where they're coming from.And
even if the ultimate idea at the
end is that,like,I still don't
necessarily agree like what
they're doing,but there's
probably a way to get like why
they're doing it or like what are
the themes or what's going
through their mind as they're
doing it.Um,the other tricky
thing that's been brought up a
lot of times cuz you know,
especially.maintainers,like we
spend a lot of time just talking
to members,right?Members come to
us and they tell us what's going
on,and we always have this open
policy where you can always tell
us like what you're feeling,what
you're thinking about
interactions,what are your
thoughts in this space,you know,
like it's,I think like,like we
try and be a safe space always
for people to share their
experiences and thoughts and
feelings.Um,a lot of times folks
will say like,I'm not sure if I
navigated this well or I'm not
sure if I did the right thing
here.Um,or you know,like very
frequently,like most,you know,in
the,in the coffees are on video
and we're speaking,but you know,
a lot of VC communication happens
in the Slack and that's all text
based and context is like super
hard when it's text-based,you
know,and the thing you sort of
never get is like a body language
or people's emotional reactions
or just like where they're coming
from from the day and there's a,
I don't know,there's a bunch of
things in there and I feel like
it all boils down to we are
always going to be trying to say
things of good intent.Um,if that
is received negatively,like
that's where like the actual
conversation begins.Like,where do
we go from there and can we get
this back to a good place?And
sometimes like,well,can I get
this back to a good place alone?
Or maybe I need to ask for
support.And that's another place
where the maintainers can like,
be a great value and a great
asset,you know.Um,but always,
always,always this idea of,at
least for me,coming into every
conversation with the person I'm
talking to,um,is a good and
wonderful person.They have like,
they have a need to communicate
and like values that they want to
share and express and be
understood.And it is in my job,
like it is in like,it's kind of
like,I don't know,for me,My duty
is one who wants to like keep
this space as good as it is to
like recognize that and then use
that as my lead into further
conversation.Even if the
conversation ends up being like,
Hey,this action like may not be
in line with our community
standards,or,Hey,this response
may not be in line of our
community standards,but it's
never Yeah,go
Julia: Hey,this response may not
be in line with like,Who,you
know,how you see yourself,right?
Like,and that,and that could be a
hard thing to say to somebody
directly,but I think it's a,I
think it's an important thing to
reflect on,right?That sometimes
the things that we say and do,
like maybe aren't,maybe we,you
know,I don't think we can expect
perfection out of anybody.I'm not
perfect,you know,like I've said
and done things that I'm like,oh
shoot.But like,part of it is
owning that.Like when you,when
you,you know,when somebody says,
Hey,that hurt.Um,being like,oh,
sh well shoot,that was not my
plan.Like,you know,help me un you
know,if,if you can help me
understand why that was hurtful,
you know,if it's not immediately
obvious And that's kinda what I
mean about like,if you want the
community to grow,like,you know,
I,I know that part of the
conversation around like assume
good intent me maybe being not a
great standard is that it puts
the burden on the person who is
like in a less powerful position.
and so I think like the way to
maybe handle that to some extent
is for,is for people who,whose
intent is being challenged to be
like,oh,like now is the time for
me to step back and like,and act,
you know,and sort of actively
seek to remediate whatever harm I
might have caused.Like I.It's not
that we expect people to be a
hundred percent perfect all the
time,it's that we expect people
to try to do better.and I just
like,in terms of simple
strategies,one of the things I
really like that Bekah that you
do is that you'll,you'll say
like,I don't know what I think
about this right now.Like,I'm
gonna think about this and come
back to this.And like,we could
probably all stand to do that.I
dunno,I did sort of cut you off.
I.
Kirk: No,I,I think those points
were great.And yeah,like in a,
sometimes in a time where it
feels like you're always expected
to have a stance and a strong
stance and an immediate stance on
whatever topic become your way.I
do think it's very powerful
sometimes to be like,I am not in
the place,or I am not ready to
have this conversation yet.Um,
and just like gracefully allow
yourself that time to kind of get
there.Uh,but yeah.The last thing
I was just sort of thinking about
in like the context of all this,
it kind of reminds me of exercise
in a weird way.Like in a sense
like exercise is like being like
sometimes uncomfortable for the
sake of like long term comfort.
You know,like when you finish
doing like,like your muscles
hurt,your legs hurt.It's like,
but it's acute.And like that is
assumed to be a good thing.Like
in the general scheme,like that's
a good thing.Chronic pain is bad.
So a lot of times when I think
about community interactions,you
know,like what's going through my
head is not like,oh,there were no
uncomfortable conversations this
week.This was a good week.Right?
Because that's not a,like,that's
not the right frame of mind.It's
like,oh,we had some income from
conversations,but we navigated in
them and like got to a good
place.That feels good for me.
Like that's like acute discomfort
that leads to long-term comfort
because then like,we're now more
empowered to have those
conversations and everyone can
feel safe having like,I don't
know,and this,this is like a very
negative thought,but I always
have this idea of like,
empowerment is like still feeling
safety in moments of discomfort,
you know?And like being able to,
to like dis like establish what
is like long-term chronic.Bad,
and like moments of bad,I feel
like I can deal with this moment
of bad,um,because the other
people around me,like we're all
working together to get out of
this,you know,it's like being on
an island with a bunch of other
people or being on an island
naked by yourself and pooping in
the water.You know,they're
fairly,they're very different.
but yeah,and that is,you know,
like,and the reason why the
maintainers,like what we're
having this conversation now is
like,as we've just collected a
bunch of like,surveys from the
members and we've been having all
these conversations really,
really,really like putting in the
time into thinking about,um,how
we want the community to move
forward as a community.What does
good stewardship look like?What
does support look like?What does
moderation look like?And all
these conversations kind of come
into play.And like,the big answer
is,it's hard and complicated,but
like,I.One of the pillars is if,
for me at least,if we end up in a
place where when a difficult
conversation happens,there's not
a moment of feeling like panic or
loss of control for the people
involved and like,okay,we're here
now,but we can probably get out
of here in a good place.That's
what feels good to me.Not a space
where no one ever does any
difficult conversations,cuz I
don't think that's possible.
Bekah: Yeah,and I think when that
happens,you're l.Using
opportunities to grow,right?Like
you're settling for not being
uncomfortable.And one of the
great things about being part of
a supportive community is that
you have those opportunities to
be uncomfortable.You can fail and
you can learn from that
experience,right?You can ask for
forgiveness,you can ask for
feedback and to grow.And so I
think that,yeah,sometimes it does
get exhausting having those hard
conversations,but like you're
saying,the it is valuable to have
those hard conversations and to
figure out how to work through
them.
Kirk: Yeah.And to,to your point,
just sort of like,also,one of the
nice things about an online space
is like,again,a lot of times,
like you have the buffer to
choose when you want to opt in to
like,I.There's not always a sense
of like,immediacy,even though
that's how we feel,you know?
Like,and it's,it's okay to say,
hey,like,well,I need to take a
step back right now.Um,not
because this is unimportant,but
because this is important,you
know?And I wanna like come back
when,when I can,like,when I can
learn and grow from this as best
as I can and like I can like meet
people where they are.And when I
can empathize for other people,
that's something I really want to
do.Um,and I'll,I'll say this
conversation,I'll mention the
conversation I had once with my
dad.My father as a interesting
man,but one time he was like,you
know,Kirk,you and your brother
are so nice.You're such nice
guys.I'm not nice like you are.
And I was feeling not in my most
empathetic place at that point in
time with my father.And I was
like,no man.We just try to be
nice.Like we're not,there's
nothing magical about whatever is
is happening.You know,like it's
just trying really hard sometimes
to like,even,even in the moments
where I don't want to,still
trying to maybe do my best and if
I can't do my best,I take five
minutes.I'm like,okay,maybe I can
do it in five minutes and then
maybe I can do it in10minutes.
You're like,maybe I need to like
eat a sandwich first.Many times I
need to eat a sandwich first.You
know,that it's not,it's not
something that goes away.And I
think like if you sort of like
never choose to go into those
moments,then you're kind of like
opting out of some important
things.But also in the context of
all of this,like we all have our
lived lives and we all have our
traumas and we all have our
journeys.So it's also a thing
that like,I never wanna like
force on anyone.I just want to
say that like I would like this
community to be a space where it
is a space where you can also do
those things,you know,and feel
like even though it's hard in the
moment,it's gonna be like good in
the long run.That is not what I
told my dad I was,I was,I had to
apologize after.
Bekah: I was gonna say that's a
really great way to end this
episode,but maybe it's still a
really great way.Apologies are
important and useful too.Uh,does
anybody else want to wrap us up
in this conversation?
Julia: I don't know.I'm just
imagining perks,like trying to
say that.Try anyone trying to say
that to their father.Just I feel
like that's a tough dynamic.Um,
and,and that's like maybe
there're maybe there's a place
to,to wrap things up.Sometimes
the dynamics between two given
people like are kind of rough
and,you know,we're all here to,
to help you navigate and
hopefully,you know,help people
see the,the good in each other.
And,so I'm from a very quiet
family.I don't know.We're just
not,we do a lot of not talking
and,my partner's family is the
opposite.And I very,I,I remember
the first time I like went to
visit with their whole family
there and it was like there was
one piece of chicken left after
everybody had eaten and it was
like,Oh my God.People are gonna
come to blows over a chicken
thigh,like,what is going on?and I
was like,I was really stressed
and I was like,oh my God,I can't,
I can't handle this.Like I'm
getting indigestion.Um,and
afterward,and I kind of,I was
like,you guys,you guys like,it's
gonna be okay.There's more to
eat.And people were looking at me
like,there was something wrong
with me.Like,why is she reacting
this way to like,what was for
them a very ordinary conversation
about who,who had the right to
the last piece of chicken.And
like,there's no right way or
wrong way to communicate in that
situation.and like sometimes
you're gonna get freaked out by
the way other people communicate.
And it doesn't mean they're bad
people and it doesn't mean
they're actually going to come to
blows over a piece of chicken.
and it doesn't mean that they
think there's anything wrong with
your communication style either.
curiosity is really powerful.and
I think in those moments where
you like,feel a little
apprehension about other people,
like it's good to try to turn
that apprehension into some
curiosity.And,
Kirk: That's the new podcast name
not sent to my dad.Um,can I do
like one more call to action
maybe.Um,yeah.So like one last
thing,you know,as we're,it's like
if you're listening and like any
of this seems interesting to you
or important to you or valuable
to you,again,like just super
encouraging everyone,reach out to
us,reach out to the maintainers.
We're always looking for feedback
from members.Um,we're always
happy to talk.I'm always happy to
talk.And you know,like we're,
we're really trying to like,in
the idea that like we will
constantly,like we will never
stop trying to improve these
things and make them better.So
we're always open to hearing what
people have to say.So it is never
too late.Like,don't,like give,
missed your chance,what the
surveys are done to like,talk to
us.You can always talk to us and
just let us know.And every single
piece of feedback from any member
here helps us,uh,make this a
better space.and my actual final
thing is,Julia,that attitude of
your is over.That chicken is not
gonna help you on the desert
island.You need
Julia: But I'm by myself.
Kirk: are you really?There's
dangers out there.
Julia: I think I'm by myself.
Bekah,am I by myself?
Bekah: Um,maybe there are
alligators,I guess.
Dan: Just,just don't drink,don't
drink the water on the east side
of the island.
Julia: eat with your left hand.
That's
Bekah: Well,thanks everybody for
listening to this episode of the
podcast.We hope that you found
some value in the conversation
that we had.Uh,and thank you If
you're one of our community
members for sticking with us.
Julia: Hi.Thanks everybody.
Dan: Thanks everybody.Thank you
so much for listening to this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
Podcast.This episode was produced
by Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot
Weigel,and edited by Ashley
Mulder.If you have questions or
comments,you can hit us up on
Twitter@VirtualCoffeeIO or email
us at podcast@virtualcoffee.io
You can find the show notes,sign
up for the newsletter,buy some VC
merch,and check out all of our
other resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io If you're
interested in sponsoring virtual
Coffee,you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week.