Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season eight, episode two of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
. I am Bekah, and this is a
podcast that features members
of the Virtual Coffee community.
Virtual Coffee is an intimate
tech community of people at all
stages of their tech journey,
and they're here on this podcast
and sharing their stories and
what they've learned here with
me today is my co-host, Dan.
Dan: What up Bek?
Bekah: what's up?
Dan: Yo.Um, not much.
Um, today we have another great
as usual episode for y'all.
Um, we have Alex Curtis-Slep,
uh, here with us.
Alex is a self-taught software
developer, and a long time,
you know, Virtual Coffee
member, Virtual Coffee
volunteer, and uh, really.
All around great person.
He's one of our, you
know, I think most
common, uh, room leaders.
He does an amazing job at that.
And, um, is, uh, you
know, I don't know.
He's a great, he's a great,
uh, member of our community,
so, uh, we're very happy to
have him on the podcast today.
Bekah: Yeah.
And one of the things that
I really like from this
episode is Alex talking a
lot about balancing learning
as a developer, but also
there's other hobbies and
passions that you bring
as a human person, right?
Like we're not just developers.
We have these other things
that we do, and I think that.
It's really important to
acknowledge all of the different
pieces of us, and I appreciate
Alex, uh, tolerating maybe,
uh, encouraging our questions
to, um, dive into some of
those other parts of us that
become really important to
understand who we are as people
and by extension developers.
Dan: Yeah, I totally agree.
I, I mean, I, I think he had
a, a really awesome outlook
on, on all that stuff.
How to, how to stay healthy
and, you know, in general
happy as as a developer.
And, um, he had a lot of
good ideas to sort of help
you do that, uh, in a.
manageable way, right?
As, uh, we still have to
work, you know, uh, sometimes
even, even sometimes when
we're not feeling great.
And there's, there's a lot
of, there's a lot of ways to
help you get through that.
And I think Alex had some, some
great ideas for that process.
Bekah: Absolutely.
We start every episode of the
podcast, like we start every
Virtual Coffee with introducing
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do in
a random check-in question.
We hope you enjoy this episode.
today's question is, would
you rather go on road trips
or fly to a different country?
My name is Bekah.
I am a person in tech from
a small town in Ohio, and I
think that it has to do with
who you're taking a trip with.
I think road trips can be really
fun, but if it's like road trip
with my kids where we're driving
in a car for a long amount
of time, they are not going
to be happy and then that's
not going to be super fun.
So maybe I would fly with them
to a different country, but I
would not road trip with them.
Although I think road
tripping would be very fun.
Dan: Nice.Uh.Hi, I'm Dan.
I am also a person in tech
and I live in Cleveland.
And, uh, yeah, I love road trips.
I mean, I, I don't mind flying
places or whatever, but, um, I'm
a big, big fan of road tripping
and I would, I have road
tripped in two other countries,
you know, well, I guess one,
but, you know, I've done it.
I'm gonna do it again.
Uh, it's good times.
Um, it would be cool to.
Go to Europe and drive around.
I suppose they have like all the
trains and stuff like that too.
But you
Bekah: I feel like
you're cheating.
You're like, I'm going to
fly to a different country
and road trip there.
That's not the question
Dan: gosh, uh, can you drive to,
can you drive to South America?
Like from North America?
Is there a bridge over
like the canal and stuff?
Alex: I dunno one.
Bekah: feel like you're
pushing it there.
Dan: I've driven to of
times and I'm gonna do
it again this summer.
So, yeah, I, I'm with road trips.
Road trips are fun.I like them.
That's my answer.
Alex: Cool.
Bekah: Welcome, Alex.Go ahead.
Alex: Thanks for having me.
I'm Alex.
I'm a software developer  in
the Tampa Bay, Florida area and.
My choice would be to
fly to my destination.
As much as I also love
road trips, I think flying
is, is my number one.
Bekah: Nice.Sounds good.
Dan: I'm not a big
fan of airports or
like being in planes.
I mean, like, I I like being
in the air, but it's just
like the, these planes with
all the, you know, you're all
packed in together and stuff.
Alex: Yeah,
Dan: I think that's
my main thing.
Bekah: I took my girls to
Houston last week, Texas.
And so we had to fly and it
was their first time on a plane
and I some of it, but it was so
funny, like they were so loud
because they were so excited.
They're like, did you feel that?
What?Look at that.
And I was just like, the,
joy that they had flying for
the first time was so fun.
Alex: Yeah, that's cool.
Bekah: So welcome Alex.
We are very, very
happy to have you here.
Alex is a longtime member and
volunteer at Virtual Coffee,
and we wanna get started
with your origin story.
So before we jump into that,
what is one word that describes
your developer journey?
Alex: Well, I think at this
point, I'll say gratifying.
I think that so many people
have welcomed me with open
arms and given me great
support and allowed me to be.
Who I am and really just try to
cater to what I'm trying to do.
And I just think that that's
been so moving for me on
a lot of different levels.
And so I would just say
gratifying ultimately.
Bekah: I love that.
That's really great.
So talk to us a little bit
about what that journey
looked like for you.
Alex: Yeah.so.
I'd always been interested in
I've had a blog since early
2002, and so my first exposure
to coding was customizing
HTML and CSS on, on that site.
And I didn't think too much, uh,
about coding at the time as far
as, uh, the importance or the
frequency that I would do it.
I was just trying to make my
site look how I wanted it, Later
on 2019, um, I was following
Madison Cannon's, uh, YouTube
channel and email list, and,
uh, she made a course about.
Creating a developer roadmap.
And I thought, okay, you
know, I'll give this a shot,
um, just one time fee and
you know, just 50 bucks and
I'll get this a shot and
see, see what I think of it.
Um, got nothing to lose
and I really liked it.
Um, I took a course from
Treehouse on, on front end
development and that was kind
of my, my aha so to speak,
about coding and, and this
software development stuff,
and went from there and,
Did react and open source,
and of course jumped into VC
and got to meet more people.
Um, so it just really kind of
brought light to the whole,
uh, the whole scene and,
and now I'm meeting more of
these people in person and
it's just been an uh, uphill
climb, I guess you could say.
And, uh, it's been fun.
So there's a lot of great
people here and we're all just
supporting each other and, and.
Enjoying enjoying it.
So I think that's ultimately
what life's about.
Bekah: Yeah, I love that.
Okay, and I wanna take
a step back for a second
because I think you're
the only person I've ever
heard talk about Madison.
And can's course.
So, uh, how did you
first discover it?
Was it through Twitter and
then you started the course?
Alex: Um, so I don't know if
the course is currently still
active, but, um, at the time I.
Initially found her YouTube
channel just looking different
random stuff on YouTube,
and I was on her email list
and then she subsequently.
Notified us about the course
and uh, now I think that
we're still running the code
book club there on Discord.
And uh, so that's still
a weekly active thing and
uh, I tend to be there.
I've missed the last couple
weeks, but I love that group.
And there's a core group of
people that have been around,
uh, since around the same time.
VC started in 2020, and
that's a great group of
people and we always really.
Like, just like if you do
in vc, we grow together
and we really work on our
skills and it's fantastic.
Bekah: That's great.
So what was that course like?
Alex: That course,
um, was more about.
Exploring different options.
Okay, you can take courses on
this platform or that platform,
and here's the comparison
of maybe a self-directed
path to a bootcamp path.
And it was more about exploring
the options you have to, to
become a developer and, and then
just trying to encourage people
to jump into the option that
they felt was best for them.
Bekah: I love that.
I think that's really important.
And a lot of the challenges
that new folks have coming
into tech is figuring out
that exact thing, right?
Especially like there's
so much out there that you
could be doing or learning.
And I know at one point
I was doing a Udacity
Nanodegree program and it
was like, Soul crushing it
wanted me to die inside and
Alex: Oh wow.
Bekah: you know, I, I'm, I'm
not cut out for this because
I can't sit here and watch
these videos and finish it.
And then I found Flatiron
School and that ended up
working way better for me.
And it was a, it
was a game changer.
But when you're first exploring
that thing, especially if you
don't have a group of people
there to kind of advise you
or to ask questions to, it
can be really hard to figure
out what works for you.
Alex: For sure.
And, um, you know, Madison
definitely helped me in a lot
in the beginning, like taking
time to just do one-on-ones
and just see where I was,
going and progressing and
having that support and,
and that community, whether
it be virtual or in person.
Uh, Like we cultivate here at
VC is, is critical and it really
just enables people to level up
and it allows people to, to get
the feedback that they need to,
to change courses they need.
And I think that really
just helps people so much.
And it's something that
really is, uh, a chord of
how I try to live my life.
And it's been inspiring
to see how we do that on
a, on an everyday basis.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's
great AVO advice and I wanna,
um, turn to one of you.
Your tweets and we'll link
it in the show notes, but it
was from February, I think,
of this year, and it says,
take care of yourself to
bring your best each day.
Stay active, well rested,
eat fresh foods, hydrate, and
maintain great relationships
as much as possible.
You'll write better code and
have a lot better day today.
And I just love that
so much because I feel
like we often get lost.
Um, in all the heaviness of the
stuff that's going on around us
or the stress of learning or the
stress of getting a promotion
and all of those things.
And it can be really hard to
stay well-rounded and balanced.
And I think one of the things
I've always been most impressed
with you about is that you seem
to do a really good job of that.
So, so can you talk a little
bit about how you kind
of maintain that balance?
Cause it can be really hard.
Alex: Well, thanks,
uh, for, for thinking.
I do a great job of it.
It's definitely a volatile thing.
There's no, there's
no doubt about it.
I actually got to, uh, my
office 10 minutes before this
podcast, so, uh, there we go.
Um, but.You know, I think it's
just important to, to
acknowledge our humanity,
but then try to do our best.
Um, I think if we're prepared,
then we're just so much,
everything's so much easier.
So, um, just, uh, trying to
do your best to know what your
goals are and try to attack them
and have fun doing it and, and,
uh, and bring your best to that.
You know, I think sleep
is such a underrated,
under talked about thing.
It just.
Of course makes us so much
better and people cut corners.
And I think we all do
that at times and that's,
that's perfectly fine.
But there's certain things
that we really just need
to do on a regular basis.
And, um, your performance is
ultimately what should inspire
you and help you remember that.
That's true.I mean, and that's,
that's how it is for me.
Like, cause when I, you know,
go through my day and I'm able
to do all the different things
I try to do and, and then.
Do it pretty well, do it with
a decent amount of smoothness.
It just, it just shows me the,
the importance of why I do what
I do and, uh, how important
I can, the impact I can have.
Like, ultimately we do the
things that make us our best
to have an impact, right?
So when my impact is strongest,
I feel my best and I feel
like I'm, uh, I'm giving
something that really just.
Adds more value to people's
lives and, uh, my own.
So ultimately that's what
I wanna to, that's where I
wanna be as much as I can.
And I think when you can
align your goals with that
idea or whatever that is for
you, it can really help you
take care of yourself to,
to bring that and be that.
Bekah: I love that and I know
that we have a lot of people
who are looking for jobs,
especially now, um, because
there have been so many
layoffs, so many new folks
coming into tech, and so what.
Advice would you give them
when they're kind of on that
part of the journey that
feels really frustrating.
They're overwhelmed, they're,
you know, putting out tons
of resumes or they're working
really hard and they feel
like they're not making any
progress, like they're stuck.
Uh, what would you say to them?
Alex: Yeah, I think it's
important to document
the small wins, right?
Just let's say you get an
open source contribution
merged into a project.
It could be a big one.
It could be a small
one, ultimately.
Even though some things are
less, they seem less tangible.
There are wins, there are things
that are probably happening.
I remember initially, of course
in my tech journey wanting to
get interviews and then, you
know, not getting them and
then finally getting them and
I was thinking, oh yes, great.
I've got interviews.
So that's the first step.
So you have to, you have to take
it in steps and realize that.
No one just got to
the top of the ladder.
They, they climbed up each step.
They didn't skip steps to
get to the top of the ladder.
I mean, in, in a real
life situation, right?
So maybe, maybe they can
skip steps in tech or, or in
some parts of their lives.
But on a real ladder,
no one skips steps.
And ultimately that's where
we all are in the, especially
in the beginning of our tech
journey, we're on a ladder.
And so you gotta just, Do
what you need to do and stay
positive and, and find that
balance, get that rest and, and
do something outside of tech.
I think we're always
so focused on tech.
We're always so focused on code
and this tool and that tool and
all these different things that
are the new hotness, right?
So getting a, getting
away from that can help
you get better into that.
As odd as that sounds.
Um, so it's, it's
really important.
It's, it's really
how we avoid burnout.
It's how we persist.
It's how we bring our best.
I, I know I, we've
talked about that.
So it's, uh, just stay positive.
Try to try to get
outside of tech.
Try to do something that gives
you that smile, gives you joy.
And then go back to tech with
that feeling, with that, um,
greater sense of appreciation
and then see how you go.
Bekah: I was laid off,
as you know, about five
weeks ago, and the.
I, I've been trying to
rediscover all of those things
that you're talking about, Alex,
because I think at some point
I just kind of started letting
the weight of things crush me
and I like physically, I feel so
much better now and I'm trying
to also build in good habits.
We've mentioned Arthur Doer's
talk a couple of times on
the podcast about burnout.
Uh, and he was a guest a
couple of weeks ago, or this
will be a different season.
Uh, he was a guest last season.
Um, But one of the tips that
he either said in the talk
or we had in a conversation
after the talk was, um, to
avoid burnout, you have to
prepare good habits before
going into the next thing.
And so before I move on
to the next role that I'm
taking, I'm trying to like
reinforce those good habits.
What are the good things that
I could be doing every day?
And building on that.
So then when I do get into
another role, I don't,
I don't let myself fall.
Slide back into these things
that were just really stressing
me out and like literally
felt heavy on my shoulders.
And so, you know, part
of that is, you know,
finding those hobbies.
Somebody asked me, oh, is
my son Like, well, what are
your, what are your hobbies?
What do you do?
I'm like, I don't know.
I got four kids.
Like, you are my hobby.
But even like taking a
10 minute walk outside
every morning, that's been
something that I found to be.
Really impactful.
And during my day, and it's,
it's 10 minutes, you know,
it's not a huge bit of time.
And some days, some
days it's really cold.
It's getting warmer now in Ohio.
But, but um, I think like
that idea of making sure
that you have those things
and building time into
that is really important.
And I think that's
also something that
you do really well.
And one of the things that
I find refreshing about,
You're like following
your Instagram, right?
Like you're posting exotic
fruits and I love to see it,
you know, cuz so much of our
community on social media
and tech is so tech focused.
And to be able to see, hey,
there's other cool things
out there that we can talk
about and it doesn't have to
be tech all the time actually
like is really refreshing.
Alex: Yeah, I really like it
because I love other things.
I mean, we all don't just
love tech, at least I think.
And um, you know, it's great
to love tech and we can
always dig into tech, but
there's other things to life.
There's, I like fruit,
I like basketball.
I like taking care of myself.
I like my friends and family.
I like traveling.
I like languages.
I mean, everyone has, has their
handful or, or more of things
and, and that's what we need to.
To have fun with.
I mean, we're not always
just gonna be working.
We're not always just gonna
be coding, and we should be
coding and we should be enjoying
that whole process, but we.
Be well-rounded people.
We wanna be more
than just developers.
And, uh, I think it's important.
One thing you, you mentioned
the 10 minute walk.
It doesn't have to be
a big time investment.
Five or 10 minutes can,
can really do a lot.
It could be stretching, it
could be meditating, it could
be going for that walk or going
for a quick run, quick sprints.
Something that really
resonates with you, that
doesn't necessarily take a
lot of time, can make a big
impact on your daily reality.
Bekah: I think I have to draw
the line at sprints we can.
Sprints are hard.
I did sprints the other day
and my lungs hated me for the
rest of the day, so, um, Yeah,
I, I think that that idea is
really important and I like
the idea of being able to
celebrate your little wins.
And I was talking to somebody
recently who's been searching
for a job for a while, and
they were kind of getting, they
were really discouraged, right?
But they had an
interview and I said, I.
Having an interview
is a win, right?
And celebrating each of those
tiny things becomes important
because you can't, you're
right, like you're not going to
skip to the top of the thing.And
when you're going through
that process, the interview
process can be really grueling,
especially for your first job.
Alex: Mm-hmm.
Bekah: celebrate those, it's
going to become really hard to.
Bring your best self to the
interviews that you are doing.
Alex: It's very true, and the
interview process I think is.
Maybe the most grueling part
of the process, even more
than learning all this stuff.
I think, um, just sometimes
we make it more personal
than just business, because
ultimately it's just business.
And if a company makes a
decision, it's not necessarily
a reflection on you, but of
course you have control over how
you perform in the interviews.
So, uh, that's a thing where
I think you really wanna
be gentle with yourself.
You wanna just understand that.
It's a business decision.
It's not a personal,
like you're a bad person.
I'm not gonna hire you decision.
It's just a decision based on
what's best for the business.
And I think removing that
personal aspect is will allow
you to really just move with
so much more brevity and,
and get the result you're
looking for a lot faster.
Bekah: Yeah, and I, I've heard
circumstances of, you know,
people putting out hundreds
of job applications and
getting really discouraged by
that, but I recently heard.
Listen to an audiobook.
I can't remember who it was
by, but they said they look
at resumes for 30 seconds and
then if you're interesting,
they'll Google you and
look at your, like, what?
How you show up in the
search results for a minute.
So you have a minute and a half.
And so I, I think, I know
that it's really hard when
you're putting out so many
resumes and cover letters to
get down on yourself or to
be constantly tweaking it.
But, but the fact is like,
30 seconds is not a whole
lot of time to really get to
know and understand someone.
And so, you know,
finding those ways to be
positive is important.
So, you know, what are
some of the ways that you
were able to do that as
you were interviewing?
Alex: That's a good question.
I think, I think there was a
lot going on in my life when I
was trying to, the, the majority
of this journey getting into
tech, you know, COVID was going
on and, uh, living at this
apartment that I no longer live.
It just, you know, I think it
was, uh, Just trying to fit in
the time to, to, to do this.
And, uh, as far as staying
positive with that man, I
think it was up and down.
I think there were times
when I really just felt,
what am I doing here?
Am I gonna be able to get
this thing I'm looking for?
And there were times when
I would code and do stuff
and I just thought, you
know, this is so cool.
And I'm really just, I'm making
contributions to open source.
I'm, I'm building
this React project.
I've built this Madlibs game.
I think it was really, All
over the place, in all honesty.
But I think what kept me
positive was just the fact that
I, just thinking back to when
I started thinking back to when
I found the joy for front end
and just development in general,
um, and just also remembering,
like, I remember for some
reason when I was really young
and I was reading something,
I, I remember I learned about
what APIs are and for some
reason that stands out for me.
And that just something is, that
I think is cool and something
that I always remember.
And so I just know like.
Where I come from with this
and why I'm here and why
I'm doing what I'm doing.
That ultimately
is what guides me.
But, um, I think it
was really up and down.
There were times I felt really
great about my resume and
what I was putting out there.
And there were times when
I felt like I'm just going
through the motions and this
thing is just spinning around
and not not going anywhere.
And um, so I think just sticking
with it overall, despite how you
feel is, is the way to do it.
Bekah: There's, um, A like
trending audio on Instagram
reels, that's on a bunch
of, I think it's like,
well, I've got like the
weightlifting algorithm, right?
So those are the majority
of the videos that,
the reels that I get.
But, um, it, it, it kind of
talks about the same thing
like, Nobody else is gonna
show up for you if you don't
show up for yourself, right?
And sometimes it's going to
be easy and sometimes you're
going to see that progress,
and other times it's gonna
be months and you are not
going to see that progress.
And so it's not about the
gains, it's not, it's about you
get up and you have to do it.
And that's really,
really hard sometimes.
And that's why I think like
forming those good habits and
trying to stay, have a positive
mindset is really important.
And then, In those times where
it feels impossible to do that.
That's why having a good
supportive community around
you is so important because
there are times that you feel
like, Hey, I can't do this.
I cannot submit one more
resume or do one more rep or
whatever, and then someone.
Someone come.
There's the, okay, so I'll
tell a weightlifting story
about, I don't remember.
One time I was deadlifting
and like couldn't move
it off the ground, right?
And then one of the
guys from the gym came.
He's like, come on,
you got this right?
And I was like, all
right, I got this.
And then I did it, right?Like
Alex: Yeah.
Bekah: there was, I was the
same amount of strong that
I was three seconds ago.
But having somebody cheer me
on give me that little bit
of confidence that I didn't
have in myself was enough
for me to lift that very
heavy thing off the ground.
And I feel like that's a
really good metaphor for
why community matters.
Alex: Yeah, I mean, I think
that our own self-confidence is
our biggest catalyst, and what
that person did was instilled
self-confidence within you.
So, um, falling in love with
the process is, is important.
And I think that's, A big
part of my, uh, my reality.
But, uh, if you are
self-confident, then like
you could be not even the
best developer you could
be, not even the best
weightlifter, whatever, but
that confidence and that that.
If you have it, people will
know, and it, you'll exude that
confidence and you'll be able
to be that much better off.
You'll really just stand out and
you'll, uh, you'll be, you'll
be that much better because
you're believing in yourself.
And that's, that's a big
part of, I think, getting
into this, uh, software
development is just remembering
that you're worth it.
You're here for a reason,
you have a place here.
And, uh, just standing
that ground and, and
making cementing it.
Dan: I love that so much.
I was actually like, I wanted
to go back a little bit to some
of the stuff we were talking
about when you were talking
about, um, how important
sleep is right to your,
your outlook and everything.
And, and I totally agree with
it, but I, I was wondering as
a person who sometimes maybe
struggles with some of that
balance and some of the sleep
stuff, if you have any specific.
I don't know, habits or
whatever, you know, to, to
help yourself get the right
amount of sleep and get, you
know, and like figure out
that cycle and get it, you
know, like in good shape.
Alex: Yeah, so it certainly
goes up and down for me as well.
Uh, one thing that I think
is helpful is kind of
turning off all your screens,
uh, as early as possible.
Our screens are very
stimulating, lots of different,
uh, blue light and all
that fun stuff, dopamine.
so the sooner we can get away
from that and kind of start
to chill and, uh, you know,
Get into maybe a self-care
routine, like turning off your
screens and then, you know,
cleaning your teeth or, um,
sometimes that's what I'm doing.
Or I read my, I read a book, um,
like, you know, certain people,
sometimes books wake them up.
Sometimes books
will chill you down.
Depends on the topic.
Depends on the person.
Um, maybe it could be
a stretching routine.
I just, one of the big things
I would say, like I said, is
turning those screens off.
Um, finding that centered space,
um, getting away from what you
were doing on those screens,
the topics like just kind
of mellowing out in any way.
Uh, that, you know, for
me, I like to clean my
teeth and read a book.
Um, I know everyone's
a little different.
It could be a nice little
stretching routine.
Um, maybe some kind of
like hot compress on
your eyes with a towel.
Could be a nice way to
chill and, uh, mellow out.
But, uh, those are
my preferred ones.
Dan: Nice.
I like the idea of like
doing the hot compress just
at, at night every day.
That's, that sounds really nice.
It sounds pleasant.
Alex: Yes.
Um, I don't go for that
one at night too often,
but it's a good one.I like that.
Dan: uh, I wanted to
echo what you said about
stretching before bed.
Actually, advice my therapist
gave me when I was having
some trouble, like falling
asleep was like just a
simple stretching routine.
Um, and.And it helped so much.
And it was, it was so weird cuz
it wasn't like I was laying in
bed like, oh, my muscles are
sore, or something like that.
You know what I mean?
It, it wasn't really like
directly related, but it's just
like, well, we all know our mind
and our bodies are obviously
very much connected and uh, it
made a big difference for me.
Uh, so I think that's
good advice too.
And that's, that's all
I had to say about that.
Bekah: Yeah, and exploring just
different ways to wind down
to get your mind and your body
prepared to go to sleep, I think
can be, can be really hard.
That's a skill, right?
It it can be really challenging
to be able to do that.
Alex: Well, I think it,
it's a habit and it's
built by consistency.
I think consistency.
Is discipline, if
that makes sense.
People talk about
discipline, but I think
ultimately consistency
makes discipline so easy.
So just make it a habit and
try to stick with it and it'll,
it'll get easier over time.
Bekah: Yeah, I find that I'm
really good at things like that
until I, uh, fall off track
and then it becomes really
hard to get started again.
Like, you know, I'll, I'll
eat super healthy for like six
months straight and then I.
I go visit a friend and
get totally off track, and
then it takes me like two
months to get back on track.
Alex: Yep.It's, it's real.
Um, depends on your
level of commitment.
I think that's where you
realign with your why.
And then boom, it's,
you get back on track.
You, you jump back on the train.
Um, but you really gotta
resonate with your why
and, and connect with it.
Reconnect with it as you
need to, to get you back.
Bekah: Yeah, I like that idea
of reconnect with your why,
and I think that's part of,
you know, the issues that I
was really facing in the last.
Six months with stress is like
not knowing what the why was.
At some point I lost that,
and then it became really hard
to get back on track and then
doing just like a lot of, I
would say, self-destructive
things, not just like low
key, right, bad habits.
Not sleeping well, not
doing things that I know
enrich my life and lead to
good decisions, you know?
Um, and then just kind of going
with it because it lost that
idea and didn't know how to,
kind of like, first of all, I
didn't realize that I lost it.
And second of all,
once I did kind of.
See, I wasn't really sure how
to recalibrate after that.
So do you have any thoughts on,
you know, if people are in that
situation, how to kind of like
figure out what that why is?
If they're feeling like, I
don't know what it is right now.
Alex: That's a good question.
Um, I think just, uh,
consider what drives you.
Consider what makes you
wanna wake up in the morning.
Try to try to see where your
passion, your fire comes from,
and then, Define and align your
goals in parallel with that?
I am, you know, cause I'm gonna
get up every day and, and dig in
and love and, uh, go crazy about
the things I love all the time.
Like, that's just, I feel
like my life in a sense, like
the things I love are the
things that drive me and the
things that keep me going
and, uh, keep me engaged.
And so if you fall
off, think about.
Why, what do I love?
What do I, what do
I wanna always do?
What am I always keen for?Right?
And then just
redefine your goals.
To bring your best for that.
You know, like could be, you
know, I love running every day.
I'm gonna, you know, train to do
this 5K, or, you know, anything.
I love writing.
I'm going to write a hundred
words, 300 words that are
really solid and really verbose.
In a, in a, they,they say a lot.
These 300 words are
really meaningful.
Um, so developing tangible,
small, doable things
that, Uh, you know, go
along with your passion.
Uh, really can, can
get you back over time.
Bekah: I like that.
I found one of the
things too that's been
helpful for me recently.
You know, when you're in tech,
everything moves so quickly.
There's always
something new to learn.
There's always.
Always a different way to grow.
There's a new podcast or
there's a new audio book
that everybody should read to
help you improve your life.
Right.And I felt like probably
at some point I was on
information overload, like
constantly learning, and
sometimes it's just too much.
And so now if I take a walk in
the morning, or if I run, I'm
usually listening to music.
And before I wouldn't do that.
I'm like, this is a good time
for me to learn something new.
I'm like, you know what?
My brain just needs to
chill out for a little bit.
And, and that's okay.
You don't always have to
be doing something to that
seemingly improves your life
because the simple things
sitting down and enjoying life,
you know, listening to my kids
laugh or, you know, walking
around the neighborhood without.
Like having a secondary
mission for learning or
whatever is important,
maybe just as important
as learning something new.
Alex: Oh yeah.
I mean, finding the times to
relax and, uh, bring more levity
and just, uh, have fun laugh.
I think it's, it's just
as important as the work
and the consistency.
Um, So definitely
make space for that.
Hopefully you've got family,
friends, uh, around you.
Um, if you don't, then
just try to seek them out.
You know, my sister and
I started doing fruit lux
because, uh, we wanted people
that were interested in fruit
to come together and build
a community of, you know,
vegan and fruit loving people.
And so that's what we did.
And, um, we've, you know, made
tons of friends from that.
So, uh, make it, if it's not
there and just, uh, create
what you're looking for.
Bekah: I love that.
Make it if it's not there.
I think that that is
really, really great advice.
And sometimes it can be
scary, sometimes it can be
an accident, but like finding
those things that enrich your
life are really important.
And if you see something that
you wanna do, then find a
way to put it into action.
Alex: Exactly.
Bekah: I remember once I was
talking to, this is kind of
circling back a little bit.
I was talking to a mom who was
learning how to code and she
was saying how hard it was for
her to retain the information.
She's like, I'm going over
the same stuff all the time.
And so he said, okay, well,
like what is your process?
Walk me through how
you're learning.
And it was something like,
well, you know, after my kids
go to bed, I will code from.
10: 00 PM until midnight.
And then I wanna get some
coding in before they wake up.
So I'll get up at four and
then I do it from four to six.
I'm like, you're getting
four hours of sleep.
That's why you're not
retaining anything.
And it, it often feels like
there's this race to get ahead.
Right.
And I even felt coming outta
my bootcamp, I remember
very naively thinking like,
oh, once I land a job now
I'll be able to breathe.
Like, no, you are, you are not
going to be able to breathe.
It's g it's about
to get even harder.
Um, and so again, back to
that idea of building good
habits, but like, don't
undervalue that there's a
process and it takes time.
And for every person it's
going to be a different path
and it's going to take a
different amount of time.
Crushing your, your body and
your spirit is not going to
help you get there any faster.
Alex: Yeah, I mean, I think.
I can echo the same thing
from my own experience.
I mean, just being about four
months into my, my first job
here, I feel like it's taken
me up to this point to get
into the flow and into the,
um, ways to really optimize
my schedule and my week.
Um, you know, soon after I
started it was the holidays.
So, um, that took me away for
a couple weeks and, uh, outta.
You know, building up the flow
and, uh, understanding how
to be my best and knowing,
you know, how much to take on
work-wise outside of work and,
you know, all that good stuff.
And, um, you know, it does
take time and you really wanna
respect that process and you
wanna just know that you're
gonna get to a better place.
You're gonna level out, you're
gonna find that balance and,
uh, It does take a good amount
of time, but that's what
good things take is time.
And just remember that cliche
and you'll be much better off.
Bekah: And what does that
adjustment look like for
you, going from not having
this job to starting it
to where you are now?
Alex: Um, well, I think a lot
of it was just understanding
how much to do in the evening.
Cause I think that,
like I was doing a lot.
I would jump on the Virtual
Coffee co-working room.
I would really try to go to the
meetups and stuff that happened
virtually, uh, a lot and.
Like, that's great and there's
a time and place for that.
But when you're working,
you need to kinda give
yourself some time to chill.
Give yourself some time away
from the screen and make
sure your, your body's right.
Make sure you're getting
that rest that we,
that we talked about.
Um, so I think that
it was really just.
The first couple months still
trying to engage and still
trying to really kind of do
what I used to do, but then
realizing and pivoting and
saying, okay, now I need to take
a little bit off my shoulders.
I need to just do a little
bit less, but uh, still show
up, still have my presence,
be known, and, um, just bring
it more for when I'm working.
And then that's
the most important.
And it also helped me because
when I was initially working,
I was a lot in, I was in the
office all the time, but now
I'm hybrid, so, I'm in the
office today, but I'm only
in the office twice a week.
So I think that really helped
me kind of give myself more
time, let myself do other
things to make my, like,
get my workouts in in the
morning and stuff like that.
And, um, so I think it's
just been a progression.
And luckily where I work,
they're really open-minded.
They're really, uh,
receptive to, to what I
have to say and, and what
I know will help me and.
So we're just working on it
together and it's getting better
over time, which is fantastic.
It's been, it's
been a fun process.
Bekah: Yeah.
That's really great to hear.
I, I know that, um, one
of the things that I've.
Done to kind of help with that
balance too, is when, when
you are working remotely, you
are in front of a screen all
the time and then meetings are
in front of a screen, right?
You're talking.
So it's just never ending.
So I do have the under the
desk treadmill, but I started
taking, um, meetings with my
camera off and going for a walk.
So I'll just use my
cell phone network.
Put in my earbuds and
then I'll listen to the
call and be outside.
And for me, that's kind
of like a compromise.
You know, I'm getting away
from the computer, I'm still
doing what I need to be doing
for work, but this is better
than me sitting in front of
the computer all day long.
Um, I still need to figure
out a good outside setup
because the glare on my
computer screen is really bad.
And then my umbrella
always like, Flies away.
So one of these days
I'll figure that out.
Alex: Yeah, that'll be good.
That is a smart way
to take meetings.
Um, I would like to try that too.
I'm sure that's a nice way
to, to get away from the
screen, but still be working.
Dan: Yeah, it could be.
I used to do that.A lot.
Uh, now, now there's
too much screen sharing.
I feel like it's hard.
You know, I, I have to
have my, pull my phone out
and like, look at my phone
and it's really small or
whatever, you know, every,
every time I try to do it.
But I used to do that a lot.
Uh, I would actually
go in the backyard.
I, I played disc golf.
I would go and practice, like
practice putting and stuff
while my, while I was on calls.
Um, one of my problems with
that is I start not paying
attention to the call when
I'm, when I'm not, when
I'm doing other things.
So that's, you know, it, uh,
it has, it's something you,
I, I would encourage people
to try, try different things
though, and see if it works.
You know, sometimes it
might not, might not end up
working, but, uh, sometimes
it, you know, it can.
Um, but I think
that's good advice.
And like, yeah, getting
outside is like just the
best thing every time I.
I'm working long and I'm
like, why do I feel like crap?
You know?And then I go out, I
walk outside, I'm like,
oh, you know, like, I'm
like, oh yeah, the sun.
Like I don't, I don't have any
windows in my office, you know,
so it can like turn into this
weird, you know, cave situation.
And, um, sometimes it's hard
to like notice that thing
while it's happening, you know?
It's like that.Um, what is it?
Like the, the frog?
Boiling in water slowly, or
what, I forget what, like
how does that metaphor go?
But like, yeah.
Where, where you don't
really notice it, you know?
It's like, and, and I think,
I feel like that kind of thing
can creep up on you in lots
of different ways, not just if
you're in a boiling cauldron.
Um, you know?
Alex: Yeah.Yes, certainly.
Bekah: cauldron.
Dan: Right, right.Uh, yeah.
And like getting outside
is just like, for me
especially, it is just always.
It always improves
my, like, everything,
you know what I mean?
It improves my, my like my
mental whatever capacity
and my mood and my energy.
I don't know, like it's
good advice, you know?
I also, I'm always trying to
figure out something to work
outside and yeah, there's like
glare and, you know, whatever.
I don't know.
Alex: Yeah,
Dan: It's tough, I'm sorry,
I'm just rambling now.
But like, there is, there's
a, a disc golf course in
Ashtabula, Ohio that's like,
I like playing there, but they
have like, in one of their
pavilions wifi, like there's
a sign that's like free wifi,
you know, it's just like in the
middle of this park, you know?
I'm like, whoa,
that is really cool.
I'm not gonna like drive
to Ashtabula to work, but,
uh, You know, I don't know.
Um, I could see that, you
know, maybe I'll, maybe I'll
try to push for that, you
know, in Lakewood somewhere,
Alex: Yeah,
Dan: you know, get a picnic
bench under, uh, a tree and
I feel like then you're, then
you're in good shape because
you don't have the glare, but
you don't have to worry about
your umbrella flying away.
You know, it's the best,
best of both worlds.
Bekah: just plant a
Alex: go.
Dan: Just gotta watch out for,
uh, mean squirrels, I guess.
Alex: Yeah,
Bekah: I will befriend
the squirrels.
Dan: Sure.Yeah.
Alex: they'll try.
Dan: right, that's
the right call, you
Bekah: of the squirrels, I
Dan: Ooh,
Alex: Don't let 'em
take your food though,
then you'll be okay.
Bekah: I, I think along the
lines with all the stuff
we've been talking about,
one of the other issues
that's challenging is to turn
work off when work is done.
And I think it all comes
back to this idea of forming
good habits and finding those
things that enrich your life.
And I was even thinking
recently with remote work.
Most people are not
doing a commute, right?
I mean, maybe they'll go to
a coworking space or coffee
shop or something like that.
But in some ways a commute
is a really good time to like
detox from work and then move
on to that next thing, right?
Like, I'm going home
and now I am home Bekah.
I'm not like developer
Bekah or whatever, you know?
Um, cuz I can't like, My
office is in my house,
and so it's nearly, it's,
it's always there, right?
I can always step back
into work, and I am
frequently guilty of.
Working beyond my hours or up
until the point I have to pick
up my kids like to the minute
and then I'll just jump in the
car and then doesn't really
give me time to turn off.
And I was talking to my old
manager yesterday, maybe,
uh, about different w work
options that I have right now.
And um, one of them
would be contract work.
And he said, well, you
know, one of the issues
for you is going to be.
Turning, turning off like
you're, you are going to want
to do more, so you really
need to guard your hours and
make sure that you're not
working beyond that amount
of time because it doesn't
serve you to, to do that.
And it's true, like
that is for sure.
One of my weaknesses and one of
the, the things that I, I need
to put into have it now is maybe
like before I go pick up my
kids, Go take a 10 minute walk
and then that, that becomes my,
my kind of commute time, right?
To clear my mind, be done
with work, and be ready to
move on to you know, who I am
outside of work because work
should not be defining me.
Dan: Yeah, I.
I agree with that a lot.
And that's, I think that's some,
I mean, I've been independent
sort of work from home ish for
a very long time, you know, but
a lot of people started doing
this when the pandemic happened.
Uh, and I've, I've,
you know, I think it's
a pretty common thing.Um, the.
There's this, there's this
concept of like, uh, going
through a threshold, like
actually like spiritually,
um, can, can have a, have a
make a, make a difference.
Make a transition in your,
in your mind, you know?
And, um, that's like, I feel
like that's a big part of this
is, is when you have a separate
workplace and a separate living
space, it's, he's, it's like
a lot easier to turn it off.
And you're like, well, okay.
And you can even like, leave
your computer at work, you
know, and then there's no, no
temptation, but, uh, It's hard.
It's hard when you're,
when you're home and it's
all, it's all there and
it's, it's, you know, plus
phones and everything.
You have your emails.I dunno.
Yeah.It, it can be really hard.
Um, we were just talking about
that in Virtual Coffee, um, in
my breakout room on, on Tuesday.
Alex: on that note, I think, you
know, sometimes even designating
a part of your house, like
this is the workplace.
This is my desk,
this is my office.
And then just, you know, I.
Zoning it out like that.
Like this, this is the,
the small space where I do
my work and I'm gonna shut
this computer down and then,
you know, I'm only gonna
use my personal computer
or phone or what have you.
Uh, having that separation, um,
can also sometimes help with,
with getting away from work and
then just being you, the person.
Bekah: That's one thing I never
do is shut down my computer.
So that's, that's probably
a good thing I should try
every once in a while.
Alex: I've been pretty
consistent about it
Bekah: Nice.
Alex: yeah, it's, it's helps
like when I'm, when I'm done, I.
Close it down.
I might use my second screen
from work for my personal
computer, but that's about it.
Bekah: That's great.
Uh, I love this idea,
all the things that we
talked through today about
forming these good habits.
Because it enriches us as people.
And like you said in that tweet,
being able to take care of
yourself is really important
to being able to, um, you
know, like be a human being
that you wanna be, but also to
be a good performer at work.
Because when you feel
healthy and positive and
happy, that kind of goes
everywhere in your life.
So, um, it's not something
that's, Just like, well,
it's just good for this part.
Like, no, it's, it's
good for all of you.
So as we move to the end of
this podcast episode, what
is one word that you would
use to describe yourself?
Alex: I'd say inquisitive.
Bekah: Can you tell
us a little bit more?
Alex: Yeah, I think that
I really just have a great
hunger for knowledge.
Um, so I have my interests
and like I just dive so
deep, you know, whether
it be fruit, basketball,
languages, um, traveling.
I just think that like,
I try to find parallels
with those interests.
So, you know, uh, for
example, fruit, you have
a lot of different, um,
culture and language.
Uh, Uh, sprinkled into that.
For example, like my sister's
favorite Mango is a Burmese
mango and has a Burmese name
like it, and you know, it has a
different name here in the us.
Uh, so just being able to
find, uh, to find those
parallels, dig deep, um, on
those types of things, I think
is really something that.
That just brings me so much joy.
It brings more of a more
depth and more of a story
to, to what it to my life.
And, uh, I don't just want
my life to be just simplistic
and, uh, face value.
I like to kind of give it, give
it a story and say, you know,
this person, uh, dude did this
and uh, um, then now I'm eating
a product of that based on this
story, you know, for example.
Um, and, you know,
I just think that.
I'm always interested in
new things and I think
I always have so much to
grow and learn in my life.
Uh, so just loving that
process and, uh, continuing
that process over time.
And then just trying to share
that I think is just why I
would say that I'm inquisitive
and that's just, that's just
a big part of my myself.Yeah.
Bekah: I love that.
That was a really
beautiful way to put that.
Well, thanks Alex for joining
us today and for talking
through all of this with us.
I know that I.
I feel, uh, in a happy
place right now after having
this conversation, and I
hope that everybody else
who listens does as well.
Alex: Yes.Thank you guys.
It was fantastic.
I love this community, so
it's so great that we can have
these conversations and, and
share the amazingness that
we're cultivating together.
Dan: All right.Thanks Alex.
Bekah: Bye.
Alex: All right.Bye.
Dan: Thank you so much for
listening to this episode of
the Virtual Coffee Podcast.
This episode was produced by
Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot Weigel,
and edited by Ashley Mulder.
If you have questions
or comments, you can
hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO or email us
at podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,
sign up for the newsletter, buy
some VC merch, and check out
all of our other resources on
our website, virtualcoffee.io.
If you're interested in
sponsoring Virtual Coffee,
you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to
our podcast and be sure
to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and
we'll see you next week.