Bekah: Hello and welcome to
season eight,episode three of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I'm Bekah,
and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate group of
developers at all stages of their
journey,and they're here on this
podcast sharing their stories and
what they've learned here with me
today is my co-host Dan.
Dan: What up Bek?Uh,hey,how's it
going?
Bekah: It's going well.How's it
going with you?
Dan: It is going fantastic.Kali f
fantastically.It's going well.
Well,I feel like going fantastic
is not good,you know,proper
grammar,right?Because.It's
fantastic as an adjective and not
an adverb.And so,yeah,but
fantastically is a weird sounding
word,so.Anyway,I'm fantastic.Um,
anyway,today's episode features
Carmen Kolohe and she is a DevOps
engineer.And,um,we had a really
great time,uh,talking with,with
Carmen.Uh,she had a lot of.Great
things to share about her
process,like how she got into
tech and how she got into DevOps
in particular.And I thought she
had a really unique perspective
on,on making connections and,uh,
you know,involving your community
and your network and furthering
your career goals and furthering
your developer journey.And I
dunno,it was,it was cool.It was,
it was a good conversation.
Bekah: Yeah,I appreciated that
she talked about being an
introvert,and I think she's
mentioned that she might be shy
too.And so it was a good example
of what happens when you take
yourself out of your comfort zone
a little bit and how,uh,
impactful that can be on the rest
of your career.I.
Dan: Totally.And not,not just
taking yourself out of your
comfort zone,but ways to do that.
Um.But feel more comfortable
doing it,which is sort of,I don't
know,uh,a weird thing to say
about going out of your comfort
zone,you know,but,uh,ways,ways to
make your,maybe it's just ways to
expand your comfort zone.I don't,
I don't know.Um,but either way,
uh,we'll let Carmen do the
talking for,for us,uh,cuz she did
a good job explaining it and I am
not doing a good job explaining
it.
Bekah: No,it was really great to
learn from her in this episode
and learn a little bit more about
what DevOps is and to,I think,
inspire some people who are in
the middle of their career
journey.we start every episode of
the podcast,like we start every
Virtual Coffee.We introduce
ourselves with our name,where
we're from,what we do,and a
random check-in question.We hope
you enjoy this episode.Today's
random check-in question is if
you could have a superpower that
only worked while you were
sleeping,what would it be?My name
is Bekah.I am the developer
experience lead at Open Sauced
from a small town in Ohio.And I
think like the superpower.Okay,
so there's two options here.Like
the ability to like really engage
with your dreams and remember
them,like those become actual
worlds.That would be pretty cool.
Um,or having my whole house
cleaned while I'm asleep.So that
one's not as cool,but definitely
practical and I would appreciate
that.So I think,I think I'm gonna
have to go with my house being
cleaned when I woke up.
Dan: Uh,all right.That's fair.
You know,that makes me weird.
Like,do you remember,um,What is
that King Arthur Disney movie
called,uh,the Sword and the
Stone?Um,you know,where the,like
the wizard,the Merlin starts
doing the like,you know,but they
get out of control after if he
doesn't pay attention to him.
That,that like worries me,you
know?You know,like,like when a
Roomba,I don't know,gets,gets
into trouble,right?So
Bekah: that in King Arthur?Is
that in Fantasia
Dan: No,no,no.It was,well,maybe
both actually.I'm not sure.I
haven't,I watched Sword Stone a
lot more than I watched Fantasia,
so.I'm not gonna say it's not
advantageous,but I'm thinking
specifically of sword and stone.
But anyway,the like non-conscious
control over something that is
like cleaning things,you know,
like could be,it could be
problematic,but in general that
does sound nice.Um,
Bekah: my house is pretty messy,
so I don't think it would get
that worse.
Dan: Right.Uh,okay.I'm Dan.I do
development.I live in Ohio and in
Cleveland,I suppose.And,um,not,I
suppose that's where I live and,
uh,what I do development,I,I
think,um,I think I'm gonna go
with like Wolverine level,you
know,regeneration,healing,you
know,so you could go to sleep and
like anything that's like wrong
or broken,you know,gets fixed up
while you're sleeping.Um,that was
the first thing that popped in my
head.And,and I,I haven't thought
of anything better,so I'm gonna,
I'm gonna go with,yeah.
Regeneration,you know,healing.
Healing powers while you're
sleeping seems,seems nice.Maybe
it'd fix up some of my.Just
general aches and stuff too,you
know,I could pop out of bed in
the morning,uh,you know,I dunno.
Uh,so yeah,that's gonna be my
answer.And,um,here's our guest.
Carmen,go ahead.
Carmen: Hi.Hi friends.I'm Carmen,
I'm a DevOps engineer in
Portland,Oregon.And,uh,Bekah you
actually inspired me for,and it's
like,uh,have either of you
watched Rick and Morty?
Dan: A little bit.
Carmen: Terry.Well,scary Terry is
like a reference to uh,Freddie
Krueger,but it's not like I'm
gonna like hurt people in dreams.
I just wanna be in other people's
dreams,you know,and like travel
through dreams,I guess,and other
people's dreams type of thing.I
think that would be cool cuz my
sister and I both have very vivid
dreams.It'd be cool to actually
like be in her dream and make my
own choices and not,she tells me
what I did in her dream,you know?
And then it's like,I'm sorry that
I did that,or,you know,I would've
done it differently probably.
Dan: Uh,yeah,that made me start
thinking about like,inception,
you know,or where they like
design,design the dreams and are,
act actively like,you know,
acting in them and stuff.Uh,
some,you know,some scary
possibilities though if you're
able to go in anybody's dreams,
you know,uh,like Steeler Secrets
or whatever,I suppose.I don't
know.Um,but I think that'd be
cool.Um,Yeah.Especially if you
could do it with a buddy,you
know,be like,Hey,let's meet up.
Bekah: Maybe they have to give
you a password,
Dan: Yeah.Oh,
Bekah: in the dream that allows
you to be in their dream.
Carmen: Uhhuh Uhhuh.
Dan: your handshake.
Carmen: Yeah.That's so
Dan: I love it.
Carmen: I,uh,I had a very vivid
room this morning and it was,I
was taking a test and my phone
kept going off during the exam,
and I kept having to turn it off.
Come to find out I was actually
turning my alarm off on my phone
that was trying to wake me up,
and I turned off four of them.
Luckily,I set like10of them,so I
was like,what a,what?Dreams are
just crazy.Huh?
Dan: funny.Your subconscious is,
you know,just telling you you
need some more sleep,I guess.
Carmen: Oh,yeah,and,and that I
have an exam coming up.
Dan: Right,right,right.
Bekah: Well,Carmen,we're really
happy to have you here with us
today.Thanks for being here.And
we always like to get started
with your journey into tech.So
how did you get from Pretech
Carmen to where you are now?
Carmen: Yeah,thanks for having
me.I've been listening to the
podcast for a bit now.Uh,so how
did I get to here?Um,well it all
started in Poland.Um,I was born
in Poland and uh,I grew up in
Chicago and only,I don't have a
Polish accent,but I do have a
Chicago accent.When I say Chicago
Hot dog or Costco.Other than
that,you would've no idea where
I'm from.Uh,and yeah,I,uh,I
initially,uh,got my degree in
psychology.I've always wanted to
help people and,uh,you know,that
was my goal.Like for early on,
very early on that I was gonna
get my doctorate,I was gonna get
into psychology and,uh,yeah,that
I got my degree and I realized
that's not what I wanted to do.
So I decided to,um,you know,I,I
graduated,I was living in Hawaii
at the time,and,uh,then I
graduated,you know,lived my best
life in Hawaii and then decided
to travel through Europe for a
bit.And,uh,then when I got back
from Europe,um,I was just,uh,in
Colorado,just hanging out in
Colorado.And,uh,my friend,uh,my
childhood friend shows up and
she's like,let's learn html,c s s
and JavaScript,just randomly one
night.And I was like,sure,why
not?Like,what else are we gonna
do tonight?You know?And uh,it was
really cool.It was fun.Uh,And,
uh,that's when,uh,I decided to,
uh,move to Seattle with,uh,a
partner at the time and go to,I,
I researched this one bootcamp
that I really wanted to do
because,uh,then I could do the
bootcamp and work part-time at a
restaurant or something and then,
you know,just not be,be able to
do both.Um,then2020happened.Uh,
That fun time and we were in
Seattle and that was like ground
zero,right?Uh,so everything shut
down.Um,and I was like,if there
was a sign from the universe that
I should just.Do nothing but
learn something new or do a
career change,it's now I have the
opportunity to do that.Uh,so,uh,
yeah,yeah,yeah.I,I,I got into the
bootcamp that I wanted to,and it
was all remote.Um,they did a
hybrid between Seattle,Portland,
and,uh,people that were outta
state too.And,um,it was hard.
They call it a bootcamp for a
reason.Like it's not a joke.It
was intense and uh,and you know,
you have everything on top of
that.You know,you have covid
happening.There was wildfires
going a around,so the air was
toxic with disease and smoke.Uh,
so it was a tough time.And,uh,
you know,uh,towards the end of
it,I had no idea how people made
money.Just Cody,I'm like,you're
gonna pay me to code.Like,how
does that work?And,uh,in this
last like hail Mary attempt to
like,figure things out,I,um,I
sent an email to a really good
friend of mine now,but,so,so I
guess,let me back up.The,the
bootcamp they would do,uh,um,
Like lunch speakers during lunch,
and one of them,uh,was,uh,this
fine gentleman named Jonin,uh,
and,uh,in fact,you know,jonin.
Yeah.Uh,he,uh,he's a developer
relations,uh,person.Great human
being.Um,just.Great person.Uh,
and I,I sent him an email,you
know,it'd been like five months
since he did the lunch and learn,
but I just,I sent him this novel
of an email and I was like,my
life is a dumpster fire right
now.Uh,but it keeps me warm and
um,it gives me light,you know?
Cause I,I've made a bunch of
friends.You know,we were all
trauma bonded through our
bootcamp too,cuz we,all we had
was each other and we all had to
try and figure it out and get
jobs from this somehow.Uh,and
Jonah actually,he replied and he
was like,these are really good
questions.Cause I asked a bunch
of questions like,how do I make
money?What is this?You know?And
he's,he,he responded.He's like,
these are great questions to,um,
that I feel a lot of other people
just starting out in tech would.
Would want answers to.And uh,he
was like,would you be open to
like,come on,uh,my Twitch stream
and ask them.And like then other
people can have these answers
available to them as well.And I
am introverted and very shy and I
was like,uh,can I bring my
friends with me?And I brought two
of my friends from the bootcamp
cuz I figured they also had
questions to ask.And you know,
it's always good when you're an
introvert and you have an
extrovert friend,cuz then it
takes the pressure off of you.
Uh,
Bekah: Yep.
Carmen: yeah.So,uh,then,uh,then
we,uh,did this stream.It turned
into like a weekly thing,uh,all
of2020.Uh,it was really good cuz
um,we were all really isolated.
You know,you couldn't go outside.
Uh,And,uh,met a lot of people
through it.Like,uh,Nick that goes
to Virtual Coffee.Um,it was just
a safe space,uh,you know,and that
that's what Virtual Coffee is,
uh,as well.But we were more like
virtual happy hour cuz we would
have drinks.Um,uh,it was late,
late,it was at night.Uh,so,uh,
yeah,we would just,we would a,
take questions from either,um,
the chat or,uh,We had questions
obviously,cause we were still in
bootcamp.Uh,and it turned into a
really wonderful thing that I,I,
I cherished a lot.Um,it was a
good time.And,uh,then,uh,yeah,so
the bootcamp,uh,the bootcamp
happened and with this bootcamp
they offer an internship and I
got this internship.Uh,and my
task as an intern was to build a
full stack app.Uh,and I did.
Because,you know,a great poet
once said,you know,you only get
one shot,one opportunity to seize
everything you ever wanted.One
moment.Would you capture it or
let it slip?Right.And I did.Um,I
Dan: That's cha,that's chaser,
right?That's a,
Carmen: You know your poetry,
huh?
Dan: that's,I'm an English major.
You know,don't like to brag about
it too much.
Carmen: Uh,but yeah,I,I saw the
opportunity and I built it and at
the end of my,uh,internship,I was
in one of their meetings where
they were going over their like
quarterly,uh,Goals.And in quarter
four,uh,they were looking to hire
a junior developer.And I was
like,Hey,let me help you meet
this goal sooner.Like thi right
now,like,how about you just hire
me and I'll maintain this app?
Cause we were about to deploy and
everything like that.And they,
they said yes.I'm like,you like
me,I like you.Like,not ruin a
good thing.And,uh,yeah.Uh,I got
hired as a junior developer
there,and it,it was,uh,for a
nonprofit.Uh,and,uh,it,it was,it
was really,really cool work cuz
the,the work I was doing was
helping people and uh,that,
that's when I knew like,this is
how I could help people was like
in tech and especially in2022cuz
businesses were closing down.
Like people were trying to figure
out ways to get online to do
anything.I was like,this is how I
directly can help people.And,uh,
the.The first job meant a lot to
me because it also goes like full
circle.Uh,the friend that,you
know,came over that one day and
was like,Hey,let's do this on a
Friday night.Uh,her life was
saved.Uh,so the nonprofit is for
organ and,uh,tissue,uh,donation
and,and transplantation,um,and
procurement.And that friend,her
life was saved by a liver
donation when she was a baby.And
so it just was like a full circle
moment.Like my first job was,you
know,doing something that,you
know,that got me to this point.
So it was really cool.Uh,and
yeah.And then,uh,the DevOps
engineer decided to take,uh,um,
an opportunity elsewhere.So the
position was open.I was like,
Hey,I like you,you like me?Like,
how about I try,try the DevOps
position,you know,instead of
hiring someone else,like,well,
let's see if I could do it.And
they,you know,they believed in me
and,uh,I,I stepped up and,and
started doing DevOps for them.
And then,uh,and then,yeah,and
then I,uh,got another opportunity
offered,uh,where I could,um,grow
and work with people at a,you
know,a larger scale work with,
uh,um,Leadership,uh,and,uh,so,so
I left that place and,uh,I'm at
this place now as the DevOps
engineer and uh,it's really
great.It's really cool stuff.So
that,that's kind of,it's.
Bekah: That's awesome.What an
incredible journey.Um,before we
move on,for our listeners,can you
describe what a DevOps engineer
is and what they do?
Carmen: Me,uh,gosh,uh,DevOps
means everything and nothing,not
nothing,but,uh,means something
different to everyone and every
company depending on what their
ne needs are.Uh,some people think
DevOps should only be there at
the very beginning or at the very
end,or,You know,but it's,uh,it's
a,it's a Jedi way.It's a,it's a,
it's a mindset,you know?Uh,
overall I think,uh,how I see
DevOps is like,you see the whole
big picture and then can like
zoom into like one specific part,
whether it's development,whether
it's deployment,uh,you know,all
of it together.Um,so,uh,It kind
of just,and it's,you know,those
famous words to it on every team.
Someone always says,it depends.
It depends.So a DevOps engineer
Yeah,they're,they're not,uh,you
know,I,I,I'm not just,uh,focused
on,you know,front end work,but I
can be,if you need me there,I can
be there and I can do it.Or if
it's backend work or if it's,um,
deploying or if it's networking,
you know?So,uh,yeah.But overall
it's,it's a way of,of thinking of
things.Uh,yeah.
Bekah: And what kind of
interested you in moving in that
direction?
Carmen: Um,because I feel like I
was already doing it as a junior
developer because we were a small
team.It was just me and the
DevOps engineer and,uh,All I,all
that was missing was access to
Azure.Then I feel like I was,you
know,basically helping,you know,
do the work too.And yeah,it,it's
good.It's nice to see the overall
picture cuz then you can.Code
more mindfully if it's,you know,
front end work or backend work
because you see how it can impact
things or how,you know,things,
uh,have to scale or,um,yeah,so
that,that's why I move towards
that,that route.
Dan: I think you'd find that in
a,in a lot of small teams where
people are wearing lots of hats,
right.And,I've certainly,like,I
never considered myself a DevOps
engineer,you know,but I've
certainly done a lot of things.
Engineer does.Right.You know,and
so like,I,I like your description
of,you know,seeing the big
picture and,and sort of having,
having an idea,uh,like a bird's
eye view of the whole ecosystem,
right.Of your app or your company
or,or whatever.Um,cuz there's
lots of pieces that go into it.
Um,and it's a,I I just,uh,I
enjoyed your description of that.
It's,it's cool.Cool.
Carmen: Thanks.
Bekah: So in a lot of this
journey,you talked about the
people who have been a part of
that journey and it seems like,
you know,developing those
relationships and those
friendships have been really
important in your journey.So,um,
just what advice do you have for
our listeners out there about
building those relationships and
especially like you talked about
being an introvert too,so how
does that play into it and,and
how can other people.Get that
energy too.
Carmen: Uh,I think what really
helped was,uh,Having the
bootcamp,I went to be remote.I
never did remote school.Uh,so
like for,for example,when when I
got my,my degree,I,I think I made
two friends in college.Because I
was so shy,but when I,when I did
the,the bootcamp and so I got
the,when I got my first job,I had
to sign my paperwork in Seattle,
but then I drove to Portland
because I made so many friends in
Portland and everyone,almost
everyone in the cohort all met up
at a park.And we all,you know,I
don't,we all just wanted to be
friends and that's why I moved to
Portland.Uh,and I think,uh,I
think it's for,for introverts.
it's easier to make friends,I
guess,because,uh,remotely or like
online,because you know you're in
your safe space.You know,and,uh,
if something feels awkward or
unsafe,you can just close the
window and be like,whoops,power
went out.You know,like you,you
have,uh,you have more escape
route,I guess.But,uh,joking
aside,um,what was really cool was
when I was first starting out,
um,I just started reaching out to
people when Twitter was a thing.
I don't know if it's still a
thing,but I'm not on Twitter
anymore,but when I was like,I
would watch like a,a,a YouTube
tutorial about how,how to use
some.Some package,some N P M
package,and I would directly go
and message this person and be
like,Hey,th thanks this tutorial
really helped me do this.It's
really cool.Like,would you have
time to like,you know,jump on a
call or,or talk more about it?
And you,I was so shocked at first
how many people were like,yeah,
let's do it.Cuz people just wanna
nerd out and,and talk about the
work that they're doing.Cause
they're excited and they,they
love what they do and.That's how
um,I made a lot of,um,friends was
just reaching out to people cuz
they wanna talk about the things
that they're excited about
building.Uh,and then Virtual
Coffee too,like,uh,so we,uh,with
the stream end ending in a sense
of,you know,everyone life
happened and,uh,So,uh,you know,
everyone found jobs and,uh,moved
or,um,were on different time
zones,so we stopped doing the
stream and then I,I really leaned
on Virtual Coffee,uh,you know,
so,and then same thing,I would
just reach out to people and be
like,Hey,like,do you have time to
talk about this?And yeah,it's,
it's been,I've had a really great
experience meeting people that
are just very welcoming and kind
and,uh,wanna just.Build cold
stuff together.
Bekah: Yeah,I think that's great
that it,um,that's a lot of my
journey as well,and I didn't try
to come into tech,but like one of
the things that brought me here
was the great community of
people.So I was just kind of like
learning a little bit on my own,
started tweeting about it,and
then people were so positive and
like cheering me on if I had a
problem.Somebody would wanna
help.And I was just shocked
because I had not experienced
that in other ways.And like I,I
think that it really did help,
like one that I was online and so
like that introvert to shyness
kind of,it was much easier.But
then I,I was even reflecting on
this the other day,I feel like I
have overcome a lot of my shyness
in the last couple of years
because of all of the positive
interactions that I've had.And I
think it takes like one person
saying something positive to you
to help you,like,move in the
direction of like getting up the
courage to ask somebody for help
or sending that email like the
one that you sent to Joann.And I
imagine like that experience was
it,was it nerve-wracking for you
to send him that email with all
of those questions?
Carmen: Uh,Well,was it
nerve-wracking?No.Cuz it was like
my,like a Hail Mary because,uh,
everything kind of was a dumpster
fire at the moment.Like,uh,I had
to move in three days across the.
And live back with my,uh,with my
parents because like,you know,I
was unemployed and,uh,you know,
at that point I was like,I will,
we'll see what happens.And if,if
they don't respond,that's fine,
but it,it can't,it can't hurt to
ask.Right.Uh,so that,that's how I
felt.It's like if they don't have
the bandwidth to reply,then.Uh,
then they won't,but it's no harm
to just ask,uh,this and then
that.That's how I feel.It's like,
you know,you just,just ask.And if
someone has the time and the
bandwidth to,to reply and you
know,and,and be there to help
you,they will.And I,I feel like
the same thing goes to like when
you're trying to find like a
mentor or something.Uh,that was
another thing that,um,I
discovered,uh,well,I heard about
was like,you should get a mentor,
like that would help.And it's
like,how does one get mentor?You
know?How do you find that?Like,
it's not like they're,you know,
displayed or,uh,but it's,uh,it,
it,it's a,it's just asking.And
then if that person does have the
time and wants to do it,they,
they will or they'll say no,and
that's okay too.Um,Yeah,I forgot.
Was that the question?I think I,
I think I went off on that one.
Dan: We're big fans of tangents
here at Virtual Coffee Podcast,
so,um,I like.What you talked
about with the mentorship too,
that I was wondering if you
could,um,talk a little bit more.
You don't have to like share
specific details if you don't
want to,but,uh,about your
experience like finding a mentor
and you know,how that worked.
Carmen: Yeah.Yeah.Um,since I was
like on a,such a small team,uh,
I.Yeah,I,I made it like my
mission to kind of try and find a
way to work with people.Not
necessarily look for a mentor,
but,well,once I stepped into like
a,the,the DevOps position,I was
like,I need a mentor.I'm by
myself right now,and this is a
little daunting.Uh,and,uh,yeah,
I,I would just,uh,I reached out
to some people and just asked,
uh,if it was,you know,front end
work or something,and,uh,I don't
know if it was luck or,or what,
but yeah,they were like,yeah,
let's set up weekly check-ins and
if you have any questions or
anything like that,we can discuss
it or work through a problem or
uh,uh,things like that.But,um,I
think it's just asking,uh,I don't
know.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah.So,so,so this was,
these were people like you didn't
personally know yet,
Carmen: No,
Dan: are,are the people you did
know.
Carmen: Mm.
Dan: Yeah,you didn't know.And so
it was like kind of a cold call,
you know,not cold call make,that
makes it sound bad,but like,you
know,uh,sort of out of the
blue-ish sort of thing,and you
just asked,Hey,I am,you know,
doing this stuff.I was wondering
if you.time to be a mentor.I,I'm
asking because I really don't
like,this is something that I've
thought about myself a lot and
I've never got like,gotten
through actually following
through with it.And so I'm always
looking for advice as far as like
finding a mentor,uh,and that kind
of thing.So that's why I'm,
that's why I'm like,I keep asking
about it.
Carmen: Yeah.Um,I think when I
was a junior developer,it was,
uh,when we were doing the stream
all the time,and there was one
particular developer that showed
up every time we did the stream
and had great advice to give,uh,
in the chat and just was like
supplemental,like on,on top of
like what we were,uh,what we were
giving and uh,just.Uh,I,I just
reached out to them after the
stream being like,thank you for
giving such great advice and
being,you know,so supportive to
others.Um,and then I was like,
well,gee,that's how I asked
there.And then,uh,for,for DevOps,
it was,uh,through Virtual Coffee,
just going to,to Virtual Coffee
and then hearing,you know,you
know,when you do the intros and
then being like,Hey,like I,I,I
just stepped into DevOps,or I
have some questions.Or posting
in,uh,in Slack as well with
questions.And you know,the people
that have the bandwidth will
reply and then I would would
message them and be like,Hey,
like,you know,have some more
questions.And do you,do you have
time?Uh,yeah.
Dan: I love that.
Bekah: Yeah,I think that there
are a couple of things that I.I
just wanna make sure that we
highlight here because it's said
a lot of great things,like one,
if people have the bandwidth,
then they'll respond to you just.
It can be nerve wracking or scary
to send somebody a message and
ask for mentorship.And sometimes
people will respond and sometimes
people won't respond,and that's
okay.Like,that's not on you.
Right?That's,they might not have
that time or the capability to do
that.Right.Um,so I think that
that idea like reach out and ask
you at the,the very least,They
might say,Hey,I'm,I can give you
a little bit of my time.Um,the
second thing that I wanna
highlight,you said you,when you
reached out to somebody,I,I think
that you said like,thank you for
those answers.Those were really
helpful.And so when you're asking
someone for something,you know,
it's nice to engage in that
conversation a little bit first
and let them know like that you
do appreciate what they've given
you already.And this has been a
really great place.This might be
a good place to start,like,uh,
more of a relationship or deepen
that into some sort of
mentorship.And so I think that
like there are also,you mentioned
like multiple modes of
mentorship,so that might be a
one-on-one thing.It might be a
conversation with a group of
people.It might be Slack messages
in a particular channel.Like all
of these things are mentorship.
Anything where you're learning
and growing,I think.Is a form of
mentorship,so sometimes it's
important to think outside of
what the traditional definition
of mentorship might be.
Carmen: Yeah.Yeah.Um,I agree.
Because sometimes it's just
having a place to rubber doc.
It's like you have a question and
then you write it all out,you
know,and then you send it and
it's like,oh,solve this.Thanks
for,you know,being a great
mentor.And it was just giving me
this space to send this to
someone.Uh,but yeah,it,it can
take many forms and,uh,yeah.It,
it's,it's.I think that was the,
biggest hurdle was just to,uh,to
know that,you know,just reach out
and,uh,if they don't respond,
that's okay.And if they respond
negatively,that's not someone
that you should interact with.I
feel,uh,there's other options out
there.Um,So,yeah.Yeah.Just,uh,
making it less daunting to,to
reach out to people that either
have good,uh,good feedback or
experience in things that you
wanna learn or do.Cause more than
likely they wanna share it with,
Bekah: Are there any specific
conversations that you can
remember that really impacted
your journey or what you know
about DevOps?
Carmen: I am still learning so
much,uh,constantly learning
DevOps things.Uh,I don't know.
It,it's been a journey like,when
we were talking about dreams too,
it's like right now I,I was
working in Azure previously and
now I'm moving to a w s.And now
I'm getting AWS certified.So my
dream about taking an exam and my
alarm going off is very,is
accurate.I'm in the middle of
studying for the,for aws,so
Bekah: Wow,that's,that's a lot.
Um,how are you balancing all of
this with.Work and being involved
in the community.
Carmen: Uh,gosh.Oh,you know,
it's,it's part of work.it's,you
know,especially when you,you find
a,a job that invests in,in
furthering your education,cuz
they know that it will,it's
mutual.You learn,you know,and
that,that helps,um,your work.
it's setting,uh,calendar events,
you know,like this is the lot of
time I have for coding stuff or
stuff in the code.And it's like
hard stop,don't keep,continue
down the rabbit hole.And then
it's shifting to,uh,to studying
and then learning.yeah.
Dan: Was it their like idea to
get,get the AWS certification and
all that stuff?Is it like a
requirement or anything?Or is it
just like,Hey,this might be fun
or something,you know,like how,
how did that,how.I least
suggested Yeah.That,that,
Carmen: and I was all for it.I,I
love learning and it's really
great and especially,you know,
shifting.Uh,From,from Azure to
aws.There's,it's,it's similar
services.They're just name
different things and it's knowing
the differences in names and
they're,yeah.So,but the concepts
are all the same.How,how to,uh,
work in the cloud.Um,
Dan: How to connect all the pipes
together.Just a whole set,
separate set of acronyms to
memorize,right?
Carmen: so many acr.It's what one
of the whiteboards says is just
acronyms.
Dan: Yeah.Yeah,that's one of my
biggest struggles.Cause I don't
like get into,into AWS stuff very
often.And so every time I do,I
have to like,refresh my memory
on,on all of it.Cuz it's like,
cuz they internally re refer to
everything with their acronyms,
you know?Um,and yeah,it,it can be
frustrating if you don't,if you
don't have it all in your brain.
Uh,so that's cool.So how's study?
So what does the exam like?Is it,
what does that experience look
like?Uh,not studying,but more of
like,do you know what the exam is
going to look like?Is it.An hour
or I,I,I've never done that,so I,
I'd be curious to,you know,what
does an A certification entail?
Carmen: Oh yeah,so I'm not sure
how long it takes.I know that,
um,you can choose to do it
remotely,uh,and you need to have
your laptop.Properly set up.And
you know,they,they,this is all
I've heard,I don't know yet.Uh,
and you have to do a pretty
rigorous process to prove that
you're not cheating.Uh,and so
then it's,people have been,uh,
Telling me to just go do it.I in
a facility,in person,because then
it's less,uh,less of a headache
to get like,to proof that,you
know,there's no way you can cheat
that,you know,your system is
good,uh,to take it remotely.But I
have not looked into it further.
I'm still,uh,going through the
tutorials to,to know all the
acronyms.
Dan: So,yeah,so it is a,it is
like a sort of traditional.
Carmen: Mm-hmm.
Dan: Like one time test thing,
like,like in school,right?Like,
yeah.That's really interesting.
Yeah,that's,I could see how your
subconscious would get,start to
get worried about something like
that.I,uh,I haven't taken a test
for a long,long time,so it makes
me a little nervous just thinking
about it.
Carmen: Yeah,I knew I was in a
dream though when like this
Scantron like where you have to
like shade in the bubble.It was
like really big and I was like,
this is ridiculous.Like this
can't be real.
Dan: Remember to turn your phone
off,I guess,when you take the
test straight.
Carmen: Yeah.
Bekah: I wanted to circle back a
little bit,um,to what we were
talking about before with meeting
new people and friendship
building.Uh,cuz I,I think one of
the things that I.Heard a lot of
people say that,especially people
who are learning.I don't have the
time to meet new people or to
join communities.It's
overwhelming.Right.I also went to
a bootcamp.I was working,I had
four kids and I was going to
bootcamp at the time,and it does
feel overwhelming.It feels like.
You can't put one more thing on
your plate.And I imagine in a
similar circumstance,like what
you're,you're working now,you are
studying for this exam,it can be
overwhelming.So in cases like
that,why do you think it is
important to still maintain those
friendships or nurture those
relationships that you've built?
Carmen: Uh,yeah,because that's
what friends are for.They're your
support system,right.Uh,and it's,
it's good to know that you're not
alone.And,uh,that's why I make
it,like I,I put in my calendar
Virtual Coffee,6:00AM Tuesdays,
you know,it's,uh,it's something
that I strive to,to make because
it's,it's.You know,you could,I
could be lost in AWS world and I
feel like,or nothing is working
in the code.And,you know,you feel
very isolated and then,you know,
you,you,uh,you have a community
to go to and be like,Hey,I've
been down this rabbit hole too.
And it's like,you're not alone.
And there is someone that can,
you know,either whether just to
listen or to,you know,It,it's,
uh,it's good to have if,if you
have,if you can,uh,in some way or
another,uh,whether it's,uh,going
to an actual,like meetup
virtually or,or in person or,um,
staying active on a Slack channel
or Discord.I,I was invited to a
lot of Discord channels and that
got overwhelming.I was like,I
can't do this.I can't,um,be
active on,on all of these
discords.But,um,yeah.Uh,I found
that was good.Or,or hack Tober
Fest too.That's also a really fun
way to,to meet people and to,to
directly work on things and help
each other out and,um,bond over,
you know,a PR or,uh,learn
something together.Um,that was
another thing that I thought was
really daunting at first,uh,when
I first started off,uh,was
contributing to like open source.
I thought that was extremely
daunting.Cause you don't know
them.And I was working on a small
team,so,uh,the whole,uh,poll
request and,uh,everything like
that wasn't as,uh,refined as some
open source are.And that was
another thing a,a friend and I
did was we wanted to stream.Uh,
maintaining an open source
project on Octoberfest and,and,
uh,humanizing.What,what a PR is
that it's not,it's not personal,
it's not a judgment on,on your
code or anything like that.It's,
you know,the person,uh,the
maintainer,learning what you
wrote,and then,uh,offering
suggestions and then the,the
author learning something new
maybe from that suggestion.Uh,so
that was,uh,another.Thing that I
thought was,uh,neat to do with
friends.
Bekah: That sounds awesome.Are
those videos still up somewhere
or are they gone?
Carmen: I don't know.I don't
think so.Cause I think it
depends.I could check,but Twitch,
uh,Twitch doesn't keep videos
after a while,and I think it's
been two years since we did that.
Uh,really wanted to continue
doing that,but,you know,life
happens and it's,uh,you know,
especially,and streaming is,you
know,a whole,whole other world in
general because you have to make
sure the,the stuff works and the
sound is heard and the music is
heard.And you both,no,you're both
nodding.
Bekah: It was literally last I
decided to live stream this week.
A couple of days ago,I was really
struggling to like,focus.I was
really tired and I was like,
well,livestream and it'll make me
accountable.Like I'll feel
accountable.And then like my
sound wasn't working,my video
wasn't working.I'm like,this is
not why I decided to livestream.
So then I was navigating those
problems live.Um,but it's okay.
Like I did,I didn't end up
getting that.I merged in my own
pr.That's,that's just the way
that I do things these days,this
morning.So,
Carmen: you're not alone.Like
literally that was us every
stream.Our sound never worked.We
would go live with no sound,not
know until someone in the chat
would tell us that they can't
hear us.And we just,so we knew
we'd have a good stream.So you,
you're not alone,but streaming as
a whole other beast.And uh,I
commend anyone that does it and
maintains it.
Bekah: Yeah,it can be.
Dan: Oh,go ahead,Bekah.
Bekah: No,you.
Dan: I was just gonna say,have
you been doing any streaming
lately?Any code related stuff
Carmen: Uh,no,it would be so fun
to to,to get back into it.My,my
friends and I,we,we talk about
it.The friends that I,I did
streaming with,uh,uh,we're such
good friends now.I'm even in one
of their weddings.Like,
Dan: Oh,nice.
Carmen: really cool.But,uh,it's,
uh,No,no.Life happens.I moved and
started a new job and someone
else moved to Europe and we're on
a12hour difference and it's,uh,
it's been hard to,to stream.
Maybe one day it would be,it
would be cool to,to do again.
Dan: can be hard to even,even if
you're just doing it by yourself,
it's can be really hard to keep,
keep anything like that up,you
know?Especially when you have
other people involved.Yeah.Life,
like you said,life,life happens.
Can be tough.
Bekah: Yeah,I think it's
important to prioritize those
things that.Are working for you
too,right?And like I think
sometimes when it starts to feel
like that extra thing is a drag
and you don't wanna do it
anymore,or you know,it's just
like overwhelming to think about
it,then that's probably like the
time to let it go for a little
bit.
Carmen: Yeah,I,I completely
agree.That's how I felt,uh,
about,uh,yeah,the first time I
did hack Octoberfest when we were
trying to stream it,maintain an
open source,do all of the things,
and it's like,this is supposed to
be fun.If it's getting stressful,
let's stop.Cuz it's supposed to
be for fun.It's supposed to be
to,to help people and educate
people.But if it's starting to
turn into a stressor,then it's,
uh,no know your limits and
boundaries and yeah,be kind to
yourself.Um,cause something's
gonna,Uh,yeah.Suffer in it.
Bekah: Yeah,and I think.this is
kind of a tangent,but like taking
a personal inventory is something
that we've talked about,uh,in the
last couple of months at Virtual
Coffee.Just to kind of see where
you are,where you are,like what
your needs are,what your
strengths and weaknesses are,but
also to kind of identify those
types of things.You know,if
you're feeling overwhelmed by is
this,you might have needed that
thing three months ago and it
might have been really good for
you in that moment,or like that
community that you're a part of.
That was really great for you
last year,but it's not so great
for you this year and like
recognizing that like,hey,we
change and we grow as people and
we have different needs all the
time.Figuring out like what is
helping me to accomplish the
things that I need to be doing
every single day is really
important,but also like sometimes
really hard to identify If you
don't stop for a second.And,and
really think about like,what is
enriching my life right now?What
is helping me be the person that
I wanna be,rather than like,this
was helping me three months ago.
It should still be helping me
now,and then trying to power
through it.
Carmen: Mm-hmm.Yeah,I agree.
Bekah: Um,okay.So I guess maybe
one way that we can start to wrap
things up here is talking about
that introverted experience and
what advice you have for
individuals who are feeling
really nervous about coming into
tech and interviewing for their
first or second job.Because I
think that,you know,being an
introvert makes it.Maybe a little
bit harder to interview for that
job and to be able to find those
connections.So do you have any
advice for how to approach that
in a way that doesn't seem
overwhelming?
Carmen: Um,gosh.It's,uh,it's hard
for me to answer this one because
both of my,like interviews in
tech have been very,uh,
non-traditional because,uh,first
one was an internship and it was
just like,I like you,you like me,
let's be a happy DevOps family
type of thing.And then the second
job was actually through,uh,a
friend I made in Virtual Coffee.
So,uh,both of them were very
non-traditional because they were
like,I know that you know the
things cuz you talk about them in
Virtual Coffee.So I don't need to
interview you technically about
the things,and it's like,I wanna
work with you.Uh,so I guess,uh,
that's one way to go about it is
make friends and then friends
wanna work with friends because
you,you get along,you know,uh,
you,you know how each other.Tick
kind of.So it's like,you know how
to approach each other.Uh,so,so I
guess that's one way of going
about it.
Bekah: I,I think that's really
great advice,right?Like making
those connections can help ease
that interview process for sure.
And that's been.All of my jobs in
tech too,I think.Uh,and it,it
didn't start with meeting people.
It started with tweeting about it
and then writing about it and
then talking about it in
different ways.And so maybe like
there's,I.There's a place where
you feel kind of comfortable or
you don't feel as uncomfortable
or as exhausted from those
interactions,and you can still
have a community and you can
still meet people if you're
blogging about it or if you're
writing about it,or if you post a
YouTube video.You don't have to
have that face-to-face
interaction.But I do think that
it's easier to have that
face-to-face interaction once
you've engaged with people on
other platforms.
Carmen: Yeah.Yeah,definitely.
And,and also you're interviewing
them,like,do you wanna work with.
Best person,so I guess it goes
both ways.
Bekah: Yeah,absolutely.All right,
Carmen,thanks so much for being
here with us today and sharing
your story.We really appreciate
this.I think that it's gonna be
helpful to a lot of people who
are going through some struggles
now and have in the past,and
feeling like they're not alone in
that experience.So thanks so much
for sharing your story with us
today.
Carmen: Thank you.
Dan: Thanks Carmen.Thank you so
much for listening to this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
Podcast.This episode was produced
by Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot
Weigel,and edited by Ashley
Mulder.If you have questions or
comments,you can hit us up on
Twitter@VirtualCoffeeIO or email
us at podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,sign
up for the newsletter,buy some VC
merch,and check out all of our
other resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io.If you're
interested in sponsoring Virtual
Coffee,you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week.