Bekah: Hello and welcome to.Is
Season eight,episode four of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast.I'm Bekah,
and this is a podcast that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community.Virtual Coffee
is an intimate tech community of
people at all stages of their
journey,and they're here on this
podcast sharing their stories and
what they've learned,and we're
here to share it with you.Here
with me today is my co-host,Dan.
Dan: What up back?How's it going?
Bekah: It's going good.How's it
going with you?
Dan: It's going very,very well.
Um,we just finished recording a
really great episode with Caitlin
Floyd.So Caitlin is a front end
developer who transitioned into
tech from a background in
linguistics and education and
nonprofit management.Um,and,uh,
she had a really interesting
journey.She,she was doing
bootcamp in the,the middle of
bootcamp is when the pandemic,
uh,shutdowns happened.And so that
was a really fascinating story to
hear about.And um,and then she
shared with us a lot of thoughts
on,um,mentorship.And it was a
really,really good conversation.
Bekah: Yeah.I appreciated hearing
all of her thoughts on,uh,how to,
how to be mentored,how to be a
mentor,and how we all can kind of
men.Mentor each other.I think
that she did a good job of
redefining what we traditionally
think of mentorship in a way that
will be really useful to a lot of
people.
Dan: Yeah,totally.There's,
there's a lot of,uh,Details and,
you know,the,the mentor mentee
relationship can look different
in a lot of different ways.And I
think that Caitlin did a,a great
job of breaking down,uh,breaking
down those differences and,you
know,some of the benefits and
downsides of,of different
relationships and,um,ways that we
can find those relationships in,
in our,in our careers,in our
lives.Uh,whether it's from the
mentee perspective or the mentor
perspective.Um,she had a lot of
great thoughts on that.
Bekah: Yeah,so we start every
episode of the podcast,like we
start every Virtual Coffee.We
introduce ourselves with our
name,where we're from,what we do,
and a random check-in question.
We hope you enjoy this episode.
Today's random question is,if you
were a character in a video game,
what would your special ability
or power up be?I.My name is
Bekah.I am the developer
experience lead at Open Sauce.
I'm from a small town in Ohio and
my special ability or power up,
what was I,I was playing Smash
Bros the other day,and there were
some cool abilities,but like
somebody I think created a portal
and could jump through it.That
was a pretty cool one.But I
always did like in Mario,like the
getting the fire flower or
whatever it's called,but like who
are you gonna hit with the fire?
Like you In real life,you can't
really just like fireball
somebody I don't think.
Dan: I mean,you could,but it
would be illegal
Bekah: Would it be nice?
Dan: probably immoral.
Bekah: So I guess just a portal.
Dan: Uh,okay.Yeah,I am Dan.I live
in Cleveland and I do website
development.And,um,yeah,I mean,
so the question starts with if
you're a character in a video
game,so like,are you in,in the
video game or is this like,I can
take a power from any video game
and just apply it to my
Bekah: Oh,I suppose it meant in a
video game,but I decided to apply
it to real life instead.
Dan: I mean,right.They're
different,right?So like,I mean,
the easy answer for me is the
star,you know,for Mario,right?
Where you just become invincible
and you get some later ones,you
become faster and stuff,and
you're really flashy and
Bekah: you destroy
Dan: uh,sure.Yeah.I'm not big on
destroying people.Uh,I know
that's kind of your jam,but,uh,
portals made me like,that was a
good call too.Um,there's the game
portal and I think it's called
Portal.Uh,it's a video game and
it's really,really cool.So you
have like a gun and you can,you
know,shoot a.The entrance one
place and then the exit,another
place,you know,and,and uh,
basically just instantly
transport to anywhere.That's
cool.That's cool too.So if I,if
I'm going real life,I'm gonna do,
do the portal thing.If I'm going
video game,I suppose the,the
power up,you know,the star from,
from Mario,you know,plus you get
to wear overalls all the time,
which is cool.He got a nice hat.
So,I dunno,that's my answer.Go
ahead Caitlin.
Caitlin: Um,yeah,this is a tricky
one.My,the first thing that came
to mind was just like I.Power up,
like energy.I'm always tired.Uh,
so it would be nice to do that.
But the portal thing is
interesting too.I like,there's a,
a similar concept in this classic
Japanese,um,cartoon where he has
like a door that can take him
anywhere,but he also has these
like pills you can take to learn
anything you want.You just like,
it's like a tiny little book and
you eat it and you can learn
anything you want.I think it's
for24hours or something,but that
could be really handy too.Um,
It's not a video game,it's a
cartoon,but I feel like that
could be a video game.Power to
just knowledge,power.Uh,I'll go
with that.
Dan: I like that.And can you,uh,
for the listeners do
Caitlin: Oh,I didn't do my intro.
Sorry.I was so,I was thinking so
hard about my answer to the
question.Yeah,sorry.My name is
Caitlin.Uh,I use she her
pronouns.Um,I am based in the
Washington DC area and I'm a
front end developer here.Um,and
yeah,knowledge would be my
superpower of choice.
Bekah: I like it.
Dan: Yeah,there's that.Also not a
video game,but uh,the movie
Limitless.You know,there's that
pill and just like makes you,I
guess,super smart,but also able
to learn things very quickly.I
don't,I haven't watched that
movie for a long time,but you
know that,that.If there was no
side effects,that always seemed
like a pretty cool,uh,you know,
fake thing too.It's just the
ability to use your brain better,
you know?
Bekah: Yeah,I could use that.I'm
using my brain better.
Caitlin: Couldn't we all?
Bekah: Well,Caitlin,thanks so
much for being here with us
today.We're very happy to finally
have you on the podcast
Caitlin: Yeah.Thanks for having
me.
Bekah: Um,we always like to get
started with your origin story,
so let us know like how you got
to this point in your career.
Caitlin: Sure.Yeah.So,um,yeah,
thanks for having me today.I'm
very excited to be here.Um,so my
journey into tech,um,felt.In some
ways kind of inevitable,but it
was a very intentional decision
on my part.Um,like a lot of
people in the VC community,I had
a previous career,uh,before going
into tech.My,my career was in
language access.Um,so I studied
linguistics as an undergrad,went
into teaching English to speakers
of other languages,both
domestically and abroad.Um,did
some teacher training,so teaching
teachers.How to teach.Um,and
then,uh,moved into nonprofit
management at a refugee
resettlement agency where I
oversaw the education program
there.Um,so I loved that whole
career.Uh,it was really
rewarding,but uh,at the same time
I was starting to experience
pretty intense burnout,um,and.
Decided to kind of take stock of
what I wanted out of a career,
because I kind of realized I
hadn't been super intentional up
until that point about crafting
my career.Um,and burnout was a
great,uh,motivator to do that.So
I,I realized that,um,I already
knew that.I loved linguistics,
communication,problem solving,
um,like pattern recognition.
Those were things I liked and,
um,that I was good at.Um,but as
far as what I wanted from a job,
I knew that I wanted something
that was a change of pace from
constant triaging of problems,
uh,like you do in.Bekah,as you
know,in teaching,um,as well as in
nonprofit management.Um,and so I
wanted something that allowed me
like deep work and flow state.
Um,and I also wanted something
more importantly that would give
me flexibility to kind of,um,I
have work-life balance.Uh,I
wanted to.Work to live,not live
to work.Um,and so something that
could give me flexibility about
where I wanted to work from,uh,
the concept of remote work was
really novel in2019.Uh,less so
now,but it's still a big benefit
to working in tech.Um,and you
know,also when you're working.
Um,so these were all factors that
kind of,I had this mixing pot of
ideas and it kind of distilled
down into,I should really
consider software engineering.
Um,this is kind of a.Great fit
for all of those factors.It's,
it's new and exciting.It's a
growing industry.Um,and so I,uh,
I went to a coding bootcamp,um,
and,uh,it was a struggle,but I,I
made it through.There were some
tears shed,but,um,I made it.Uh,
and then,um,I landed at my
current job,um,at a news agency,
uh,where I'm doing front end
development.And it's been,um,a
really rewarding,um,Job,and I'm
really happy that I made that
change.
Bekah: That's so good to hear.
Uh,can you talk a little bit more
about your bootcamp?Were you in
person online?How long did that
take?
Caitlin: Yeah,so I signed up for
an in-person bootcamp,but uh,we
were supposed to finish in May of
2020,so it did not end as an
in-person bootcamp.Uh,we started
in-person,um,and then I was also
in New York City at the time,so
that was,uh,hit quite early,um,
in the country.So,uh,Yeah,we were
in person for most of the
learning modules.The second half
of the bootcamp was,um,more
project based and that we had one
week in person before they told
us we were gonna try remote for
quote unquote,for maybe a week or
so.Uh,we never saw each other
again,which was,uh,unfortunate.
It was a good learning
experience,though I had a great
team and,um,we learned trial by
fire.We learned how to
collaborate remotely.Um,Luckily,
we were all very,you know,
communication was something we
all valued.So,um,it was,um,yeah,
I mean,I don't have anything to
compare it to.I've always
collaborated with other
developers remotely,uh,because
of,of the nature of how things
played out,but I really enjoy it.
Um,yeah.Yeah,it was great.
Bekah: I think you might be the
first person,that we talked to.
Um,who was impacted by the
pandemic during their bootcamp
experience,cuz so many people
decided during the pandemic to
change careers,but you were in
the midst of it during that,
which I think is probably more
chaotic because,I don't know,
like with my kids coming home,
like they sent home all their
books and stuff,but nobody knew
what to do.The,the learning
experience was awful just
because,It was not anticipated.
That had to be.That sounds like
it was a,a big challenge.
Caitlin: Yeah,definitely it was,
um,Yeah,I was not prepared for,
for that.I mean,no one was
prepared for the pivot,but it was
an interesting time to have quit
my job and entered,uh,not very
junior friendly workforce as an
engineer.Um,but I mean,luckily
our teachers,you know,were very
tech savvy,uh,being,you know,
tech professionals.So that pivot
I think was.It's easier for them
than other teachers I've known
who worked in,you know,not in the
tech space.I think that I,like my
heart went out to so many,I knew
a lot of English teachers who
were having to figure that out.
My mom also is a teacher,uh,and
she was having to teach her peers
how to,like,what is Zoom?Like
what is a webcam?Uh,and it was,
uh,it was chaotic for all of us.
But yeah,that,that was an
interesting time to be going
through bootcamp.
Dan: Aside from,you know,the.I
don't know,technical adjustments
that ev everybody would expect.
Are there like any,how did the,
like learning process,I mean,I
know it changed,but,you know,
comparing and contrasting since
it was the same class right?You
know,halfway through whatever.
Um,how,how did it,you know,how
did not being in the room with
people affect your,like the
learning process and maybe your
enjoyment and or effectiveness of
it?Um,
Caitlin: Yeah,I mean,I am really
grateful that we at least had
that initial period of time to
get to know each other.So I was
at least more comfortable asking
my teachers questions or my peers
because I had,you know,like run
into them,uh,at the,in the
kitchen or something.And,and we
had that foundation,but pivoting
into being remote,um,it was just
such a,A paradigm shift of how,
how do I approach even like pair
programming.Uh,we had to,we were
like,all right,let's Google,you
know,remote pairing tools,uh,
figure it out.Um,and so I think
our default was to just
over-communicating,which I think
was the right call of just,you
know,if,if you have a question,
just ask it.Um,and if you,you
know,if you are.You know,I don't
know if you see foresee a
possible problem,just bring it
up.Um,my,my project,um,teammates
and I were pretty much on Zoom
all day,which was,uh,that was
before we had ever heard the term
Zoom fatigue.But um,yeah,it was
kind of interesting because in
some ways it was kind of,
Exciting to kind of realize,
okay,we can share screens and we
can both be researching separate
things at the same time,still see
each other's screens.We can be
looking at docs and kind of like
distill down,um,what we've been
learning or watching a video.Um,
and so I think that kind of
helped me to think more flexibly
in terms of how I was learning
and kind of think more,um,I feel
like it,it made me work the
elasticity of my brain in a
different way.Um,so yeah,I mean,
again,I,I don't have anything
like to compare it to like my
chaotic version was,was the
version.I know.Um,but I think it
helped me to get an appreciation
for some of the collaborative,
collaborative tools that are
available to you.Remotely that
are not available to you in
person.Usually you hear people
making the opposite case.Um,
there's valid arguments to be
made there,but I think there are
some benefits to working remotely
that you don't get working in
person.So,
Dan: Yeah,totally.I,I,I,uh,I was
just,I was curious because I,I
feel like the stories that we've
heard of people doing boot camps
that were more successful,I.Um,
were often ones where there's
more contact,more communication
with other students.Um,you know,
whether that's in person or,um,I
know one member like did just on
their own,but,you know,made a
study group with,with the other
students,uh,and communicated like
that together.Right.Um,and,uh,I
feel like the,the people that had
a good experience,um,you know,
in,in boot camps,uh,often have
similar stories like that,you
know,and so I was,I was curious
and it's good to hear that you
guys worked it out,right?The,
that,the,um,Since you already
knew each other,maybe it was a
lot easier to just try to push
through some of those things.
Whereas if you had started all
remote,you know,it's all just
strangers and,um,maybe it
would've been a harder,uh,
especially if the,the teachers or
whatever don't encourage that
sort of thing,you know,or don't,
um,put a emphasis on it.Um,so I
don't know.That sounds cool.It
sounds like you,you all did like
a really good job of,of,uh,
making it through that
Caitlin: Yeah,we did our best.
Dan: Yeah.
Caitlin: Yeah.
Bekah: What was the mentorship
like as you went through boot
camp?Was that a thing?Do,do you
feel like you had good
experiences there?
Caitlin: Yeah,we,so our program
had,I,I think this is pretty
common in bootcamps of some kind
of a TA position,um,where those
are people who have recently gone
through the bootcamp and they're,
uh,there to serve as extra
support for,um,current students.
And so we had that program,um,
Which was really,really helpful
because sometimes you feel a
little,you,something's not
clicking very quickly,and if
you're talking to your teacher
who knows it,like the back of
their hand,it can be a little
intimidating to ask questions.
So,um,having someone who's a
little bit more closely.More
recently gone through,the
experience you had gone through
was really helpful for,um,asking
technical questions or even
asking more career strategic,uh,
questions of like,you know,how do
I work on a resume or something
like that.Um,and so I thought
that,um,our program did a really
great job of picking,uh,People
for those positions who were
interested in helping us to
develop our skills,who were not
just like looking for a resume
booster,but actually had,um,some
of the skills to back it up,um,
the technical skills and the more
the soft skills,um,needed to
support very vulnerable people
who are feeling dumb every day.
Um,and,and yeah,I thought that
was a,a pretty crucial part of my
experience.
Bekah: What do you think some of
those skills are that make
somebody a good mentor?
Caitlin: Ooh,great question.Um,I
think that first and foremost,
um,having a strong sense of
curiosity,um,and being,I think
that seeking mentorship can be a
very vulnerable position.And so
having empathy for that and,um,
Not being judgmental of someone
who's asking you questions is,is
a really important starting
point.Creating that trust,uh,
with someone to open up and seek
advice.Um,yeah,I would say that's
probably the most important
thing.Um,and f for on the,on the
empathy point,being able to put
yourself in someone else's shoes,
um,whether or not you've
necessarily had the exact same
experience,being able to relate,
um,experiences to your own and,
and considering.What might be
different and what challenges
someone might be facing that are
different than you,um,will help
you to give better advice than if
you're just kind of just making
it like all about me.This is,you
know,everything that worked for
me.Um,considering what might have
worked for you might not work for
someone else.
Bekah: Yeah.I love that.It's so
important,um,to be able to.Get
yourself in somebody else's
viewpoint because everybody
learns in different ways.They
understand differently,and you
have to be able to explain those
things.And I think that,you know,
Caitlin,you've done a great job
at Virtual Coffee and a lot of
other places in supporting other
people.So do you wanna talk a
little bit about how that role
has shifted for you?So how you
went from being the one mentored
to being the mentor?Yep.That's
it.
Caitlin: Yeah.Thanks so much for
saying that.That's very,um,nice
of you to say,um,Yeah,I think
that my introduction to the
concept of mentorship was very
much from a place of desperation
and like,I need someone to help
me and tell me what to do because
I don't know what I'm doing.Um,
and that is not the best,uh,
place to be coming from.I think,
uh,what really helped me as a
mentee,uh,was.Starting to reframe
that relationship as,um,you know,
not like this all-knowing person
who's distilling knowledge down
to me,but just someone else who's
been where I'm at and has
experience to share and that I
can learn from.Um,kind of see it,
reframing it that way was helpful
to me in not being afraid to seek
out mentors.Um,I also,it was
really helpful to me hearing
about the concept of peer
mentorship,uh,because that also
made it a little bit more
attainable that,oh,like I can
seek mentorship from my peers.I
could also give mentorship to my
peers.Um,you know,I might have
some experience in a specific
area,uh,that's valuable to them.
Um,so I think kind of what helped
me start to shift into taking on
some mentor,some mentoring
opportunities was I.Uh,kind of
trying to embody that duality of
having the curiosity of more of a
student.Um,and also kind of
trying to take on some of the,
more of the generosity of a
teacher,um,and realizing that you
can do both.You don't have to be
like,I am now a mentor.I am no
longer a mentee.Like it's,it's a
fluid relationship there.Um,and
you might even have relationships
with some people where you fill
both of those roles depending on
the day.I like,for example,I have
a,um,A colleague that I work
with,uh,we started on the exact
same day.Um,and we check in
regularly and sometimes she is
giving me more advice,sometimes
I'm giving her more.Um,and so
like that helped kind of ease me
along the river of mentorship,I
guess where I,I was kind of
understanding that it's not a
finite position that you take.
It's,it's just kind of a,it's
just relationships at the end of
the day.It's just scary words to
describe relationships that we
all have.
Dan: Do you have an,in your
current situation,any,like any,
um,Any mentor or mentee
relationships that are like
defined that way?You know,uh,I
mean the,the relationship between
your colleague sounds like really
good and healthy,you know,work
relationship.But,um,I was just
curious if there's,if there's a
situations that you're in now
where,there,where it's like it
is,it does have that scary word
attached to it,you know,like
officially.
Caitlin: Yeah.Um,at my job I
don't currently have.Either a
formal mentor or mentee.Um,but I
do,uh,volunteer often with the
collab lab,which,um,I know you've
both heard of,uh,there's a lot of
people in Virtual Coffee,but for
anyone listening,if they don't
know,it's a program that is
designed specifically to provide
mentorship to or early career
developers.Um,And I started there
as a mentee,uh,like as a,we call
them collabs.Um,and you know,I
formally had a few people,uh,who
were my mentors.Actually Jono was
one of my,uh,mentors.Um,and that
was really nice having,sometimes
it is helpful to have a defined
relationship where you are like,
okay,this is the person that I'm
asking advice for.There's a time
limit set.Um,so it's less
pressure,um,for someone to accept
that position.Um,And I've since
moved into,you know,the other
side where I'm mentoring.Um,
there and there,there definitely
are some benefits to having that
structured relationship.Um,but it
definitely can be a little bit of
a daunting label to put on.So
just keeping in mind that it's,
it sounds scary,but it doesn't
have to be.It's just,you know,
cultivating a relationship with
someone.Um,and.it,it,I think it
feels transactional when you use
the word mentorship.Um,but that
doesn't have to be a dirty word.
Um,and you can always,even as a
mentee,you can always be sharing
your experience.Um,you,you are
always bringing something to the
table so you can still benefit
your mentor even if,even in that,
uh,closely defined relationship.
Bekah: Yeah.I also think like as
developers,it's important to be
around other people of lots of
different levels,and you might
naturally find yourself in the
role of mentor,but it also helps
you to understand user experience
too,right?Like there are
different.People at all different
stages.You're not always building
for somebody with,um,years of
experience and vast amounts of
knowledge.So to be able to
clearly communicate with a large,
uh,audience,I think it that makes
it kind of essential to embrace
the idea of horizontal mentorship
and be willing to listen to other
people and to associate with
them.Otherwise,you start to get
tunnel vision.
Caitlin: Yeah,for sure.I think
it's so important for,um,anyone
who's working in tech to have a.
Uh,to constantly have a,a
beginner's mindset and always be
wanting to learn.So even if you
are a,you know,a staff engineer
talking to a junior engineer,
like to kind of have an extreme
example,like coming to that
conversation and,and being
willing to learn something,um,I
think is,uh,a really important
skill and really beneficial,um,
in terms of long,long-term career
growth.
Bekah: Yeah,I was recently on
Twitter and somebody was asking
like,how do you even find a
mentor?I'm trying to learn,and so
I know I,I.You probably have
thoughts on this,so,you know,if
you were to offer that person
advice,what would it be?
Caitlin: Yeah,I definitely have
been that person before of like
desperately wanting mentors and
not knowing where to look.Um,I
think one,I mean,one starting
point is seeking out peer
mentorship.That can be a lot less
daunting.I.Or it's,it's a lot
more accessible to you.So if
you're in a bootcamp,um,you know,
linking up with other people in
your bootcamp and kind of helping
each other out that way,um,
There's also a great talk that I
saw,um,by,uh Kay Woo on Twitter.
Um,I can share the link
afterwards,but she talks about
the idea of being a stealth
mentee,um,where the person who is
your mentor doesn't have to know
they're your mentor,uh,
necessarily.Like if we broaden
our.Um,our definition of what
mentorship is,um,it becomes a lot
more accessible.So if you are
just having a conversation with,
um,for example,uh,a developer on
your team or just chatting with
someone at a,at a conference,um,
you can learn a lot.You can ask
questions,uh,to benefit from
their experience.Um,and that's
really what mentorship is at the
end of the day.Um,you could even,
I.Kind of,it's a little bit,uh,
outside of the traditional,um,
definition of mentorship,but you
could read a blog post or watch a
video from someone and there's
not even necessarily a direct
relationship there,but you're
still getting the benefits of
mentorship if you're learning
from their experience.So I think,
um,Being less strict with your
definition can help you to kind
of ease into finding different
avenues for mentorship.Um,and
then eventually if you're
constantly seeking that out,
you'll,you'll kind of start to
foster those relationships that
can lead to more traditional,um,
mentorship relationships.
Bekah: I love that so much.Uh,it
reminds me.Me,I think it was an
Instagram story I saw with,um,
Sarah Blakely,the founder of
Spanx,and she met this woman,I
don't know,it was like at the
store.She just ran into her.The
woman was so excited.She was
like,you are my mentor.And she
had a list of five mentors,which
were like celebrities or people
that are prominent in their
field.And she said that,She,
these are people that she always
listens to what they're saying.
She watches their talks,she reads
their books or listens to their
podcasts or whatever because they
have so much knowledge that
they're sharing and she knows
that she'll probably never have a
personal relationship with those
people.But it's not,it,it's,they
are still providing her with
mentorship.In a different way.
And so it was expanding that
definition to really glow it,
grow in that knowledge.And so it,
even if you go that far,which I
think might feel like the extreme
opposite end,it's all about like
being open to growing and
learning from different people.
And so I really love the idea of
just.Thinking about it in new
ways,you know,it doesn't have to
be that one-on-one relationship.
And like,to be honest with you,I
think the,the most impactful
mentorship that I've had has been
being part of a community because
it's just like everybody,just by
the nature of developing
relationships,respecting each
other,trusting each other,
growing together.We all kind of
mentor each other in a way that's
really authentic.And I think when
that happens,that's for me
personally,something that is,um,
a really great experience.
Caitlin: Yeah,I totally agree.I
think like,um,networking is
another one of those words that
sounds scary and it,it,it's like
has all this pressure associated
with it,but really it's just
forming relationships and
community.Um,and I'm really
grateful to vc.I feel like it's
really helped me to expand,um,
And like take off some of the
pressure of what I associated
with networking.Um,you're just
meeting people and cultivating
relationships.Um,and that is a
much more comfortable way of
forming those kind of mentoring
relationships if you are just
chatting with someone and getting
to know them as opposed to like
sending a cold message on
LinkedIn of like,I want to be my
mentor.Like,that's,that's a lot
of pressure if you're just
starting to get to know someone.
It's a lot more of a,of a natural
way of forming that relationship.
Bekah: Yeah,and that can be
really hard.Uh,there's a lot of
people that want the one-on-one
time,and I,I do feel like
sometimes there's a time and a
place for that.But group
mentorship in a lot of ways can
be more impactful because you
hear other people asking
questions.And I don't know,
there's something about that.I
think there's a couple of things.
Like one,it helps you to see,it
helps,it helped me to overcome
imposter syndrome.Like,oh,that
person has that question too.Um,
it also helps you to learn how to
communicate with other people
because you know,no matter where
you are,you're,you need to be
asking questions to learn and to
grow and what is the right way to
do that?I mean,there's no one
right way,but there are
definitely ways that are going to
help you progress and grow a lot
more.Um,if you know how to ask
the right questions or what the
process looks like.And so even
like group mentorship,actually
Virtual Coffee,coffee table
groups I think are kind of a good
example of this cuz we have
people at all different levels
who are sharing and being part of
these groups together.And that
the um,diversity of level of
folks in those groups,I think
allows people to learn and grow a
a lot more.
Caitlin: Yeah,I totally agree.I
think too,another benefit of
group mentorship as opposed to
one-on-one is that when you're
getting one-on-one mentorship,
you always have to be aware that
this is one person's opinion
based on their lived experience.
They might have,you know,
blinders on as to certain factors
that might impact you,as opposed
to if you're getting,um,feedback
from a group of people,you're
getting a,a little bit more of a
balanced,um,Perspective on your
problems.And so,um,yeah,I think
there's a ton of benefits to
getting,um,less conventional
types of mentorship.
Dan: Yeah,I'd agree with that.
And,and that's like that,uh,the
value of like having more eyes on
a,on a thing is,is true in,in
mentorship,is true in code.It's
true in a lot of ways,you know,
and I think I.I mean,not to,you
know,pump up Virtual Coffee even
more in our own podcast,but,you
know,it,it's,it is one of the
like really awesome things,you
know,and when we're doing,like,
octoberfest,right?We have people
that have never done open source
before.We have people that are,
you know,do it for their work.
Like all involved in the same,in
the same thing.And,you know,a
nice channel where,where people
can ask questions and all that
stuff.And,and you're right,you
get,you get lots of different
answers.Here's what works worked
for me.Uh,here's what worked for.
Five other people,right?And,uh,
sometimes it's gonna be the same
answer.You know,like sometimes
it's all just everybody's saying,
yes,that thing is,that thing is
good,that solution is the right
one.And sometimes it's,you know,
most times in tech or career or
whatever,there's not one right
answer.And,um,the,the more,the
more you can get,uh,you know,
there's diminishing returns,I
suppose,you know,if you ask a
question on Twitter just for
everybody to answer.The,the
results may vary,right.You know,
uh,but,but that's,that's the
value of having,you know,a,a
smaller group or a smaller
community where you do know
people and you know their
histories and all that stuff.Um,
it's,it's really good.
Caitlin: Yeah.And getting to know
those people over time too,so you
can kind of understand.Um,It
gives you a little bit more
context,uh,for where they're
coming from as opposed to like,
you know,going on Stack Overflow
is not the same as going to like
a VC group and asking a question.
Um,it's a lot more,um,of a
personalized experience.So,yeah,
I,I think it's finding those
communities,um,can really help
you to,to develop that kind of a,
a rapport.
Dan: Yeah.And the,the over time
aspect of it I think is,is one of
the big,is one of the big.Pieces
of this,right?And,and this is
true even with,uh,single mentor,
you know,mentee relationship,is
that I think the value of it will
increase over time,right?Uh,
because you both know more about
each other.Um,and the same with
groups and things like that.I,
and I think this is probably a
good value of,uh,collab lab too,
right?Is is it's,it's not just a
one time thing or,or random
groups.I mean,I suppose it.I
don't know.I don't know how they
choose,you know who the groups
are,but the groups are small.
Right?And then it's the same
group for eight,eight weeks.Is
that what it is?
Caitlin: Yeah,it's eight weeks.
Yep.
Dan: right.Yeah.And so you,you
end up learning the same thing,
uh,the same kinds of things about
the people in the group over,or I
would imagine,anyway.I've not,
I've never done it.But it seems
like that that would be a value
of that,of that kind of group
too.Um,is over time,you know,
you,you develop those connections
and the,the,the answers become
more specific,you know,uh,and
things like that.Um,Yeah.I,I
Caitlin: with that.
Dan: yeah.Yeah.I,I,I actually
like speaking of collab lab,I was
wondering if you could talk a
little bit more just about,
specifically about the
experience,um,as a mentor,cuz you
were a mentor.How many times have
you
Caitlin: I've mentored.Yeah,so
I've mentored,um,a few times in a
few different ways.So there's.
Two main ways that I've mentored,
um,as a project mentor,which is,
uh,what you're describing where
there's eight weeks and you're
paired with a small team.Um,we
also have,um,mentors that work
with our,um,career lab program.
Um,and so that is short,a
shorter,um,period of time and
more focused on helping someone
to develop,um,either their mock
interview or their job interview
skills,um,or their LinkedIn,um,
and things like that.Um,And so
those are pretty different types
of,uh,relationships there.The,
the career lab is a shorter term,
uh,relationship with a more
focused goal of,you know,
developing this one part of
someone's,um,job hunting package.
Um,
Dan: just,is that one on one or?
Caitlin: Yeah.Yeah.So,so there
is,there's kind of a group,
there's a cohort that goes
through career lab.Um,and then,
uh,each person is paired with a
few different mentors to help
them with a few different pieces
of their,um,job hunting package.
So they might be paired with one
person for a mock,uh,behavioral
interview,another for a mock
technical interview,and another
for reviewing their LinkedIn,uh,
materials,which again,like you're
getting different.They're
focusing on different things,but
you're still getting three
different people's perspectives
and they might have different
advice to give you.Um,so it's,
it's beneficial in that way.Um,
and then,so the other,uh,type of,
uh,mentorship,uh,that I've gotten
to take part in is the project
mentor.Um,and that too,uh,we have
four collabs,four developers,and
then three mentors that are
paired that are,um,Grouped with
them.Um,and so again,you're
getting to benefit from multiple
people's experiences and getting
to kind of distill that
information into what works for
you.Um,and that is,uh,over eight
weeks.So you've got a little bit
of time to develop re
relationships with them.Um,you
can interact with them in a group
setting with the rest of your
team.Um,sometimes we'll have
office hours so you can kind of
talk one-on-one or ask questions.
Um,and so I,I,I value both types
of,uh,relationships,but.It is
really nice to get to see someone
over time.Um,you know,thinking
from the perspective of a mentor.
They,they wanna help you,they
wanna see you growing,so it's
kind of nice to have a longer
term relationship and get to see,
um,how you're growing and
developing.Um,you know,hopefully
from the benefit of their advice.
Dan: It sounds really awesome.It
sounds really valuable from both
sides.Like it sounds valuable as
a,as a mentee,somebody learning,
you know,but also,I mean,I mean,
maybe you could speak to this,
but it sounds like very valuable,
uh,as a,as a mentor,um,to,I don't
know,to,to learn from other
people and,and practice this kind
of thing.Um,It just seems like a
cool project,so
Caitlin: Yeah,totally.I think
it's good to keep in mind for
mentees too,that you know,like
what is the benefit to my mentor
for this?It's probably they,they
feel good about helping you and
they wanna see you develop.And
so,uh,one thing you can do to be
a good mentee is to demonstrate
that,like show them,Hey,I
followed up on this advice and,
and it really worked for me.Or,
you know,I followed up on your
advice and I'm still struggling
with it.Maybe we can follow up.
Um,thinking about that as a
mentee can help you to develop
even better relationships with
your mentor.
Bekah: I love that.I don't think
I've ever heard that advice given
before,but I think that's a
really great way to look at it.
Um,one of the challenges that I
see in mentor-mentee
relationships sometimes is that
I.The mentee becomes too
dependent on the mentor.And so
rather than spending that,
spending extra time,it's just
kind of like the knee jerk
reaction to like,I'm stuck,I've
gotta ask my mentor.And then just
that continued behavior,um,which
makes it hard for them to grow,
right?Like to separate themselves
from that relationship.And I
think it's also challenging as a
mentor.To identify that and to
kind of like guide them in the
right direction when you see that
happening.I don't know if you
have any thoughts on that or
advice,but I,I think that that
gets a little tricky.
Caitlin: Yeah,for sure.Um,and I,
I can relate as someone who
doesn't,you know,sometimes hasn't
always had confidence and just
wants to ask someone for help,
um,I think that's a really
natural thing.Um,As a mentor,
something that you can do for
that is maybe leaning more
towards coaching than mentoring.
Um,so mentoring is generally when
you're giving someone advice
based on your own experience,um,
and,and just kind of letting them
use that to help solve their
problems.Uh,whereas coaching can
sometimes be differentiated
where.It's a little bit closer to
teaching where you're asking
questions to help someone come to
their own conclusions.Um,and so,
you know,if someone's asking you
like,how do I solve this problem?
Instead of just being like,well,
this is what I did in the past.
You could lean more towards
asking questions like,well,uh,
what kind of documentation do we
think we should look for?Or,you
know,like,what,um,What are some
keywords we can search for online
to help us find a problem?Is
there a stack trace we can use
to,you know,start from there and,
and follow up?So,um,asking
questions is a really good way to
help kind of take off some of
those training wheels and help
someone to start to find their
own answers to the questions so
that they're able to kind of
exercise those skills even when
you're not there.
Dan: I agree.I,I was just gonna
say,I,I love that advice and you
know,it's like even,um,From a
parenting perspective,right?I
have,you know,young kids and
it's,it's the same kind of thing.
It's,they asks the same question
over and over again,you know,
and,um,trying to pro provide for
them,uh,the tools to figure the
answer out themselves,uh,
although more complicated and
takes a little more effort,uh,
you know,in the initial stages,
um,can yeah.Pay a lot of
dividends,uh,in the end.So it
just made me think,yeah.Ben,you
know,you know where to find out
what's for dinner.We,we write it
down on the fridge.Go,go look at
it.Don't yell at me from the
couch.What's for dinner?
Caitlin: Yeah,I'm sure as a
parent you have those skills down
pat.Like if you're dealing with
someone who has,you know,has
learned the life skills,it's way
easy to just point them towards
just Google it.
Dan: Right.How would you find
that information out
Bekah: ask Alexa.I need someone
to check my math homework.Alexa
will check your math homework.
Um,oh wait,I,I had an another
question that I don't know.I feel
like this is a tricky topic too.
Um,we see a lot of people in job
situations who are forced to
mentor,like,You are a senior
developer,you must mentor this
junior developer because that's
what senior developers have to
do.And I think,I think that
mentorship is a skill that needs
to be developed,and some people
are better at it than other
people.And I don't know that I
necessarily agree with the idea
that.Everybody should be a
mentor.Like we all have our
strengths and weaknesses,things
that bring us joy and energy.And
so I don't know what your
thoughts are on that and I feel
like I kind of put you on the
spot here a little bit with that
question.Um,but I think that it's
good to kind of have this
conversation since it's
definitely something that we've
heard over and over at Virtual
Coffee.
Caitlin: Yeah,for sure.I totally
agree that.It's not a great
starting point.If someone is
feeling forced into a
relationship with someone,that
other person is often probably
gonna feel like a burden,like
they're not wanted and,and not
really feel comfortable seeking
out mentorship.Um,I,I think it is
a complicated issue.Um,I totally
agree that there are skills that
you need to learn to be a good
mentor.Um,and I think that,It's
good for there to be an
expectation that more experienced
people on a team should be
mentoring,um,less experienced
people.But I think that really.
This is a,a,a kind of lofty goal,
but as an industry,we need to
really value those skills that
are important for mentoring.If we
think that a senior developer
should be mentoring,then we
should be valuing the skills that
help them to be a good mentor.
And those should be important for
someone to be demonstrating
before they're getting those
promotions where they're going to
have to serve as a mentor to
someone.So,you know,valuing those
collaborative skills,um,you know,
being able to,um,see someone.
Having an ability to teach other
people if they're not
demonstrating it,their manager
should be helping them to develop
those skills before they get to
the point of being the like
person forced into mentorship.
Um,so that's,I mean,that's kind
of like easier said than done.
Um,if someone is finding themself
in a position of being forced to
mentor,um,there's lots of great.
Resources out there where you can
learn those skills because it is,
it,it is a skill that can be
learned,um,you know,if you're
going to like lead dev or
something like that.And,um,
really prioritizing those skills
because it's,if you want to have
a functioning team,you need to
have people who are continuing to
grow.And so it is,um,kind of
important for managers and other
people like that to.To put their
money where their mouth is and
value,um,those skills.And if
someone isn't demonstrating it to
like invest in teaching them
skills.
Bekah: I think that's super
important and something that's
overlooked.I don't know why it's
so overlooked.I think it's like
similar to that idea where people
just kind of max out and they
throw'em as a manager,like,okay,
you've reached a skill level,now
you're a manager.And that,that's
a different skill set and I,I
think it just needs to be
recognized that.Hey,like people
are good at different things.We
just need to make sure that if
this is the path that we're
sending them on,that we equip
them to do that.And I don't think
it should be an expectation that
every senior plus developer knows
how to mentor.Um,and in fact,
like some of them were not
mentored in.Anyway,uh,there have
definitely been people who have
had those experiences,which makes
it even more challenging for them
to learn and grow.And also,like,
you gotta evaluate,is this,is
this the best person to mentor?
Because that idea that you talked
about before in peer-to-peer
mentoring,I think that,you know
that you can,it,I think it's
possible to have a junior
developer mentor,another junior
developer.It's just about like,
Looking at those skill sets,
looking at the communication
skills and the collaboration and
does this make sense?And,you
know,then maybe providing some
upper level support if there are
questions.But I,I think that it
does come down to like evaluating
that,that side of things.
Caitlin: Yeah,I totally agree.
Yeah,it exactly like you said,
it's sometimes people.People
shouldn't be a manager or
shouldn't be a mentor.Um,or maybe
not that they shouldn't be,but
they're not ready yet.Uh,and need
to be prepared for that kind of,
um,shift cuz it's totally
different position than what they
have been doing before,what
they've been evaluated on before.
And you can't just say,oh well,
like this person's good at
juggling,so let's go make them a
lion tamer.Like that doesn't make
any sense.Um,you need to evaluate
the skills needed to do a job.
Yeah.
Bekah: Okay.Before we go,
Caitlyn,I've got one last
question for you.I'm just trying
to pick what is the right one.
We'll end on a positive note cuz
my other question was a little
bit negative.Um,uh,what are some
tips or,uh,some bits of advice
that you have for mentors to be
able to help their mentees kind
of level up setting,whether
that's setting career goals,
learning something new,or landing
that first job.
Caitlin: Ooh,good question.Um,so
I think two things I'll say.One
is that,um,if you're a mentor,
really I.Try to put a lot of
energy into listening to the
mentee before you're jumping in
and like giving them advice.Make
sure you're listening to the
problems that they're actually
wanting to solve,um,and not just
assuming that they want to do the
exact same thing that you've
done.Uh,because I think we all
have experience,uh,giving or
receiving unwanted advice,and
it's not,you know,it,it's not
really helpful to anyone.So
making sure that you are
understanding what kind of advice
someone wants,um,before you.Jump
into providing feedback.The other
thing I'll say is that,um,again,
try not to think of mentorship as
this huge thing,like this huge
responsibility of like a huge
commitment.Um,it can be a lot
more manageable if you break it
down.You can,you can really help
someone.Um,By,you know,thinking,
identifying a small problem that
they're having and giving them
advice to solve that problem,um,
can be just as beneficial as,as
finding a big problem and,and
helping them work through it,
like whatever your capacity is.
Finding ways of helping people,I
think is,um,Just start there.
And,um,yeah,whether it's
mentorship or sponsorship as
well,you can also,um,be really
helpful in like,providing
opportunities for people.Um,or,
you know,like opening a door for
someone.Um,try not to think of it
as a huge undertaking.Try and
just start with baby steps
because that's,uh,A more
approachable way of,um,getting
into mentoring and it's,it's
really gonna help someone.If
you're anything is better than
nothing,well usually,uh,any
giving,giving help,uh,whether
small or large,uh,is,is,uh,gonna
help benefit someone,but be
mindful about it.
Bekah: I am glad I,I chose that
question cuz that was a really
good way to,uh,end the episode.
You did a really good job of
answering that question and
sharing some things to think
about.So thanks Caitlyn so much
for being here with us today and
talking about mentorship.We're
happy to have you on the podcast.
Caitlin: Thanks for having me.
Dan: Thanks,Caitlin.Thank you so
much for listening to this
episode of the Virtual Coffee
Podcast.This episode was produced
by Dan Ott and Bekah Hawrot
Weigel,and edited by Ashley
Mulder.If you have questions or
comments,you can hit us up on
Twitter@VirtualCoffeeIO or email
us at podcast@virtualcoffee.io.
You can find the show notes,sign
up for the newsletter,buy some VC
merch,and check out all of our
other resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io.If you're
interested in sponsoring virtual
Coffee,you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a review.
Thanks for listening and we'll
see you next week.