Bekah Hawrot Weigel: Hello and
welcome to Season 8, Episode 5
of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. I'm
Bekah, and this is a podcast
that
features members of the Virtual
Coffee community. Virtual Coffee
is an intimate community of
people at all stages of their
tech journey. And they're here,
on this podcast, sharing their
stories and what they've
learned. And we're here to share
it with
you. Here with me today is my
co-host, Dan.
Dan Ott: Yo. What up, Beck?
How's it going?
Bekah: It is going fantastic.
Dan: Nice.
Bekah: How's it going with you?
Dan: It's going great. We have
another great episode for y'all.
We are sitting down with Reda.
Reda is a front-end developer
from Morocco. And we had a
really great talk ti- time
talking to
him. He actually started his
career in marine mechanics,
which is pretty interesting. And
during the pandemic,
decided to switch tracks into,
you know, web development and
front-end development in
general. And it was a really
good time
sitting and talking with him.
We- we learned a lot about his
story and--
I dunno. He's a very interesting
guy.
Bekah: Yeah, it was really
fascinating to hear, like, he
had
completed all of the stuff that
he needed for the marine
mechanics degree. The-- and- and
then after completing that,
decided to go into
coding, and did the whole self-
self-taught, route and what
that journey was like for him
and finding a job, you know? I
think
that it's really fascinating to
see that career pivot
happening right at the pandemic
and then that journey to find
the first job.
Dan: Yeah, totally.
Reda: Hi.
Dan: A-a-and he's- he's one of
the fewer people I've
talked to recently who is
self-taught but didn't go the
bootcamp route, right? He- he
followed freeCodeCamp and a lot
of, just, self-guided things.
And-- I don't know. I mean,
it's- it's really
great hearing from somebody who
had-- kind of did the
self-driving, you
know, educations route and--
Bekah: Yeah, the importance-
Dan: [Chuckles] I don't know.
[Unintelligible].
Bekah: -of community as part of
that, right?
Like, he talked a lot about
Virtual Coffee — being a part of
that, freeCodeCamp, Collab Lab,
and all of the ups and downs
that you
have as a self-taught learner,
and how important it is to have
community as part of that. So I
felt like this really captured
the essence of Virtual Coffee
and what we're trying to do
here.
Dan: Absolutely.
Bekah: We start every episode of
the podcast like we start every
Virtual Coffee. We introduce
ourselves with our name, where
we're from, what we do, and a
random check-in question. We
hope you enjoy this episode. Our
random check-in question today
is, what
is your third space? So the
space where you feel like you
belong,
something that's not home or
school. I give you a second to
think
about that while I do my intro.
My name is Bekah. I am
Developer Experience Lead at
OpenSauced. I'm from a small
town in
Ohio, and my third space, I feel
like the woods is a good place.
It's like the woods are the
library because those have
always
been places that I've loved
since I was a kid, and I could
just go,
like, hike, or explore, or sit
and read a book for hours. And
those
have always been, like, very
comforting spaces for me.
Dan: Nice. Yeah. Hi, I'm Dan. I
do front-end development or
whatever-- full stack
development? I don't know. I- I
made a decision
earlier to just say I do full
stack even though I don't like
that phrase. But it is something
that more accurate to what I do.
So, anyway--
oh, Cleveland area, and-- yeah.
I mean, I-- I'd say the woods
in general as well. Maybe
specifically, like, we have a-
a-- my
family has a cabin out in
Pennsylvania. But I'm really
comfortable in any- any-
anywhere I have a backpack on
and, [chuckles] you know,
maybe my pet-- my tent with me.
The woods-- the woods are good
for, like, all the reasons you
said, honestly. And e-exploring
especially is one of my-- one of
my favorite things to do. So,
yeah.
And-- yeah. So, introducing our
guest, Reda, go ahead.
Reda: I am Reda. I am a
front-end developer based in
Morocco. And
my third place is, I think, I'll
go with the- the sea. Back in
college, I used to have this
coffee shop. It's, like, in
front of
the-- of the beach to be more
accurate. And I used to
hang out there a lot. Yeah.
Bekah: That sounds awesome. I
love it. Well, thanks so much
Reda for
being here with us today. We're
happy to have you on the pa- the
podcast. I like went-
Reda: Yeah.
Bekah: -Midwestern. The padcast
[chuckles]. I'm not [chuckles]--
I'm from Eastern
Ohio. We don't say it like that
here, I apologize [laughs]. And
we always
like to get started with your
origin story. So I know that you
have a really fascinating one.
So why don't you let us know,
like,
what you were doing before you
came into tech and what the
journey was like to getting your
first job.
Reda: Yeah, sure. I was in the
marine big-- mechanics field.
So, like,
I used to go for-- in the
fishing ships. But I didn't
really, like, start working. I
just had training there. But,
like, my education was focused
on that, on the ma- marine
mechanics. So during
my-- during my graduation, the-
the pandemic hit. So--
yeah.
It hit when I-- when I was
preparing for my final projects
for the graduation. My final
project was kinda like related
to, programming? Not really. But
I had some parts of the pro-
programming
in it. It was kinda like a- a
black box to me. I didn't
really, like-- I can say this. I
wasn't really working on the
programming part, but I was
curious about it. So I had-- I
was doing some, like, simulation
with MATLAB. I don't know if
you've ever heard of that. It's
like a software for simulation
but it- it has some stuff, like,
with programming in it. But I-
I- I
didn't think I really touch it.
I was just copy paste the code
there, working [??] with
it. Also, I had some- some
classes, like, in the-- some
classes
back in college related to basic
algorithms and- and I-- if I
remember good, C++. And I really
liked them. So from there, it
started, like, my- my passion,
too, and, like, my interest in
programming. So after
graduation, the-- I- I- I hadn't
really a lot to
do. Because the pandemic, I'm
stuck at home. There's nothing I
can do.
So I started, like, searching
about these things, that it was,
like,
just a black box for me. I
started with machine learning,
which is kinda like weird
[laughs]. It's-- I don't know. I
was just looking for
something to start with, you
know? And one course on Coursera
has MATLAB and also, like, the
stuff, so I just started with
machine
learning. After that-- machine
learning-- like, in that
course, they were using MATLAB.
But they-- after finishing the
course, they said that, like,
Python is much better. And if
you
wanna, like, learn more about
this stuff, you should, like, go
with- with Python. So I started
Python after machine learning
[chuckles],
even though I didn't really do
anything with machine learning.
It was just, like, out of
curiosity. Just, like, how
things
work. I started that course on--
like, "Python for Everybody" on
Coursera. It was really good,
and the- the teacher is really,
like,
amazing. The most, like-- it's-
it's the-- I can't remember the-
the name. I think Dr.Chuck? I
can't remember the name.
Anyway-- but
the course is, like, "Python for
Everybody", it was really
amazing.
And-- but after I finished that
course, I really didn't know
what to do with it. So I have
the knowledge, I have the basic
knowledge but I have no idea
what to do with it because,
like, Python
is more for backend and it
wasn't any visual, like,
feedback for me.
And they're more vis- like, a
visual person. So I started,
like,
to search for something, like,
that has more interactivity.
So I do something and then see
the results in front of me. So
more like a visual feedback as I
said. And during my search,
I was mainly searching for free
stuff because I- I wasn't
working, I was totally relying
on my parents [laughs]. So--
yeah. And I
found freeCodeCamp. So
freeCodeCamp, and from there,
the-- like, the
real journey started. So the--
just like the first challenge in
freeCodeCamp, you just do, like
... like small challenge, and
you see the result in front of
you, like, in the same moment,
and
that was amazing. It was like,
"Oh, wow. I- I did something,"
you know?
Even though I spent maybe three
months on the-- on the
specialization of Python, I
never felt the same when I--
when I saw
the results in front of me,
like, in- in the same moment.
Yeah. So I
finished freeCodeCamp, and after
that, I just was-- yeah. I was
just, like, building projects
until I got into The Collab Lab.
And after The Collab Lab, I got,
like, my job directly after
that, like, after finishing The
Collab Lab. Yeah.
Bekah: Awesome. Thanks so much.
It's such an interesting story
to
hear that. And that process of
where you were in university and
what brought you to here-- I'm
curious, what kind of projects
were you working on in between
the end of freeCodeCamp and
Collab Lab?
Reda: Yeah. I- I was mainly
doing, like, the- the
freeCodeCamp
projects because the- the
problem was in the-- in
freeCodeCamp--
it's not a problem, but it's
just more of like the hard
part on freeCodeCamp is all the
learning is ... is text based,
you know? So it was kind of like
hard to understand some parts.
So I was, like, going to look on
YouTube, and on different blog
posts, and so on, and, like,
keep, like, re- revising what I
was doing
before. And then I'm back to
the-- to projects on
freeCodeCamp.
So I did the projects on
freeCodeCamp and then I was
looking for, like, projects on
YouTube, projects on, you know--
but- but that's the-- that's
tutorial hell. So [laughs]--
yeah. It was
pretty much hard to get out of
it. It's-- the hardest part
was--
the hardest part was when you
just look at the screen and you
don't know, like, from where to
start. But the built end
projects
in freeCodeCamp were pretty
much, like, they- they give you
the ... what you have to do, you
know, like, steps. They don't
give you,
like, what you have to do but
what's you are supposed to do.
So,
like, the- the steps of the- the
process. So my projects mainly
were freeCodeCamp projects plus
some YouTube tutorials and so
on. And then, I was, like,
trying to improve the- the
projects I worked
on. So that's what I was doing.
I was, like, going in some areas
that I didn't touch during
freeCodeCamp, like testing,
accessibility, and so on.
Accessibility was covered in
freeCodeCamp but testing wasn't.
And I also was feeling, like,
the gaps because, I- I did — you
can say it's one of my mistakes
when I was learning — is the--
that I was trying to be fast, to
be like,
"Just finish this, finish this,
finish this, and go on." And
that,
like, left, like, some gaps in
the fundamentals. So-- yeah.
Projects
will help you fill out that kind
of gaps. I think I didn't really
answer your question [laughs]
but-- yeah.
Bekah: Well, I think you
definitely answered the
question. And I
think that's really important,
that idea of going through too
fast and having those learning
gaps. And I think that I also--
I went to bootcamp and it took
me a year. But I-- you know, I
was
working at a slower pace and I
still think it was a little bit
too fast for me too. And I did--
I had done a full stack program
after doing a portion of
freeCodeCamp. And there was just
so much material to get through
in that time period, but I
wondered-- I was, like, ready to
move on to the next phase of my
life,
right? Like, ready to get a job.
And I- [chuckles] I remember
thinking
afterwards like, "Oh, once I get
done with this, it's gonna be
easy." And, like, [chuckles] I
don't know why I thought that.
But then, you start
your first job, you're like,
"Oh, that was the easy part and
now I've hit the hard part." And
I don't know if that resonates
with you or your experience in
Collab Lab, maybe filled in some
of those gaps and helped with
that, but I'm curious if- if you
had any of that experience too.
Reda: Yeah. There, at The Collab
Lab, I learned a lot, like,
mainly learned how to
collaborate because being a
self-taught developer are
working by
yourself. Like, 100% by
yourself. So you don't know how
to use, like--
not really how to use GitHub,
but how to use some features of
GitHub. So you don't know how to
open a pull request, you don't
know how to fix conflicts, you
don't know how-- yeah, you got
me. So-- yeah. Actually, like,
the Virtual Coffee, like,
Hacktoberfest challenge already
helps me with GitHub. Like, I
got familiar with GitHub a
little bit and I make some
contribution. But
it's different on The Collab Lab
because you are working-- like,
for over two months, you are
collaborating with three peoples
and you have mentors also, like,
they are helping you--
Bekah: What you said also really
resonated with me because I
went to a bootcamp but it was
self-paced. So I wasn't working
with other people either. And I
remember-- so, for anybody that
doesn't know, Dan was the first
person to hire me out of
bootcamp. And we were, like,
going through all of this stuff,
and--
actually, it was four years ago.
I think I started July 1st--
anyway, side- side note
[chuckles]. But-
Dan: Long ago.
Bekah: -[chuckles] it-- I
remember he- he was walking
me through it. He was like,
"Yeah, you just work through the
issue
and then when you're done, you
create a pull request." And I
was
like, "Okay. I know what a pull
request is. I've done that once
or
twice [laughs]." But, like, now,
I'm like, "Okay, that seems like
something
that's really basic." But even
in bootcamp, I was working on my
own
projects. And so I wasn't making
pull requests. I- I once-- so,
when I
built my first website, it was
my blogs, okay? And so I'm
writing these blogs but I didn't
even know that you could run it
locally. And so I was just,
like, pushing everything live,
and then
looking at it, seeing what
worked and what didn't, and
then, like,
recommitting. I-- actually all
that commit history is still
there. So
anybody can go and- and see what
[laughs]-
Reda: Yeah.
Bekah: -what that process was
like. It- it
was a lot of, like, the basics.
What- what I would see now as
basics of writing commit
messages, committing
frequently, running things
locally to test [chuckles] it
before it goes live,
and pull requests. Like, none of
that stuff was natural to me
after that experience or really
emphasized as part of the
process. And you were talking
about freeCodeCamp because
you're not really making pull
requests there. And even-
Reda: Yeah.
Bekah: -when I did
the projects, I was doing them
in CodePen and- and-- so there's
not branches or any concept of
that kind of stuff. And that's
integral to being able to work
as part of a team.
Reda: Yeah. I- I had this funny,
like, the same issue. It's funny
because I was working most of my
projects, like, in freeCodeCamp
at first, like, on CodePen. So
after, like, the first time, I
wanted to, like,
do my project locally. I didn't
know how to do it. So [laughs]--
yeah. That's
also part of, like, filling the
gap. It's- it's the very, very
of the
basics, but it's-- that you--
that-- it's- it's hard when you
are a self-taught.
You just don't know where to go.
It's-- like, you- you don't
have a plan, you know?
FreeCodeCamp make it easier, but
still,
there- there are some gasp--
there are some gaps that you-
you just
don't know. Like, you- you
didn't even know them to fix
them, you know?
Bekah: Right.
Reda: But-- yeah. But when you
are, like, interaction with
other
people-- so, here it come the
roles of communities and-- The
Collab Lab,
Virtual Coffee. When you're
interacting with people, you see
their problems, you see what
they are doing, and you're
learning
from them, and you got some
guidance.
Bekah: Yeah, I feel like I also
formed some bad habits during
that time period because I was
just working by myself. And-- so
I didn't know that there were
other ways of doing things. And
that was also something that I
had to kind of navigate and work
through. And I don't know if you
had that experience as well.
Reda: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, the same
here. It was of lots of things
that you do. For example, I- I
didn't even know that you can
fork a repo, you know? So
[chuckles] it was, like, if I
wanted to do something with her,
I would just try to push
directly to it. It doesn't
matter if- if
it's mine or if it's someone's
projects, so-- yeah. Yeah. It-
it- it
also, like, when you are coding,
you don't know if what you are
doing is the right way, you
know? Or if it's the best way
and so on.
Dan: Yeah, totally. I-- there's
so many valuable aspects of
having, you
know, working together on a team
with some people, even if
you're-- or- or just having
extra eyes on it, right- right?
Like- like
you were saying, you- you just
don't know-- you can hope that
you--
whatever you're doing is the
best way, you know? But having-
having extra people, it-- it's
just always so valuable. And
whe- as far
as, you know, some of the open
source stuff, you know, like,
forking, right? Like, I have
been working on- on GitHub in
my, like,
small team for work, for years,
before I ever forked any
repositories, right? Because if
you're on-- if you're in an
organization, you don't need
necessarily to fork-- you know,
create your own forks. You- you-
you just create branches and do
that stuff. So I was comfortable
with that but I had not- not,
like,
ever done that whole flow,
right? Until-- honestly, until--
I mean, I think I'd done it a
little bit before Virtual
Coffee but I
really, you know, actually
understood it much better
[chuckles] once we
got into Virtual Coffee, and
started doing some of those open
source contributions, and--
yeah. There's just-- there's
just--
when you're-- when you're by
yourself as a solo person, it
can be fun and it can be
interesting. But-- yeah. I
always had that
sense, I'm sure there's
something missing [laughs]. I'm
sure there's some,
you know, some pieces that I'm-
I'm not seeing or- or whatever.
And it's- it's just so nice to
be able to have other people
are,
like, hanging around and- and-
and, you know, working together
on- on things.
Reda: Yeah. I think that the
first repo I- I forked was
Virtual Coffee, like, repo. Yeah
[chuckles].
Dan: It's a good one.
Bekah: And that- that [laughs]--
and that's one of the reasons
why our documentation for
Virtual Coffee-- to contribute
is very thorough. Like, maybe
it's
a little bit too thorough. I'm
not sure. But because a lot of
the
people that are contributing are
in the same situation that we
have both been in where we don't
have that experience of forking
or what is a commit? How do you
create a branch? And just to
make
sure that we're able to support
those people as part of that
process and decrease the
friction for people to be able
to contribute, I think is really
important. And- and the same
thing goes for people who have
been working for years. But like
Dan said, they- they don't have
to fork anything. I just taught
an
intro to open source workshop a
couple of weeks ago and I had to
talk about forking a repository.
And so I, like, went through and
I practiced because I honestly
don't know when the last time I
had to fork a repository was.
And- and it is those little
things
that become really important.
And- and so I wanted to
know — this
is, like, my very longwinded way
[chuckles] of saying — you
talked
about this open
source experience that you had
and you participated
Hacktobershi-
you're- you're rocking your
Hacktoberfest shirt today-
Reda: Yeah.
Bekah: -which is awesome. But
can you talk a little bit about
where that was
at in your journey and what
kinds of things that you were
able to accomplish during that
Hacktoberfest?
Reda: Yeah, sure. It's- it's
actually was, like, after
finishing,
like, freeCodeCamp. It's-- I- I
was in a-- okay. This is, like--
just, like, side story. It's
not, like, really answering the
question. So the-- I- I was
pretty much desperate after
finishing
freeCodeCamp. I had HTML, CSS
knowledge, basic knowledge.
I had JavaScript knowledge. But
I didn't know how to connect,
like,
between them. I- I had no idea
how-- okay. There is HTML, CSS,
there is
a JavaScript, but I had no idea
how to use both of them. And on
freeCodeCamp, it wasn't there
anything also, you know? So
after JavaScript, there is
directly React-- actually,
front-end
libraries. So I- I was lost. I
was totally lost. I was
desperate.
And at that moment, I was
actually thinking to give up
because,
you know, imposter syndrome. I
was thinking that I'm low and I
don't know how to do things. So
I- I was thinking, "Maybe,"
like, "it's
not for me," you know? Even
though it has nothing to do with
me, I
just lack something, you know?
There is something missing and I
don't know about it. So I posted
in the freeCodeCamp forum about
it. So I- I said-- I- I
literally saying like, "I am
done. I'm about to
give up and I don't know what to
do next. I have no idea." And
people there were very
supportive, you know?
They — thanks for
them by the way — they were--
they were very supportive and
they told me like, "You just
need this-- the- the document
objects
model. DOM. So you can, like--
for manipulating, like, the HTML
documents, and the browser
document, and so on." So-- and
why
I'm telling you this story is
because at that same thread,
Jessica told me about Virtual
Coffee. And when I joined
Virtual
Coffee after that, directly,
like, you were doing the
Hacktoberfe-
the Hacktoberfest, like,
challenge. And from there, I got
some energy. Yeah. I- I did-- I
did something and, like, I was,
"Yeah,
I'm- I'm able to do this. I can
do this." So, back to the
Hacktoberfest story. Well
[chuckles]-- yeah. So, for
Hacktoberfest, I had-- I had a
mentor assigned, Justin. He was
pretty much helpful. He told--
like, he told me a lot of stuff
about, like, commits, how to
fork, how to set up a stream,
just lots of information. I
don't
remember that [chuckles]. I was
like, "Okay. This is-- this is
exciting," you
know? "[Chuckles] Exciting and
at same time, scary." All-- I
didn't know all of
that. I didn't know anything.
So, yeah. He was, like-- he
taught
me all of that stuff and, like,
give me some resources to- to
search for open source projects.
But the hardest part
about that is finding issues.
That's was the-- yeah. And
that's
an- that's another thing. So
when you don't find issues or
you--
there- there is-- there are
issues, but the most of them you
don't,
like, you don't know how to do
them. So I- I- I got, like,
frustrated again. So I don't
[chuckles]-- like, it's-- you
think that it's you
who don't know anything but
actually, the- the tech industry
is pretty, like, much broad, you
know? There- there are a lot of
stacks, there are a lot of
things that you don't know of
course.
So-- yep. After that, I was,
like, searching for things
that I know-- I know how to do.
So I was searching for some
issues, I found, like, some,
like, small projects. They are--
they were--
maybe they were also learners.
They weren't, like- like, a big
companies or anything. Maybe
they were also learners or
something
like that. So I- I found this
small [??] projects. Like,
people
that own that small projects.
And I worked on small issues,
for
example, adding local storage to
a to-do app. It was something
out of my comfort zone but also,
like, I know-- I- I- I know that
I can
do it, you know? So I did some
of those issues and I also did
one maybe for Virtual Coffee--
or two, I can't remember. Yeah.
But that actually boost my- my,
like, self-confidence, you know?
I- I can
do stuff than-- and- and that's
what I was lucky than before,
when I was
just by myself. Like, every
time-- every time I don't know
how to
do something or-- I'm- I'm
blaming myself. And- and that
was, like, the darkest points.
Yeah.
Dan: I think any developer who's
been developing for an
amount of time has gone through
those- those- those times. I
know I
have a bunch of times over my
career. And I- I thi- I mean,
I'm
glad-- I just wanna say thank
you for sharing that because
it's-
it's- it's good for people to
hear because-- especially when
you
are, like, you-- like, a lot of
us are at the beginning kind of
by
yourselves and on your own. It
can be hard to know that- that
sort of
thing is pretty common [laughs].
I feel like that-
Reda: Yep.
Dan: -feeling of- of "I don't
know how to do this. I don't
know how to do anything", you
know, is un- unfortunately, I- I
guess, a part of this-- part of
this, like,
world as far as I've can tell
[laughs]-- and from my own
experience and my--
experience of m-most of my
friends. It-- i-it's, like, you
just
come across those- those times,
you know? And I think it's a
sign,
honestly. I-- it's a sign that
you're pushing yourself, you
know, and
trying to learn more. And I
think it's, in general, a good
sign,
although it's not ever fun when
you're-
Reda: Yeah.
Dan: -in the middle of it
[laughs].
Reda: Yeah.
Dan: I think it's-- I think it's
a good sign because it means
you're-
you're-- you know, you're
learning, right? And you're
trying
things that you don't know
necessarily how to do it at the
beginning. And that's- that's
something that- that, by myself,
I've- I've run into as well as I
realized that I'm just, like,
have
been very comfortable for a long
time, you know, and just doing
the same things. And so-some of
it is a little bit boring but--
or-- like,
there's a little bit of boredom
that sits in but it's mostly
just
this sense-- again, it's that
sense, you know, that you were
talking
about, where you know that
there's something out there
[chuckles] that you probably-
Reda: Yeah.
Dan: -could be doing better, or
probably could be doing
differently, or a-anything like
that. And it-- and for me, it
kind of
creeps up on me. But then you--
once you start, like, stretching
out again, you are risk-- run
the risk of running into those
feelings again [laughs]. So
it's- it's a never ending cycle,
you know? But
I think it's a healthy one, in
general. And I think it
sounds like the ways that you've
gotten through it are good in
healthy ways, you know, to do
it, you know? Finding
communities,
and finding people to work with,
and-- I don't know, everything
like that.
Reda: Fi- finding inspiration
also, like, there are some
people in communities like that.
They- they just inspire you and
you wanna, like, be like them,
you know? That keeps you, like,
to-
to push yourself, like, harder
and just to not give up. Yep.
Dan: Yeah, absolutely.
Bekah: Okay. So I wanna move
forward just a little bit on
this journey cuz I know that
there's-- okay. So you did
freeCodeCamp,
you did Collab Lab, and then
you're interviewing for jobs. At
what point did you decide, "I'm
ready to interview for a role,"
and then what- what did that
journey look like?
Reda: Yeah. Well, I would-- if
I-- if I wa- if I didn't join
[chuckles]
Virtual Coffee, again [laughs],
I would never apply for jobs, I
think. I remember my
first-- my first, like, Coffee
chat was- was about my-- I put
the question about-- I asked a
question about this-- about when
you are ready to apply for jobs.
And someone told me,
"Yesterday."
And- and-- yeah. And- and I- I--
that clicked, you know? So you-
you just
need to apply. You will never
feel ready. It's, again,
im-imposter
syndrome, again. You will never
feel that you are ready. You
will
never feel that you know enough
to apply for job. So-- yeah. I
think after- after, like,
freeCodeCamp, directly, like--
not
directly, but after finishing
some React projects, after I had
some React knowledge, I started
applying for jobs. That's also
as a pretty much hard. It was,
like, the- the worst period I
think,
again, with frustration. And
whenever I get a rejection,
I blame myself. I take it
personally, you know? Yep. So
whenever I- I get rejection, I-
I just, like, drop everything
for two
days [laughs]-- two or three
days. I just drop everything and
do nothing because
it was, like, hard on me, you
know? Because you- you kinda--
you don't know if the path you
choose is correct, you know?
There is
this- this- this doubt about
will you ever-- will you ever be
able to
do it, you know? There is also,
like, the- the- the society,
like,
pression, you know? You are--
you are, like, without a job.
You-
you studied and you are doing
nothing. It's not nothing. You
are,
like, you are actually, like,
studying another thing. But
what--
at-- there is always that
question, "What if I failed?"
You know? And
rejections always remind- remind
me of the-- of failing, you
know, of the
end. If- if maybe-- if- if- if
it wasn't, like, the- the right
path. If all what I was doing is
just [chuckles]-- how I can say
it? Yeah. I guess you got me
[laughs].
Bekah: Oh. I definitely get
that. And it-- I even-- when I
was laid off
earlier this year, that-- it was
such a weird space to be in.
I'd never
been laid off before and I was
like, "I don't know. Maybe I
should
just not be in tech," like,
"maybe this isn't for me," you
know? And
it- [chuckles] it really messes
with your head, I think, when
you start to
second guess yourself and- and
you feel that rejection in some
way,
whether or not, you know-- I
went through layoffs, they said
it was
restructuring or whatever. So
there was nothing that implied
like, "You did a bad job, so you
got fired," right? Or maybe the
pandemic hits and you lose your
job for a little while. But
it-- no matter what, all of
those things still feel-- they
don't feel
good and they make you question
like, "Is this the right place
for me?" And so, can you talk a
little bit more about how you've
navigated those frustrations?
Cuz I know it's really hard out
there for job seekers now,
especially for folks looking for
their first-
Reda: Yep.
Bekah: -job in tech.
Reda: Yeah, sure. I mainly was,
like, taking rest as I said
before. Like, if-- [chuckles] I
don't know if this is, like-- if
this is really the
good way to go but I was doing
that. I was taking rest for--
so, for
a day, for two days, I just
don't do anything just to- to
get to myself, you know? Because
trying to learn new things or
trying to do, like-- or trying
to, like, prepare your resume,
or
your cover letter, or whatever
you are doing to-- for the job
hunting
while you are in a bad state of
mind, when you're, like, so
frustrating, it would just make
it worse, you know? And- and I
even did
experience that. So for example,
if I got a rejection and I try
to apply for another job, like,
the same day or something like
that, I- I find myself for--
okay. For- for example, if I try
to-
to apply to- to a job, I- I will
just, like, look. And they will
say, okay, I am unqualified, you
know? I'm not good for- for
applying
for this. So that rejection will
affect you. So what I was doing
is just, like, resting a little
bit, maybe try to focus on
learning
new things. Yeah. That-- that's
it mainly. And-- yeah. I will
try to
came up with something else. I
can't [chuckles]- I can't think
of any right now.
Bekah: I love that. I think that
it can be really hard to take a
rest and then what you do is
just burn yourself out during
the job search. And that idea of
learning something new I think
is really
good. Because you also start to
feel like stagnant when all
you're doing is applying for
jobs and so you're not learning.
And there's-- I don't wanna say
a balance cuz I don't know that
there can be balance when you're
interviewing for a role. But it-
it helps to keep your morale up,
I think, a little bit when you
can
see like, "Hey, I did this thing
today and now I know something
new," versus, "I did these
interviews today and I didn't
get a job,"
which feels bad. So you gotta,
like, fill up that win bucket a
little bit somehow, and it's
often not going to be through
interviewing.
Reda: Yeah. I was also, like, in
the meanwhile, like,
preparing for quizzes for
interview questions. So it was--
I think that the hardest part in
this part of the journey is to-
to, as you said, is to have a
balance between learning, and
applying for roles, and, like,
studying for interviews. It's-
it's- it's just a mess
[chuckles]. But one thing also
that helps me is
the community, again. So being
inside the community, you see
that
there are a lot of people like
you, you know? And the moment
they got
the-- their first job or they
got the-- anyway, when- when-
when they--
when they get their, like, the--
their dream job or whatever,
it's- it's, like, kind of a
motivation to you. So, again,
[chuckles] finding community is,
like, the-- was the key.
Bekah: Yeah, I think that's so
important. And so, how did you
end up landing the job that
you're currently at now?
Reda: Yeah. I- I consider
myself, like, lucky [chuckles],
I guess. So I- I
didn't actually apply for the
job I am currently at right now.
So they find me through GitHub.
They, like-- they put, like, a
query search
there. So, you know, GitHub have
this- this query search, you
know? So
you can put queries and you can,
like, search for- for some
criteria, you
know? And I was-- yeah, again, I
was lucky that I was part of
those people. So they contact me
on LinkedIn-- ah, sorry. I-
I was lucky that I was part of
the result of the search
[laughs]. Yeah. So,
they contact me, like, on
LinkedIn, and they said, "Hi, we
find your
profile interesting, and we
would like to talk about the
...," yeah. So I
said, "Okay, we can talk." We-
we, like, schedule, like, a
meeting. I
thought it was just a meeting to
talk about, like, how things
will
go, you know? What's they're
looking for, what they are, and
so
on. But it turns out, like, it's
an interview and [laughs]--
yeah. But it was
pretty much smooth. They- they
were, like, cool people. It was
pretty much smooth because-
because I-- when I asked how,
like, they choose me, actually
they said, like, they- they-
they went
through the code, actually, you
know? They went through my code,
they went through my projects.
So I think that the process of
hiring is- [chuckles] is the
main cause why I- I am where I
am right now. Yeah.
So I-- it's may not be the- the
case for- for everyone, but just
put
yourself out there, you know? If
you have any projects, even if
they are small or if they are,
like, really not that
interesting.
I don't wanna say that they're
not interesting but just put
your
projects out there. Put them on
Twitter, GitHub, everywhere.
And-- yeah. That's it. So--
anyway, sorry, I [laughs]--
Bekah: Don't be sorry.
Reda: Yep. So after the
interview, I-- they actually,
like, just sends me the- the
offer. Yeah.
Bekah: Wow.
Reda: Yeah, it was pretty-- so
they-- it was kinda like the-
the moment
they contact me, they already
made their mind that they're
gonna
hire me. So it was just about if
I say yes or no. So-- yeah.
Bekah: That's awesome. Is it a
company in your country?
Reda: Yeah, it's in my country
but it's remote. It's 100%
remote.
So yeah. It was actually too
good to be true. So [laughs]--
Bekah: [Chuckles] I almost [??]
like- like the idea of a
surprise interview cuz
then you're not really nervous
if you just think that you're
going
in to talk to them and then
they're [chuckles] like, "Oh,
surprise interview." And you're
like, "Well, I didn't have the
last three days to panic. So I
guess, here I am." Like
[laughs]--
Reda: Yeah, yeah. But- but it-
it wasn't any hard, you know? It
was more of a discussion than an
interview, you know? But it- it-
it was, like, the first and the
final [laughs]. So it's-- it
was pretty much good.
Because I had-- previously, I
had some pretty much bad
experience with going through
three interviews and in the end
getting, like, rejected. So--
[chuckles] yeah.
Bekah: Do you-- did you find,
like, living in Morocco, that
the job search was even more
challenging if you were looking
for remote work?
Reda: It was more challenging
for me because I didn't have--
I didn't have a degree, you
know? I didn't have a degree in
computer science. I have a
degree in marine mechanics, but
not in computer science. And in
Morocco, it's- it's kinda-- I
di- I wasn't
even applying for jobs in
Morocco because I thought it's-
it's impossible for me to get a
job here.
Bekah: Wow.
Reda: As most of companies, they
are, like, asking for a degree,
you know? And the funny thing
is, during my interview with my
current company, the first thing
I
said is, "I don't have a degree.
Just for information, I don't
have
a degree in computer science."
But surprisingly, they said
like,
"What matter is talent and not,
like, a piece of paper." And
that
was, like-- e-even if I didn't,
like, get in the- the company,
that was a boost for me. Yeah.
Bekah: That's awesome.
Dan: It's good to hear. I mean,
that- that- that aligns, I
think, with a lot of the people
that I end up, [chuckles] you
know, enjoying working
for, right? The- the degrees
are-- I don't know. It's-- it
almost
seems silly sometimes. I mean,
not that getting a degree is
silly.
But, like, the idea that in our
field, a degree after four
years,
I feel like is going to be so
out of date [chuckles] to be
almost-- I-- not
useless, obviously. You-- like,
in college, I think the
important
thing is to, like, learn how to
learn, right? That's- that's
more--
you know? But at the same time,
somebody with a- a certain
amount of experience is going to
have the same, if not a better,
you know, handle on all that
stuff than somebody who just-
Reda: Yeah. Yeah.
Dan: -going [??] to college, you
know?
Reda: That's- that's a good
point because that-- the current
company, like, they told me that
they interview, like, people
with degrees and, like,
engineers, you know, like,
before me. But the-
the only difference is I had
projects. I had, like-- I know
how to
search for information and how--
I know how to learn by myself.
Yeah. And, like, one of the plus
for me is that I was a
self-taught
developer. So they know, like,
they- they won't need-- it--
it's just a sign that you can
learn by- by yourself, you know?
Dan: Yeah, a hundred percent
with that. I mean, that-- that's
always-- that's always gonna be
a- a point in your favor in my
book.
Just-- I mean, as a self-taught
developer myself [laughs], you
know? I mean,
but I know-- I understand, like,
what the struggles are and,
like,
how much it takes to continue
through that process, you know,
and that career. And so I--
that-- that's-- I was just glad
to hear
that, you know [chuckles], you
found a place that- that
respects that sort of thing-
Reda: Thank you, thank you.
Dan: -because it-- it's not
always, you know, it's- it's--
you're not-- not
everybody's gonna feel the same
way and-- I don't know. It's
nice
to hear when- when that sort of
thing works out well like it has
in your case.
Reda: Yeah.
Bekah: Well, Reda, we wanna
thank you for being here with us
today.
Are there any new-- last words
of advice that you have for our
listeners about their job search
or being self-taught?
Reda: Yeah. Thanks for having
me. And I know, like, the- the
situation in the US — I don't
know if it's in all the world
[??] — but it's
pretty much tough with the--
with all the layoffs happening--
the
layed offs happening. So-- yep.
Stay- stay strong, and you can
do it. Yeah.
Dan: Okay. Alrite. Well, cool.
Well, thank you, Reda, for
joining us so
much and-- yeah. We will catch
everybody next week. Alrite.
Thanks, Reda.
Bekah: Bye.
Reda: Thank you.
Dan: Thank you so much for
listening to this episode of the
Virtual Coffee Podcast. This
episode was produced by Dan Ott
and Bekah Hawrot Weigel, and
edited by Ashley Mulder. If you
have questions or comments, you
can hit us up on Twitter
@VirtualCoffeeIO or email us at
podcast@virtualcoffee.io. You
can find the show notes, sign up
for the newsletter, buy some VC
merch,
and check out all of our other
resources on our website,
virtualcoffee.io. If you're
interested in sponsoring Virtual
Coffee, you can find out more
information on our website at
virtualcoffee.io/sponsorship.
Please subscribe to our podcast
and be sure to leave us a
review. Thanks for listening and
we'll see you next week.